<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html</id>
    <title>Industry Feed</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T22:08:43.724Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS urges more women to take up cervical screening invitations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247993</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-urges-more-women-to-take-up-cervical-screening-invitations/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T23:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of women are being urged to come forward for cervical screening as figures show a third of eligible under 50s didn’t take up the potentially lifesaving offer. The latest figures show that as of December last year, 65.8% of the 11 million eligible women aged 25-49 took up their cervical screening invitation and were screened within […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chair announced for PrimaryCareLearnings 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876967</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/chair-announced-primarycarelearnings-2024/article/1876967"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T16:09:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join Dr James Waldron, GP Educator  and Portfolio GP for this free, face-to-face, educational meeting in September]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Child death overview panels: contacts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T15:26:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Contact details of the people in child death overview panels (CDOPs) who are responsible for receiving child death notifications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic referral system switched off after ‘continuing’ IT issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150056</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/electronic-referral-system-switched-off-after-continuing-it-issues/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:59:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An electronic referral system has been turned off for SystmOne practices in Essex after it kept crashing practice computers putting clinical data at risk. The Local Medical Committee said they had campaigned for TPP’s iRefer system to be switched off completely after months of problems with no solution in sight. In a letter to practices,
The post Electronic referral system switched off after ‘continuing’ IT issues appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synnovis cyber attack – statement from NHS England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248025</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/synnovis-cyber-attack-statement-from-nhs-england/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:54:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 3 June, Synnovis, a pathology laboratory which processes blood tests on behalf of a number of NHS organisations, primarily in South East London, was the victim of a cyber attack. NHS England has been made aware that a cyber criminal group published data last night which they are claiming belongs to Synnovis and was […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice forced to close after car crashed into its building]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150070</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/premises/gp-practice-forced-to-close-after-car-crashed-into-its-building/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:53:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP practice in Hereford had to close and cancel appointments after a car crashed into the front of its building. West Mercia Police told Pulse that the force was called to a report of a car that ‘had collided’ with the surgery building on Eastholme Avenue in Belmont around 10.30am yesterday (20 June). Belmont
The post GP practice forced to close after car crashed into its building appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why our high-performing practice in a deprived area had to close]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149952</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/the-very-last-resort-handing-back-our-contract/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:23:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, the East Barnwell Health Centre in Cambridge announced it was handing back its GMS contract after years of financial struggles. Here, the partners share their story with Pulse. Last week we – the partners at East Barnwell Health Centre – announced we were handing back our GMS contract. It was a devastating decision
The post Why our high-performing practice in a deprived area had to close appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What health and care need from the next government: #4 – improving access to treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/what-health-and-care-need-from-the-next-government-4-improving-access-to-treatment.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/what-health-and-care-need-from-the-next-government-4-improving-access-to-treatment.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - The fourth briefing in this series looks at waiting times for health care – the biggest cause for public dissatisfaction with the NHS and a central battleground of this election. It suggests seven tests that must be met which should be put to politicians as they battle to convince the public they have the answers. Briefing Nuffield...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Draft joint UK asthma guidance promises major changes to practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878082</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/draft-joint-uk-asthma-guidance-promises-major-changes-practice/article/1878082"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T12:51:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Draft NICE/BTS/SIGN advice on asthma backs changes to prescribing and use of diagnostic tests that are likely to have a major impact on clinicians.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patient data published online following south east London cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177763</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/patient-data-published-online-following-south-east-london-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T12:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyber criminals have published patient data online which they claim was stolen as part of an attack on Synnovis, NHS England has confirmed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP concern as cyber criminals publish alleged NHS patient data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150045</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gp-concern-as-cyber-criminals-publish-alleged-nhs-patient-data/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T11:15:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The perpetrators of a recent cyber-attack on a pathology laboratory have published data which they claim belongs to NHS patients. NHS England is investigating this as a ‘matter of extreme urgency’ to determine the content of the files and establish whether NHS patients have been affected. GP practices in London continue to be impacted by
The post GP concern as cyber criminals publish alleged NHS patient data appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accelerating transformation: how to develop effective NHS-industry partnerships]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/accelerating-transformation-how-to-develop-effective-nhs-industry-partnerships.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/accelerating-transformation-how-to-develop-effective-nhs-industry-partnerships.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T11:13:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - This guidance aims to understand and unblock the barriers to making the potential of partnership a reality – exploring issues such as culture, trust and the challenge of stepping outside health system operational norms. It seeks to support the NHS and industry to develop, contract, implement, measure and deliver effective partnerships. It was jointly developed by the...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How likely is a general election to transform health and social care?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-likely-is-a-general-election-to-transform-health-and-social-care.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-likely-is-a-general-election-to-transform-health-and-social-care.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T10:50:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The King's Fund - Nicholas Timmins looks back at the last three big political transitions to ask - how fast might things change for health and social care? Long read The King's Fund - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[West Hertfordshire Teaching rolls out OptiRad radiology tech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177699</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/west-hertfordshire-teaching-rolls-out-optirad-radiology-tech/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T10:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[West Hertfordshire Teaching Hospital NHS Trust has rolled out Hexarad technology which aims to boost the performance of its radiology departments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitor social media for abusive patients, LMCs advises GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149838</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/special-investigations/gp-abuse/monitor-social-media-for-abusive-patients-lmcs-advises-gps/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T10:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[London GP leaders have urged practices to be ‘proactive’ in monitoring threats of patient abuse, including via social media and the design of their premises. They warned that a ‘failure to pro-actively engage’ with patients on social media ‘risks damage to the practice’s local reputation’ which could lead to more frustrated patients. In a new
The post Monitor social media for abusive patients, LMCs advises GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visits To NHS Website’s Hay Fever Page More Than Double]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247991</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/visits-to-nhs-websites-hay-fever-page-more-than-double/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T09:14:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The number of hay fever sufferers searching for NHS advice has more than doubled in the past week as temperatures rise across England. The NHS website has received an average of 11,736 visits a day since Monday compared to a daily average of 4,749 visits at the weekend – an increase of 147%. Visits to […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fifth of partners employing physician associates say they can't afford GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877934</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/fifth-partners-employing-physician-associates-say-cant-afford-gps/article/1877934"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T08:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One in five GP partners who have worked with physician associates (PAs) say they did so because they couldn't afford to recruit GPs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health’s monthly roundup of contracts and go lives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177667</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-healths-monthly-roundup-of-contracts-and-go-lives-41/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T07:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This roundup features new standard infusion pump software at Alder Hey Children’s Hospital and a new EPR for Kent Community Health’s sexual health service.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 80% of GP locums ‘cannot find work’, BMA survey finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150014</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/more-than-80-of-gp-locums-cannot-find-work-bma-survey-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 80% of GP locums have reported that they ‘cannot find work’, a BMA survey has revealed. A survey of 1,852 locum GPs in England found that that four out of five (84%) are struggling to find work and that more than 50% are ‘expecting to make changes’ to their careers ‘in the next
The post More than 80% of GP locums ‘cannot find work’, BMA survey finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP careers derailed as four in five locums can't find work, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877937</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-careers-derailed-four-five-locums-cant-find-work-bma-warns/article/1877937"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than four in five locum GPs in England are unable to find work or struggling to find enough, according to BMA polling that sheds new light on the impact of underfunding in general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP careers derailed as most locums can't find work, BMA poll shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877937</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-careers-derailed-locums-cant-find-work-bma-poll-shows/article/1877937"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than four in five locum GPs in England are unable to find work or struggling to find enough, according to BMA polling that sheds new light on the impact of underfunding in general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP career plans derailed as most locums can't find work, BMA poll shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877937</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-career-plans-derailed-locums-cant-find-work-bma-poll-shows/article/1877937"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than four in five locum GPs in England are unable to find work or struggling to find enough, according to BMA polling that sheds new light on the impact of underfunding in general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-awaited joint asthma guidance overhauls diagnostics and treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150012</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/long-awaited-joint-asthma-guidance-overhauls-diagnostics-and-treatment/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T16:02:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Long-awaited new draft UK joint guidelines on asthma care overhauls recommended diagnostics and treatment, but the review committee warned they will require ‘significant investment’. Draft NICE/BTS/SIGN guidelines on diagnosis, monitoring and management of asthma recommends significant changes to current treatment approaches, including replacing the use of short-acting beta agonist (SABA) alone with combined inhaled corticosteroid
The post Long-awaited joint asthma guidance overhauls diagnostics and treatment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS delivers 4 million spring covid vaccines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247986</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-delivers-4-million-spring-covid-vaccines/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T15:39:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 4 million people have now received their spring covid booster from the NHS just 10 weeks after bookings officially opened as part of the latest vaccination campaign. Around 7 million people are eligible for a spring covid jab this year, including those aged 75 and over, those with a weakened immune system and older […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Under the radar: Cauda equina syndrome case]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149829</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/musculoskeletal-rheumatology-sports-medicine/under-the-radar-cauda-equina-syndrome-case/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T15:33:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the first of a new series into diagnoses that could easily be missed, Dr Sharon Viner recalls when she spotted a care of cauda equina Clinical history A 30-year-old man was seen by the musculoskeletal team for acute on chronic low back pain radiating down his right leg to his foot. The back pain
The post Under the radar: Cauda equina syndrome case appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redirect ARRS and Pharmacy First funding to core GP, says DAUK manifesto]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149992</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/redirect-arrs-and-pharmacy-first-funding-to-core-gp-says-dauk-manifesto/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T14:41:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next Government should reallocate ARRS and Pharmacy First money to restore GP core funding, the Doctors’ Association UK has recommended in its election manifesto. The DAUK’s GP committee issued a 10-point manifesto to ‘relieve the pressure on general practice’, which was presented to prospective MPs during a webinar yesterday. It said that the next
The post Redirect ARRS and Pharmacy First funding to core GP, says DAUK manifesto appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse needs you: write for our new series]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149987</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/special/opinion/pulse-needs-you-write-for-our-new-series/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T14:15:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse is looking for your contributions! We have three new series to support and inform GPs, and we are looking for case studies and suggestions from readers.  The communication breakdown service A brand new column where readers can write in with real-life communication issues they have had at work. Anything from ‘I have an angry
The post Pulse needs you: write for our new series appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO issues warning on falsified medicines used for diabetes treatment and weight loss]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5a193851-d89b-4005-8476-84da5508f2c0</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/20-06-2024-who-issues-warning-on-falsified-medicines-used-for-diabetes-treatment-and-weight-loss"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T12:46:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) issued a medical product alert on falsified semaglutides, the type of medicines that are used for treatment of type 2 diabetes and obesity in some countries.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do the last five years measure up on levelling up?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-do-the-last-five-years-measure-up-on-levelling-up.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-do-the-last-five-years-measure-up-on-levelling-up.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T12:31:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Fiscal Studies - Five years ago, then Prime Minister Boris Johnson made ‘levelling up’ a central plank of the Conservative Party’s bid for re-election, with a manifesto pledge to ‘level up every part of the UK’. In 2022, the government published a thorough and ambitious White Paper setting out 12 levelling up ‘missions’ to achieve by 2030, as...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MHRA issues transparency guidance for machine learning medical devices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177609</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/mhra-issues-transparency-guidance-for-machine-learning-medical-devices/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T12:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) has published guidance on transparency for machine learning medical devices.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS App after the pandemic]]></title>
        <id>e1a8f60e-a136-47af-87f2-816581178f62</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/transformation-blog/2023/the-nhs-app-after-the-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T12:04:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Susie Day, Programme Director for the NHS App, looks at what’s changed since the app’s launch in January 2019 and how its services are evolving post-COVID.


NHS 75 is an incredibly proud moment for me and, I hope, for all the people who work so hard across the NHS and its wider ecosystem to provide care for patients up and down the country.


In the lead up to the NHS 75 celebrations, I have reflected on what has changed since NHS 70 and, particularly, about the evolution of the NHS App since its launch at the beginning of 2019.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How much funding does the NHS need over the next decade?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-much-funding-does-the-nhs-need-over-the-next-decade.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-much-funding-does-the-nhs-need-over-the-next-decade.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T11:08:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This long read projects a potential £38bn shortfall in the funding needed to improve the NHS by the end of the next parliament. With the pledges made by both the main political parties so far falling a long way short of this, the analysis raises questions about the trade-offs facing the next government in balancing the...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177359</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-147/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Digital Health's coffee time briefing includes a sustainability win for Swansea Bay University Health Board with a digital app.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177359</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-200624/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Digital Health's coffee time briefing includes a sustainability win for Swansea Bay University Health Board with a digital app.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP demands halt to recruitment of physician associates amid safety fears]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877810</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/rcgp-demands-halt-recruitment-physician-associates-amid-safety-fears/article/1877810"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:08:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP has called for an immediate halt to recruitment of physician associates (PAs) in general practice after a consultation found half of GPs were aware of 'specific examples' in which work by these staff had compromised patient safety.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCP president to step down over physician associate fallout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149964</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/rcp-president-to-step-down-over-physician-associate-fallout/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:08:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The president of the Royal College of Physicians (RCP) will step down following pressure from senior college officers and fellows over the college’s handling of the physician associate (PA) debate. Yesterday Dr Sarah Clarke informed the RCP Council of her intention to ‘step aside’ from the role of president ‘following a challenging time for the
The post RCP president to step down over physician associate fallout appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking: RCGP advises GP practices to halt PA recruitment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149965</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/breaking-rcgp-advises-gp-practices-to-halt-pa-recruitment/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP has urged GP practices across the UK to ‘halt’ recruitment of physician associates (PAs) until the profession is regulated later this year. This recommendation is based on ‘concerning findings’ from the RCGP’s recent consultation, which surveyed over 5,000 GPs and found that over 80% believe the use of PAs in general practices has
The post Breaking: RCGP advises GP practices to halt PA recruitment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ascom signs contract with Children’s Health Ireland to implement ANMS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177581</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/ascom-signs-contract-with-childrens-health-ireland-to-implement-anms/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ascom is to implement its Alerts and Notification Management System at the new Dublin children’s hospital as part of a deal with Children’s Health Ireland.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors offer government last chance to avert this month's strikes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877777</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/junior-doctors-offer-government-last-chance-avert-months-strikes/article/1877777"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T08:55:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors have written to prime minister Rishi Sunak offering him a final chance to make an improved offer on pay to avert their next five-day strike that starts on 27 June.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atos denies that financial issues could have ‘severe’ effects on NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177561</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/atos-denies-that-financial-issues-could-have-severe-effects-on-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T07:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French IT giant Atos has denied reports that it is facing financial issues that could severely impact the NHS and other public services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better-paid APMS provider to pilot new care model after partners hand back contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877656</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/better-paid-apms-provider-pilot-new-care-model-partners-hand-back-contract/article/1877656"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A popular practice forced out of business by underfunding will be replaced by a better-paid APMS provider piloting an untested new model of care, in a move GP leaders say raises 'grave concerns' for the future of general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS faces £38bn annual funding shortfall by end of next parliament]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877683</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-faces-38bn-annual-funding-shortfall-end-next-parliament/article/1877683"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS funding could fall £38bn short of the level needed to meet rising demand and deliver key improvements over the next parliament, policy experts have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PAs aren’t the enemy – this is a systemic issue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149959</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/pas-arent-the-enemy-this-is-a-systemic-issue/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T16:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Jaimie Kaffash argues that the toxicity of the debate around physician associates is detracting from the structural problems I’ve always believed that ‘punching down’ is reprehensible. And the whole debate around physician associates does make me feel uncomfortable. I say this having run a seven-part analysis and investigation into the role of physician associates
The post PAs aren’t the enemy – this is a systemic issue appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP fury as Creon shortages leave patient at risk of hospitalisation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149513</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gp-fury-as-creon-shortages-leave-patient-at-risk-of-hospitalisation/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T15:13:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP in Sheffield has told Pulse of her fury at ongoing drug shortages, after a vulnerable patient was left at risk of hospitalisation because no supplies of Creon (pancreatin) could be sourced. Dr Sarah Jones, a GP partner at the Norwood Medical Centre, said they a patient with learning disabilities who lives in a
The post GP fury as Creon shortages leave patient at risk of hospitalisation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP concerns around PAs need to be ‘seriously addressed’, says Streeting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149892</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gp-concerns-around-pas-need-to-be-seriously-addressed-says-streeting/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T14:12:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP concerns around the role of physician associates (PAs) need to be ‘seriously’ addressed, according to the shadow health secretary. However, PAs do ‘have a role to play’ in primary care, and should not be ‘thrown out with the bathwater, Wes Streeting added. Speaking at a Medical Journalists’ Association (MJA) event on Monday evening, he
The post GP concerns around PAs need to be ‘seriously addressed’, says Streeting appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chad eliminates human African trypanosomiasis as a public health problem]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:2565a01b-a1d7-4c47-abcb-57f79a517258</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/20-06-2024-chad-eliminates-human-african-trypanosomiasis-as-a-public-health-problem"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T13:02:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) congratulates Chad for having eliminated the gambiense form of human African trypanosomiasis, also known as sleeping sickness, as a public health problem. It marks the first neglected tropical disease to be eliminated in the country.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wales sets out to create a single national clinical data repository by 2030]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177517</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/wales-sets-out-to-create-a-single-national-clinical-data-repository-by-2030/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T12:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health and Care Wales (DHCW) has set out a mission to join up data by ensuring it flows to and from the National Data Resource (NDR) platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Providers deliver: achieving value for money]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/providers-deliver-achieving-value-for-money.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/providers-deliver-achieving-value-for-money.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T12:03:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This report shows how hospitals, mental health, community and ambulance services are finding new ways to provide better care and value for money. It says that the efforts of trusts must be matched by a commitment from government for capital investment to modernise buildings, equipment and technology in order to unlock greater productivity gains. It finds that...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Productivity in the NHS and health care sector]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/productivity-in-the-nhs-and-health-care-sector.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/productivity-in-the-nhs-and-health-care-sector.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T11:22:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The King's Fund - Productivity is one way people measure the performance of a sector – it compares the growth in the quantity of outputs to the growth in the quantity of inputs. This explainer looks at what productivity is and how different bodies measure health care productivity in England in different ways. The King's Fund - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wes Streeting slams ‘glacial’ pace of FDP adoption]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177511</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/wes-streeting-slams-glacial-pace-of-fdp-adoption/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T10:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow health secretary Wes Streeting has criticised the “glacial” pace of adoption of the NHS Federated Data Platform (FDP).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICB to continue Fuller-lauded funding model despite GP criticism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148217</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/icb-to-continue-fuller-lauded-funding-model-despite-gp-criticism/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T09:38:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new GP funding model based on population need has been awarded money to run until next year, despite facing criticism from local GPs. The pilot run by Leicester, Leicestershire and Rutland ICB – whereby the cost-of-staff element in the Carr-Hill formula calculation has been replaced with a needs-and-deprivation element – had been lauded in
The post ICB to continue Fuller-lauded funding model despite GP criticism appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS dementia services ‘cannot meet need of newer treatments’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149764</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/nhs-dementia-services-cannot-meet-need-of-newer-treatments/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T09:29:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS dementia services will need to make big changes to identify which patients may be eligible for new disease-modifying therapies likely to be available later this year. Currently less than 1% of patients in NHS memory clinics had amyloid biomarker testing performed, and this will need ‘urgent’ service development if patients are to access newer
The post NHS dementia services ‘cannot meet need of newer treatments’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over half of job-seeking GPs are ‘struggling’ to find role, finds RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149924</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/over-half-of-job-seeking-gps-are-struggling-to-find-role-finds-rcgp/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T09:14:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six out of 10 GPs looking for jobs ‘are struggling to find vacancies’, a new poll of RCGP members has shown. The college said that 61% of the survey respondents who had looked for a GP role in the NHS over the past year found it ‘moderately difficult’ or ‘very difficult’ to find ‘an appropriate
The post Over half of job-seeking GPs are ‘struggling’ to find role, finds RCGP appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unemployment 'scandal' as most job-seeking GPs struggle to find work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877621</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/unemployment-scandal-job-seeking-gps-struggle-find-work/article/1877621"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T08:50:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six in 10 GPs looking for jobs have struggled to find a vacancy to apply for in the past year despite record workload in general practice, a shocking RCGP poll reveals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour promises brighter future for GPs and condemns 'failure to listen' on PAs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877603</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/labour-promises-brighter-future-gps-condemns-failure-listen-pas/article/1877603"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T08:41:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice 'will do well under a Labour government' if the party wins the general election, shadow health and social care secretary Wes Streeting has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EHR system restored at Ascension following cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177451</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/ehr-system-restored-at-ascension-following-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T07:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US non-profit health system Ascension says that its electronic health records system has been restored across following a ransomware incident in May 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General practice ‘will do well’ under Labour, Wes Streeting promises]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149881</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/general-practice-will-do-well-under-labour-wes-streeting-promises/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice ‘has a lot to look forward to’ should Labour win the upcoming general election, the shadow health secretary has said. Wes Streeting was speaking at an event organised by the Medical Journalists Association in London yesterday evening, when he said that general practice ‘will do well’ under a Labour government. He also said
The post General practice ‘will do well’ under Labour, Wes Streeting promises appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting to the heart of peer-to-peer recognition]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/getting-to-the-heart-of-peer-to-peer-recognition.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/getting-to-the-heart-of-peer-to-peer-recognition.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T16:10:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - Barts Health NHS Trust (BHT) recently launched a new programme of recognition based on feedback following engagement with its workforce. One of the big changes was the introduction of a recognition platform, with the main aim of enabling staff to benefit from visible and meaningful recognition from their peers. The new scheme allows peer-to-peer recognition for those...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sessional GPs should not be expected to supervise ARRS staff, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149822</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/sessional-gps-should-not-be-expected-to-supervise-arrs-staff-says-bma/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:51:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supervising non-doctors should not form part of a sessional GP’s job description ‘unless expressly and mutually agreed’, according to new advice from the BMA. The union said that with the ‘expansion’ of the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) and the ‘diversification of the workforce’, GPs have seen a ‘dramatic increase’ in supervision responsibilities expected of
The post Sessional GPs should not be expected to supervise ARRS staff, says BMA appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pain killers don’t exist – so how can we help patients in pain?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149648</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/david-turner/pain-killers-dont-exist-so-how-can-we-help-patients-in-pain/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:47:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on a new campaign for patients with opioid dependency issues, Dr David Turner asks how GPs can best help those in need ‘Pain killers don’t exist.’ I thought this a rather curious statement for pharmacists to make, given that a significant proportion of their work is concerned with the dispensing of medication that does
The post Pain killers don’t exist – so how can we help patients in pain? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4513 - Broadcom Releases Critical Security Updates for VMware vCenter Server and Cloud Foundation]]></title>
        <id>360252d5-33e5-45b7-9a9c-b789f094f355</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4513"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisory addresses three vulnerabilities that could result in privilege escalation or remote code execution
 Advisory addresses three vulnerabilities that could result in privilege escalation or remote code execution
 Updated: 18 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA calls for investment to solve other pay disputes as SAS doctors accept uplift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877551</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-calls-investment-solve-pay-disputes-sas-doctors-accept-uplift/article/1877551"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:22:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Specialist and associate specialist (SAS) doctors have voted to accept a proposed pay uplift for 2023/24 - as the BMA said the 'right offer' could end disputes with other doctors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One in six adults go without prescription medicines due to supply issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877528</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/one-six-adults-go-without-prescription-medicines-due-supply-issues/article/1877528"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:20:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One in six UK adults report going without prescription medicines over the past two years due to ongoing supply issues, with more than a third blaming Brexit, new polling has revealed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSDG warns 150,000 patients to assume data has been published]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177423</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhsdg-warns-150000-patients-to-assume-data-has-been-published/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T12:29:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Dumfries and Galloway is warning around 150,000 patients to assume that their personal data is likely to have been stolen and published online.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[District nursing today: the view of district nurse team leaders in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/district-nursing-today-the-view-of-district-nurse-team-leaders-in-the-uk.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/district-nursing-today-the-view-of-district-nurse-team-leaders-in-the-uk.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T11:09:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Queen's Nursing Institute - Over 1500 district nurse team leaders from all countries of the UK contributed to the report, through an online survey undertaken in 2023. The survey makes extensive comparison with data gathered in 2019, illustrating trends in the workforce since the Covid-19 pandemic. The report focuses on the demographic profile of the workforce, working practices and...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How can the next government improve the health of the workforce and boost growth?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-can-the-next-government-improve-the-health-of-the-workforce-and-boost-growth.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-can-the-next-government-improve-the-health-of-the-workforce-and-boost-growth.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:54:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This general election briefing explores how the government can set the conditions for a healthy labour market for the long term. Briefing]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the month: What is the cause of this patient’s confusion?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149860</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/case-of-the-month-what-is-the-cause-of-this-patients-confusion/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:45:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the third of our monthly series, Dr Roger Henderson is asking readers to suggest what is the cause of this patient’s confusion and change of mood. Put your answers in the comments. Answers to be revealed on 20 June! The case A 38-year-old man had been experiencing anxiety, anger outbursts and some hallucinations over
The post Case of the month: What is the cause of this patient’s confusion? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE asks ICBs to ‘referee’ hospital/GP workload dump situations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149725</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/referrals/nhse-asks-icbs-to-referee-hospital-gp-workload-dump-situations/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:43:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has asked ICBs to act as ‘referees’ to resolve ‘tension’ between primary and secondary care around workload and referrals. NHSE deputy medical director Dr Kiren Collison said there is ‘a lot of tension at times between primary and secondary care’ and that NHSE is ‘trying to get away from that’. Speaking at the
The post NHSE asks ICBs to ‘referee’ hospital/GP workload dump situations appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177273</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-146/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:30:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Coffee Time includes Birdie being named one of the 500 fastest-growing tech companies and development of AI tech to predict heart events.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reform UK pledges private GP for patients left waiting for appointment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149852</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/reform-uk-pledges-private-gp-for-patients-left-waiting-for-appointment/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:19:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reform UK has pledged to give patients a ‘voucher for private treatment’ if they cannot see a GP within three days. Nigel Farage launched his party’s manifesto, which he called ‘Our Contract with You’, at an event in Wales on Monday.  He called for an ‘absolutely radical rethink’ of the way public services are run,
The post Reform UK pledges private GP for patients left waiting for appointment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most London GP practices 'feel unable to deliver safe care']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877499</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/london-gp-practices-feel-unable-deliver-safe-care/article/1877499"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:14:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most practices in London feel 'unable to deliver care that is either safe for patients or staff', GP leaders have warned as they launched resources to support safe working.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI-powered physio platform to be deployed in the NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177327</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/ai-powered-physio-platform-to-be-deployed-by-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI-powered physio clinic, Flok Health is planned to be rolled out in the NHS by Autumn 2024, with the aim of cutting physiotherapy waiting lists.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland’s blood transfusion service goes live with Clinisys WinPath]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177337</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/northern-irelands-blood-transfusion-service-goes-live-with-clinisys-winpath/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T07:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland's blood transfusion service has migrated to Clinisys WinPath, with the aim of creating a single technology platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delivering a general practice estate that is fit for purpose]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/delivering-a-general-practice-estate-that-is-fit-for-purpose.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/delivering-a-general-practice-estate-that-is-fit-for-purpose.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T15:58:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Government - GPs often work in buildings that are too cramped, too old and too inflexible for a modern health service – with a quarter of GPs’ buildings built before the NHS was founded. This report warns that the next government will need to urgently address the crumbling general practice estate. Report More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reform manifesto promises tax cuts for NHS staff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877384</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/reform-manifesto-promises-tax-cuts-nhs-staff/article/1877384"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T15:34:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Reform party has promised to scrap basic rate tax for health and social care staff for three years and write off student fees in return for NHS service as part of its general election manifesto.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS removes patient-facing material referring to PAs as ‘physicians’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149798</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/nhs-removes-patient-facing-material-referring-to-pas-as-physicians/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:57:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors have criticised ‘dangerous’ NHS posters which referred to physician associates (PAs) working in GP practices as ‘physicians’.  The posters formed part of a campaign developed by the Bradford branch of West Yorkshire ICB, aimed at helping patients to better understand new roles in general practice. The campaign material also referred to ‘cancer specialists’ working
The post NHS removes patient-facing material referring to PAs as ‘physicians’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The impact of hardship on primary schools and primary and community healthcare]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/the-impact-of-hardship-on-primary-schools-and-primary-and-community-healthcare.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/the-impact-of-hardship-on-primary-schools-and-primary-and-community-healthcare.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:42:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joseph Rowntree Foundation - Across Britain, millions of people are experiencing hardship, by which we mean they are going without basic essentials such as enough food, heating and appropriate clothing, because they cannot afford them. This report asks what impact hardship is having on the delivery of services in primary schools and primary and community healthcare setting such as GP...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA lists steps practices could take as part of collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877357</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-lists-steps-practices-part-collective-action/article/1877357"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:33:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has set out 12 steps practices could take as part of collective action later this year, as voting opened in a ballot of the profession.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA lists 12 steps practices could take as part of collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877357</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-lists-12-steps-practices-part-collective-action/article/1877357"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:33:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has set out 12 steps practices could take as part of collective action later this year, as voting opened in a ballot of the profession.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hematologic Cancer Opportunities for Patient Equality (HOPE)]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/hematologic-cancer-opportunities-for-patient-equality-hope.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/hematologic-cancer-opportunities-for-patient-equality-hope.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:25:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IQVIA Institute for Human Data Science - This report aims to quantify the trends around the availability and use of therapies for hematological malignancies across selected countries (including the United Kingdom) with reported oncology therapy access challenges and disparities. Trends in overall regulatory approvals, health technology assessments, reimbursement, and final therapy usage have been analyzed for drugs indicated in hematological...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICBs ‘increasing pressure’ on GPs to boost patient records access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149817</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/icbs-increasing-pressure-on-gps-to-boost-patient-records-access/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practices are under ‘increasing pressure’ from their ICBs to boost the number of patients with online access to medical records, according to GP leaders. Despite this pressure, the BMA’s GP Committee reminded practices that any ‘mitigations’ identified by their Data Protection Impact Assessment (DPIA) should be followed in order for records access to be ‘legal’.
The post ICBs ‘increasing pressure’ on GPs to boost patient records access appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General election 2024: the health and care manifesto pledges]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/general-election-2024-the-health-and-care-manifesto-pledges.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/general-election-2024-the-health-and-care-manifesto-pledges.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:03:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The King's Fund - This resource is intended as a summary of the commitments the three largest parties in England have made for the NHS, social care and public health in their manifestos, associated costing documents and media reports ahead of the general election on 4 July. Long read]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debate: Will AI replace clinicians?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148011</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/debate/debate-will-ai-replace-clinicians/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T13:52:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of the ongoing conversation of artificial intelligence in healthcare, two GPs debate whether or not AI is a threat to the workforce YES: ‘AI will replace clinicians and reduce the workforce to 10% of what it currently is’ Like it or not, artificial intelligence is becoming an increasingly dominant force in healthcare, and
The post Debate: Will AI replace clinicians? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 800 operations postponed since London cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177335</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/more-than-800-operations-postponed-since-london-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T12:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 800 planned operations and 700 outpatient appointments were rearranged in the week following a cyber attack on Synnovis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs urged to vote ‘yes’ to collective action as BMA ballot opens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149807</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gps-urged-to-vote-yes-to-collective-action-as-bma-ballot-opens/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T11:06:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are being urged ‘take a stand’ and vote ‘yes’ to collective action, in a BMA ballot opening today.   The union is currently planning for potential GP collective action to commence on 1 August, depending on the result of the ballot which will close on Monday 29 July. In the ballot, GP partners are being
The post GPs urged to vote ‘yes’ to collective action as BMA ballot opens appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs urged to back collective action as BMA ballot opens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877288</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-urged-back-collective-action-bma-ballot-opens/article/1877288"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:47:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have urged the profession to vote in favour of collective action over 'derisory' funding uplifts for general practice, as a BMA ballot opened on 17 June.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How PAs can be a successful part of an MDT]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149808</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/special-investigations/how-pas-can-be-a-successful-part-of-an-mdt/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:47:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse’s review into the role of the physician associate has highlighted issues around GP recruitment and clinical risk. Now, Stephen Nash, Chief Executive of UMAPs, puts forward the positives of having PAs in a multi-disciplinary team It has been glaringly obvious for some time that one narrative regarding physician associates (PAs), and medical associate professions
The post How PAs can be a successful part of an MDT appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Semaglutide can sustain weight loss for four years and cut CVD risk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147623</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/semaglutide-can-sustain-weight-loss-for-four-years-and-cut-cvd-risk/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:46:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weight loss in patients with semaglutide can be sustained for up to four years, according to results from the SELECT study presented at the European Congress on Obesity and published in Nature Medicine. A second as yet unpublished analysis from the same trial also presented at the conference found it delivered cardiovascular benefits irrespective of
The post Semaglutide can sustain weight loss for four years and cut CVD risk appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ming Tang announced as keynote at AI and Data 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177319</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/ming-tang-announced-as-keynote-at-ai-and-data-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ming Tang, the national leader at the forefront of the NHS’ data revolution in England, returns as national keynote at Digital Health AI and Data 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How much spending on the NHS have the major parties committed to in their election manifestos?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-much-spending-on-the-nhs-have-the-major-parties-committed-to-in-their-election-manifestos.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-much-spending-on-the-nhs-have-the-major-parties-committed-to-in-their-election-manifestos.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T09:54:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - To help inform the debate around the imminent general election, this explainer looks at the manifesto commitments that have been made on NHS spending by each of the main parties. How do they stack up, and what would it mean in practice for the NHS budget in coming years if their commitments were enacted? Explainer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 general election: manifesto briefing]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/2024-general-election-manifesto-briefing-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/2024-general-election-manifesto-briefing-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T09:51:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This briefing provides a summary of the main health and social care commitments, and other relevant policy commitments, made by the Liberal Democrat, Conservative, and Labour parties. Briefing More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP services 'staggering under the weight of hardship' among patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877257</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-services-staggering-weight-hardship-among-patients/article/1877257"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T09:35:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP services are 'staggering under the weight of hardship' among their patient populations, often directly providing food banks, facing increased workload and struggling to cope with patients unable to follow medical advice because of poverty, a report shows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs recognised in King's birthday honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877241</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-recognised-kings-birthday-honours/article/1877241"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T09:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs, including King Charles's GP and the GP who is head of the Royal Medical Household, have been recognised in the King's birthday honours list.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lewisham and Greenwich NHS Trust goes live with CardMedic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177309</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/lewisham-and-greenwich-nhs-trust-goes-live-with-cardmedic/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T07:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthcare translation app CardMedic has been downloaded by nearly 400 members of staff at Lewisham and Greenwich NHS Trust since its roll out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA roadshow diary: GPs 'angry and exhausted', says Dr David Wrigley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877170</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-roadshow-diary-gps-angry-exhausted-says-dr-david-wrigley/article/1877170"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With a ballot on collective action in general practice opening this month, BMA England GP committee leaders are touring the country to talk to the profession. Deputy chair Dr David Wrigley writes about pressures on general practice after roadshows in Stafford and Warrington.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff among those recognised in 2024 King’s Birthday Honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247740</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-staff-among-those-recognised-in-2024-kings-birthday-honours/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T21:39:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff including paramedics, nurses and doctors are among dozens of frontline workers recognised in the 2024 King’s Birthday Honours list, released today (Friday 14 June). The head of the NHS, Amanda Pritchard, has said the awards recognise the dedication and skill of NHS staff. Among the staff recognised for their hard work and dedication […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: Birthday Honours 2024: Ambulance Service list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/birthday-honours-2024-ambulance-service-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/birthday-honours-2024-ambulance-service-list"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T21:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recipients of the King's Ambulance Service Medal 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO concerned about escalating health crisis in West Bank]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5ce74b93-7081-41fc-bbf9-c59567f952db</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/14-06-2024-who-concerned-about-escalating-health-crisis-in-west-bank"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T19:24:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO remains concerned about the escalating health crisis in the occupied Palestinian territory, including the West Bank, where attacks on health infrastructure and increased restrictions on movement are obstructing access to health care.  

A spike in violence in the West Bank, including East Jerusalem, since the war in Gaza started has resulted in the deaths of 521 Palestinians, including 126 children between 7 October 2023 and 10 June 2024. In addition, over 5200 people, 800 of them children, have been injured, adding to the growing burden of trauma and emergency care at already strained health facilities.

As of 28 May, WHO has documented 480 attacks on health care in the West Bank since 7 October 2023, resulting in 16 deaths and 95 injuries. The attacks affected 54 health facilities, 2…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SystmOne investigates IT crash issue with diagnostic test ordering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149778</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/systmone-investigates-it-crash-issue-with-diagnostic-test-ordering/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T15:48:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practices are being asked to provide more information about a SystmOne issue that has been causing computers to crash when clinicians try to order diagnostic tests. In a letter to practices, Mid and South Essex ICB said all practices had been reporting IT systems crashing when printing out pathology forms but this had now extended
The post SystmOne investigates IT crash issue with diagnostic test ordering appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PAs ‘small but important’ part of workforce plan, says NHS chief]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149792</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/pas-small-but-important-part-of-workforce-plan-says-nhs-chief/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T15:33:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Physician associates (PAs) are a ‘small but important’ part of the NHS workforce plan and ‘crucially’ need to be ‘well-supported as colleagues’, NHS England’s chief executive has said. Speaking at the NHS Confederation Expo in Manchester earlier this week, Amanda Pritchard said that NHS England ‘must work’ with royal colleges and the GMC to ‘ensure’
The post PAs ‘small but important’ part of workforce plan, says NHS chief appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS is circling the drain – the care merry-go-round is exasperating]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149718</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/the-nhs-is-circling-the-drain-the-care-merry-go-round-is-exasperating/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T14:20:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Copperfield is fed up with the dizzying circus that is accessing care in the NHS, and the position in which it leaves GPs So proud of the NHS this week. And I’m sure you were, too, when you heard the widely reported story of how superbly the service dealt with a patient in Telford
The post The NHS is circling the drain – the care merry-go-round is exasperating appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integrated Care Systems report 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/integrated-care-systems-report-2024.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/integrated-care-systems-report-2024.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T13:53:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Association of Directors of Public Health - Integrated Care Systems (ICSs) were formalised across England as legal entities with statutory powers and responsibilities in July 2022. Directors of Public Health (DsPH) and their teams have adapted and sought to collaborate with ICSs effectively for the benefit of the health and wellbeing of local populations. This report summarises the results of...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What health and care need from the next government: general practice and dentistry]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/what-health-and-care-need-from-the-next-government-general-practice-and-dentistry.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/what-health-and-care-need-from-the-next-government-general-practice-and-dentistry.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T13:29:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - This briefing looks at general practice and dentistry, two of the most visible points of contact with the NHS, both of which are struggling to meet the needs of their patients. It suggests six tests for general practice and three for dentistry that the next government must meet to tackle the problems surrounding these services. Briefing Nuffield...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General election: The parties' pledges on general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877112</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-election-parties-pledges-general-practice/article/1877112"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T13:25:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPonline rounds up the key points on general practice from the Conservatives, Labour, Liberal Democrats, Green Party and Plaid Cymru manifestos.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kent Community Health sexual health service goes live with EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177225</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/kent-community-health-sexual-health-service-goes-live-with-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T12:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kent Community Health NHS Foundation Trust's sexual health service has implemented a new electronic patient record provided by Inform Health.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public harms: racism and misogyny in policing, education, and mental health services]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/public-harms-racism-and-misogyny-in-policing-education-and-mental-health-services.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/public-harms-racism-and-misogyny-in-policing-education-and-mental-health-services.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T11:41:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Black Equity Organisation - This project draws together women’s experiences across three themes: mental health, policing and education. It aims to amplify the experiences of Black women who face the greatest harm within these institutions while also connecting with the broader experiences of women from other backgrounds, to reimagine a feminist, anti-racist and anti-discriminatory model for public services. Report Black...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OOH provider tells GPs to review all patients seen by PA before discharge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149442</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/urgent-care/ooh-provider-tells-gps-to-review-all-patients-seen-by-pa-before-discharge/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:49:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out-of-hours GPs in Doncaster will now have to review ‘all assessments’ made by a physician associate (PA) before a patient is discharged, in a bid to address safety concerns.  Clinical leaders at FCMS, a provider of GP OOH services in Doncaster and across Lancashire, have ‘formally agreed’ the new policy following ‘concerns regarding legislation around
The post OOH provider tells GPs to review all patients seen by PA before discharge appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How much does your area rely on physician associates?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149745</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/special-investigations/the-rise-of-the-physician-associates/how-much-does-your-area-rely-on-physician-associates/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:43:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse’s analysis has shown the areas where physician associates are most likely to be employed. See how much your region relies on them Our investigation into the rise of the physician associates has revealed that, while numbers remain relatively low, they are increasing. The data analysis into what kind of practices and primary care networks
The post How much does your area rely on physician associates? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Warnings of rising cases of dengue fever in European countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149761</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/warnings-of-rising-cases-of-dengue-fever-in-european-countries/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:09:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public health officials have warned that cases of dengue fever in Europe are continuing to rise as climate change creates favourable conditions for invasive mosquitoes. Figures show that last year there were 130 cases of dengue acquired in a European country compared with 71 in 2022. Between 2020 and 2021 there were only 73 locally
The post Warnings of rising cases of dengue fever in European countries appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital platform offers online consultations with community pharmacists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177245</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-platform-offers-online-consultations-with-community-pharmacists/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new digital platform has been launched, allowing patients to book free online Pharmacy First consultations with community pharmacists.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Devastated' partners at highly-rated GP practice hand back contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876776</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/devastated-partners-highly-rated-gp-practice-hand-back-contract/article/1876776"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP partners at a highly-rated 8,000-patient practice in Cambridge have handed back their contract - warning that soaring premises fees and inadequate local and national funding left them no choice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calderdale and Huddersfield awarded HIMSS stage 6 for analytics capabilities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176865</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/calderdale-and-huddersfield-awarded-himss-stage-6-for-analytics-capabilities/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T07:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Calderdale and Huddersfield NHS Foundation Trust has achieved a stage 6 validation from HIMSS for its use of data and approach to data science.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: GP unemployment crisis, general election manifestos, physician associate regulation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876975</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-gp-unemployment-crisis-general-election-manifestos-physician-associate-regulation/article/1876975"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T07:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GPonline team discusses the latest news affecting primary care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO releases report on state of development of antibacterials]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:90da8491-404e-4d83-a3d5-bbe6d6f0cf8e</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/14-06-2024-who-releases-report-on-state-of-development-of-antibacterials"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T07:09:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today released its latest report on antibacterial agents, including antibiotics, in clinical and preclinical development worldwide. Although the number of antibacterial agents in the clinical pipeline increased from 80 in 2021 to 97 in 2023, there is a pressing need for new, innovative agents for serious infections and to replace those becoming ineffective due to widespread use. 
First released in 2017, this annual report evaluates whether the current research and development (R&D) pipeline properly addresses infections caused by the drug-resistant bacteria most threatening to human health, as detailed in the  2024 WHO bacterial priority pathogen list (BPPL). Both documents aim to steer antibacterial R&D to better counter the ever-growing threat of antim…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detention of United Nations and non-governmental organization personnel in Yemen]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:abd0e8c0-5908-4cb5-b332-44e90cbafb08</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/13-06-2024-detention-of-united-nations-and-non-governmental-organization-personnel-in-yemen"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T17:08:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We, the Principals of the affected United Nations (UN) entities and international non-governmental organizations (NGOs), call for the immediate and unconditional release of all personnel held in Yemen by the Houthi de facto authorities. 
We are extremely concerned about the Houthi de facto authorities’ recent detention of 17 members of our organizations [UN entities and INGOs] and many others associated with civil society organizations, national and international NGOs, and other organizations supporting humanitarian activities. 
These detentions are unprecedented – not only in Yemen but globally – and directly impede our ability to reach the most vulnerable people in Yemen, including the 18.2 million people who need humanitarian aid and protection.
We ask the de facto authorities to confirm the exact whereabouts of those detained and the conditions in which they are being held, as well as for immediate access to them. 
International law prohibits the arbitrary deprivation of liberty. International Humanitarian Law requires all parties to armed conflict to respect and protect humanitarian personnel, including against harassment, mistreatment, and unlawful arrest or detention. 
The targeting of humanitarian, human rights, and development workers in Yemen must stop. All those detained must be immediately released. 
 
Signed by:
Achim Steiner, Administrator, UNDP 
Amitabh Behar, Executive Director (interim), Oxfam International
Audrey Azoulay, Director-General, UNESCO 
Catherine Russell, Executive Director, UNICEF
Cindy McCain, Executive Director, WFP 
Inger Ashing, Chief Executive Officer, Save the Children International
Michelle Nunn, President and CEO, CARE
Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, Director-General, WHO
Volker Türk, United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights, OHCHR]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open consultation: Community water fluoridation expansion in the north east of England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/community-water-fluoridation-expansion-in-the-north-east-of-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/community-water-fluoridation-expansion-in-the-north-east-of-england"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T15:59:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government is seeking views on expanding community water fluoridation schemes in the north east with new arrangements or by varying existing arrangements.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General practice needs more GPs but must embrace reform, says NHS chief]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876958</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-practice-needs-gps-embrace-reform-says-nhs-chief/article/1876958"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T15:44:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice needs more GPs - particularly in some parts of the country - but must embrace reform to cope with rising demand, NHS England's chief executive has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How low-funded practices are more likely to rely on physician associates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149587</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/special-investigations/the-rise-of-the-physician-associates/how-low-funded-practices-are-more-likely-to-rely-on-physician-associates/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T14:56:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the fourth part of our series on the rise of physician associates, Madeline Sherratt and Jaimie Kaffash dig deep into the data to look at the characteristics of GP practices and PCNs that are more likely to employ PAs. And the results are illuminating… We have already reviewed the effect of physician associates on
The post How low-funded practices are more likely to rely on physician associates appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs asked to order alternatives as Sanofi’s QIVr flu vaccine unavailable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149751</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/vaccinations-prevention-screening/gps-asked-to-order-alternatives-as-sanofis-qivr-flu-vaccine-unavailable/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T14:50:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been advised they should order alternative vaccines from an approved list, after Sanofi told health officials their recombinant quadrivalent influenza vaccine would not be available for this year’s flu programme. The UK Health Security Agency confirmed to Pulse that an alternative has been secured to meet demand for flu vaccines this coming winter
The post GPs asked to order alternatives as Sanofi’s QIVr flu vaccine unavailable appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners protest against Palantir at NHS Confed Expo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177167</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/campaigners-protest-against-palantir-at-nhs-confed-expo/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T12:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demonstrators gathered outside the NHS Confed Expo conference to protest against its sponsorship by US data analytics giant Palantir.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4512 - MicroDicom Releases DICOM Viewer Software Update]]></title>
        <id>90e84f8a-cc60-4913-aab8-04a06d9e632c</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4512"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T11:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Low
 One vulnerability could allow an attacker retrieve and plant medical image files and another could lead to arbitrary code execution
 One vulnerability could allow an attacker retrieve and plant medical image files and another could lead to arbitrary code execution
 Updated: 13 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour manifesto promises reform to 'bring back the family doctor']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876885</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/labour-manifesto-promises-reform-bring-back-family-doctor/article/1876885"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T11:14:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Labour party has promised 'thousands more GPs' and to 'bring back the family doctor', with trials of new neighbourhood health centres to move care out of hospital in its general election manifesto.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour to ‘reform’ general practice with new ‘neighbourhood health centres’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149728</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/labour-to-reform-general-practice-with-new-neighbourhood-health-centres/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:54:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour’s manifesto has pledged to ‘reform’ primary care, trialling ‘neighbourhood health centres’ which would have GPs and other community health staff ‘under one roof’. According to the document, published this morning, ‘GPs are the front door to the health service for most people’, with ‘excellent primary care’ the ‘key to earlier diagnosis’. However it claimed
The post Labour to ‘reform’ general practice with new ‘neighbourhood health centres’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England must respond to GP unemployment crisis, senior official says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876880</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-england-respond-gp-unemployment-crisis-senior-official-says/article/1876880"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:45:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A senior NHS England official has said the health service must respond to the GP job shortage that has left thousands of GPs struggling to find work, and doctors about to qualify fearing for their futures.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workforce census reports]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/workforce-census-reports.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/workforce-census-reports.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:41:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Radiologists - These two reports - one on the clinical radiology workforce and the other on clinical oncology workforce - are based on surveys of cancer centre heads and clinical directors of radiology departments. They reveal concerns on the current state of cancer care in the UK due to workforce shortages. They conclude that delays in diagnosis...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176911</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing130624/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing includes the relaunch of System C's CareFlow EPR and an online genetic support programme for MSD from Sano Genetics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176911</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing includes the relaunch of System C's CareFlow EPR and an online genetic support programme for MSD from Sano Genetics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practices are paid 'less than the cost of an apple a day' per patient, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876873</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/practices-paid-less-cost-apple-day-per-patient-bma-warns/article/1876873"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:08:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices receive just 30p a day for every patient registered with them - less than the cost of the proverbial 'apple a day to keep the doctor away', a BMA campaign warns.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cancer treatment delays ‘have become routine and put patients at risk’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149722</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cancer/cancer-treatment-delays-have-become-routine-and-put-patients-at-risk/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:08:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delays in starting vital cancer treatment have now become ‘routine’ with hundreds of thousands of patients waiting longer than they should over the past decade. A report from Cancer Research UK found that 382,000 cancer patients in England were not treated on time since 2015. Only 66.6% of people in England received their diagnosis and
The post Cancer treatment delays ‘have become routine and put patients at risk’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS tech is at ‘tipping point’, says Amanda Pritchard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177161</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhs-tech-is-at-tipping-point-says-amanda-pritchard/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England chief executive, Amanda Pritchard said the NHS is at “a tipping point” when it comes to the use of technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lowest-funded GP practices have twice as many patients per staff as highest funded]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149663</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/lowest-funded-gp-practices-have-twice-as-many-patients-per-staff-as-highest-funded/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T09:41:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GP practices in the bottom 10% of funding per patient have around 1,200 patients per clinical staff member, compared with around 600 in the top-funded practices. Exclusive Pulse research, based on NHS Digital data, also found that in those practices in the lowest decile in terms of payments per patient, around 3.5% of medical
The post Lowest-funded GP practices have twice as many patients per staff as highest funded appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS continues to face record demand for services, new data shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247511</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-continues-to-face-record-demand-for-services-new-data-shows/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T09:37:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff continue to face significant demand for urgent care, with new figures showing that A&Es in England managed their busiest ever month for attendances in May. New monthly performance data also shows that it was a record April for the number of elective appointments delivered for hundreds of thousands of patients. The latest statistics, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital heart check service to integrate with NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177115</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-heart-check-service-to-integrate-with-nhs-app/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T07:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PocDoc's home testing kit for cardiovascular disease is to be integrated with the NHS App, allowing patients to see test results on their NHS patient record.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Myths and facts: HIV]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149679</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/sexual-health/myths-and-facts-hiv/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T16:25:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the third of a new series exploring some common misconceptions about conditions seen in general practice, GP Dr Toni Hazell debunks some myths about HIV – and explains some less well known facts Myths 1. Pre-test counselling is needed before an HIV test is requested We don’t all remember the stigma present in the early
The post Myths and facts: HIV appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greens pledge increased GP funding and ‘rapid access’ guarantee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149706</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/greens-pledge-increased-gp-funding-and-rapid-access-guarantee/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T15:15:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Green Party MPs elected on 4 July will ‘push for’ increased funding to primary care, with an aim for additional annual spending to reach £1.5bn by 2030. The Greens, which currently have just one member of Parliament, also said they want a ‘guarantee’ for ‘rapid access to a GP and same-day access in case of
The post Greens pledge increased GP funding and ‘rapid access’ guarantee appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4510 - Microsoft Releases June 2024 Security Updates]]></title>
        <id>1852598a-74ab-4f99-92a8-db9df9223437</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4510"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T14:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products, including security updates for 50 vulnerabilities
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products, including security updates for 50 vulnerabilities
 Updated: 12 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP at-scale pilots to be ‘integral’ to NHS future, says chief executive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149698</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-at-scale-pilots-to-be-integral-to-nhs-future-says-chief-executive/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T14:35:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pilots of new ways of working for GP practices – modelled on the Fuller Stocktake – will be ‘integral to the future of the NHS’, NHS England’s chief executive said today. Amanda Pritchard was speaking at the NHS Confederation Expo in Manchester today when she said that the NHS needs ‘a modern vision for primary
The post GP at-scale pilots to be ‘integral’ to NHS future, says chief executive appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS identifies over half a million more people at risk of type 2 diabetes in a Year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247480</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-identifies-over-half-a-million-more-people-at-risk-of-type-2-diabetes-in-a-year/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T13:22:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over half a million (549,000) more people in England have been identified by the NHS as being at risk of developing type 2 diabetes in a year, NHS figures show. The latest National Diabetes Audit shows that 3,615,330 people registered with a GP were found to have non-diabetic hyperglycaemia – also known as pre-diabetes -in […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kettering General Hospital cuts neurology waiting list through telemedicine tech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177053</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/kettering-general-hospital-cuts-neurology-waiting-list-through-telemedicine-tech/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T12:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kettering General Hospital has reduced its neurology waiting lists by 50% by using telemedicine technology to triage patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More money, more choice, more of the private sector: can the next government repeat the feat of the 2000s and cut waiting times?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/more-money-more-choice-more-of-the-private-sector-can-the-next-government-repeat-the-feat-of-the-200.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/more-money-more-choice-more-of-the-private-sector-can-the-next-government-repeat-the-feat-of-the-200.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T11:46:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - NHS waiting times are a central issue of the 2024 election campaign. Proposed solutions – more money, more staff, more use of the independent sector and strengthening patient choice – are mostly shared between the two main parties. More money, more choice and more private sector provision helped reduce median waiting times (under old measures) from...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4511 - Arm Releases Security Advisory for Exploited Mali GPU Driver Vulnerability]]></title>
        <id>5eaa15f8-dd94-40e6-ae38-368ea32c352b</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4511"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T11:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Exploitation could allow a local attacker to gain access to freed memory
 Exploitation could allow a local attacker to gain access to freed memory
 Updated: 12 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Green Party manifesto pledges primary care funding boost and junior doctor pay restoration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876705</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/green-party-manifesto-pledges-primary-care-funding-boost-junior-doctor-pay-restoration/article/1876705"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T11:04:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Green Party MPs in the next parliament will push for increasing the share of NHS funding that goes to primary care and an immediate boost to NHS staff pay, including pay restoration for junior doctors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England director admits GP trainee jobs ‘are not there for them’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149690</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/nhs-england-director-admits-gp-trainee-jobs-are-not-there-for-them/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T11:01:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The jobs that newly qualified GPs would want ‘are not there for them’, NHS England’s national director of primary care has admitted. Dr Amanda Doyle made the comments in a talk on best practices in primary care at the NHS Confederation Expo in Manchester this morning. She said that NHS England has heard from young
The post NHS England director admits GP trainee jobs ‘are not there for them’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPC campaign urges voters to make GP crisis the doorstep election issue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149678</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gpc-campaign-urges-voters-to-make-gp-crisis-the-doorstep-election-issue/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:43:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA’s GP Committee has launched a new patient-facing campaign ahead of the general election, titled ‘GPs Are On Your Side’. The GPC has produced leaflets that voters can put in their window during the run-up to the election and it is urging patients to make general practice the doorstep election topic. Highlighting that GP
The post GPC campaign urges voters to make GP crisis the doorstep election issue appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish Government invests £3.6m in Hospital at Home for older people]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176971</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/scottish-government-invests-3-6m-in-hospital-at-home-for-older-people/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Scottish Government has announced an additional investment of £3.6 million to fund its Hospital at Home initiative for older people in 2024- 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: National flu immunisation programme plan 2024 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/national-flu-immunisation-programme-plan-2024-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/national-flu-immunisation-programme-plan-2024-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The annual flu letter describes the national flu immunisation programme and outlines which groups are eligible for flu vaccination.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Cornwall and Isles of Scilly ICS restoring systems following IT outage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177105</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhs-cornwall-and-isles-of-scilly-ics-restoring-services-following-it-outage/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T07:30:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Cornwall and Isles of Scilly Integrated Care System (ICS) has confirmed that its IT systems are "coming back online" following a network outage.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medicines shortages triggering ‘moral distress’ in GPs, survey shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876581</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/medicines-shortages-triggering-moral-distress-gps-survey-shows/article/1876581"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T15:39:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost nine in 10 GPs say prescription drug shortages are severely impacting their ability to practise safely, with three quarters experiencing ‘moral distress’ as a result, a survey shows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How effective are PAs and do they reduce GP workload?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149542</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/special-investigations/the-rise-of-the-physician-associates/how-effective-are-pas-and-do-they-reduce-gp-workload/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T15:39:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the third part of our series on physician associates in general practice, Eliza Parr asks whether the increase in numbers is worth the money, and whether they are easing pressures on GPs For those cynics among you, it may seem unlikely that the Government will listen to doctors’ concerns about the clinical safety of
The post How effective are PAs and do they reduce GP workload? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 80 fellows declare no confidence in RCP in physician associates fallout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149659</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/more-than-80-fellows-resign-from-rcp-in-physician-associates-fallout/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T15:36:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 80 fellows of the Royal College of Physicians have declared a lack of confidence in the college’s leadership over its handling of the debate around physician associates (PAs). There have also been calls for the RCP president to resign, with five senior officers writing to the college to demand Dr Sarah Clarke’s resignation.
The post More than 80 fellows declare no confidence in RCP in physician associates fallout appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gavi to boost access to life-saving human rabies vaccines in over 50 countries: Gavi, WHO and UAR]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:d038eb3a-e7db-46b3-a5b6-b5e18629b27a</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/13-06-2024-gavi-to-boost-access-to-life-saving-rabies-vaccines-human-in-over-50-countries-gavi-who-and-uar"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T14:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, in collaboration with partners, is announcing support for human rabies vaccines for post exposure prophylaxis (PEP) as part of routine immunisation. Eligible countries are receiving guidance on how to access these vaccines under Gavi’s cofinancing policy. The first round of applications will be reviewed in July 2024. Ninety-five percent of human rabies deaths occur in Africa and Asia, most often in marginalised communities that lack access to care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4509 - Critical Security Update Released for IntelliJ-based IDEs and JetBrains GitHub Plugin]]></title>
        <id>31f7c1b1-d478-4c06-8557-eee708b68765</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4509"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T14:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Exploitation of the vulnerability could lead to the disclosure of access tokens to third-party sites
 Exploitation of the vulnerability could lead to the disclosure of access tokens to third-party sites
 Updated: 11 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conservative manifesto promises to 'modernise primary care services']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876556</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/conservative-manifesto-promises-modernise-primary-care-services/article/1876556"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T13:48:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Conservative manifesto promises to 'modernise primary care services' - but experts said the party's plans on general practice were 'a drop in the ocean' compared with what is needed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ensure best outcomes from inhaler use with a MIMS Learning webinar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876537</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/ensure-best-outcomes-inhaler-use-mims-learning-webinar/article/1876537"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T13:32:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join a free evening webinar on Thursday 18 June to understand more about how to prescribe inhalers effectively and achieve the best outcomes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Rewired 2025 opens for registration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176929</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-rewired-2025-opens-for-registration/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T12:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Registration has opened for Rewired 2025, the largest UK digital health expo  the use of digital and data to deliver improvements in health and care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medicine shortages cause ‘moral distress’ for three-in-four GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149631</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/medicine-shortages-cause-moral-distress-for-three-in-four-gps/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T12:02:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three quarters (74%) of GPs experience moral distress because they are unable to prescribe medicines patients need due to ongoing shortages. This is the finding of a survey carried out by indemnity provider MDDUS, which also found almost a third of this group (30%) suffer moral distress every day at work; and 37% several times
The post Medicine shortages cause ‘moral distress’ for three-in-four GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4508 - Critical Vulnerability in PHP]]></title>
        <id>5c861db6-ec67-4868-ad15-4d63ecdfe5a0</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4508"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T11:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 New versions of PHP address a critical vulnerability that could lead to arbitrary PHP code execution
 New versions of PHP address a critical vulnerability that could lead to arbitrary PHP code execution
 Updated: 11 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Masterclass: A complete GP’s guide to chronic kidney disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149601</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/renal-medicine-urology-mens-health/masterclass-a-complete-gps-guide-to-chronic-kidney-disease/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T11:10:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the next in our Masterclass series, consultant nephrologist Dr Colin Jones explains the latest knowledge and best practice in the management of CKD in primary care.  This series showcases content from our Pulse Reference site, which supports GPs in making diagnoses. We are expanding this service to include advice on managing and treating conditions
The post Masterclass: A complete GP’s guide to chronic kidney disease appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPC manifesto to demand 15% share of NHS budget for GP and community care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149621</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gpc-manifesto-to-demand-15-share-of-nhs-budget-for-gp-and-community-care/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:59:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive The BMA’s GP committee will ask the next Government to ensure that funding for out-of-hospital care gets ‘at least a 15% share’ of the NHS budget, its chair has revealed. Dr Katie Bramall-Stainer told Pulse that this would form part of GPC England’s manifesto, which is also expected to include ‘an ambition towards’ a
The post GPC manifesto to demand 15% share of NHS budget for GP and community care appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176813</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing110624/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This Coffee Time Briefing includes a call for countries to align health checks across borders through WHO’s Global Digital Health Certification Network.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[University Hospitals Coventry and Warwickshire to launch new EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176919</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/university-hospitals-coventry-and-warwickshire-to-launch-new-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new EPR is to be deployed at University Hospitals Coventry and Warwickshire NHS Trust with the aim of improving patients' experience.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP 'black alert' trial will allow struggling practices to divert patients elsewhere]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875870</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-black-alert-trial-will-allow-struggling-practices-divert-patients-elsewhere/article/1875870"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T09:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices under extreme pressure will be allowed to divert patients elsewhere and offered additional support under a hospital-style 'black alert' scheme being trialled in part of England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lib Dems pledges ‘small surgeries fund’ to protect rural GP access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149609</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/lib-dems-pledges-small-surgeries-fund-to-protect-rural-gp-access/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T09:06:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Liberal Democrats would set up a ‘Strategic Small Surgeries Fund to ‘sustain services in rural and remote areas’, according to its election manifesto. The document, published yesterday, also pledged to ‘remove’ existing ‘top-down bureaucracy’ to ‘let practices hire the staff they need’. Health policy experts said the plans were ‘ambitious’ but ‘light on detail’.
The post Lib Dems pledges ‘small surgeries fund’ to protect rural GP access appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Digital babies’ created to advance infant precision medicine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176897</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-babies-to-advance-infant-precision-medicine/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T07:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A joint Irish-German study is exploring the use of 'digital babies' to help advance precision medicine for infants with inherited metabolic diseases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lib Dems promise £1bn plan for 8,000 GPs and hint at relaxed ARRS rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876396</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/lib-dems-promise-1bn-plan-8000-gps-hint-relaxed-arrs-rules/article/1876396"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Liberal Democrats have promised a £1bn package to improve general practice, with a manifesto promising 8,000 more full-time equivalent (FTE) GPs in England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Chaand Nagpaul to give keynote address at Pulse Live Birmingham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149612</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/pulse-live/dr-chaand-nagpaul-to-give-keynote-address-at-pulse-live-birmingham/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T16:23:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Live will come back to Birmingham tomorrow (11 June), with a keynote speech from former BMA chair Dr Chaand Nagpaul, among a host of clinical education sessions. Dr Nagpaul will be discussing what GPs can do to stay afloat in the final session of the day, at the National Conference Centre in Solihull. Alongside
The post Dr Chaand Nagpaul to give keynote address at Pulse Live Birmingham appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The debate around the clinical responsibilities of physician associates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149521</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/clinical-areas/long-term-conditions-prescribing/the-debate-around-the-clinical-responsibilities-of-physician-associates/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T14:38:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the second part of our analysis of the role of physician associates within general practice, Eliza Parr looks at what clinical responsibilities they are being given, and the potential risks in their practice A handful of high-profile, tragic cases involving physician associates have caught public attention over the last year. Emily Chesterton, a 30-year-old
The post The debate around the clinical responsibilities of physician associates appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour scraps plans to reintroduce pensions lifetime allowance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149584</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/labour-scraps-plans-to-reintroduce-pensions-lifetime-allowance/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T14:16:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour has abandoned its plans to reintroduce the pensions lifetime allowance, with the BMA saying this will help ‘help retain doctors in the NHS’. It was abolished last year, as part of chancellor Jeremy Hunt’s plan to ‘help people extend their working lives’. The Labour Party shortly after said it would reverse the move if
The post Labour scraps plans to reintroduce pensions lifetime allowance appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Standard infusion pump software to go live at Alder Hey Children’s Hospital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176613</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/standard-infusion-pumps-with-new-software-to-go-live-fully-at-alder-hey/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T12:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peter White, CNIO at Alder Hey Children’s Hospital, tells Digital Health about a project to create standardised pediatric datasets for infusion pumps.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and pharmacists call for action on volatile drug costs as prescribing bill spirals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876325</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-pharmacists-call-action-volatile-drug-costs-prescribing-bill-spirals/article/1876325"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T11:02:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and pharmacists have called for action to tackle volatile drug costs after a £500m surge in prescribing spending in 2023/24, with spending on some medications more than doubling.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP confronts Prime Minister over ‘constructive dismissal’ of general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149571</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gp-confronts-prime-minister-over-constructive-dismissal-of-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:26:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The public is ‘not stupid’ and will not allow the Conservatives to ‘replace’ doctors with ‘half-qualified’ staff, a heckling GP told Rishi Sunak last week. Locum GP Dr Jane Lees-Millais confronted the Prime Minister on the ‘constructive dismissal’ of general practice during an election rally on Friday. She interrupted Mr Sunak during his visit to
The post GP confronts Prime Minister over ‘constructive dismissal’ of general practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA calls GP unemployment a ‘national disgrace’ after GP confronts Sunak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876299</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-calls-gp-unemployment-national-disgrace-gp-confronts-sunak/article/1876299"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:10:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has declared the current GP unemployment crisis a ‘national disgrace’ after a GP confronted prime minister Rishi Sunak over the 'constructive dismissal' of general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only one in six patients experience antidepressant withdrawal, finds study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149435</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/only-one-in-six-patients-experience-antidepressant-withdrawal-finds-study/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Only one in six people who stop taking antidepressants will experience withdrawal symptoms as a direct result, according to a new study.  This is a much lower proportion than other studies have suggested, with previous estimates that over half of patients experience symptoms. The research, published in the Lancet Psychiatry (5 June), found that overall
The post Only one in six patients experience antidepressant withdrawal, finds study appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS issues urgent call for O-type blood donors following London cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176879</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhs-issues-urgent-call-for-o-type-blood-donors-following-london-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Blood and Transplant has urgently called for donations of O type blood following a ransomware attack which has disrupted pathology services in London.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belfast Health and Social Care Trust goes live with digital record system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176853</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/belfast-health-and-social-care-trust-goes-live-with-digital-record-system/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T07:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Belfast Health and Social Care Trust has announced that it has gone live with the encompass digital record system, replacing paper processes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does the influx of physician associates mean for GP recruitment?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149489</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/special-investigations/the-rise-of-the-physician-associates/what-does-the-influx-of-physician-associates-mean-for-gp-recruitment/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T15:23:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the first of our series looking at the role of physician associates in general practice, Eliza Parr looks as whether they really are replacing GPs ‘There are literally no salaried jobs in Birmingham at all. Where has all the work gone? You could explain it away for a few months, you could explain it
The post What does the influx of physician associates mean for GP recruitment? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public health funding cuts criticised as cases of gonorrhoea and syphilis rise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149505</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/sexual-health/public-health-funding-cuts-criticised-as-cases-of-gonorrhoea-and-syphilis-rise/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T15:03:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public health experts have called for more investment into sexual health services after figures showed concerning rises in gonorrhoea and syphilis in England. Figures from the UK Health Security Agency showed a 4.7% overall rise in sexually transmitted infections (STI) in 2023 to 401,800 compared with 383,789 the previous year. But gonorrhoea cases increased 7.5%
The post Public health funding cuts criticised as cases of gonorrhoea and syphilis rise appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atorvastatin most-prescribed drug by GPs, with diabetes and HRT drugs on rise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149554</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/diabetes-endocrinology/atorvastatin-most-prescribed-drug-by-gps-with-diabetes-and-hrt-drugs-on-rise/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T14:08:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Atorvastatin was once again the most prescribed item by GPs in England last year, while endocrine system drugs saw the largest rise. Cardiovascular drugs accounted for 30% of all items prescribed by the NHS in the UK and dispensed in the community in England 2023/24, according to the latest statistics from the NHS Business Services
The post Atorvastatin most-prescribed drug by GPs, with diabetes and HRT drugs on rise appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4507 - Directory Traversal Vulnerability in SolarWinds Serv-U]]></title>
        <id>de5ed9a8-0e16-433c-a6be-41f3c5991460</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4507"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T13:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security update addresses a vulnerability that could lead to unauthorised access of confidential files
 Security update addresses a vulnerability that could lead to unauthorised access of confidential files
 Updated: 07 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great Western Hospitals to deploy Zebra devices in standardisation project]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176791</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/great-western-hospitals-to-deploy-zebra-devices-in-standardisation-project/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T12:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A standardisation project at the Acute Hospital Alliance, will see Great Western Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust deploy mobile computers from Zebra.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to take on weight loss management under NICE tirzepatide guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149481</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-to-take-on-weight-loss-management-under-nice-tirzepatide-guidance/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T11:02:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs will be able to prescribe tirzepatide for weight loss under NICE recommendations currently out for consultation. The weekly injection has been recommended alongside diet and exercise advice for people with a BMI of at least 35kg/m2 and one weight-related comorbidty with lower thresholds for people from some ethnic minority backgrounds. But in contrast to
The post GPs to take on weight loss management under NICE tirzepatide guidance appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Urgently see GP about missed whooping cough vaccination, RCGP urges parents]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149520</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/urgently-see-gp-about-missed-whooping-cough-vaccination-rcgp-urges-parents/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:48:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP has issued urgent advice for parents to check their children’s vaccination status – and urgently book a GP appointment if they are not protected against whooping cough. It has joined forces with other medical royal colleges to also urge pregnant women to take up the offer of pertussis vaccination, following devastating news of
The post Urgently see GP about missed whooping cough vaccination, RCGP urges parents appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE cancels digital pathways framework for modern general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149525</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/nhse-cancels-digital-pathways-framework-for-modern-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:23:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England will no longer publish a digital pathways framework, providing approved ‘modern general practice’ tools. The framework was going to help ICBs, PCNs and practices deliver the modern general practice access plan, providing a list of approved tools that would be available to practices for functions including booking, messaging and online consultations. It was set
The post NHSE cancels digital pathways framework for modern general practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Study highlights need for more rigorous evaluation of digital health apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176745</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/study-highlights-need-for-more-rigorous-evaluation-of-digital-health-apps/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T10:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A study from Ulster University has called for more rigorous evaluation of digital health apps rather than reliance on user ratings and download numbers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GPs standing to be MPs in the general election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875277</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-standing-mps-general-election/article/1875277"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T08:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPonline profiles the GPs standing to become MPs in the 2024 general election.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE Cancer Vaccine Launch Pad sees first patient treated]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176735</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhse-cancer-vaccine-launch-pad-sees-first-patient-treated/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-07T07:30:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first patient has been treated with a personalised vaccine against bowel cancer in a clinical trial, as part of NHS England’s Cancer Vaccine Launch Pad.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once in a lifetime: Stevens-Johnson Syndrome]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149508</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/dermatology-and-wound-care/once-in-a-lifetime-stevens-johnson-syndrome/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T16:03:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tiverton GP Dr James Wood, who has a special interest in dermatology, considers this unusual presentation in the latest of our ‘Once in a Lifetime’ series What is it? Stevens-Johnson Syndrome (SJS) is a severe dermatological reaction that is widely considered a dermatological emergency. It causes widespread, painful blistering of the skin and mucous membranes
The post Once in a lifetime: Stevens-Johnson Syndrome appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to notify cases of bloody diarrhoea amid E. coli ‘food item’ warning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149502</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-to-notify-cases-of-bloody-diarrhoea-amid-e-coli-food-item-warning/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T15:10:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been asked to notify all cases of infectious bloody diarrhoea to local health protection teams, as UK authorities issue a health warning about a serious E. coli outbreak linked to an unknown ‘nationally distributed food item’. The UK Health Security Agency are investigating an increase in the number of Shiga toxin-producing Escherichia coli
The post GPs to notify cases of bloody diarrhoea amid E. coli ‘food item’ warning appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA reveals options for GP collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149492</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/bma-reveals-options-for-gp-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T14:42:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive The BMA has revealed potential actions that GP practices could take as part of collective action later this year. Pulse understands that these include refusing to engage in advice and guidance, seeing patients ‘face to face as a default’, and switching off the GP connect functionality which permits remote NHS 111 appointment booking. The
The post BMA reveals options for GP collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Falling through the gaps?: a closer look at NHS Continuing Healthcare]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/falling-through-the-gaps-a-closer-look-at-nhs-continuing-healthcare.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/falling-through-the-gaps-a-closer-look-at-nhs-continuing-healthcare.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T14:13:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - NHS Continuing Healthcare (CHC) is care funded by the NHS, but provided outside of hospital for people with significant ongoing care needs. This briefing explains how eligibility for CHC is decided, what the data tells us about eligibility and access over time, and what the impact on individuals, carers and families can be. Briefing]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England scraps £300m digital pathways framework for GP tech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176757</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhs-england-scraps-300m-digital-pathways-framework-for-gp-tech/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T12:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has confirmed that its £300 million digital pathways framework has been cancelled, following delays caused by a legal claim.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Partners for change]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/partners-for-change.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/partners-for-change.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T11:56:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New Philanthropy Capital - This report argues that, following the general election, charities and funders should be a key partner in delivering the new government’s plans to revitalise the country and can help tackle social challenges such as health inequalities. It includes eight recommendations for putting the partnership between government and charities on a strong footing, nine recommendations in priority...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three more babies died from whooping cough in April]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149475</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/three-more-babies-died-from-whooping-cough-in-april/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T11:36:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three more babies have been confirmed to have died from whooping cough in April, the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) has said. It follow five deaths that were reported by health officials in the first three months of the year. The eight deaths were in infants who developed pertussis between January and April and were
The post Three more babies died from whooping cough in April appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are ‘not accountable’ for PA errors, says GMC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149463</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gps-are-not-accountable-for-pa-errors-says-gmc/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T11:21:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are ‘not accountable’ for the decisions and actions of physician associates (PAs) they supervise, the GMC has said. In a letter to system leaders, the regulator said that its guidance for doctors is ‘clear’ that doctors – including GPs – are not accountable for the decisions and actions of PAs and anaesthesia associates (AAs)
The post GPs are ‘not accountable’ for PA errors, says GMC appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical trials get faster]]></title>
        <id>be1ef9a4-2036-4c33-9d84-0c95b54742bb</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/data-points-blog/2023/clinical-trials-get-faster"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:59:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For International Clinical Trials Day, James Gray, NHS DigiTrials Service Delivery Manager, talks about the new Feasibility Self-Service tool that drastically cuts the time it takes researchers to find out if there are enough potential participants for their clinical trial.


“In the time it takes to make a coffee.”


That was the challenge we set ourselves early in the creation of the NHS DigiTrials Feasibility Self-Service tool. And it was a big one: it meant giving users the ability to securely interrogate national datasets containing millions and millions of records in less than 5 minutes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medicine shortage warnings triple in last two years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149462</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/medicine-shortage-warnings-triple-in-last-two-years/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:46:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than three times as many serious shortage protocols (SSPs) were issued in the two-year period between 2022 and 2024, compared with 2020 to 2022. And in a three-day period last month, the same number of SSPs were issued as those issued during the whole of 2020, according to analysis by the National Pharmacy Association
The post Medicine shortage warnings triple in last two years appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we’re modernising electronic prescribing]]></title>
        <id>68e89b19-a38b-41cd-8399-83978d93ea77</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/tech-talk/2023/how-were-modernising-electronic-prescribing"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:27:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most prescriptions are still paper-based in secondary care. Business analyst Andy Harrison describes the technical groundwork we’ve laid to allow these settings to go digital.


The little green FP10 paper prescriptions have all but disappeared in primary care. 18 years ago, we launched the Electronic Prescription Service (EPS) and it has since become an indispensable tool for primary care teams. Nearly all GP practices use it and about 95% of primary care prescriptions are now sent electronically. Last year, that amounted to 1 billion items dispensed using the service. It’s a safer, faster and more convenient way to prescribe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GMC will regulate doctors and physician associates 'as distinct professions']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875791</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gmc-will-regulate-doctors-physician-associates-as-distinct-professions/article/1875791"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:20:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors, physician associates and anaesthesia associates will be regulated as 'three distinct professions' when the GMC's remit widens later this year, the regulator has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Set aside party politics’ to solve GP ‘crisis’, LMCs urge politicians]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149453</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/set-aside-party-politics-to-solve-gp-crisis-lmcs-urge-politicians/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:17:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LMCs across the country have come together to urge politicians to ‘set aside party politics’ in a bid to resolve issues in general practice. Organised by the Rebuild General Practice campaign group, a letter signed by 80% of the UK’s LMCs has been sent to the leaders of Britain’s main political parties. It is asking
The post ‘Set aside party politics’ to solve GP ‘crisis’, LMCs urge politicians appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clanwilliam tests electronic prescription technology in Wales]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176577</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/clanwilliam-tests-electronic-prescription-technology-in-wales/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T10:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthcare IT supplier Clanwilliam is testing its pharmacy system technology in Wales to support the delivery of an Electronic Prescription Service (EPS).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new way to find patients]]></title>
        <id>d585aac1-e2b6-41d9-8964-e0366454c1eb</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/data-points-blog/2023/a-new-way-to-find-patients"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T09:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Darren Hickling describes NHS Digital’s role in developing a platform to identify the highest risk COVID-19 patients so they could receive life-saving antiviral treatments.  


As COVID-19 emerged and treatment options were limited, pharmaceutical companies began researching and developing new antibody and antiviral treatments to reduce viral replication or alleviate symptoms in immunocompromised people.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We had to follow the data, not our users]]></title>
        <id>a96bdbf2-24c5-42c6-9a5e-f90b0df14a44</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/design-matters/2024/we-had-to-follow-the-data-not-our-users"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T09:52:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chiara Garattini and Kate Burn explain how working in our Data and Analytics sub-directorate has challenged the assumptions of our user-centred design team.


A big part of early work on projects typically involves helping our colleagues to focus a bit less on the characteristics of their products and the requirements of their internal processes, and to instead start by involving users to understand their needs.


Therefore, it's been interesting to work on projects that required our team to get deep into the weeds of the process in order to, ultimately, put the focus back on users.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We had to follow the data, not our users]]></title>
        <id>a96bdbf2-24c5-42c6-9a5e-f90b0df14a44</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/design-matters/2024/we-had-to-follow-the-data-not-our-users"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T09:52:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chiara Garattini and Kate Burn explain how working in our Data and Analytics sub-directorate has challenged the assumptions of our user-centred design team.


A big part of early work on projects typically involves helping our colleagues to focus a bit less on the characteristics of their products and the requirements of their internal processes, and to instead start by involving users to understand their needs.


Therefore, it's been interesting to work on projects that required our team to get deep into the weeds of the process in order to, ultimately, put the focus back on users.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPonline launches WhatsApp channel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874645</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gponline-launches-whatsapp-channel/article/1874645"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T08:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPonline has launched a new WhatsApp channel so you have another way to stay up to date with the latest news, and receive updates about our education, GP training and career articles direct to your phone.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Official Statistics: Adult social care in England, monthly statistics: June 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-june-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-june-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T08:30:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Official statistics on a range of topics including occupancy and infection control measures in adult social care settings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult social care in England statistics: background quality and methodology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T08:30:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) puts together the data in its monthly reports.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One giant step for secure data access]]></title>
        <id>af535a23-cb35-49a3-b796-a949952b4f50</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/data-points-blog/2023/one-giant-step-for-secure-data-access"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T07:54:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Chapman, Director of Research and Clinical Trials at NHS Digital, talks about our new Secure Data Environment and explains how it is making research into life-saving treatments easier and faster.


At the outset of the COVID-19 pandemic, we built the Trusted Research Environment (TRE) service for England to enable researchers from the NHS, government, academia and industry to contribute to our collective response to the disease.


Our TRE service proved invaluable in understanding the impact of COVID-19 and the efficacy of treatments, but it wasn’t scalable or flexible enough for the wider community of researchers who we want to support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost 1,000 bed days saved by virtual wards at Leeds Teaching Hospitals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176709</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/almost-1000-bed-days-saved-by-virtual-wards-at-leeds-teaching-hospitals/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T07:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust saved an estimated 959 bed days in the first six months of a virtual ward service, according to analysis by the trust.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Britain's LMCs co-sign 'unprecedented' letter demanding action to end GP crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875738</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/britains-lmcs-co-sign-unprecedented-letter-demanding-action-end-gp-crisis/article/1875738"/>
        <updated>2024-06-06T06:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LMCs across England, Scotland and Wales have co-signed a letter to political party leaders ahead of the general election, calling for fair funding, a plan to retain GPs and more autonomy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Rons tasked with saving primary care – who do I vote for?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149419</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/more-rons-tasked-with-saving-primary-care-who-do-i-vote-for/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T14:17:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Copperfield speculates where his vote should go in the election based on their grand plans for general practice More surgeries! More appointments! More scans!  Morons! Infuriating, isn’t it, how the various political parties can magically switch into ‘fix primary care’ mode when there are votes at stake. And hilarious, too, given the current incumbent’s
The post More Rons tasked with saving primary care – who do I vote for? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP referrals ‘key’ to Pharmacy First success, analysis suggests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148177</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/gp-referrals-key-to-pharmacy-first-success-analysis-suggests/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T14:12:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Referrals from GP practices and NHS services are ‘key’ to the success of Pharmacy First, the Company Chemists’ Association (CCA) has suggested, following its analysis of Pharmacy First consultations around the country. Latest analysis of the number of Pharmacy First consultations in CCA pharmacies across England has suggested disparity between the success of the service
The post GP referrals ‘key’ to Pharmacy First success, analysis suggests appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer Schools 2024 conference programme published]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176677</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/summer-schools-2024-conference-programme-published/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T12:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The programme for Summer Schools 2024 has been published, featuring national keynotes, NHS CEOs, digital leadership plenary sessions and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mr José Luis Castro appointed as WHO Director-General Special Envoy 
for Chronic Respiratory Diseases]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:f26b6e52-e34f-4d74-b5ad-7ef4c5d5e3a2</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/06-06-2024-mr-jose-luis-castro-appointed-as-who-director-general-special-envoy-for-chronic-respiratory-diseases"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T12:14:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) is pleased to announce the appointment of Mr José Luis Castro as WHO Director-General Special Envoy for Chronic Respiratory Diseases. Chronic respiratory diseases (CRD), including asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), affect nearly half a billion people worldwide. Despite their significant impact, these diseases have often been overlooked in global health discussions, lacking the necessary recognition and resources.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176713</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-143/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T10:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thursday's briefing features healthcare communications provider Cymphony reaching net-zero carbon status and Apotti's new learning platform for its EHR.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Unplugged: The alternative approach to EPR implementation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176671</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-unplugged-the-alternative-approach-to-epr-implementation/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T10:07:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jordan Sollof is joined by Mark Hutchinson, vice-president of healthcare strategy and transformation at Altera Digital Health, to talk all things EPRs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse wins two awards for GP recruitment coverage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149425</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/special-investigations/pulse-on-workforce/pulse-wins-two-awards-for-gp-recruitment-coverage/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T10:02:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse won two awards at the prestigious BSME Talent awards last night for our coverage of the recruitment crisis and the abuse faced by GPs among other reporting. Senior reporter Eliza Parr won B2B writer of the year, and Eliza and senior report Anna Colivicchi won best use of data journalism for their analysis of
The post Pulse wins two awards for GP recruitment coverage appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs fear delayed test results amid major cyber attack on NHS pathology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149422</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gps-fear-delayed-test-results-amid-major-cyber-attack-on-nhs-pathology/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T09:14:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A cyber attack impacting NHS pathology labs in London hospitals has left GPs ‘flying blind’ with delays to test results and cancelled hospital appointments.  Synnovis, a provider of lab services for a group of London hospitals, was the ‘victim of a ransomware cyberattack’ which caused ‘interruptions’ to its pathology services, HSJ revealed yesterday.  The company
The post GPs fear delayed test results amid major cyber attack on NHS pathology appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new national purpose: harnessing data for health]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/a-new-national-purpose-harnessing-data-for-health.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/a-new-national-purpose-harnessing-data-for-health.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T08:37:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Blair Institute for Global Change - This report describes how large health and biomedical data sets, artificial intelligence and advances in biotechnology can improve and innovate health care, prevent disease and help people live longer, healthier lives. It looks at the challenges this could bring and suggests ways these challenges can be overcome. Report]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors raise over £40,000 for GMC legal challenge over PA and AA regulation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875539</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/doctors-raise-40000-gmc-legal-challenge-pa-aa-regulation/article/1875539"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T08:26:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A group representing anaesthetists has raised over £40,000 to launch a legal challenge against the GMC's plans to regulate physician associates (PAs) and anaesthesia associates (AAs).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synnovis CEO confirms ransomware attack at London hospitals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176633</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/synnovis-ceo-confirms-ransomware-attack-at-london-hospitals/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T07:30:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Synnovis CEO Mark Dollar has confirmed that a ransomware attack has interrupted pathology IT systems, causing patient activity to be cancelled.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA manifesto demands new GP contract and end to PAs replacing doctors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875530</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-manifesto-demands-new-gp-contract-end-pas-replacing-doctors/article/1875530"/>
        <updated>2024-06-05T06:55:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next government must deliver a new GP contract, improve practice premises and stop the replacement of doctors with physician associates, a BMA general election manifesto warns.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA election manifesto demands action on GP unemployment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149411</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/bma-election-manifesto-demands-action-on-gp-unemployment/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next Government should take urgent action to address GP unemployment, the BMA has demanded in its general election manifesto. The doctors’ union said that the party winning the upcoming general election should ‘cut red tape to allow practices to hire GPs and reduce GP locum unemployment’. It confirmed to Pulse that it was referring
The post BMA election manifesto demands action on GP unemployment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors raise £25k to legally challenge GMC over PA/AA regulation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149405</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/doctors-raise-25k-to-legally-challenge-gmc-over-pa-aa-regulation/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T15:15:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A group representing anaesthetists of all grades has raised over £25,000 to fund a legal challenge against the GMC over its handling of the regulation of physician associates (PAs) and anaesthetist associates (AAs). Anaesthetists United said it is commencing a legal case against the regulator as it believes the regulation process is ‘blurring the distinction’
The post Doctors raise £25k to legally challenge GMC over PA/AA regulation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practice pays tribute to ‘well-loved’ GP who died in paddle-boarding accident]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149393</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/scotland/practice-pays-tribute-to-well-loved-gp-who-died-in-paddle-boarding-accident/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T14:19:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paddle-boarding GP
The post Practice pays tribute to ‘well-loved’ GP who died in paddle-boarding accident appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicines eligible for Northern Ireland MHRA Authorised Route]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T14:15:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out medicines that can be moved to Northern Ireland to meet patient need.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drexit: Moral injury is destroying the foundation of our NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149298</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/drexit-moral-injury-is-destroying-the-foundation-of-our-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T14:07:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Seema Haider explores the collective ‘moral injury’ that doctors are facing, and confronts the institutional failings contributing to it We are all too aware of the systemic problems within the NHS: chronic underfunding; recruitment and retention issues; growing public expectation coupled with increasing medical complexity; not to mention navigating the aftermath of an unprecedented
The post Drexit: Moral injury is destroying the foundation of our NHS appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs 'flying blind' as cyber attack disrupts lab results service]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875503</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-flying-blind-cyber-attack-disrupts-lab-results-service/article/1875503"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T12:58:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs fear 'flying blind' for weeks after a cyber attack on a pathology lab service forced hospitals to cancel or move appointments and disrupted access to test results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Critical incident at Synnovis disrupts pathology services across SE London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176575</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/critical-incident-at-synnovis-disrupts-pathology-services-across-se-london/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking news: A critical incident at Synnovis has disrupted services at Guy’s and St Thomas’ NHS FT and King’s College Hospital NHS FT.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP workload concern as private hospital admissions reach ‘record level’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149372</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/gp-workload-concern-as-private-hospital-admissions-reach-record-level/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T10:43:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Private hospital admissions reached record levels last year, with more people choosing to pay for their treatment, according to new data. GPs told Pulse that this is due to long waits for treatment on the NHS, and it is a worrying trend as it is generating more work in general practice. The latest figures from
The post GP workload concern as private hospital admissions reach ‘record level’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the month answers: Did you get what caused the non-vertigo dizziness?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149374</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/neurology/case-of-the-month-answers-did-you-get-what-caused-the-non-vertigo-dizziness/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T10:31:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the second of a new monthly series, we are asking readers to help solve this case involving a 67-year-old man who has dizziness and an ‘odd thing he has noticed today’. Find the answers below! You are the duty doctor on an interminable-feeling shift full of all the usual coughs, sore throats and febrile
The post Case of the month answers: Did you get what caused the non-vertigo dizziness? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176511</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-142/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T10:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tuesday's coffee time briefing includes the news that the Scottish government will fund the roll-out of closed loop technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176511</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T10:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tuesday's coffee time briefing includes the news that the Scottish government will fund the roll-out of closed loop technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Norfolk and Waveney ICB publish tender worth £1.25m for PHM solution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176535</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/norfolk-and-waveney-icb-publish-tender-worth-1-25m-for-phm-solution/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T10:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Norfolk and Waveney Integrated Care Board is looking for a population health management digital solution to underpin its PHM strategy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP registrar applies to work for Tesco as general practice jobs evaporate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875381</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-registrar-applies-work-tesco-general-practice-jobs-evaporate/article/1875381"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T09:58:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP registrar weeks from qualifying has applied for work with supermarket giant Tesco after being unable to find a job in general practice, GPonline has learned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy First would be expanded to acne and chest infections under Tories]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149366</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/pharmacy-first-would-be-expanded-to-acne-and-chest-infections-under-tories/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T09:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Conservative Party has pledged to expand Pharmacy First to include more conditions, as well as have pharmacies provide more contraceptive options and menopause support, if elected at the general election. The expansion would double the number of GP appointments saved by the scheme – from 10 million to 20 million, the party said. It
The post Pharmacy First would be expanded to acne and chest infections under Tories appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most GP practices in England 'struggling to keep doors open', warns BMA GP leader]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875376</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-england-struggling-keep-doors-open-warns-bma-gp-leader/article/1875376"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T08:08:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most GP practices in England are struggling to keep their doors open and the imposed 2024/25 contract has already triggered closures, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RHN to go live with PatientSource AI tool to detect patient deterioration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176487</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/rhn-to-go-live-with-patientsource-ai-tool-to-detect-patient-deterioration/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-04T07:30:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A PatientSource AI tool that enables early patient deterioration detection is to go live in one of the Royal Hospital for Neuro Disability’s (RHN) 13 wards.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs demand ‘more severe sanctions’ for violent patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147856</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/special-investigations/gp-abuse/gps-demand-more-severe-sanctions-for-violent-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T14:56:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs want ‘more severe sanctions’ for perpetrators of threatening and violent behaviour towards GP practice staff. In a vote at last month’s UK LMC conference, delegates demanded that ‘the criteria for inclusion in violent patient schemes should be relaxed’. The also called on UK governments to ‘ensure that the funding for violent patient schemes is
The post GPs demand ‘more severe sanctions’ for violent patients appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Request a baby loss certificate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/request-baby-loss-certificate</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/request-baby-loss-certificate"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T14:27:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If your pregnancy ends before 24 weeks, you can get a free certificate in memory of your baby.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS online weight programme can lead to losses of more than half a stone, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148193</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/nhs-online-weight-programme-can-lead-to-losses-of-more-than-half-a-stone-study-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T14:18:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS Digital Weight Management programme, available to both health staff and patients, is effective at leading to ‘clinically meaningful weight loss’, latest research has shown. The study, highlighted by NHS England in its primary care bulletin last month, found that people who adhered to and finished the 12-week programme shed over half a stone in weight.  The
The post NHS online weight programme can lead to losses of more than half a stone, study finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS online weight programme can lead to losses of more than half a stone, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148193</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/obesity-and-nutrition/nhs-online-weight-programme-can-lead-to-losses-of-more-than-half-a-stone-study-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T14:18:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS Digital Weight Management programme, available to both health staff and patients, is effective at leading to ‘clinically meaningful weight loss’, latest research has shown. The study, highlighted by NHS England in its primary care bulletin last month, found that people who adhered to and finished the 12-week programme shed over half a stone in weight.  The
The post NHS online weight programme can lead to losses of more than half a stone, study finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The paradox of plenty – where have all the jobs gone?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148186</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/margaret-ikpoh/the-paradox-of-plenty-where-have-all-the-jobs-gone/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T13:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Margaret Ikpoh ponders the contradiction of our workforce crisis, and what future there is for GP trainees We are approaching panel season, where the review and assessment of the skills and competence of our exciting bright-eyed and bushy-tailed GP registrars will take place. As a GP trainer myself, one of the joys from the
The post The paradox of plenty – where have all the jobs gone? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/pharmacy.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/pharmacy.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T13:17:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health and Social Care Select Committee - This report finds the current Community Pharmacy Funding Framework not fit for purpose and urges an overhaul to reduce its complexity. It concludes that a new framework is necessary to deliver adequate funding and prevent damaging cross-subsidy between clinical services and prescription dispensing as is currently the case. Reductions in core funding to...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England slashes investment in NHS AI Lab by £111m]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=175635</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhs-england-slashes-investment-in-nhs-ai-lab-by-111m/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T12:30:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has slashed investment in NHS AI Lab from a promised £250 million to just £139m, Digital Health News has learned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Hoeksma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corridor care: unsafe, undignified, unacceptable]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/corridor-care-unsafe-undignified-unacceptable-1.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/corridor-care-unsafe-undignified-unacceptable-1.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T11:35:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Nursing - This report reveals that more than 1 in 3 (37 per cent) nursing staff working in typical hospital settings delivered care in inappropriate settings, such as corridors, on their last shift. The report shares the results of a survey of almost 11,000 frontline nursing staff across the UK. It calls for mandatory national reporting of...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England appoints first medical director for mental health and neurodiversity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=246980</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-england-appoints-first-medical-director-for-mental-health-and-neurodiversity/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T10:30:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Adrian James has been appointed by NHS England today (Monday 3 June) to a new role supporting the transformation of services for people with mental health needs, autism, a learning disability and those who are neurodiverse.  Dr James was President of the Royal College of Psychiatrists from 2020 – 2023 and is currently a […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conservatives pledge to ‘build 100 new GP surgeries’ if they win general election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148170</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/conservatives-pledge-to-build-100-new-gp-surgeries-if-they-win-general-election/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T10:23:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Conservative Party has announced a pledge to build 100 new GP surgeries and ‘modernise’ a further 150, should they win the upcoming general election. The Tories said they would also expand Pharmacy First to ‘free up a total 20 million GP appointments’ and build 50 new Community Diagnostic Centres. The plans would be backed
The post Conservatives pledge to ‘build 100 new GP surgeries’ if they win general election appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One year on: The latest on our Secure Data Environment]]></title>
        <id>1e4241ae-b6b3-4081-8fb8-a0deb29a9e47</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/data-points-blog/2023/one-year-on-the-latest-on-our-secure-data-environment"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T10:07:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liz Gaffney, Head of NHS England's Secure Data Environment, reflects on the developments of the service one year on.


In January, Michael Chapman blogged about our ambitious plans for the NHS England Secure Data Environment (SDE), starting with migrating customers to the service, testing its capabilities and processes, and then scaling up the service to handle wider use.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One year on: The latest on our Secure Data Environment]]></title>
        <id>1e4241ae-b6b3-4081-8fb8-a0deb29a9e47</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/data-points-blog/2023/one-year-on-the-latest-on-our-secure-data-environment"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T10:07:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liz Gaffney, Head of NHS England's Secure Data Environment, reflects on the developments of the service one year on.


In January, Michael Chapman blogged about our ambitious plans for the NHS England Secure Data Environment (SDE), starting with migrating customers to the service, testing its capabilities and processes, and then scaling up the service to handle wider use.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black and ethnic minority people underrepresented in virtual wards]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176447</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/black-and-ethnic-minority-people-underrepresented-in-virtual-wards/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T10:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An NHS England analysis of the effectiveness of virtual wards has found that black and ethnic minority people are underrepresented in patient cohorts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices must carefully check they are being paid PCN money, accountants warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148172</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-practices-must-carefully-check-they-are-being-paid-pcn-money-accountants-warn/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T09:49:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practices need to double check they are receiving the income they are due from their PCNs as part of measures they can take to improve cash flow, medical accountants have warned. Experts from the Association of Independent Specialist Medical Accountants (AISMA) have said an average practice can earn income of £150k to £200k a year
The post GP practices must carefully check they are being paid PCN money, accountants warn appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conservative promise of 100 new practices 'no use without more GPs']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875168</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/conservative-promise-100-new-practices-no-use-without-gps/article/1875168"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T07:30:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservative plans to build 100 new practices and refurbish 150 more would have limited impact without better recruitment and retention of GPs to work in them, GPs have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Infix national theatre scheduling tool to be rolled out across Scotland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176429</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/infix-national-theatre-scheduling-tool-to-be-rolled-out-across-scotland/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-03T07:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A national theatre scheduling tool that reduces hospital waiting times and enhances operating theatre efficiency is to be rolled out across Scotland.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly – Daily update: 1 June 2024]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:b2804f27-8da4-49a9-a25b-0b4b5b2ea4e7</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/01-06-2024-seventy-seventh-world-health-assembly---daily-update--1-june-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T19:57:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World Health Assembly agreement reached on wide-ranging, decisive package of amendments to improve the International Health Regulations, and sets date for finalizing negotiations on a proposed Pandemic Agreement
In a historic development, the World Health Assembly, the annual meeting of the World Health Organization's 194 member countries, today agreed on a package of critical amendments to the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR), and made concrete commitments to completing negotiations on a global pandemic agreement within a year, at the latest. These critical actions have been taken in order to ensure comprehensive, robust systems are in place in all countries to protect the health and safety of all people everywhere from the risk of future outbreaks and pandemics.
These decisi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World Health Assembly agreement reached on wide-ranging, decisive package of amendments to improve the International Health Regulations]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:3e88ad6d-56ea-48f9-a57f-d09bfed8cfae</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/01-06-2024-world-health-assembly-agreement-reached-on-wide-ranging--decisive-package-of-amendments-to-improve-the-international-health-regulations--and-sets-date-for-finalizing-negotiations-on-a-proposed-pandemic-agreement"/>
        <updated>2024-06-01T17:40:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In an historic development, the World Health Assembly, the annual meeting of its 194 member countries, today agreed a package of critical amendments to the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR), and made concrete commitments to completing negotiations on a global pandemic agreement within a year, at the latest. These critical actions have been taken in order to ensure comprehensive, robust systems are in place in all countries to protect the health and safety of all people everywhere from the risk of future outbreaks and pandemics.
These decisions represent two important steps by countries, taken in tandem with one another on the final day of the Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly, to build on lessons learned from several global health emergencies, including the COVID-19 pandemi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly – Daily update: 31 May 2024]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:cf838ec9-b4b5-4ac6-905a-8eac3bd5c1ca</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/31-05-2024-seventy-seventh-world-health-assembly---daily-update--31-may-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T17:49:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Landmark resolution passed on health and climate change
In a resounding call to action, the Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly has recognized climate change as an imminent threat to global health, passing a resolution which underscores the urgent need for decisive measures to confront the profound health risks posed by climate change.
The resolution, supported overwhelmingly by Member States, presents an overview of the existential threat that climate change poses to human health. The Health Assembly asserts that radical action is imperative to safeguard the health of the planet, underscoring the interdependence of environmental sustainability and public health.
Urging the global health community to mobilize on an unprecedented scale, the Health Assembly calls for the amplification and …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Questions: The general election and industrial action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148165</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/big-questions/big-questions-the-general-election-and-industrial-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T15:27:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse summarises May’s talking points – what does a general election mean for general practice, and what industrial action will the BMA partner ballot lead to What does the election mean for general practice? It was like something from a rom-com: the pouring rain; his finest suit; and asking people to just give him a
The post Big Questions: The general election and industrial action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA will support female GPs in discrimination claim against GP at Hand owner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148143</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/bma-will-support-female-gps-in-discrimination-claim-against-gp-at-hand-owner/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T15:22:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive The BMA will support female GPs who have been made redundant by GP at Hand owner eMed, after legal advice showed there is an ‘actionable claim’ for indirect discrimination. The online NHS GP provider, which serves around 100,000 patients in London after being launched by Babylon in 2017, was taken over by US company
The post BMA will support female GPs in discrimination claim against GP at Hand owner appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice nurses encouraged to join LMCs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148154</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gp-practice-nurses-encouraged-to-join-lmcs/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T15:15:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice nurses (GPNs) should be encouraged to take up positions on their local medical committees (LMC) and challenge the ‘status quo’, it has been suggested. Ruth Colbeck, lead nurse at West Leeds Primary Care Network (PCN), discussed her journey into her local LMC and how other nurses should strive to do the same during
The post GP practice nurses encouraged to join LMCs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4506 - Baxter Welch Allyn  Connex Spot Monitor Vulnerability CVE-2024-1275]]></title>
        <id>e4eb27d0-d1f9-4a27-a013-c46b4bca83d2</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4506"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T15:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Low
 Successful exploitation of CVE-2024-1275 could lead to data compromise, resulting in impact and/or delay in patient care
 Successful exploitation of CVE-2024-1275 could lead to data compromise, resulting in impact and/or delay in patient care
 Updated: 31 May 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Petrol: health effects, incident management and toxicology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/petrol-properties-incident-management-and-toxicology</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/petrol-properties-incident-management-and-toxicology"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T14:21:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information on petrol (also known as gasoline), for use in responding to chemical incidents.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Public Health England - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Locum GP employment is 'in crisis', warns BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875044</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/locum-gp-employment-in-crisis-warns-bma/article/1875044"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T14:13:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Employment of locum GPs is 'in crisis’ because chronic underfunding has led to a collapse in the resources practices have available to hire them, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4505 - Linux Kernel Use-after-free Vulnerability]]></title>
        <id>1881cd46-5f8c-4683-a7f2-1860c86d57e4</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4505"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T12:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Linux kernel contains a vulnerability that could allow an attacker to achieve local privilege escalation
 Linux kernel contains a vulnerability that could allow an attacker to achieve local privilege escalation
 Updated: 31 May 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI chest X-ray tool made available to radiologists at more than 40 NHS trusts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176403</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/ai-chest-x-ray-tool-made-available-to-radiologists-at-more-than-40-nhs-trusts/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T12:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six imaging networks in England have selected global health tech firm Annalise.ai as the preferred provider to support early lung cancer diagnosis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>DHI News Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awards for outstanding contributions to public health presented during the Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:802d0b9d-4106-4132-9341-5079d217c8f4</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/31-05-2024-awards-for-outstanding-contributions-to-public-health-presented-during-the-seventy-seventh-world-health-assembly"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:46:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During a special ceremony at the Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly in Geneva on Friday, 31 May 2024, eight winners from four WHO Regions were awarded for their outstanding contributions to public health.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICB will allow overwhelmed GP practices to divert patients in pilot scheme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147849</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/icb-will-allow-overwhelmed-gp-practices-to-divert-patients-in-pilot-scheme/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:21:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An ICB has agreed to allow GP practices overwhelmed with demand to close and divert patients if they declare an operational pressures escalation level (OPEL) black alert. Kent and Medway ICB will soon begin a pilot of the response framework, developed with Kent LMC, which allows practices to self-declare their OPEL status based on their
The post ICB will allow overwhelmed GP practices to divert patients in pilot scheme appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Primary care staff cuts loom amid 'immense financial strain', poll reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874986</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/primary-care-staff-cuts-loom-amid-immense-financial-strain-poll-reveals/article/1874986"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:12:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most primary care leaders say they will have to reduce clinical and non-clinical staff to balance their books this year, according to a survey highlighting 'immense financial strain' on NHS providers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statement by Principals of the Inter-Agency Standing Committee (IASC): No time to lose as famine stalks millions in Sudan 
amid intense fighting and access denials]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:74eafbb5-4d70-4ebf-b876-a4fbabd27078</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/31-05-2024-statement-by-principals-of-the-inter-agency-standing-committee-iasc-no-time-to-lose-as-famine-stalks-millions-in-sudan-amid-intense-fighting-and-access-denials"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:12:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the conflict now in its second year, 18 million people are acutely hungry, including 3.6 million children who are acutely malnourished, and famine is quickly closing in on millions of people in Darfur, Kordofan, Aj Jazirah and Khartoum.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movers and Shakers news roundup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176407</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/movers-and-shakers-news-roundup-48/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T10:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Movers and Shakers roundup includes interim appointments at Surrey and Borders Partnership and East London NHS Foundation Trusts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices told to plan for October start for autumn Covid jabs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148131</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/gp-practices-told-to-plan-for-october-start-for-autumn-covid-jabs/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T09:58:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has told GP practices to plan for an ‘early October’ start to the Covid-19 autumn vaccination programme, in a letter published yesterday. It said that it will agree a precise start date for both the flu and Covid jab campaigns ‘in due course’. And with advice still to come from the Joint Committee
The post GP practices told to plan for October start for autumn Covid jabs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The state of NHS finances 2024/25]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/the-state-of-nhs-finances-202425.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/the-state-of-nhs-finances-202425.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T09:57:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - This report examines the financial challenge facing NHS organisations in 2024/25 and finds that the number one challenge facing NHS leaders and their staff is how they balance their books while protecting patient safety given many organisations are having to achieve significant efficiency savings. The survey of NHS leaders carried out by the NHS Confederation shows that...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One month left to get spring covid jab as NHS rolls out joint appointment booking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=246894</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/05/one-month-left-to-get-spring-covid-jab-as-nhs-rolls-out-joint-appointment-booking/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T09:36:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With only one month left of this year’s spring covid vaccine programme, the NHS is urging all eligible people who haven’t yet had their top-up to come forward and get protected before 30 June 2024. The reminder comes alongside the roll-out of joint appointment booking, which can be done online or via 119. By selecting a joint booking, two eligible people aged […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summary care records application to switch off next week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148128</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/summary-care-records-application-to-switch-off-next-week/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T09:27:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The technology that allows healthcare professionals to view summary care records will change on Monday (3 June), GP practices have been warned. The Summary Care Record application (SCRa) will be fully switched off and replaced by the National Care Record Service (NCRS), which provides access to more than 63 million records. Users will automatically be redirected to NCRS,
The post Summary care records application to switch off next week appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medicines shortages could derail Pharmacy First scheme, MPs warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874976</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/medicines-shortages-derail-pharmacy-first-scheme-mps-warn/article/1874976"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T08:50:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs have urged the government to 'get a grip' on the medicines supply chain and hand pharmacists powers to switch medicines - warning drug shortages could derail the Pharmacy First scheme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBC investigation links NHS IT failures to patient harm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176413</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/bbc-investigation-links-nhs-it-failures-to-patient-harm/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T07:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A BBC News investigation found 126 instances of serious harm linked to IT issues across 31 acute trusts, including three patient deaths.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>DHI News Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: BMA GP ballot and the general election, GP funding and deprivation, LMCs conference]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874816</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-bma-gp-ballot-general-election-gp-funding-deprivation-lmcs-conference/article/1874816"/>
        <updated>2024-05-31T07:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How will the general election affect the BMA's ballot on collective action by GPs, why GP funding needs to change to tackle health inequalities and our round-up of the key debates from the UK LMCs conference]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of NHS patients to access trials of personalised cancer ‘vaccines’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=246872</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/05/thousands-of-nhs-patients-to-access-trials-of-personalised-cancer-vaccines/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T23:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of cancer patients in England are set to gain fast-tracked access to trials of personalised cancer vaccines following the launch of a world-leading NHS trial “matchmaking” service to help find new life-saving treatments. The NHS today announced it has treated its first patient in England with a personalised vaccine against their bowel cancer, in […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly – Daily update: 30 May 2024]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:1a52e2ed-8bf4-4952-bfe1-fe3d37f5b10e</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/30-05-2024-seventy-seventh-world-health-assembly---daily-update--30-may-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T18:36:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delegates approve groundbreaking new agreement on transplantation
On 29 May 2024, Member States (with the initiation of Spain) approved a new resolution on increasing availability, ethical access and oversight of transplantation of human cells, tissues and organs. 
Transplantation is a life-saving treatment. The latest data of 2022 from the Global Observatory on Donation and Transplantation indicate that more than 150 000 solid organ transplants (≤ 10% of global needs) are performed worldwide annually, which is an increase of 52% compared with 2010.

However, there is still an apparent insufficient growth in and asymmetrical development of transplantation worldwide with many countries not having established the appropriate systems, including legislation, governance, specialized workforce, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘LMCs can choose to separate themselves from same-day hubs, or get involved’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148100</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/letters/lmcs-can-choose-to-separate-themselves-from-same-day-hubs-or-get-involved/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T15:34:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a letter to Pulse, the LMC chairs for Berkshire, Buckingham and Oxfordshire explain the relationship between on-the-ground GPs and the ICB regarding the plans for same-day hubs in the region We are writing to you to pre-empt a likely error of interpretation in your recently published article in Pulse, ‘ICB rubber-stamps plans for same-day
The post ‘LMCs can choose to separate themselves from same-day hubs, or get involved’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of new GPs could be unemployed this summer, warns BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148067</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/thousands-of-new-gps-could-be-unemployed-this-summer-warns-bma/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T15:14:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of newly qualified GPs could be unemployed this August due to a ‘nearly non-existent’ job market in some areas, the BMA has warned. Speaking at the UK LMCs conference last week, chair of the union’s GP registrars committee Dr Malinga Ratwatte warned that of the 4,000 registrars achieving their CCT over the summer, many
The post Thousands of new GPs could be unemployed this summer, warns BMA appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What GPs need to know about NICE’s vitamin B12 deficiency guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148078</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/gastroenterology/what-gps-need-to-know-about-nices-vitamin-b12-deficiency-guidance/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T14:42:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP Dr Ed Pooley summarises NICE’s new guidance on vitamin B12 deficiency in over 16s Vitamin B12 is an essential water-soluble vitamin required for metabolism, DNA synthesis, nerve cell functioning and maturation of erythrocytes. It is widely found in meat, shellfish, liver, eggs, poultry, dairy products, and as a fortification agent in breakfast cereals. Symptoms
The post What GPs need to know about NICE’s vitamin B12 deficiency guidance appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government puts ’emergency ban’ on private prescribing of puberty blockers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148105</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/sexual-health-and-gynaecology/government-puts-emergency-ban-on-private-prescribing-of-puberty-blockers/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T14:22:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has brought in an emergency ban on private prescribing of puberty blockers to children and young people. Earlier this year, NHS England banned routine prescription of puberty blockers on the NHS for children with gender dysphoria, after a working group found there is not sufficient evidence to support their ‘safety or clinical effectiveness’.
The post Government puts ’emergency ban’ on private prescribing of puberty blockers appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4504 - Check Point Releases Security Hotfix for Exploited Zero-Day Vulnerability CVE-2024-24919]]></title>
        <id>2d997862-be0f-4b7f-9bdc-24b583975168</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4504"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T14:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: High
 Active exploitation of Check Point security gateway devices
 Check Point has released security advisories relating to ongoing exploitation of a zero-day vulnerability in the Quantum Gateway and CloudGuard family of products
 Updated: 30 May 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General election 2024: Health leaders share their views on digital priorities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176383</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/general-election-2024-health-leaders-share-their-views-on-digital-priorities/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T12:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the government announcement of a general election, we asked health tech leaders and think tanks what the priorities should be for digital health.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices delivered 25% more appointments this April than in 2019]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874809</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-delivered-25-appointments-april-2019/article/1874809"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T12:14:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices in England delivered almost 25% more appointments this April compared with the same month in 2019 - with around 3% fewer GPs, official data show.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176325</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-141/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T11:16:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's briefing includes Bruntwood SciTech launching its new Life Science Accelerator programme and a new 24/7 mobile service in Neath Port Talbot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leicester launches NHS trial of smart inhalers for children]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176323</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/leicester-launches-nhs-trial-of-smart-inhalers-for-children/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T10:37:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Around 300 children and young people in Leicester will be given smart inhalers that monitor use via a smartphone app, as part of an NHS-funded study.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>DHI News Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ambulance crews ‘bullying’ practices to access GP, warn LMCs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148090</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/urgent-care/ambulance-crews-bullying-practices-to-access-gp-warn-lmcs/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T10:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LMCs are pushing back against ambulance crews who ‘inappropriately’ insist on speaking to a GP immediately when attending 999 calls. This month, both Lancashire and Cumbria LMCs and Leicester, Leicestershire and Rutland (LLR) LMC have put out guidance emphasising that practices have ‘no contractual obligation’ to give clinical advice to ambulance teams. Staff at the
The post Ambulance crews ‘bullying’ practices to access GP, warn LMCs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fruit and veg prescription pilot reduced GP appointments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147979</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/obesity-and-nutrition/fruit-and-veg-prescription-pilot-reduced-gp-appointments/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T09:33:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A charity behind a pilot scheme to prescribe fruit and veg on prescription has called for national rollout, after reporting benefits on physical and mental health and a reduction in GP appointments. In the first eight months of the scheme being run in Tower Hamlets and Lambeth nine in ten participants have seen health improvements
The post Fruit and veg prescription pilot reduced GP appointments appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA surveys GPs about employment as ‘increasing numbers’ struggle to find work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148017</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/bma-surveys-gps-about-employment-as-increasing-numbers-struggle-to-find-work/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T09:21:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP locums are being asked to share their experiences of the current employment crisis as part of a BMA survey. The doctors’ union said it has heard from ‘increasing numbers’ of GP locums that they are ‘having difficulties in obtaining suitable locum work’, and that the nature of locum work ‘has become ever more challenging’.
The post BMA surveys GPs about employment as ‘increasing numbers’ struggle to find work appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Millions more GP appointments in April than before pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=246761</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/05/millions-more-gp-appointments-in-april-than-before-pandemic/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T08:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP teams delivered more than 30 million appointments for patients last month (April 2024), up by almost a quarter on the same period before the pandemic. NHS data published today shows there were around 30.5 million appointments delivered by GPs and their teams in just one month, compared with 24.5 million in April 2019 – […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sudan’s children trapped in critical malnutrition crisis, warn UN agencies]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:6f1a124d-6ea9-4f0f-95ff-58b5985f0bc6</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/30-05-2024-sudan-s-children-trapped-in-critical-malnutrition-crisis--warn-un-agencies"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T07:36:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three United Nations agencies today issued a stark warning that all indications point to a significant deterioration of the nutrition situation for children and mothers in war-torn Sudan. The lives of Sudan’s children are at stake and urgent action is needed to protect an entire generation from malnutrition, disease and death.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Rewired Pitchfest 2025 entries now open to start-ups]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176303</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/digital-health-rewired-pitchfest-2025-entries-now-open-to-start-ups/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-30T07:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Entries for Digital Health Rewired Pitchfest 2025 are now open to start-ups, providing the opportunity to pitch to an audience of NHS leaders and investors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly – Daily update: 29 May 2024]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:10d452fe-94b0-4649-b32b-e2fcfa89b1a8</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/29-05-2024-seventy-seventh-world-health-assembly---daily-update--29-may-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T16:56:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First-ever resolution on social participation for primary health care approved

Member States have agreed on a resolution on social participation in national health planning and implementation, which paves the way for people, communities, and civil society to have a stronger voice in influencing the decisions that affect their health and well-being. 

The resolution aims to tackle health inequities and the erosion of trust in health systems, which is crucial in the face of the unprecedented challenges the world is facing such as climate change, conflicts, and pandemic threats. 

Growing evidence shows the transformative potential of social participation to foster trust in health systems, advance equity and align healthcare with people’s lived experiences. Two-way dialogues between governme…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[News story: New restrictions on puberty blockers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-restrictions-on-puberty-blockers</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-restrictions-on-puberty-blockers"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T16:06:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New regulations restrict the prescribing and supply of puberty-suppressing hormones to children and young people under 18.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP trainee recruitment requires more than half-baked commitments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148085</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/gp-trainee-recruitment-requires-more-than-half-baked-commitments/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T15:50:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse editor Jaimie Kaffash makes the case for prioritising GP training in any future workforce plans Even when the NHS and Government tries their best to promote general practice, they don’t quite get it right. Last year, the NHS’s major workforce plan laid out how it intends to increase the number of GPs in England.
The post GP trainee recruitment requires more than half-baked commitments appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remove contractual restrictions on GPs seeing patients privately, say UK LMCs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148073</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/lmcs-conferences/remove-contractual-restrictions-on-gps-seeing-patients-privately-say-uk-lmcs/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T14:58:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should have the ability to treat patients privately ‘in the same way that other clinicians can’, UK GP leaders have said. LMCs acknowledged during their conference last week that patients are ‘increasingly’ looking to access care privately due to ‘underfunding’ in general practice, and demanded that GPs are allowed to see their patients privately.
The post Remove contractual restrictions on GPs seeing patients privately, say UK LMCs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Closed consultation: Health and social care statistical outputs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/health-and-social-care-statistical-outputs</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/health-and-social-care-statistical-outputs"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T14:48:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are seeking views on health and social care statistical outputs published by DHSC (including OHID), NHSBSA, UKHSA, ONS and NHS England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4503 - RCE Vulnerability in Atlassian Confluence Data Center and Confluence Server]]></title>
        <id>24362ad3-ceac-42d0-820d-7f0b1e2c6c05</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4503"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Proof-of-concept exploit code released for RCE vulnerability CVE-2024-21683
 Proof-of-concept code released for RCE vulnerability CVE-2024-21683
 Updated: 29 May 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP gives compensation to GP trainees affected by exam fiasco]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148031</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/education-and-training/rcgp-gives-compensation-to-gp-trainees-affected-by-exam-fiasco/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T12:53:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP trainees who were unable to complete a new component of the MRCGP exam due to an IT outage have received compensation from the RCGP. Last year, a number of candidates had difficulties completing the Simulated Consultation Assessment (SCA) after an issue with the IT system that the RCGP said was due to ‘an unprecedented outage by a global
The post RCGP gives compensation to GP trainees affected by exam fiasco appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man jailed for six-and-a-half years after violent attack on GP and practice staff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874616</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/man-jailed-six-and-a-half-years-violent-attack-gp-practice-staff/article/1874616"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T12:40:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man has been jailed for six-and-a-half years after attacking a GP with a metal pole and strangling a member of practice staff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHSC publishes social care digital skills support tender worth £475k]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176295</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/dhsc-publishes-social-care-digital-skills-support-tender-worth-475k/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T12:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Department of Health and Social Care has published a tender to secure an organisation to develop the digital skills of the adult social care workforce.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social prescribers back accreditation and standardised training]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874599</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/social-prescribers-back-accreditation-standardised-training/article/1874599"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T11:32:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The National Association of Link Workers, which represents social prescribing link workers, has voted to back steps that would help professionalise the role of social prescribers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man jailed for six and a half years over Manchester GP surgery assaults]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147970</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/special-investigations/gp-abuse/man-jailed-for-six-and-a-half-years-over-manchester-gp-surgery-assaults/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:53:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man has been sentenced to six and a half years in jail after pleading guilty to four assaults of staff at a GP surgery in Manchester. Olumuiwa Oduntan received the sentence last week (23 May), having attacked members of staff at a GP surgery in 2021 with a metal barrier pole after he was
The post Man jailed for six and a half years over Manchester GP surgery assaults appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy First ‘will fail’ if people ‘keep having to return to their GP’, MPs warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148045</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/pharmacy-first-will-fail-if-people-keep-having-to-return-to-their-gp-mps-warn/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:27:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy First ‘will fail’ if patients ‘keep having to return to their GPs’, a group of influential MPs has warned. A new report by the House of Commons health and social care committee said that patients’ concerns about ‘being referred back to the GP’ if they go to community pharmacies to receive care ‘should ring
The post Pharmacy First ‘will fail’ if people ‘keep having to return to their GP’, MPs warn appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors announce strike in run-up to general election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874575</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/junior-doctors-announce-strike-run-up-general-election/article/1874575"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:24:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors in England are to stage a five-day strike that will run from 7am on 27 June to 7am on 2 July.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking stock of the Government’s delivery plan for recovering primary care: one year on review]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/taking-stock-of-the-governments-delivery-plan-for-recovering-primary-care-one-year-on-review.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/taking-stock-of-the-governments-delivery-plan-for-recovering-primary-care-one-year-on-review.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:23:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PAGB - The Self-Care Strategy Group, founded by PAGB in 2019 with representatives of leading pharmacy and healthcare organisations, has published a report marking one year since the launch of NHS England's Delivery plan for recovering access to primary care. The delivery plan, published in May 2023, has been framed as a first step to address access challenges ahead of...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surrey and Borders select Better and Avenue3 for new integrated platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176225</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/surrey-and-borders-select-better-and-avenue3-for-new-integrated-platform/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T10:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Surrey and Borders Partnership NHS FT has selected Better to provide a new digital health platform and Avenue3 to implement a mental health patient portal.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour pledges to clear NHS elective backlog within five years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148034</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/referrals/labour-pledges-to-clear-nhs-elective-backlog-within-five-years/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T09:35:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Labour Party has pledged to eradicate elective waits over 18 weeks within five years, if they are elected on 4 July. A Labour government would invest £1.3bn to reduce hospital waiting times, via a doubling of the number of scanners; paying NHS staff to work evenings and weekends; as well as funding private surgeries.
The post Labour pledges to clear NHS elective backlog within five years appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government has ignored call to investigate GP unemployment crisis, BMA says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874470</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/government-ignored-call-investigate-gp-unemployment-crisis-bma-says/article/1874470"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T08:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government has ignored calls for an urgent review into the unemployment crisis that has left thousands of GPs struggling to find work, the BMA's sessional GP leader has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First implementation phase of Guernsey’s new EPR delayed to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176205</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/first-implementation-phase-of-guernseys-new-epr-delayed-to-2025/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-29T07:30:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guernsey Government has announced that the first phase of the island's EPR implementation has been delayed to 2025 due to patient safety.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour promises five-year plan to end NHS backlog]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874496</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/labour-promises-five-year-plan-end-nhs-backlog/article/1874496"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Labour party has promised to end NHS waits of more than 18 weeks within the next parliament - bringing a major driver of GP workload front and centre in the general election campaign.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO Member States agree way forward to conclude Pandemic Agreement]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:9eab43db-65d9-43fb-aff6-23c4328d31e6</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/28-05-2024-who-member-states-agree-way-forward-to-conclude-pandemic-agreement"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T19:43:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Assembly (WHA) today recognized the progress made over the past two years by Member States to develop a pandemic agreement and strengthen the International Health Regulations (IHR, 2005). Governments meeting in Geneva for the Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly are in talks to advance these two efforts, which aim to boost the world’s ability to better able to prevent and respond to the threat of future pandemics.
 
WHO Member States agreed to continue to work during the World Health Assembly, which ends on 1 June, with the aim to:

finalize the package of amendments to the IHR (2005)
agree the timing, format and process to conclude the pandemic agreement.

 During today’s session, the WHA first considered agenda item 13.4 on the draft pandemic agreement. Delegates acknowledged the extensive work undertaken by the Member State-led Intergovernmental Negotiating Body (INB), and the Bureau steering the work, since governments launched the process in December 2021 to develop the world’s first pandemic accord to prevent a repeat of the global health, economic and social impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic.
 
Member States reiterated that the world needs a pandemic agreement built on the principles of equity, sovereignty, and prevention, preparedness and response, and to ensure future generations are safeguarded from the threat of inevitable future pandemics.
 
WHA delegates also considered agenda item 13.3, which laid out the work undertaken to negotiate the amendments to the International Health Regulations(2005) to build on lessons learned from the global response to the COVID-19 pandemic.  
 
Member States stressed that agreement on updated and stronger International Health Regulations were essential for ensuring global health security.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly – Daily update: 28 May 2024]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:9083381a-bb1e-4ebf-bb3a-13a875c6499d</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/28-05-2024-seventy-seventh-world-health-assembly---daily-update--28-may-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T19:01:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World Health Assembly approves a global health strategy fit for a challenging future 

Delegates at the Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly (WHA 77) approved a four-year, US$ 11.1 billion strategy for global health to promote, provide, and protect health and well-being for all people, with an emphasis on climate change, aging, migration, pandemic threats, and equity, and adapted for a time of fast-moving geopolitics, science and technology. 

The strategy, the Fourteenth General Programme of Work   (GPW 14), treats 2025–2028 as an exceptional window of opportunity to build resilient, fit-for-future health systems and, in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic, to get back on track to reach the health-related Sustainable Development Goals.

GPW 14 has six strategic objectives which reflect maj…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO’s investment case launch draws expressions of support, pledges to sustainably finance four-year strategy]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:a999d78a-b669-4c3b-a9b3-62fb0d42dfc2</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/28-05-2024-who-s-investment-case-launch-draws-expressions-of-support--pledges-to-sustainably-finance-four-year-strategy"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T15:44:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO on Tuesday launched an investment case that lays out the Organization’s essential contribution to global health and seeks investment in its 2025–2028 strategy to save 40 million lives and improve the health of 6 billion people. 

The investment case underpins WHO’s Investment Round, which kicked off on Sunday and has gained many robust expressions of support, commitments from countries to co-host, and a number of initial pledges that build momentum toward the Investment Round’s culmination later this year. 
Statements of support and funding commitments came from Member States, and the European Union during Tuesday’s launch event at a strategic roundtable of the Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly (WHA77). 

“I thank Brazil, which will host the Investment Round as President of the G20…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government ‘likely’ to only offer additional 4% GP pay uplift, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148019</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/government-likely-to-only-offer-additional-4-gp-pay-uplift-says-bma/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T15:28:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA says a further GP pay uplift of 4% for this financial year is ‘likely’ following a recommendation from the doctors’ pay review body in July. This would mean GP practices receive a total uplift of just 5.9% for 2024/25, including the 1.9% already announced as part of this year’s contract imposition.  NHS England
The post Government ‘likely’ to only offer additional 4% GP pay uplift, says BMA appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A preventative approach to public services: how the government can shift its focus and improve lives]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/a-preventative-approach-to-public-services-how-the-government-can-shift-its-focus-and-improve-lives.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/a-preventative-approach-to-public-services-how-the-government-can-shift-its-focus-and-improve-lives.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T15:07:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Government - This report sets out how the next government can use the opportunity of a new parliament to shift to a preventative approach to public services that seeks to address and manage citizens’ problems before they reach crisis point. This would reap financial and political benefits by helping tackle the crises in the NHS, criminal justice, youth...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England told to boost GP practice numbers participating in research trials]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147981</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/nhs-england-told-to-boost-gp-practice-numbers-participating-in-research-trials/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T14:53:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS should be ‘ambitious’ in boosting the number of GP practices who undertake commercial research, a paper presented to the NHS England board has said. Currently only around 3% of practices take part in commercial clinical trials, the report said. Yet as the focus of delivery of services shifts from secondary care to local
The post NHS England told to boost GP practice numbers participating in research trials appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man charged with grievous bodily harm after GP stabbed at practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874461</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/man-charged-grievous-bodily-harm-gp-stabbed-practice/article/1874461"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T14:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man has been charged with grievous bodily harm after a GP was stabbed at a practice in south-east London, police have confirmed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time to put action into words]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147938</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/time-to-put-action-into-words/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T14:19:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Copperfield pens an open letter to patients following the BMA’s announcement for planned industrial action to start in August So now we know. The initial sabre rattle of industrial action will be something along the lines of not doing fit notes, scripts, and investigations which should have been arranged by secondary care. In other
The post Time to put action into words appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4502 - Cisco Releases May 2024 ASA, FMC, and FTD Software Security Advisory]]></title>
        <id>b07ee3f0-d3ed-48a5-8107-3be7d2c1f240</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4502"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T14:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Six advisories are included in the semi-annual Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance Software (ASA), Firepower Management Center (FMC) Software, and Firepower Threat Defense (FTD) Software Security Advisory bundled publication
 Six advisories are included in the semi-annual Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance Software (ASA), Firepower Management Center (FMC) Software, and Firepower Threat Defense (FTD) Software Security Advisory bundled publication
 Updated: 28 May 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reverse the trend: reducing type 2 diabetes in young people]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/reverse-the-trend-reducing-type-2-diabetes-in-young-people.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/reverse-the-trend-reducing-type-2-diabetes-in-young-people.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T14:09:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diabetes UK - This report reveals a 40% rise in type 2 diabetes diagnoses in younger people between 2016-17 and 2022-23. There are now almost 168,000 people under 40 years in the UK who live with type 2 diabetes, an increase of more than 47,000 since 2016-17. Diabetes UK is calling on all political parties to commit to tackling the...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefighters vote in favour of opposing ‘dangerous’ use of physician associates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147999</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/firefighters-vote-in-favour-of-opposing-dangerous-use-of-physician-associates/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T13:54:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The use of physician associates (PAs) in the NHS has been opposed by firefighters and other workers within fire and rescue services across the UK. The Fire Brigades Union voted in favour of a motion calling its executive council to ‘use its influence’ to ‘oppose this dangerous practice’, during the union’s national conference last week.
The post Firefighters vote in favour of opposing ‘dangerous’ use of physician associates appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Community pharmacy primary care network engagement role]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/community-pharmacy-primary-care-network-engagement-role.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/community-pharmacy-primary-care-network-engagement-role.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T13:39:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England - The community pharmacy primary care network (PCN) engagement lead role has been established to support the regional implementation of the pharmacy Primary Care Access Recovery Plan (PCARP) requirements, including implementing the Pharmacy First Service and expanding the Blood Pressure Checks Service and Pharmacy Contraception Service. Guidance More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global oncology trends 2024: outlook to 2028]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/global-oncology-trends-2024-outlook-to-2028.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/05/global-oncology-trends-2024-outlook-to-2028.html"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T13:26:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IQVIA Institute for Human Data Science - Latest estimates indicate that the number of patients affected by cancer will increase dramatically through the middle of the century across all regions of the world. At the same time, the innovation ecosystem that discovers, develops, and delivers breakthrough therapies in entire new areas of science is operating near peak levels. Rising incidence,...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jersey Gov to award £2m to tech that can support ageing population]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176185</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/jersey-gov-to-award-2m-to-tech-that-can-support-ageing-population/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T12:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government of Jersey is awarding up to £2 million to technology solutions that improve the lives and wellbeing of Jersey’s rapidly ageing population.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA opposes NHSE plans for trainees to spend three years in general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147988</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/education-and-training/bma-opposes-nhse-plans-for-trainees-to-spend-three-years-in-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T11:06:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA is opposing NHS England’s plans for GPs in training to spend all three years in general practice posts. According to the union’s registrar committee, GPs in training should instead spend one year in secondary care or community settings, alongside two years in primary care. Speaking at the UK LMCs conference last week, committee
The post BMA opposes NHSE plans for trainees to spend three years in general practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five devices recommended by NICE to ease home testing for sleep apnoea]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147683</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/five-devices-recommended-by-nice-to-ease-home-testing-for-sleep-apnoea/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T10:49:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NICE has recommended five devices that can be used at home to diagnose and assess the severity of obstructive sleep apnoea hypopnoea syndrome. The draft guidance which applies to those over the age of 16 could help the NHS identify people with the condition more easily, NICE said. More research is needed on the home-testing
The post Five devices recommended by NICE to ease home testing for sleep apnoea appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176149</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-140/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T10:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This briefing features Aliter acquiring healthcare ICT provider Bates IT and Apple Watch’s AFib feature being approved as a medical device by the FDA.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rotherham NHS FT rolls out diagnostic booking solution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176159</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/rotherham-nhs-ft-rolls-out-diagnostic-booking-solution/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T10:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rotherham NHS Foundation Trust has announced the launch of a diagnostic booking solution, developed in partnership with Netcall.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demand end to Gaza health worker attacks, 600 GPs urge Government]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147886</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/demand-end-to-gaza-health-worker-attacks-600-gps-urge-government/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T09:56:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of GPs have signed an open letter to the Government expressing their ‘deep concern’ about the ‘catastrophe unfolding on the Gaza Strip’, including the destruction of healthcare facilities.  The letter, written by trade union Doctors in Unite and signed by more than 1,500 doctors including 600 GPs, called on the Government to ‘demand from
The post Demand end to Gaza health worker attacks, 600 GPs urge Government appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five top tips for better chronic pain management]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147976</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/pain/five-top-tips-for-better-chronic-pain-management/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T09:49:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest in our Pulse Live series, where experts summarise their presentations from Pulse Live events, Dr Alan Fayaz, consultant in anaesthesia and pain medicine at University College London Hospital NHS Foundation Trust, dispenses his top tips on managing chronic pain Chronic pain (pain in any part of the body persisting beyond twelve weeks) is
The post Five top tips for better chronic pain management appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DDRB uplift could leave practices £350m behind 2019 funding, warns GP leader]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1874367</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/ddrb-uplift-leave-practices-350m-behind-2019-funding-warns-gp-leader/article/1874367"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T09:21:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice faces a £350m funding shortfall this year compared with 2019 even if a new government implements a further contract uplift, BMA England's GP committee chair has predicted.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England and NICE announce plan to speed up innovative tech adoption]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176143</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/05/nhs-england-and-nice-announce-plan-to-speed-up-innovative-tech-adoption/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-28T07:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England and NICE have outlined a joint proposal to help fast-track clinically and cost-effective products for use by the healthcare system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 8000 people, including sports and health champions, join 5th WHO Walk the Talk in Geneva]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:64e4a394-3828-4fbf-b4ab-df940f6d414a</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/27-05-2024-over-8000-people-including-sports-and-health-champions-join-5th-who-walk-the-talk-in-geneva"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T15:33:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO together with Swiss and Geneva partners, the UN family, Member States, athletes, local sports clubs, and health partners came together on Sunday 26 May 2024, to celebrate the importance of healthy lifestyles and to kick off the Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Director-General’s Award for Global Health go to Prime Minister of Barbados and developers of mRNA vaccines for COVID-19]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:74d2f4c8-fec4-45b7-a591-13e652be063a</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/27-05-2024-director-general-s-award-for-global-health-go-to-prime-minister-of-barbados-and-developers-of-mrna-vaccines-for-covid-19"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T11:43:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus presented his Award for Global Health to the Prime Minister of Barbados and two scientists for their contributions to advancing global health at the Seventy-seventh World Health Assembly.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS announces 143 hospitals to roll out ‘Martha’s Rule’ in next step in major patient safety initiative]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=246572</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/05/nhs-announces-143-hospitals-to-roll-out-marthas-rule/"/>
        <updated>2024-05-27T08:09:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS has today announced the 143 hospital sites that will test and roll out Martha’s Rule in its first year. Confirmation of the first sites to test implementation of Martha’s Rule is the next step in a major patient safety initiative, following the announcement in February of NHS England funding for this financial year. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO launches its first Investment Round to sustainably finance its Health for All mandate]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:7d1ead01-9e88-4d2f-845a-e1ae6de8e747</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/26-05-2024-who-launches-its-first-investment-round-to-sustainably-finance-its-health-for-all-mandate"/>
        <updated>2024-05-26T19:26:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) launched its first-ever  Investment Round on Sunday as part of a broader plan to transform the way the Organization is funded heading into an era of climate change, mass migration, pandemic threats, an ageing world population, and turbulent geopolitics.
The launch, on the eve of the Seventy-Seventh World Health Assembly, marks the start of a year-long series of engagements and events, co-hosted by countries, where Member States and other donors will be invited to contribute funds to WHO’s strategy for 2025 through 2028 and show high-level political commitment to WHO and global health. 
The Investment Round will culminate in November with a major pledging event to be hosted by Brazil around the G20 Leaders’ Summit.
“It’s about ensuring WHO is fully funded…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO announces winners of the 5th Health for All Film Festival]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:091163dc-b29a-44b7-90a8-55b541b2d9be</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/26-05-2024-who-announces-winners-of-the-5th-health-for-all-film-festival"/>
        <updated>2024-05-26T08:33:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization has announced the official selection of this year’s winning films of its 5th Health for All Film Festival. The awards were announced today at a special event launching WHO’s Investment Round on the eve of the Seventy-Seventh World Health Assembly in Geneva.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>