<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html</id>
    <title>Industry Feed</title>
    <updated>2024-08-25T09:10:29.261Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workload dump impacting GP ability to provide safe care, LMC warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152564</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/workload-dump-impacting-gp-ability-to-provide-safe-care-lmc-warns/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T15:08:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Workload dump is impacting London GP practices’ ability to deliver safe patient care, the local LMC has warned. London-wide LMC said that the number of practices whose ability to deliver safe patient care is being impacted by workload shift ‘remains high’, and that 76% are ‘unable to absorb’ that additional workload. Of 247 practices taking
The post Workload dump impacting GP ability to provide safe care, LMC warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Abortion statistics: protocol for the release of personal data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/abortion-statistics-protocol-for-the-release-of-personal-data</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/abortion-statistics-protocol-for-the-release-of-personal-data"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T14:44:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to apply for the release of and use confidential abortion data for scientific research purposes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Checker: New collective action, Musk to take over GP services and all-new Zardi centres]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152468</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/pulse-checker/pulse-checker/pulse-checker-new-collective-action-musk-to-take-over-gp-services-and-all-new-zardi-centres/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T14:38:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Checker returns with its not-entirely-serious take on the month’s events. None of these news stories are true (to the best of our knowledge) BMA suggests ‘talking at slightly lower volume’ as next form of collective action The BMA’s GP Committee England have added new forms of collective action for GPs to undertake, including speaking
The post Pulse Checker: New collective action, Musk to take over GP services and all-new Zardi centres appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drones can successfully fly blood packs, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203289</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/drones-can-successfully-fly-blood-packs-study-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T12:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Drones can be used as a safe mode of transport for delivering blood packs, according to a study run by NHS Blood and Transplant.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government extends puberty blocker ban until end of November]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152540</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/government-extends-puberty-blocker-ban-until-end-of-november/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T11:33:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has renewed a temporary ban on private prescribing of puberty blockers which was introduced under the Conservatives.  Last month, health secretary Wes Streeting said he is ‘defending’ the emergency ban, which was being challenged at the High court by transgender rights activists.  It was brought in by former health secretary Victoria Atkins in
The post Government extends puberty blocker ban until end of November appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs still face blood testing disruption two months after cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152534</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gps-still-face-blood-testing-disruption-two-months-after-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T11:03:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices continue to face disruption following a major cyber attack on a pathology lab over two months ago. The latest NHS update has revealed that GP practices in three out of six south east London boroughs are yet to return to usual blood testing services.  At the start of June, Synnovis, a provider of
The post GPs still face blood testing disruption two months after cyber attack appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research suggests link between semaglutide and suicidal thoughts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152461</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/research-suggests-link-between-semaglutide-and-suicidal-thoughts/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T11:01:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have found an apparent disproportional risk of suicidal thoughts with semaglutide compared with other diabetes drugs. A study based on a World Health Organisation global database of adverse drug reactions found while cases were very rare patients were significantly more likely to report suicidal thoughts while taking semaglutide compared to other medication. The increased
The post Research suggests link between semaglutide and suicidal thoughts appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alzheimer’s treatment gets MHRA approval, but is too costly for the NHS says NICE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886023</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/alzheimers-treatment-gets-mhra-approval-costly-nhs-says-nice/article/1886023"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T10:21:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lecanemab has been shown to slow down progression of Alzheimer's disease - but the benefits are too small to justify the costs, NICE has concluded in draft guidance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England signs digital urgent and emergency care contracts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203467</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/nhs-england-signs-digital-urgent-and-emergency-care-contracts/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T10:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has signed two contracts to support the digital transformation of urgent and emergency care, totalling £86 million in value.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England releases guidance to GP practice in wake of racist riots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885061</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-england-releases-guidance-gp-practice-wake-racist-riots/article/1885061"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has written to GP practices offering advice on how to support staff in the wake of the recent racist riots that swept the country.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feeling the pressure: what the 2023 Commonwealth Fund survey reveals about the state of the UK health system]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/feeling-the-pressure-what-the-2023-commonwealth-fund-survey-reveals-about-the-state-of-the-uk-health.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/feeling-the-pressure-what-the-2023-commonwealth-fund-survey-reveals-about-the-state-of-the-uk-health.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T09:05:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This report found that the UK’s performance on hospital-based care is consistently near the bottom in a public survey of 10 high income countries. The analysis of the 2023 Commonwealth Fund survey highlights key areas where the UK performs poorly, particularly on long waits for specialist care, lack of access to out-of-hours care and affordability for...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fifth of patients have long COVID at some GP practices in north of England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886002</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/fifth-patients-long-covid-gp-practices-north-england/article/1886002"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T08:53:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One in five patients at some GP practices in northern England are living with long COVID - driving up workload particularly in practices serving deprived populations, a report reveals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking the next step for working carers: introducing a new right to paid Carer’s Leave]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/taking-the-next-step-for-working-carers-introducing-a-new-right-to-paid-carers-leave.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/taking-the-next-step-for-working-carers-introducing-a-new-right-to-paid-carers-leave.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T08:26:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Carers UK - This report argues that introducing paid Carer’s Leave could boost productivity, whilst improving millions of workers’ lives. It estimates that it would cost the Government between £5.5 million to £32 million annually, if the statutory right to five days of unpaid Carer’s Leave for all employees with unpaid caring responsibilities was turned into paid Carer’s Leave. In...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[North London Mental Health Partnership goes live with PHR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203361</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/north-london-mental-health-partnership-goes-live-with-phr/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T07:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[North London Mental Health Partnership (NLMHP) has gone live with a personal health record from Patients Know Best.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 actions the government can take to improve NHS working conditions]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/10-actions-the-government-can-take-to-improve-nhs-working-conditions.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/10-actions-the-government-can-take-to-improve-nhs-working-conditions.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T16:24:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The King's Fund - The workforce crisis is at the heart of many of the challenges facing the NHS in England. This briefing outlines early actions the government can take to enable NHS staff and leaders to deliver the highest possible quality of care in the coming months. Briefing The King's Fund - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Join a discussion on health inequalities in women in a free MIMS Learning webinar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885957</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/join-discussion-health-inequalities-women-free-mims-learning-webinar/article/1885957"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T16:07:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join an expert panel – menopause specialist Dr Louise Newson, consultant gynaecologist Mr Abdelmageed Abdelrahman and GPwSI gynaecology Dr Anita Sharma – for a free MIMS Learning webinar on health inequalities faced by women, and how healthcare professionals can support patients at 7pm on Tuesday, 10 September 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA and Capita in disagreement over thousands of ‘missing’ GP pension records]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152481</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/bma-and-capita-in-disagreement-over-thousands-of-missing-gp-pension-records/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T15:48:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of GPs in England are experiencing significant issues with their pension records due to ‘maladministration’ by Capita, the BMA has claimed. According to BMA, ‘one of the biggest challenges’ that GPs face is out of date and inaccurate pension records, with ‘missing years’ of pensions data ‘due to mismanagement of pension records’ – which
The post BMA and Capita in disagreement over thousands of ‘missing’ GP pension records appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fighting for general practice: the key to a net zero health service]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151104</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/fighting-for-general-practice-the-key-to-a-net-zero-health-service/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T15:06:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Emma Radcliffe on how general practice can be used to green the NHS I have devoted a large part of the past 20 years of my life endeavouring to provide high quality health care to the community I work in: Tower Hamlets in East London. However, my mind and working life has been increasingly
The post Fighting for general practice: the key to a net zero health service appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[News story: Puberty blockers temporary ban extended]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/puberty-blockers-temporary-ban-extended</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/puberty-blockers-temporary-ban-extended"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:56:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Temporary ban on prescription and supply of puberty blockers extended.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA’s Scottish GP Committee elects new chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152465</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/scotland/bmas-scottish-gp-committee-elects-new-chair/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:39:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An LMC leader and GP partner has been elected as the new chair of the BMA’s GP committee for Scotland. Dr Iain Morrison, who has been Lothian LMC’s chair since October 2020, will succeed Dr Andrew Buist who is stepping down after six years in the role. In a message to members, Dr Morrison, who
The post BMA’s Scottish GP Committee elects new chair appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Menopause and HRT: Myths and facts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152373</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/menopause-and-hrt-myths-and-facts/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:25:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest of our series exploring some common misconceptions about conditions seen in general practice, GP Dr Toni Hazell debunks some myths about the menopause and HIV – and explains some perhaps less well known facts Myths 1. The menopause always presents with hot flushes and night sweats The menopause occurs at the average
The post Menopause and HRT: Myths and facts appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4539 - Google Releases Security Updates for Chrome]]></title>
        <id>74ab7663-66c2-40c7-acbf-7c60ea2baa00</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4539"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security update includes one exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome
 Security update includes one exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome
 Updated: 22 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hull hospital to trial video triage to assess stroke patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203159</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/hull-hospitals-to-trial-pre-hospital-video-triage-for-stroke-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T12:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hull University Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust has announced plans to trial a pre-hospital video triage scheme for stroke patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203223</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-165/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T10:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing covers Walsall Healthcare's first digital nurse role, rehab robots and a maternity EPR at East and North Herts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203223</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T10:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing covers Walsall Healthcare's first digital nurse role, rehab robots and a maternity EPR at East and North Herts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England statement on Alzheimer’s treatment lecanemab: Thursday 22 August 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251594</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/nhs-england-statement-on-alzheimers-treatment-lecanemab/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T10:18:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In response to the MHRA and NICE decisions on lecanemab, Professor Sir Stephen Powis, NHS National Medical Director, said: “The NHS now awaits a final decision from the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence that will look at the clinical benefits and cost-effectiveness of lecanemab and determine if it should be routinely offered by the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Yorkshire trusts select Nervecentre as preferred EPR supplier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203299</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/two-yorkshire-trusts-select-nervecentre-as-preferred-epr-supplier/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T10:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[York and Scarborough Teaching Hospitals and Harrogate and District NHS FT have selected Nervecentre as their preferred EPR supplier.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ARRS GPs could be hired under 'less favourable terms', BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885850</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/arrs-gps-hired-less-favourable-terms-bma-warns/article/1885850"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T09:41:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs employed through the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) may be offered employment benefits such as holiday and sick pay below the level required under the BMA salaried GP model contract, the union has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NICE rules Alzheimer’s-slowing drug lecanemab too expensive for NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152447</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/nice-rules-alzheimers-slowing-drug-lecanemab-too-expensive-for-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T09:32:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK medicines regulator has approved lecanemab – the first drug shown to slow cognitive decline in patients in the early stages of Alzheimer’s – but NICE said it was too costly for the NHS. NICE’s draft guidance, published today, has been put out for a four-week consultation after the committee concluded the benefits of
The post NICE rules Alzheimer’s-slowing drug lecanemab too expensive for NHS appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England and Medical Schools Council to join forces to manage the Specialised Foundation Programme recruitment process for 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251520</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/specialised-foundation-programme-recruitment-process-for-2025/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T09:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England and the Medical Schools Council have launched a new partnership that will give students the opportunity to apply directly to medical schools for certain Specialised Foundation Programmes in England. The Specialised Foundation Programme has been created to offer medical school graduates the opportunity to develop skills in research, teaching and leadership alongside their […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultation outcome: Standard adult ready-to-drink oral nutritional supplements: ACBS policy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oral-nutritional-supplements-acbs-policy</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oral-nutritional-supplements-acbs-policy"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T08:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We want your views on changes being proposed to Advisory Committee on Borderline Substances (ACBS) policy about standard adult ready-to-drink oral nutritional supplements listed in part XV of the Drug Tariff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK worst on hospital waits but best on GP access, 10-country survey shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152437</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/uk-worst-on-hospital-waits-but-best-on-gp-access-10-country-survey-shows/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T08:21:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK general practice has been shown to perform well on access and speed of getting an appointment, in a large survey across 10 high-income countries. A report from the Health Foundation said 97% of respondents in the UK said they had regular access to a GP with only the Netherlands scoring higher. On getting an
The post UK worst on hospital waits but best on GP access, 10-country survey shows appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs facing extra pressure as seven pharmacies a week close down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885657</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-facing-extra-pressure-seven-pharmacies-week-close-down/article/1885657"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T08:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy closures are adding to pressure on general practice and threaten to undermine patient care, GP leaders have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Betsi Cadwaladr University Health Board to roll out ePMA in 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203339</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/betsi-cadwaladr-university-health-board-to-roll-out-epma-in-2026/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T07:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Betsi Cadwaladr University Health Board has partnered with Better to deliver an electronic prescribing and medicines administration system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK healthcare 'near bottom of the pack' compared with similar countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885805</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/uk-healthcare-near-bottom-pack-compared-similar-countries/article/1885805"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients' experience of healthcare in the UK is 'near the bottom of the pack' compared with other developed nations despite relatively strong performance on rapid access to a GP, analysis of a major international survey reveals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health board forced to apologise to patients ‘left out’ of GP catchment area]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152414</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/wales/health-board-forced-to-apologise-to-patients-left-out-of-gp-catchment-area/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T15:53:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Welsh health board was forced to apologise after a ‘discrepancy’ in GP practice boundaries meant patients could not access GP services. Betsi Cadwaladr University Health Board told Pulse that it was aware that ‘a small number of residents’ in Saltney Ferry, Flintshire, ‘had issues’ accessing GP services’ due to a discrepancy relating to practice
The post Health board forced to apologise to patients ‘left out’ of GP catchment area appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA warns GPs taking collective action not to plug service gaps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152390</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/bma-warns-gps-taking-collective-action-not-to-plug-service-gaps/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T14:52:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has warned GP practices against plugging gaps in local services which have arisen as a result of collective action. The union’s GP Committee for England has issued additional guidance for LMCs and practices, in light of collective action which began earlier this month, after taking legal advice. It said that although legally only
The post BMA warns GPs taking collective action not to plug service gaps appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I actually have sympathy with Streeting over his ARRS plans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152393</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/i-actually-have-sympathy-with-streeting-over-his-arrs-plans/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T14:24:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Jaimie Kaffash reflects on the health secretary’s plans to include GPs in the ARRS I do not expect to say these words too often: I have sympathy for Wes Streeting. Not in general, but specifically with regards to his plan to put GPs in the additional roles reimbursement scheme. Now, quick declaration of interest
The post I actually have sympathy with Streeting over his ARRS plans appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Milton Keynes University Hospital trials Dora AI assistant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203121</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/milton-keynes-university-hospital-trials-dora-ai-assistant/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T12:30:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Milton Keynes University Hospital is trialling a conversational AI assistant in its ophthalmology department.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHSC insists GP contract uplift should cover partners, salaried GPs and other staff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885741</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/dhsc-insists-gp-contract-uplift-cover-partners-salaried-gps-staff/article/1885741"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T10:22:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government officials have insisted that the 2024/25 GP contract uplift is intended to deliver a 6% pay increase for partners as well as for salaried GPs and other practice staff - despite warnings that it will fall short.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Falls prevention app helps reduce care home ambulance call-outs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203157</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/falls-prevention-app-helps-reduce-care-home-ambulance-call-outs/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T10:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A falls prevention app has been adopted by 37 care homes in Greater Manchester after trials led to a 57% reduction in ambulance call-outs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA urges Streeting to give GP ARRS funding directly to practices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152381</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/bma-urges-streeting-to-give-gp-arrs-funding-directly-to-practices/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T09:58:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ARRS funding to hire GPs must be provided to practices directly rather than to PCNs, the BMA has demanded in a letter to the health secretary. At the beginning of this month, the Government agreed to fund the ARRS with an extra £82m to allow PCNs to hire GPs, with this funding intended cover the
The post BMA urges Streeting to give GP ARRS funding directly to practices appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking about adversity, trauma and resilience: recommendations from FrameWorks UK]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/talking-about-adversity-trauma-and-resilience-recommendations-from-frameworks-uk.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/talking-about-adversity-trauma-and-resilience-recommendations-from-frameworks-uk.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T09:52:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Association of Directors of Public Health (ADPH) - Earlier this year, ADPH invited FrameWorks UK to present a set of evidence-based recommendations to Directors of Public Health and other public health professionals to enable them to better explain the causes and impact of adversity, trauma and resilience in infants, children and young people to policy makers and the wider public....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI will never be a replacement for a highly-qualified GP, warns RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885715</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/ai-will-replacement-highly-qualified-gp-warns-rcgp/article/1885715"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T09:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence (AI) should never be considered a replacement for a highly-qualified GP, the RCGP has warned - but the college said it would welcome the chance to help develop AI-driven health analytics to support the profession.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government pauses work on ‘major conditions’ strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152332</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/government-pauses-work-on-major-conditions-strategy/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T08:36:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A plan to tackle six major health conditions has been put on pause by the new Government, a health minister has confirmed. The previous Government wanted to set out a strategy to tackle the conditions contributing to England’s ‘burden of disease’, with then health secretary Steve Barclay saying that ‘for too long our healthcare services
The post Government pauses work on ‘major conditions’ strategy appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Humber Teaching NHS FT deploys patient communication platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203013</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/humber-teaching-nhs-ft-deploys-patient-communication-platform/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T07:30:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Humber Teaching NHS Foundation Trust has signed a three-year contract with Accurx for a patient communication platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE urging GPs to streamline patient SMS practices to avoid fraud]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152371</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/nhse-urging-gps-to-streamline-patient-sms-practices-to-avoid-fraud/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T16:05:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices and other NHS providers are being requested to exclusively use ‘NHSNoReply’ and block other variations by 5 November 2024, the latest primary care bulletin has said. The National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) is updating guidance to reduce the number of SMS SenderID variations, ensuring they reflect the service consumed and minimising the risk
The post NHSE urging GPs to streamline patient SMS practices to avoid fraud appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in devolved nations still waiting for 6% pay rise confirmation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152363</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gps-in-devolved-nations-still-waiting-for-6-pay-rise-confirmation/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T15:44:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices in the devolved nations are still in the dark about how the 6% pay uplift will be allocated by their governments.  At the end of July, the Review Body on Doctors’ and Dentists’ Remuneration (DDRB) recommended a 6% pay increase for GPs in all of the four nations.  Last week, an internal BMA
The post GPs in devolved nations still waiting for 6% pay rise confirmation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing the NHS for the AI era: a digital health record for every citizen]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/preparing-the-nhs-for-the-ai-era-a-digital-health-record-for-every-citizen.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/preparing-the-nhs-for-the-ai-era-a-digital-health-record-for-every-citizen.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T14:55:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Blair Institute for Global Change - This report proposes a digital health record (DHR) to drive improvements to health and care, and ensure that the NHS is ready for the artificial-intelligence era. Each person’s DHR would be the “single source of truth” for their health and care data – data that currently sit in silos across hospitals, GP practices,...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We need to be better at reaching out to burnt out colleagues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152324</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/dr-burnt-out/we-need-to-be-better-at-reaching-out-to-burnt-out-colleagues/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T14:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[True to his name, Dr Burnt Out reflects on how GPs can offer support to colleagues suffering from burn out and exhaustion  Sadly, we live in a health care system, and more specifically a primary care environment, where there is currently an epidemic of work-related stress and burnout. Doctors become seriously unwell due to work
The post We need to be better at reaching out to burnt out colleagues appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A call for change: tackling inequalities in access to mental health support for children with social work involvement and those living in poverty]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-call-for-change-tackling-inequalities-in-access-to-mental-health-support-for-children-with-social-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-call-for-change-tackling-inequalities-in-access-to-mental-health-support-for-children-with-social-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T13:47:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[National Children's Bureau - This report finds children with social work involvement for current concerns are more likely to be rejected by NHS mental health services compared to their peers. The research, undertaken with Cambridge University, found overall, children from the most deprived areas are twice as likely to be rejected than those from the least deprived areas. Report Press...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Networks launches council for clinical safety officers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202801</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-networks-launches-council-for-clinical-safety-officers/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T12:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Digital Health Networks Clinical Safety Officer (CSO) Council has been launched for CSOs to share knowledge, experience and best practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New GP contract should build care around 250,000-patient populations, says think tank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885659</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/new-gp-contract-build-care-around-250000-patient-populations-says-think-tank/article/1885659"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:57:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS primary care should be reorganised around populations of around 250,000 patients under a new GP contract that ignores geographical areas, according to an influential think tank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speediatrics: Can you solve this quick case of a child’s rash?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151863</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/paediatrics/speediatrics-can-you-solve-this-quick-case-of-a-child-s-rash/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:20:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new series, Pulse clinical adviser Dr Keith Hopcroft poses some quick quizzes around paediatric care. We kick off with the case of a child with atopic eczema
The post Speediatrics: Can you solve this quick case of a child’s rash? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dev Support</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices should be scaled up to 250k-patient lists, says Tony Blair think tank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152311</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/gp-practices-should-be-scaled-up-to-250k-patient-lists-says-tony-blair-think-tank/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:18:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Blair’s think tank has put forward a new vision of primary care with ‘far fewer groups of GP practices’ and 250,000-patient lists.  In a report published yesterday, the Tony Blair Institute (TBI) also urged the Government to implement a ‘digital health record’ for every citizen, which would replace the GP record, by 2029. The
The post GP practices should be scaled up to 250k-patient lists, says Tony Blair think tank appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP given three-month suspension after M25 climate protest conviction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885593</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-given-three-month-suspension-m25-climate-protest-conviction/article/1885593"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:05:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who was jailed twice after taking part in an M25 climate change protest has been suspended for three months from the GMC register.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP given three-month GMC suspension after M25 climate protest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885593</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-given-three-month-gmc-suspension-m25-climate-protest/article/1885593"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:05:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who was jailed twice after taking part in an M25 climate change protest has been suspended for three months from the GMC register.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202707</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-164/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T10:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health's latest Coffee Time Briefing includes Sussex's new £2 million robot surgeon and an AI study on pressure ulcers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202707</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T10:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health's latest Coffee Time Briefing includes Sussex's new £2 million robot surgeon and an AI study on pressure ulcers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blair Institute calls for crash programme of digital health records]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203155</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/blair-institute-calls-for-crash-programme-of-digital-health-records/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T10:27:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tony Blair Institute for Global Change has proposed a programme to create digital health records for all UK citizens within five years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Hoeksma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Women smoking during pregnancy at record low thanks to NHS support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251449</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/women-smoking-during-pregnancy-at-record-low-thanks-to-nhs-support/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T10:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smoking rates among mums-to-be are at an all-time low thanks to support from NHS teams. This year also saw the biggest annual fall in smoking during pregnancy since records began, meaning 6,000 fewer pregnant women smoked when compared to the previous 12 months, protecting thousands of babies from potential harm. NHS England is working to […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bring in AI doctors and strip GP practices of sole data controller role, says Blair think tank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885581</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bring-ai-doctors-strip-gp-practices-sole-data-controller-role-says-blair-think-tank/article/1885581"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T09:32:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government should strip GPs of their role as sole data controllers of patient records and bring in 'AI doctors' to support decisions about care as part of a major NHS digital overhaul, an influential think tank has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What can integrated care systems in England learn from the devolved nations?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-can-integrated-care-systems-in-england-learn-from-the-devolved-nations.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-can-integrated-care-systems-in-england-learn-from-the-devolved-nations.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T09:15:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - Approaches to integrating health and care services to improve efficiency and meet population needs have varied across the United Kingdom’s four devolved nations. Given the differences in approach to integration across the four nations, the NHS Confederation, supported by Novartis, has developed this resource to showcase both examples of good practice and lessons learned in Wales, Scotland...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Realising the potential of primary care provider collaboratives]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/realising-the-potential-of-primary-care-provider-collaboratives-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/realising-the-potential-of-primary-care-provider-collaboratives-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T09:03:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - The new Labour government has set out an intention to move care closer to home with a shift of resources to primary and community care. This report highlights the role of primary care provider collaboratives in supporting transformation. The report – informed by interviews with 20 leaders in collaboratives and two roundtables with wider partners, including integrated...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telephony system reduces missed GP appointments in Birmingham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203011</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/telephony-system-reduces-missed-gp-appointments-in-birmingham/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T07:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A ‘check and cancel’ appointment solution at Hall Green Health GP practice in Birmingham has helped save patient and staff time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LMC sets out list of ‘workload dump’ requests GPs should decline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151154</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/lmc-sets-out-list-of-workload-dump-requests-gps-should-decline/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T16:24:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have set out a comprehensive list of requests GPs should ‘decline’ and send back to hospitals, in a bid to tackle workload dump. A new document produced by Humberside LMCs summarised the ‘most common interface workload transfer’ from other providers to GP practices, as well as their recommended response. The LMCs have argued
The post LMC sets out list of ‘workload dump’ requests GPs should decline appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unleashing health and prosperity throughout Britain]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/unleashing-health-and-prosperity-throughout-britain-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/unleashing-health-and-prosperity-throughout-britain-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T15:53:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - While a theoretical understanding of the links between health and wealth is increasingly recognised, the practical elements of what makes it work on the ground are less evidenced. Based on engagement with five local areas in England and Wales, this paper puts forward a set principles that have proven to aid successful social and economic development: making...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An overview of the National Minimum Wage]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/an-overview-of-the-national-minimum-wage.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/an-overview-of-the-national-minimum-wage.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T15:37:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - This guide provides an overview of the National Minimum Wage (NMW), sets out how to calculate the NMW, and frequently asked questions (FAQs). Guide More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultant doctors and dentists pay progression system guidance for employers]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/consultant-doctors-and-dentists-pay-progression-system-guidance-for-employers.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/consultant-doctors-and-dentists-pay-progression-system-guidance-for-employers.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T15:29:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - The 2024 amendments to the 2003 consultant contract introduced provisions to move to a new pay structure supported by a new pay progression system. This guidance is produced in association with the British Medical Association (BMA) and the Hospital Consultants and Specialists Association (HCSA). Guidance More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA urges GP registrars to vote ‘yes’ to Government pay offer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152275</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/bma-urges-gp-registrars-to-vote-yes-to-government-pay-offer/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T14:53:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has urged GP registrars to vote in favour of accepting a pay offer made by the Government to junior doctors in England. The union’s GP registrars committee has recommended that members vote to accept the offer, which would increase pay by 22.3% over two years, in a referendum of more than sixty thousand
The post BMA urges GP registrars to vote ‘yes’ to Government pay offer appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How females are disproportionately affected by the employment crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152090</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/how-females-are-disproportionately-affected-by-the-employment-crisis/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T14:28:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Seema Pattni considers the impact of the employment crisis on female GPs ‘Both my job offers have fallen through. I’m really panicking. I’m stuck in limbo trying to decide what to do.’ These are the words of a female GP who I spoke to recently.  The employment crisis in general practice is rife and
The post How females are disproportionately affected by the employment crisis appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) Emergency Committee regarding the upsurge of mpox 2024]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:08be502f-4acd-4af5-8b03-4e9fd9971151</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/19-08-2024-first-meeting-of-the-international-health-regulations-(2005)-emergency-committee-regarding-the-upsurge-of-mpox-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T14:21:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Director-General of the World Health Organization (WHO), having concurred with the advice offered by the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR or Regulations)  Emergency Committee regarding the upsurge of mpox 2024 during its first meeting, held on 14 August 2024, has determined, on the same date, that the ongoing upsurge of mpox in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) and in a growing number of countries in Africa constitutes a public health emergency of international concern (PHEIC) under the provisions of the Regulations. The communication of the Director-General regarding the determination of the above-mentioned PHEIC on 14 August 2024 is available  here.
The Director-General is hereby transmitting the report of the first meeting of the IHR Emergency Committee regardin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA urges junior doctors to back pay offer as referendum opens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885532</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-urges-junior-doctors-back-pay-offer-referendum-opens/article/1885532"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T13:44:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A BMA referendum on a new pay deal for junior doctors including GP registrars has opened, with doctors' leaders urging the profession to back the pay offer and bring an end to long-running strike action.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portsmouth Hospitals expands digital patient communications]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202643</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/portsmouth-hospitals-expands-digital-patient-communications/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T12:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Portsmouth Hospitals has expanded digital patient communications through a new patient portal, waiting list validation and digital letters.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[M25 climate protest GP suspended for three months]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152251</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/m25-climate-protest-gp-suspended-for-three-months/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T11:18:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who took part in a climate protest blocking the M25 motorway will be suspended for three months, a medical practitioners’ tribunal has decided. The Medical Practitioners Tribunal Service (MPTS) hearing, which concluded last week, examined allegations that Dr Diana Warner had breached a court order by protesting on the M25 in 2021 and
The post M25 climate protest GP suspended for three months appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NICE recommends additional treatment for uterine fibroids]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152174</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/nice-recommends-additional-treatment-for-uterine-fibroids/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T10:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As many as 30,000 women could benefit from a new treatment to manage uterine fibroids, the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) has estimated. Linzagolix, a GnRH antagonist, has been recommended as a longer term treatment – more than six months – for people with moderate to severe symptoms. It follows two clinical
The post NICE recommends additional treatment for uterine fibroids appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Bolton Hospital deploys Miya patient flow system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202793</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/royal-bolton-hospital-deploys-miya-patient-flow-system/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T10:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bolton NHS Foundation Trust has deployed a new patient flow system from Alcidion to boost bed availability at Royal Bolton Hospital.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Care into the Future]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/we-care-into-the-future-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/we-care-into-the-future-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T09:06:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - Introduced for the first time in July 2019, the We Care into the Future interactive careers event aims to inspire young people in the Doncaster and Bassetlaw area, by challenging their perceptions around the career opportunities available across health and care. Case study]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice staff faced Islamophobic death threat during riots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885420</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practice-staff-faced-islamophobic-death-threat-during-riots/article/1885420"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T08:58:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP practice was forced to shut its doors after a man threatened to kill a member of staff at the height of Islamophobic and racist rioting earlier this month, GPonline has learned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northumbria Healthcare goes live with CLEO SOLO EPS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202731</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/northumbria-healthcare-goes-live-with-cleo-solo-eps/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T07:30:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northumbria Healthcare NHS Foundation Trust has gone live with the CLEO SOLO electronic prescription system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What you don’t know about… S2 funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151519</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/what-you-dont-know-about/what-you-dont-know-about-s2-funding/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T14:17:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest instalment of our series looking at policies, funding pots and new initiatives that may have slipped your notice, Dr Lucy Douglas investigates the S2 funding route and why GPs may want to recommend it to patients What is S2 funding? The Planned Treatment Scheme (S2 funding route) entitles eligible patients to NHS funding
The post What you don’t know about… S2 funding appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs told to set up mpox isolation procedures and check PPE stocks in light of new variant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152211</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/gps-told-to-set-up-mpox-isolation-procedures-and-check-ppe-stocks-in-light-of-new-variant/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T13:53:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices have been told to set up isolation procedures and check PPE stocks, as concerns grow around a new more fatal version of mpox. The Clade 1b mpox variant (MPXV) has been spreading rapidly across parts of central and East Africa since first being discovered in September last year, killing 537 people in the
The post GPs told to set up mpox isolation procedures and check PPE stocks in light of new variant appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delivering with dignity: a framework for strengthening commissioning and provision of healthcare services for people seeking asylum]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/delivering-with-dignity-a-framework-for-strengthening-commissioning-and-provision-of-healthcare-serv.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/delivering-with-dignity-a-framework-for-strengthening-commissioning-and-provision-of-healthcare-serv.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T13:48:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British Red Cross - This report finds that people seeking asylum in England often have complex health needs and yet face barriers to accessing timely, quality, and appropriate health care. It sets out a framework of good practice to remove these barriers and ensure people can access the health care that they are entitled to. Report British Red Cross -...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy concerns raised over trust’s AI data-sharing deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202923</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/privacy-concerns-raised-over-trusts-ai-data-sharing-deal/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T12:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A privacy campaign group has raised concerns over a data sharing agreement between the Royal National Orthopaedic Hospital and an AI startup.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New RSV vaccination programme could cut GP consultations by 35,000]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152162</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/new-rsv-vaccination-programme-could-cut-gp-consultations-by-35000/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T12:18:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new RSV vaccination programme due to start in September could prevent 20,000 GP consultations for poorly babies, public health experts predict. The analysis by the UKHSA and London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine also suggests the vaccine could prevent 5,000 hospitalisations in infants in England and Wales. The analysis which assumes 60% uptake
The post New RSV vaccination programme could cut GP consultations by 35,000 appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice advised to break up or hand back contract as new premises delayed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152199</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/premises/gp-practice-advised-to-break-up-or-hand-back-contract-as-new-premises-delayed/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T11:03:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive A good-rated GP practice at risk of having no premises from October was ‘shell-shocked’ at being advised by its ICB it could ‘hand back the contract’.  Another option suggested was to work from a range of different other practices while awaiting new premises. St James Medical Practice in Walthamstow, run by a father and
The post GP practice advised to break up or hand back contract as new premises delayed appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Humanitarian pauses vital for critical polio vaccination campaign in the Gaza Strip]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:ca556dce-263d-4d3e-8e10-c4fba6da0256</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/16-08-2024-humanitarian-pauses-vital-for-critical-polio-vaccination-campaign-in-the-gaza-strip"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T10:20:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two rounds of a polio vaccination campaign are expected to be launched at the end of August and September 2024 across the Gaza Strip to prevent the spread of circulating variant type 2 poliovirus (cVDPV2).  
WHO and UNICEF request all parties to the conflict to implement humanitarian pauses in the Gaza Strip for seven days to allow for two rounds of vaccination campaigns to take place. These pauses in fighting would allow children and families to safely reach health facilities and community outreach workers to get to children who cannot access health facilities for polio vaccination. Without the humanitarian pauses, the delivery of the campaign will not be possible. 
During each round of the campaign, the Palestinian Ministry of Health (MoH), in collaboration with the World Health Organiza…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jersey’s EPR plans delayed by ‘patchy WiFi’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202739</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/jerseys-epr-plans-delayed-by-patchy-wifi/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T10:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plans to update Jersey’s electronic patient record (EPR) system have been delayed owing to WiFi issues, according to an annual report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rise in GP practices participating in research studies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152196</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/diabetes-endocrinology/rise-in-gp-practices-participating-in-research-studies/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T09:49:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s been an increase in the number of GP practices taking part in health research, new data has revealed. The growth has allowed more patients to participate in local clinical trials used to develop new treatments. Fresh data has shown during 2023/24 more than half of all GP practices in England (56%) took part in
The post Rise in GP practices participating in research studies appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flu and Covid vaccination campaign to run from 3 October to 20 December]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152179</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/flu-and-covid-vaccination-campaign-to-run-from-3-october-to-20-december/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T09:34:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should vaccinate eligible groups against flu and Covid between 3 October and 20 December, NHS England has said in its latest update. NHSE announced in March that the flu vaccination programme would be moved from September to October this year in order to maximise vaccine effectiveness, with Covid vaccination to commence at the same
The post Flu and Covid vaccination campaign to run from 3 October to 20 December appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man jailed after GP practice break in and laptop thefts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885141</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/man-jailed-gp-practice-break-laptop-thefts/article/1885141"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T07:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man has been jailed for four months after pleading guilty to breaking into a GP practice and stealing laptops.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health’s monthly roundup of contracts and go lives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202767</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-healths-monthly-roundup-of-contracts-and-go-lives-43/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T07:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This latest roundup includes Northampton General Hospital signing a 10-year Nervecentre electronic patient record (EPR) contract.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: GP contract uplift, will ARRS GP jobs work, plus GP working hours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885232</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-gp-contract-uplift-will-arrs-gp-jobs-work-plus-gp-working-hours/article/1885232"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T07:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GPonline team discusses what the uplift to this year's GP contract in England means for GP practices, GP pay and staff salaries, plans to add GPs to the ARRS and the number of hours GPs work.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once in a lifetime: Acoustic neuromas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151940</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/neurology/acoustic-neuromas/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T15:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mr Gerard Kelly, consultant ENT and skull base surgeon at Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, outlines this unusual presentation in the latest in our series of conditions that GPs may expect to encounter once in a lifetime What is it? An acoustic neuroma (more correctly termed a vestibular schwannoma) is a benign (non-cancerous) tumour that
The post Once in a lifetime: Acoustic neuromas appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public health warning over rising rates of antibiotic-resistant gonorrhoea]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152150</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/sexual-health/public-health-warning-over-rising-rates-of-antibiotic-resistant-gonorrhoea/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T15:19:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public health officials are warning of a concerning rise in antibiotic-resistant gonorrhoea infections in England. Data from the UK Health Security Agency shows there have been 15 new confirmed cases of ceftriaxone-resistant Neisseria gonorrhoeae between June 2022 and May 2024. This includes five cases which were extensively drug-resistant to first and second line antibiotics as
The post Public health warning over rising rates of antibiotic-resistant gonorrhoea appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finance Diary: How GPs can make the most out of childcare funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150935</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/finance-diary/finance-diary-how-gps-can-make-the-most-out-of-childcare-funding/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T15:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mazars client director Lisa Pennington shares how GPs can check their eligibility to childcare funding and what measures can be taken to maximise access Many parents who work in primary care either as GP partners, salaried GPs or staff members want to continue working after having a child, but childcare costs can be prohibitive. To
The post Finance Diary: How GPs can make the most out of childcare funding appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Damp and mould: understanding and addressing the health risks for rented housing providers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/damp-and-mould-understanding-and-addressing-the-health-risks-for-rented-housing-providers</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/damp-and-mould-understanding-and-addressing-the-health-risks-for-rented-housing-providers"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T14:32:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This guidance delivers on the government’s commitment in response to the Coroner’s 'prevention of future deaths' report on the death of 2-year-old Awaab Ishak due to mould in the home.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP team climbing Three Peaks to raise money for suicide prevention]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151995</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gp-team-climbing-three-peaks-to-raise-money-for-suicide-prevention/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T13:26:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A team of GPs is climbing the National Three Peaks to raise money for suicide prevention among doctors.  Over the next week, a group of five GPs, six consultants and three dentists will climb Ben Nevis in Scotland, Scafell Pike in England and Snowdon in Wales to raise money for Doctors in Distress. The group
The post GP team climbing Three Peaks to raise money for suicide prevention appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Millions to get protected ahead of winter in NHS vaccine rollout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251227</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/millions-to-get-protected-ahead-of-winter-in-nhs-vaccine-rollout/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T12:52:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of children and adults across England will be offered their flu, COVID-19 and respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) vaccinations as the NHS sets out plans for protection ahead of winter. The vaccines provide vital protection to keep people from developing serious illnesses and ending up in hospital during busy winter months. This year, based on […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kootenai Health cyber attack impacts 464,000 patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202669</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/kootenai-health-cyber-attack-impacts-464000-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T12:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US healthcare provider Kootenai Health has revealed that data belonging to 464,000 patients has been compromised following a cyber attack.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA spells out scale of GP crisis in Darzi review evidence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885233</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-spells-scale-gp-crisis-darzi-review-evidence/article/1885233"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T11:34:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demand for GP services has outstripped supply, with underfunding driving practice closures and a growing gap between the workforce and numbers of patients that has undermined continuity of care, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs need to be 'alert' to new mpox strain, warns UKHSA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885219</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-need-alert-new-mpox-strain-warns-ukhsa/article/1885219"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:55:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs need to be ‘alert’ to the possibility of clade 1b mpox infection if a patient has a link to a country listed with confirmed or possible cases, the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202413</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-163/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Coffee Time Briefing includes Leeds Teaching Hospitals trialling an app to remotely monitor heart rhythm disorders in patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP review submissions warn Darzi over loss of care continuity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152137</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gp-review-submissions-warn-darzi-over-loss-of-care-continuity/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:27:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lord Darzi has been warned by GP leaders of risks to continuity of care, insufficient funding, and rising workload dump, in his Government review of the NHS. Last month, health secretary Wes Streeting revealed that Professor Lord Ara Darzi will lead an ‘independent investigation’ into the state of the NHS, in one of his first
The post GP review submissions warn Darzi over loss of care continuity appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UKHSA updates mpox guidance for doctors amid global health alert]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152135</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/ukhsa-updates-mpox-guidance-for-doctors-amid-global-health-alert/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:09:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) has updated its guidance to advise doctors to be aware of a new more fatal variant of mpox, currently spreading in parts of central and East Africa. The UKHSA warning, issued today, comes after the World Health Organisation declared mpox a public health emergency yesterday. There are particular concerns
The post UKHSA updates mpox guidance for doctors amid global health alert appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share of £32m AI funding to speed up prescription deliveries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202575</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/share-of-32m-ai-funding-to-speed-up-prescription-deliveries/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A project to speed up NHS prescription deliveries using AI algorithms is to receive a share of £32 million in UK government funding.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newly-qualified GPs could be 'driven away' by ARRS jobs plan, warns BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885120</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/newly-qualified-gps-driven-away-arrs-jobs-plan-warns-bma/article/1885120"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Newly-qualified GPs could be 'driven away' from the NHS under plans to create jobs through the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) - while experienced GPs struggling to find work risk being left out in the cold, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexarad closes £11.2m growth round for radiology platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202587</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/hexarad-closes-11-2m-funding-round-for-radiology-platform/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T07:30:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Radiology platform Hexarad has announced the closure of a €13 million (£11.2m) growth round with reinvestment from existing shareholders.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UKHSA warns of 'concerning rise' in antibiotic-resistant gonorrhoea cases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885111</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/ukhsa-warns-concerning-rise-antibiotic-resistant-gonorrhoea-cases/sexual-health/article/1885111"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T23:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) has warned that a 'concerning rise' in antiobiotic-resistant gonorrhoea cases in England could lead to the infection becoming untreatable in future.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO Director-General declares mpox outbreak a public health emergency of international concern]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:3a74b31d-9848-4fad-9518-86d377493cc6</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/14-08-2024-who-director-general-declares-mpox-outbreak-a-public-health-emergency-of-international-concern"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T18:55:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus has determined that the upsurge of mpox in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) and a growing number of countries in Africa constitutes a public health emergency of international concern (PHEIC) under the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR).
Dr Tedros’s declaration came on the advice of an IHR Emergency Committee of independent experts who met earlier in the day to review data presented by experts from WHO and affected countries. The Committee informed the Director-General that it considers the upsurge of mpox to be a PHEIC, with potential to spread further across countries in Africa and possibly outside the continent.
The Director-General will share the report of the Committee’s meeting and, based on the advice of the Comm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take ‘robust’ stance on racism in GP practices, NHSE advises partners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152121</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/special-investigations/gp-abuse/take-robust-stance-on-racism-in-gp-practices-nhse-advises-partners/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T15:32:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has published new guidance for GP practices on how to handle racist incidents, whether from patients or colleagues, in the wake of ‘civil unrest’ across the country. This includes taking a ‘robust’ disciplinary approach to staff involved in racist behaviour outside of work, as well as ensuring staff know what to do if
The post Take ‘robust’ stance on racism in GP practices, NHSE advises partners appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Changes to the death certification process]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/changes-to-the-death-certification-process</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/changes-to-the-death-certification-process"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T15:28:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the death certification process in England and Wales will change from 9 September 2024, including the introduction of medical examiners.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action means goodwill games are over]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152079</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/collective-action-means-goodwill-games-are-over/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T14:27:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Copperfield on why over half of England’s GP practices have not started taking collective action I found myself getting nostalgic watching the Paris Olympics, and not just for my days as a professional break-dancer. It reminded me of London 2012 and going misty-eyed at the children bouncing on NHS beds in Danny Boyle’s opening
The post Collective action means goodwill games are over appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Find help and support if you have long COVID]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/guidance/find-help-and-support-if-you-have-long-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/find-help-and-support-if-you-have-long-covid"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you have long COVID there is a range of support available.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Six NHS hospitals now fully live with NPIC digital pathology system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202493</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/six-nhs-hospitals-now-fully-live-with-npic-digital-pathology-system/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six NHS hospitals in the North of England have gone live with "digitised pathology departments" underpinned by the National Pathology Imaging Co-operative.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4537 - Microsoft Releases August 2024 Security Updates]]></title>
        <id>109955e9-5dd3-4129-8431-57e20b76a8c4</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4537"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products fix 90 vulnerabilities, including ten zero-day vulnerabilities
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products fix 90 vulnerabilities, including ten zero-day vulnerabilities
 Updated: 14 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4538 - Adobe Releases Security Updates for Acrobat and Reader]]></title>
        <id>f23828e8-5b9e-4a50-942d-224ccd27ffaa</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4538"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Successful exploitation of the critical vulnerabilities could lead to ACE or privilege escalation
 Successful exploitation of the critical vulnerabilities could lead to ACE or privilege escalation
 Updated: 14 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4536 - SAP Releases Security Update for BusinessObjects]]></title>
        <id>63eb5ba8-c97f-4427-9353-262e32dc8d76</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4536"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T11:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Successful exploitation could lead to full system compromise
 Successful exploitation could lead to full system compromise
 Updated: 14 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicines eligible for Northern Ireland MHRA Authorised Route]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T11:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out medicines that can be moved to Northern Ireland to meet patient need.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish GP practices funded to target ‘lost’ patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152110</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/scotland/scottish-gp-practices-funded-to-target-lost-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T11:01:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices in Scotland engaging with patients ‘lost’ to the system but who have the greatest need have been given an additional £1m of funds for 2024/25, following the scheme’s success last year. The Scottish government launched a programme called Inclusion Health Action in General Practice (IHAGP) in 2023 to address health inequalities in disadvantaged areas,
The post Scottish GP practices funded to target ‘lost’ patients appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA warns GPs 'now is not the time to waver' over collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885081</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-warns-gps-now-not-time-waver-collective-action/article/1885081"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T10:43:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BMA GP leaders have urged the profession to 'push on with collective action' after revealing that global sum payments to practices will rise by 7.4% in 2024/25.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England signposts upcoming £18m health and justice EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202431</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/nhs-england-signposts-upcoming-18m-health-and-justice-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T10:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has issued a pre-procurement notice for an £18 million EPR to capture health data in the justice system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Q&A: What we know so far about GP collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152081</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/contract/qa-what-we-know-so-far-about-gp-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T09:52:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action is the big story in general practice in England this summer. But, despite the headlines, there’s been no ‘big bang’ moment – instead, we’re seeing a slow but steady change to the way general practice works. Eliza Parr looks at what the action means for GP practices. Please note, this article will be
The post Q&A: What we know so far about GP collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DrDoctor steps into mental health support with Maia acquisition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202347</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/drdoctor-steps-into-mental-health-support-with-maia-acquisition/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T07:30:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DrDoctor has made its first foray into the mental health and community support space after acquiring personal health record platform, Maia.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: How is collective action affecting general practice so far?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152003</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/practice-personal-finance/analysis-how-is-collective-action-affecting-general-practice-so-far/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:58:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following Pulse’s snapshot survey on collective action, we analyse the full set of data to see what it tells us about the current climate and what could happen next Ever since NHS England’s imposed 2024/25 contract for general practice was rejected by 99% of GPs in a BMA referendum, we have been slowly walking along
The post Analysis: How is collective action affecting general practice so far? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: New MCCD: check that your organisation is on the distribution list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/new-mccd-check-that-your-organisation-is-on-the-distribution-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/new-mccd-check-that-your-organisation-is-on-the-distribution-list"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:57:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Current list of organisations that will receive the new medical certificate of cause of death (MCCD), which must be used from 9 September 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Receiving the new medical certificate of cause of death (MCCD)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/guidance/receiving-the-new-medical-certificate-of-cause-of-death-mccd</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/receiving-the-new-medical-certificate-of-cause-of-death-mccd"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:56:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to get the new MCCD if your organisation uses the current MCCD.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ARRS pay rises will be ‘unfunded cost pressure’ for PCNs, claims BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152051</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/arrs-pay-rises-will-be-unfunded-cost-pressure-for-pcns-claims-bma/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:40:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pay uplifts for Additional Roles Reimbursement Scheme (ARRS) staff will be an ‘unfunded cost pressure’ for PCNs, according to the BMA. An internal BMA letter to GPC England members, sent yesterday and seen by Pulse, has clarified how pay rises recommended by the independent pay review bodies will be implemented. At the end of last
The post ARRS pay rises will be ‘unfunded cost pressure’ for PCNs, claims BMA appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contract uplift won't deliver promised 6% pay rise for GP partners, accountant warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884980</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/contract-uplift-wont-deliver-promised-6-pay-rise-gp-partners-accountant-warns/article/1884980"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:01:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Half of GPs are unlikely to see the 6% pay rise promised by the government because a 7.4% uplift to global sum funding in 2024/25 - confirmed this week by the BMA - will not cover a pay increase on that level for partners on top of salaried GPs and other staff, an accountant has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global sum will rise by 7.4% to fund pay uplift for GPs and staff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152027</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/global-sum-will-rise-by-7-4-to-fund-pay-uplift-for-gps-and-staff/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T14:25:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government will increase the global sum by a total of 7.4% for 2024/25 in order to fund GP and practice staff pay rises worth 6%. An internal BMA letter to GPC England members, sent yesterday and seen by Pulse, said that this ‘aggregate’ rise will incorporate the 2.7% global sum uplift already awarded in
The post Global sum will rise by 7.4% to fund pay uplift for GPs and staff appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open consultation: Changes to rules - the Care Quality Commission (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-rules-the-care-quality-commission-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-rules-the-care-quality-commission-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T13:50:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This consultation is about 3 changes we want to make to rules that the Care Quality Commission will check (CQC for short).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global sum to rise 7.4% in 2024/25 as final detail of GP contract revealed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884911</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/global-sum-rise-74-2024-25-final-detail-gp-contract-revealed/article/1884911"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T12:59:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global sum payments to GP practices will rise by 7.4% in 2024/25 compared with the previous financial year, the BMA England GP committee has revealed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[East and North Herts first UK trust to select Dedalus ORBIS U EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202363</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/east-and-north-herts-first-uk-trust-to-select-dedalus-orbis-u-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T12:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[East and North Hertfordshire NHS Trust has become the first trust in the UK to adopt the Dedalus ORBIS U electronic patient record (EPR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult Social Work Apprenticeship Fund]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-work-apprenticeship-fund</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-work-apprenticeship-fund"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T11:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information about the Adult Social Work Apprenticeship Fund, introduced by the previous government to increase social worker capacity in adult social care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action plans must be put in writing to salaried and locum GPs, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884890</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/collective-action-plans-put-writing-salaried-locum-gps-says-bma/article/1884890"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T10:57:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP partners have been urged to tell salaried and locum GPs in writing if measures they take as part of collective action will significantly change employees' working day.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs with burnout already resilient and need better support, research shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151046</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gps-with-burnout-already-resilient-and-need-better-support-research-shows/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T10:32:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs who have suffered burnout do not lack resilience and need organisational support to help reduce and manage their distress, a study has found. Research based on in-depth interviews with those who had experienced burnout presented at the Society for Academic Primary Care annual conference in Bristol last month concluded that these were ‘highly motivated,
The post GPs with burnout already resilient and need better support, research shows appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201861</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-162/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T10:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Coffee Time Briefing includes a report on digital skills barriers and a new AI model for FHIR health data interoperability.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TPP awarded Sussex Community NHS EPR contract extension]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202147</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/tpp-awarded-sussex-community-nhs-epr-contract-extension/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T09:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sussex Community NHS Foundation Trust has awarded a 10-year contract extension for an EPR system from TPP, worth almost £6.3 million.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP contract uplift will not cover 6% pay rise for all practices, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884871</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-contract-uplift-will-not-cover-6-pay-rise-practices-bma-warns/article/1884871"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T09:19:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some practices will not receive enough funding through the increased 2024/25 GP contract uplift to pass on a full 6% pay uplift to salaried GPs and other staff, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP contract uplift won't cover 6% pay rise for all practices, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884871</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-contract-uplift-wont-cover-6-pay-rise-practices-bma-warns/article/1884871"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T09:19:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some practices will not receive enough funding through the increased 2024/25 GP contract uplift to pass on a full 6% pay uplift to salaried GPs and other staff, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost half of England’s GP practices have started taking collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151971</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/almost-half-of-englands-gp-practices-have-started-taking-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T08:08:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Almost half (46%) of England’s GP practices are taking some form of collective action, with one in five putting a limit on the number of patients they see in a day, a Pulse survey has revealed. The snapshot survey of 283 GP partners from different practices – representing 5% of the practices in England
The post Almost half of England’s GP practices have started taking collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Viewpoint: Is Stockholm syndrome the real reason GPs won't give up the partnership model?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884604</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/viewpoint-stockholm-syndrome-real-reason-gps-wont-give-partnership-model/article/1884604"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GP partnership model is a sacred cow that the profession is unwilling to relinquish, but a system that leaves GPs facing the pressures of running a small business on a shoestring alongside intense clinical work seems like a recipe for burnout. Maybe it's time for a rethink, says former GP partner Dr Tom Riddington.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RSV vaccination could prevent 5,000 infant hospitalisations a year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884859</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/rsv-vaccination-prevent-5000-infant-hospitalisations-year/article/1884859"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T07:45:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RSV vaccination programme for pregnant women, which is due to start from September, could prevent 5,000 infant hospitalisations a year, health officials have said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man handed suspended jail term for threats of violence at GP practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884802</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/man-handed-suspended-jail-term-threats-violence-gp-practice/article/1884802"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T07:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man has received an 18-month suspended prison sentence after pleading guilty to offences including threatening behaviour and threatening to damage property at a GP practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Shrewsbury Hospitals opens new ‘nuclear’ gamma camera]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201903</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/royal-shrewsbury-hospitals-opens-new-nuclear-gamma-camera/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T07:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first patients have been scanned a new, £3.6m gamma camera at The Shrewsbury and Telford NHS Hospital Trust.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Health and Social Care Secretary Responds to CQC Review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/health-and-social-care-secretary-responds-to-cqc-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/health-and-social-care-secretary-responds-to-cqc-review"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T23:01:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health and Social Care Secretary Wes Streeting responds to the Care Quality Commission's report outlining failings in Valdo Calocane's care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders raise ‘grave concerns’ with national PCN pilot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151960</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/gp-leaders-raise-grave-concerns-with-national-pcn-pilot/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T16:20:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have raised ‘grave concerns’ with a new national PCN pilot which puts ‘excessive’ conditions on practices. The BMA GP Committee England and a group of LMCs have highlighted several issues with NHS England’s plan, including its potential to worsen health inequalities and the requirements to share income data.  In June, Pulse reported on
The post GP leaders raise ‘grave concerns’ with national PCN pilot appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New GP model pilots could trap practices in PCN DES, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884825</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/new-gp-model-pilots-trap-practices-pcn-des-says-bma/article/1884825"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practices that join test sites piloting new models of general practice could be 'unable to opt-out of the PCN DES' for several years even if it becomes far more onerous, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England statement on collective action: Monday 12 August 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251040</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/nhs-england-statement-on-collective-action-monday-12-august-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T15:57:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Amanda Doyle, NHS National Director for Primary Care and Community Services said: “As some practices continue collective action, it is vital that patients continue to come forward for care in the usual ways – practices remain open and services are still running. “We will be monitoring the impacts of this action to ensure practices […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Communication Breakdown: ‘I’m making a complaint!’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151517</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/communication-breakdown-station/communication-breakdown-im-making-a-complaint/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T15:47:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new series Dr Ed Pooley, GP and communication expert, shares his knowledge with readers having difficulties with colleagues and patients in the workplace. In this first instalment, he tackles the age-old question – what do you do when threatened with a complaint? Dear Dr Pooley  How should I respond if a patient says,
The post Communication Breakdown: ‘I’m making a complaint!’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designated prescribing practitioners: a national conversation for community pharmacy]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/designated-prescribing-practitioners-a-national-conversation-for-community-pharmacy.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/designated-prescribing-practitioners-a-national-conversation-for-community-pharmacy.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T14:51:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Pharmaceutical Society - This report (published together with the National Pharmacy Association) examines the challenges in accessing designated prescribing practitioners (DPPs) in community pharmacy in England. The report is the outcome of a multi-professional roundtable event in June 2024 and proposes further solutions and collaborative actions to build on the current work to support pharmacists and trainees in securing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statutory guidance: Care Act 2014: supporting implementation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/care-act-statutory-guidance</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/care-act-statutory-guidance"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T13:45:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Support for local authorities to carry out the implementation for part 1 of the Care Act 2014.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: Department of Health and Social Care information asset register]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/department-of-health-and-social-care-information-asset-register</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/department-of-health-and-social-care-information-asset-register"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T12:33:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This register lists personal and non-personal information assets held by DHSC in the UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Teaching Hospitals to trial laser-activated antimicrobial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201933</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/leeds-teaching-hospitals-to-trial-laser-activated-antimicrobial/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T12:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Teaching Hospitals is to begin trials of a new laser-activated antimicrobial in an effort to cut post-surgery infections.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and frontline staff eligible for autumn Covid boosters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151956</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/gps-and-frontline-staff-eligible-for-autumn-covid-boosters/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T10:55:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and all other patient-facing practice staff will be encouraged to take up a free Covid-19 booster vaccination through the national programme this autumn. In terms of patients, ‘all those aged 65 or over, all those in care homes for older people, and those aged 6 months or over who are in a clinical risk
The post GPs and frontline staff eligible for autumn Covid boosters appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The state of medical education and practice in the UK: workplace experiences 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/the-state-of-medical-education-and-practice-in-the-uk-workplace-experiences-2024-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/the-state-of-medical-education-and-practice-in-the-uk-workplace-experiences-2024-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T10:51:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General Medical Council (GMC) - This report is based on report evidence from the GMC's annual survey of thousands of doctors, supported by in-depth interviews and other research. It includes data and insights, to highlight where action needs to be taken to address workplace pressures and help retain doctors across all four countries of the UK. The report found that...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salaried and locum GPs must take partner lead on collective action, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151923</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/salaried-and-locum-gps-must-take-partner-lead-on-collective-action-bma-warns/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T10:08:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Salaried and locum GPs need to follow the lead of their employing partners on collective action, the BMA has warned in new guidance. Collective action began this month following a ballot result in which 98% of GP partners voted in favour, with actions including capping patient contacts at 25 per day and stopping engagement with
The post Salaried and locum GPs must take partner lead on collective action, BMA warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What can the new government learn from other countries’ attempts to reform pay in social care?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-can-the-new-government-learn-from-other-countries-attempts-to-reform-pay-in-social-care.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-can-the-new-government-learn-from-other-countries-attempts-to-reform-pay-in-social-care.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:48:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - This long read looks at the lessons England might learn from other countries when it comes to reforming pay for care workers, and the key principles to consider in any pay reform. Long read]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government urged to take action as clinical negligence costs continue to rise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151928</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/government-urged-to-take-action-as-clinical-negligence-costs-continue-to-rise/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:47:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A medical defence organisation has written to the health secretary demanding urgent action to address the cost of clinical negligence to the NHS. The Medical Defence Union (MDU) said it continues to have concerns about the total cost that clinical negligence litigation poses to healthcare in the UK. The organisation has seen a ‘steady increase’
The post Government urged to take action as clinical negligence costs continue to rise appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are taking ‘collective action’: what does that mean?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/gps-are-taking-collective-action-what-does-that-mean.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/gps-are-taking-collective-action-what-does-that-mean.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:47:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - After GP partners voted on 1 August for collective action, this explainer describes what’s behind the dispute, the action that GPs plan to take, and what it might mean for patients and the government. Explainer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advice and guidance should be a DES worth millions to general practice, says BMA GP chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883319</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/advice-guidance-des-worth-millions-general-practice-says-bma-gp-chair/article/1883319"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advice and guidance is effectively 'shifting outpatients onto general practice' and should be commissioned as a multi-million pound directed enhanced service, the BMA England GP committee chair has suggested.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP who spent £40,000 to save her practice 'deserves refund']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883346</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-spent-40000-save-practice-deserves-refund/article/1883346"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who forked out £40,000 of her own money to stop her practice being handed to another provider should be fully reimbursed by the NHS, a campaigner has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP who spent £40,000 to save her practice 'deserves NHS refund']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883346</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-spent-40000-save-practice-deserves-nhs-refund/article/1883346"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who forked out £40,000 of her own money to stop her practice being handed to another provider should be fully reimbursed by the NHS, a campaigner has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A pivotal moment for regulation: regulation and oversight survey 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-pivotal-moment-for-regulation-regulation-and-oversight-survey-2024.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-pivotal-moment-for-regulation-regulation-and-oversight-survey-2024.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T08:53:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This report details the findings of the latest NHS Providers' member survey, focusing on trust leaders’ views and experience of regulation during 2023/24. The report finds that trusts are experiencing intense pressures against a backdrop of 'unrealistic' regulatory demands. Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alder Hey goes live with Meditech Expanse EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201791</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/alder-hey-goes-live-with-meditech-expanse-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T07:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alder Hey has become the second NHS trust to go live the Meditech Expanse electronic patient record system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS chief nurse urges students to consider healthcare careers through clearing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250964</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/nhs-chief-nurse-urges-students-to-consider-healthcare-careers-through-clearing/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-11T23:01:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The university clearing system is a great gateway into the NHS, health bosses are reminding would-be graduates and career-changers. As thousands of students nervously await their A-level results on Thursday (15 August), the NHS is launching a campaign to highlight the many healthcare career options available through UCAS clearing. Students reconsidering their choices after receiving […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO invites mpox vaccine manufacturers to submit dossiers for emergency evaluation]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:59281230-ec21-402b-8f8b-ac8f2e39b855</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/09-08-2024-who-invites-mpox-vaccine-manufacturers-to-submit-dossiers-for-emergency-evaluations"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T15:36:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO has today issued an invitation for manufacturers of mpox vaccines to submit an Expression of Interest for Emergency Use Listing (EUL).
The WHO Director-General announced on 7 August 2024 that he had triggered the process for EUL of mpox vaccines given worrying trends in the disease’s spread. There is a serious and growing outbreak in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) that has now expanded outside the country. A new viral strain, which first emerged in September 2023, has for the first time been detected outside DRC.
The EUL procedure is an emergency use authorization process, specifically developed to expedite the availability of unlicensed medical products like vaccines that are needed in public health emergency situations. This is a time-limited recommendation, based on a risk-benefit approach.
WHO is requesting manufacturers to submit data to ensure that the vaccines are safe, effective, of assured quality and suitable for the target populations.
Granting of an EUL will accelerate vaccine access particularly for those lower-income countries which have not yet issued their own national regulatory approval. The EUL also enables partners including Gavi and UNICEF to procure vaccines for distribution.
Mpox is a viral illness caused by the monkeypox virus, a species of the genus Orthopoxvirus. Mpox can be transmitted to humans through physical contact with someone who is infectious, with contaminated materials, or with infected animals. 
There are currently two vaccines in use against the disease, both of which have been recommended for use by the WHO Strategic Advisory Group of Experts on Immunization, or SAGE.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2+2 equals a kick up the ARRS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151840</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/22-equals-a-kick-up-the-arrs/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T15:07:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield finds that the Government’s plan for GPs to be included in the additional roles reimbursement scheme doesn’t add up So, secondly, I should point out that I’m not great at numbers. But I’ve found an envelope, located the back of it, and here goes. There are 1,250 PCNs sharing the shiny, ARRS-funded 1,000 new
The post 2+2 equals a kick up the ARRS appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global sum to rise by ‘at least 6%’, NHSE confirms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151930</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/global-sum-to-rise-by-at-least-6-nhse-confirms/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T14:49:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices will see global sum rise ‘by at least 6%’, NHS England said in a primary care bulletin today. The bulletin also said work is ‘taking place’ in order to update the Statement of Financial Entitlements (SFE) ‘so that the uplift can be passed on to practices as soon as possible’.  It also reiterated
The post Global sum to rise by ‘at least 6%’, NHSE confirms appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP out of hours service BrisDoc to deploy EPM system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201641</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/brisdoc-selects-cleo-systems-for-electronic-patient-management/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T12:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP out of hours service, BrisDoc has announced plans to implement an electronic patient management system in its urgent care services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we know (and don’t know) about GPs being added to ARRS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151875</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/workforce/what-we-know-and-dont-know-about-gps-being-added-to-arrs/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T10:53:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, the Government announced it was ‘cutting red tape’ by allowing GPs to be hired through the ARRS. Here, Eliza Parr, sets out what we know (and don’t know) about the new policy. Amidst everything going on across general practice – and, indeed, the country – last week’s announcement on the Additional Roles Reimbursement
The post What we know (and don’t know) about GPs being added to ARRS appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could prescribe new incontinence pill from October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151865</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/renal-medicine-urology-mens-health/gps-could-prescribe-new-incontinence-pill-from-october/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T10:15:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NICE has recommended a new daily pill to treat incontinence and other symptoms of overactive bladder syndrome, which GPs will be able to prescribe. The final draft guidance has approved vibegron, a bladder muscle relaxant which is produced by Pierre Fabre. Around 330,000 adults will be eligible to receive the pill following the expected publication
The post GPs could prescribe new incontinence pill from October appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sheffield Teaching Hospitals launches diabetes smart tech trial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201147</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/sheffield-teaching-hospitals-launches-diabetes-smart-tech-trial/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T10:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sheffield Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust has launched a smart tech initiative to reduce the risk of nerve damage in people living with type 2 diabetes. The Oceanic (One-Stop Screening And Intensified Care) trial is now live and will run for two years. Researchers are using wearable sensors and activity-tracking watches to monitor participants’ health […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three quarters of public concerned about pressures on GP practices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151861</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/three-quarters-of-public-concerned-about-pressures-on-gp-practices/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T09:28:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than three quarters of the public are ‘concerned’ about the level of pressure that GP practices are facing, new polling from the Health Foundation has found. Public satisfaction with the NHS was also ‘at a record low’ when people were surveyed before the general election, according to the think-tank. The poll, carried out in
The post Three quarters of public concerned about pressures on GP practices appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid and South Essex deploys AI communications solution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201645</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/mid-and-south-essex-deploys-ai-communications-solution/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T07:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A successful pilot that reduced missed appointments at Mid and South Essex NHS Foundation Trust has led to a full rollout of the solution.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whooping cough cases reach more than 10,000 in first half of 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884496</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/whooping-cough-cases-reach-10000-first-half-2024/infections-and-infestations/immunisation/article/1884496"/>
        <updated>2024-08-09T07:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 10,000 cases of whooping cough have been recorded in the first six months of 2024 as cases remain far higher that at any point in the past decade.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vast majority of public concerned about pressure on GPs, poll shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884558</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/vast-majority-public-concerned-pressure-gps-poll-shows/article/1884558"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than three quarters of the British public are concerned about the level of pressure on general practice, according to polling carried out just before the general election.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicines that you cannot export from the UK or hoard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-that-cannot-be-parallel-exported-from-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-that-cannot-be-parallel-exported-from-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T16:11:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out medicines that cannot be exported from the UK or hoarded because they are needed for UK patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do we overdiagnose autism?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151658</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/paediatrics/do-we-overdiagnose-autism/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T15:45:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP Dr Peter Bagshaw looks at potential overdiagnosis of this condition. Background Autism, also known as autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is a developmental disorder with symptoms that appear within the first three years of life. It is characterised by deficits in social communication and interaction, and restricted, repetitive behaviours, interests, or activities. Around 1 in
The post Do we overdiagnose autism? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PA legal challenge doctors raise £80k to pursue GMC – but ‘need £500k’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151843</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/pa-legal-challenge-doctor-group-raise-80k-to-pursue-gmc-but-need-500k/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T15:13:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A group of doctors seeking a legal challenge against the GMC over physician associate (PA) regulation has raised nearly £80,000 – but they say they will need £500,000. Earlier this year, Anaesthetists United – a group representing anaesthetists of all grades – said it was commencing a legal case against the GMC as it believes
The post PA legal challenge doctors raise £80k to pursue GMC – but ‘need £500k’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take our survey on collective action and potentially win £100]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151844</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/2024-25-gp-contract/take-our-survey-on-collective-action-and-potentially-win-100/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T14:59:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are asking GP partners and principals in England to take our special survey on the collective action launched by the BMA. The survey will be closing at 9am on Monday 12 August. Please note, if you are not a GP partner or principal in England, you won’t be able to take this survey. The
The post Take our survey on collective action and potentially win £100 appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to no longer refer directly into children gender services]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151830</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/gps-to-no-longer-refer-directly-into-children-gender-services/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T13:47:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs will no longer be able to refer young people directly into waiting lists for children gender services, NHS England has decided. Referrals may only be made by paediatric or mental health services, and ‘will not be accepted from any other source’, according to new documents published as part of NHS England’s plans to implement
The post GPs to no longer refer directly into children gender services appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4535 - Roundcube Releases Security Updates for Webmail]]></title>
        <id>004b7f6c-b964-430f-bb6a-c3f6ec8eb34a</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4535"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T13:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Updates address three vulnerabilities that could lead to theft of emails and contacts
 Updates address three vulnerabilities that could lead to theft of emails and contacts
 Updated: 08 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Unplugged: Chris Chaney talks Rewired Pitchfest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201825</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-unplugged-chris-chaney-talks-rewired-pitchfest/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T12:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jordan Sollof is joined by Chris Chaney, chief executive of CW+, talk all things Digital Health Rewired Pitchfest.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP media survey: What do GPs really need to know…and how do they find it out?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151812</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/resource/practice-life/gp-media-survey-what-do-gps-really-need-to-knowand-how-do-they-find-it-out/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T12:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Preview in new tab We all know that GPs need to keep up with developments in medicine and general practice.  But exactly how do GPs do this with the range of materials available to them and what is most important to them? The GP Media Survey has been tracking this for over 20 years and
The post GP media survey: What do GPs really need to know…and how do they find it out? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP media survey: What do GPs really need to know…and how do they find it out?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151812</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/resource/uncategorised/gp-media-survey-what-do-gps-really-need-to-knowand-how-do-they-find-it-out/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T12:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We all know that GPs need to keep up with developments in medicine and general practice.  But exactly how do GPs do this with the range of materials available to them and what is most important to them? The GP Media Survey has been tracking this for over 20 years and the latest edition was
The post GP media survey: What do GPs really need to know…and how do they find it out? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing medicolegal reports on asylum seekers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151481</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/writing-medicolegal-reports-on-asylum-seekers/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T10:57:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Alick Munro shares how doctors can get involved in writing medicolegal reports on asylum seekers You are probably aware that there are many tens of thousands of asylum seekers awaiting assessment of their applications by the Home Office. If past performance predicts the future, some 53-66% of the claims will be approved by the
The post Writing medicolegal reports on asylum seekers appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA urges GPs to sit ‘closer to the door’ than patients amid spate of racism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151809</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/special-investigations/gp-abuse/bma-urges-gps-to-sit-closer-to-the-door-than-patients-amid-spate-of-racism/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T10:52:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has urged GPs to sit ‘closer to the door than the patient’ during consultations to remain safe, in light of recent riots and attacks spurred by racism. In new guidance circulated yesterday, the UK GP Committees advised practices to ‘be conscious of the risks around home visits and being in consultation rooms alone
The post BMA urges GPs to sit ‘closer to the door’ than patients amid spate of racism appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another baby dies from whooping cough as cases surpass 10,000]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151808</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/another-baby-dies-from-whooping-cough-as-cases-surpass-10000/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T10:43:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A further baby died from whooping cough in England in June, bringing the total to 10 since the start of the latest outbreak in November last year. New data published today by the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) also revealed laboratory confirmed cases during the outbreak has now surpassed 10,000. In response, UKHSA reiterated advice
The post Another baby dies from whooping cough as cases surpass 10,000 appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201615</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-161/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T10:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Coffee Time Briefing features a digital skills framework for Scotland and a £300,000 tender for remote monitoring in Suffolk.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fertility startup among new cohort joining UK incubator programme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201175</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/fertility-startup-among-new-cohort-joining-uk-incubator-programme/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fertility startup POM Health is among semiconductor startups selected to join the UK government’s ChipStart incubator programme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders condemn racist riots and urge home visit safety review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883589</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-leaders-condemn-racist-riots-urge-home-visit-safety-review/article/1883589"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T09:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practices should consider whether home visits or being in consultation rooms alone with patients is safe and encourage staff to travel together amid racist rioting that has spread across the UK, BMA GP leaders have warned in a letter to the profession.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A&E staff experiencing busiest ever summer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250822</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/ae-staff-experiencing-busiest-ever-summer/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T08:51:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff working in A&E departments are in the middle of their busiest summer ever with a total of 4.6 million attendances over the last 2 months – higher than any other June and July, new figures show today. The latest performance data shows that the 3 busiest ever months for A&E staff have been […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Isle of Wight NHS Trust launches patient portal for digital letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201419</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/isle-of-wight-nhs-trust-launches-patient-portal-for-digital-letters/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T07:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Isle of Wight NHS Trust has gone live with a patient portal which allows patients to receive digital letters and manage their appointments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gene-editing therapy that could cure blood disorder thalassaemia for NHS patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250694</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/gene-editing-therapy-that-could-cure-blood-disorder-thalassaemia-for-nhs-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T23:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS patients living with a genetic blood disorder are set to be among the first in the world to benefit from a “life-changing” gene-editing treatment which offers hope of a cure. The one-off gene therapy, Casgevy, has been approved by for use on the NHS in England, from today (8 August), by the National Institute […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs ‘least satisfied’ with their job among all doctors, GMC finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151798</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gps-least-satisfied-with-their-job-among-all-doctors-gmc-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs continue to be the least likely to be satisfied with their job and the most likely to be struggling with their workload among all doctor groups, according to new GMC data. The regulator’s latest annual report into workplace accounts of doctors in the UK warned that the experiences of GPs ‘remain concerningly poor’. It
The post GPs ‘least satisfied’ with their job among all doctors, GMC finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs forced to cut working hours as overwork and low satisfaction take toll, GMC reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883549</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-forced-cut-working-hours-overwork-low-satisfaction-toll-gmc-reveals/article/1883549"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly a third of GPs cut their contracted working hours in 2023 as the profession remained more overworked and less satisfied than any other group of doctors, a GMC report shows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4534 - Progress Software Releases Security Advisory for WhatsUp Gold]]></title>
        <id>7f0cccc5-5cd7-4e75-961e-d1a9cd99b81a</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4534"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T16:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisory addresses 15 security vulnerabilities that could lead to unauthorised access
 Advisory addresses 15 security vulnerabilities that could lead to unauthorised access
 Updated: 07 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Concerns are not ‘legitimate’ if GPs are closing early for their safety]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151797</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/concerns-are-not-legitimate-if-gps-are-closing-early-for-their-safety/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T15:19:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice is disproportionately non-white, and GPs will be feeling the effects of these riots as much as anyone, argues editor Jaimie Kaffash Last week was one of the busiest weeks in terms of policy that we’ve seen for a while. We saw the closing of the ballot, the announcement of collective action, the promise
The post Concerns are not ‘legitimate’ if GPs are closing early for their safety appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS spells out support for GPs as riots put pressure on general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883521</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-spells-support-gps-riots-put-pressure-general-practice/article/1883521"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T14:47:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices across the country are closing earlier to ensure the safety of staff and patients as racist and Islamophobic riots continue to spread across the country.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Official data massively underrepresent full-time working in general practice, research shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883522</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/official-data-massively-underrepresent-full-time-working-general-practice-research-shows/article/1883522"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T14:29:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are more than twice as likely to work full-time hours as official data suggest, according to research that calls for sessions to be scrapped as a measure of family doctors' work commitment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: King’s Ambulance Service Medal for distinguished service]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/kings-ambulance-service-medal-for-distinguished-service</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/kings-ambulance-service-medal-for-distinguished-service"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T14:23:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Details the eligibility criteria for the medal, allocations across the UK and Crown Dependencies, and guidance on the nomination process for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices told to send staff home in taxis amid racist riots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151784</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gp-practices-told-to-send-staff-home-in-taxis-amid-racist-riots/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T14:18:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices in the Manchester area have been advised to send staff home in taxis after work, as the local LMC fears staff could be targeted during racist riots. The Association of Greater Manchester LMCs has written to practices advising GPs to ‘organise taxis home’ for staff if they are notified of riots in their
The post GP practices told to send staff home in taxis amid racist riots appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS software provider could get £6m ICO fine over patient data hack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151771</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/nhs-software-provider-could-get-6m-ico-fine-over-patient-data-hack/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T13:41:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An NHS software provider could be fined £6m by the ICO for failing to protect against a data hack which severely impacted GPs in 2022. As first revealed by Pulse, parts of the NHS 111 service suffered a ‘total system outage’ during the 2022 attack, and GPs working in urgent care had to share patient
The post NHS software provider could get £6m ICO fine over patient data hack appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flo Health responds to viral male-founded femtech funding debate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201687</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/flo-health-responds-to-viral-male-founded-femtech-funding-debate/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T12:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Male-founded firm Flo Health has called on investors to recognise the “vast potential” of the femtech, following a viral debate on VC funding.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS to roll out six new specialist gender centres for children and young people]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250677</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/nhs-to-roll-out-six-new-specialist-gender-centres-for-children-and-young-people/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T11:20:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England will roll out up to six new specialist regional centres by 2026 to provide tailored gender services for children and young people, based on recommendations in the Cass Review. Following the publication of a comprehensive report by Dr Hilary Cass in April, the NHS has today set out how it will deliver transformed […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the current state of NHS finances?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-is-the-current-state-of-nhs-finances.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-is-the-current-state-of-nhs-finances.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T11:02:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This briefing provides a brief history of NHS funding and outlines the current challenges NHS trusts are facing in delivering operational priorities within a pressurised financial environment. Briefing More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced fined £6m over stolen patient data in 2022 cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201709</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/advanced-fined-6m-over-stolen-patient-data-in-2022-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T10:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Information Commissioner’s Office has imposed a £6.09m fine on Advanced for failing to protect peronsal information during a cyber attack.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LMCs condemn far-right riots and urge practices to consider steps to keep staff safe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883475</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/lmcs-condemn-far-right-riots-urge-practices-consider-steps-keep-staff-safe/article/1883475"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T10:25:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LMCs have condemned far-right racist and Islamophobic rioting and have released guidelines on what practices can do to protect staff and patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synnovis rebuilds IT systems following London cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201541</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/synnovis-rebuilds-it-systems-following-london-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T10:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 60 core IT systems used within laboratories are being rebuilt following the cyber attack on pathology system provider Synnovis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP full-time definition should be six sessions per week, finds new study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151760</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/gp-full-time-definition-should-be-six-sessions-per-week-finds-new-study/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T09:55:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP full-time working should be defined as six sessions per week in order to reflect the ‘current duration of sessions’, a new study has concluded. The authors argued that the BMA definition for full-time working is ‘inappropriate’ when compared to the NHS standard of 37.5 hours per week. A cross-sectional study, based on GP Worklife
The post GP full-time definition should be six sessions per week, finds new study appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former Pulse columnist GP to compete on Strictly Come Dancing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151741</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/punam-krishan/former-pulse-columnist-gp-to-compete-on-strictly-come-dancing/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T09:12:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A former Pulse columnist will take part as one of the celebrity contestants on the new series of the BBC’s Strictly Come Dancing. Glasgow GP and TV personality Dr Punam Krishan, who wrote for Pulse in 2018 and 2019, will be a contestant on the entertainment show when it returns for a new series this
The post Former Pulse columnist GP to compete on Strictly Come Dancing appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: DHSC group accounting manual 2024 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2024-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2024-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T09:11:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mandatory annual reports and accounts guidelines for the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) group bodies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP to take part in this year's Strictly Come Dancing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883456</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-part-years-strictly-dancing/article/1883456"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T09:09:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish GP and TV doctor Dr Punam Krishan has been announced as one of the celebrity contestants on this year's series of Strictly Come Dancing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultation outcome: Changes to DHSC group accounting manual 2024 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2024-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2024-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T08:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seeks views on the DHSC group accounting manual that applies to DHSC bodies for their annual reports and accounts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Dr Katie Bramall-Stainer on GP collective action and what happens now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883341</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-dr-katie-bramall-stainer-gp-collective-action-happens/article/1883341"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T07:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BMA England GP committee chair Dr Katie Bramall-Stainer explains why GPs need to take collective action, what she hopes it will achieve and the changes that are needed to ensure a sustainable future for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs urged to sign letter highlighting pressure on practices amid Darzi review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1881805</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-urged-sign-letter-highlighting-pressure-practices-amid-darzi-review/article/1881805"/>
        <updated>2024-08-07T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are being urged to join hundreds of people who have signed an open letter to the senior doctor leading a rapid government review of the NHS, to highlight facts about the crisis facing general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How would I improve the NHS? Well, I wouldn’t start from here]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151469</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/david-turner/how-would-you-improve-the-nhs-well-i-wouldnt-start-from-here/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T15:21:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr David Turner on what he would do to improve the NHS if he could go back in time There is a famous joke about a tourist in Ireland asking a passer-by the way to Dublin. The passer-by responds:  ‘Well, I wouldn’t start from here.’ I know the feeling, and Wes Streeting must also be
The post How would I improve the NHS? Well, I wouldn’t start from here appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices move to remote appointments as racist riots spark safety fears]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883401</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-move-remote-appointments-racist-riots-spark-safety-fears/article/1883401"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T14:59:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices have been advised to move to remote delivery of appointments while racist and Islamophobic rioting continues across the UK, amid 'very high' levels of fear that have left staff frightened to come to work or deliver home visits.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices to close early amid fears of being caught up in racist riots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151712</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/gp-practices-to-close-early-amid-fears-of-being-caught-up-in-racist-riots/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T13:27:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP surgeries in North East London will close early tomorrow as they fear for staff and patients’ safety after learning of planned racist rioting in the area. The Firs Medical Centre and St James Medical Practice in Walthamstow said that they have been alerted by the police and local authorities of ‘threatened disruption’ on Wednesday.
The post GP practices to close early amid fears of being caught up in racist riots appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Healthcare leaders raise concerns about £1.3bn cut to AI funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201381</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/healthcare-leaders-raise-concerns-about-cuts-to-ai-funding/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T12:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health leaders have voiced their concerns about the UK government cutting £1.3 billion of funding for AI and technology projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[M25 climate protest GP to appear in front of MPTS tribunal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151670</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/m25-climate-protest-gp-to-appear-in-front-of-mpts-tribunal/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T10:50:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who participated in a climate protest blocking the M25 motorway is appearing in front of a medical practitioners’ tribunal this week. The Medical Practitioners Tribunal Service (MPTS) will inquire into the allegation that in September 2021 the High Court issued an injunction order preventing Dr Diana Warner from protesting on the M25, which
The post M25 climate protest GP to appear in front of MPTS tribunal appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201075</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-160/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T10:30:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This latest Coffee Time Briefing features £8m funding for UK Biobank and an initiative to accelerate motor neurone disease research.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE ‘firmly expects’ GP partners to pass on 6% pay rise to staff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151701</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/nhse-firmly-expects-gp-partners-to-pass-on-6-pay-rise-to-staff/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T10:23:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England (NHSE) has said it ‘firmly’ expects GP partners to award practice nurses and other practice staff a full 6% pay rise. A letter from NHSE primary care director, Dr Amanda Doyle, and medical director for primary care, Dr Claire Fuller, confirmed funding will be given via the Global Sum – used to deliver core
The post NHSE ‘firmly expects’ GP partners to pass on 6% pay rise to staff appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workforce is barrier to frontline digitisation, says NHS Confed report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201385</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/workforce-is-barrier-to-frontline-digitisation-says-nhs-confed-report/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T10:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Workforce and training are “significant barriers” to delivering a frontline digitised service, according to an NHS Confederation report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frontline digitisation: creating the conditions for a digital NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/frontline-digitisation-creating-the-conditions-for-a-digital-nhs-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/frontline-digitisation-creating-the-conditions-for-a-digital-nhs-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - Digital transformation is a significant enabler towards improved productivity and efficiency in the NHS. This report explores integrated care systems’ experience of frontline digitisation and highlights the reality, the common issues, challenges and areas of improvement to unlock the potential of a digitally responsive and modern NHS. Report Associated infographic]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA to push for expanded GP retainer and fellowship schemes in next year's contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883338</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-push-expanded-gp-retainer-fellowship-schemes-next-years-contract/article/1883338"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T08:40:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BMA negotiators could push for an improved retainer scheme and fully-funded fellowships for newly-qualified GPs in next year's contract to build a permanent solution to GP unemployment, England's GP committee chair has suggested.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital HIV PrEP service launches in East Sussex]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201317</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-hiv-prep-service-launches-in-east-sussex/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-06T07:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A HIV PrEP service has launched in East Sussex, giving users access to tests and medication without having to visit a clinic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than half of GP practices in England took part in clinical research last year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882855</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/half-gp-practices-england-took-part-clinical-research-last-year/article/1882855"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than half of GP practices in England took part in clinical research last year - with more than 270,000 patients recruited to studies via primary care, data from the National Institute for Health and Care Research (NIHR) show.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Third of NHS “soups and shakes” participants in remission from type 2 diabetes in a year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250484</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/third-of-nhs-soups-and-shakes-participants-in-remission-from-type-2-diabetes-in-a-year/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T22:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A major study has found that the radical NHS “soups and shakes” programme works at scale and is helping hundreds of people put their type 2 diabetes into remission across England. The study showed that of those who completed the programme and were measured twice, 1 in 3 (32%) had put their type 2 diabetes […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One third of ‘soups and shakes’ programme participants in type 2 diabetes remission]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151685</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/diabetes-endocrinology/one-third-of-soups-and-shakes-programme-participants-in-type-2-diabetes-remission/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A major study into the NHS ‘soups and shakes’ programme has given researchers and commissioners hope that type 2 diabetes remission can be achieved through at-scale intervention. Published today in The Lancet Diabetes & Endocrinology, the study assessed remission of type 2 diabetes for real-world NHS participants, finding that of those who completed the programme
The post One third of ‘soups and shakes’ programme participants in type 2 diabetes remission appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP 'soup and shake' referrals put type 2 diabetes in remission for one in three patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883297</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-soup-shake-referrals-put-type-2-diabetes-remission-one-three-patients/article/1883297"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One in three patients who completed an NHS 'soup and shake' weight loss programme put their type 2 diabetes into remission in a year, a major study has found.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Writing Competition: Could you be our next blogger?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151513</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/writing-competition-2024/pulse-writing-competition-could-you-be-our-next-blogger/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T15:54:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever fancied yourself a blogger, sharing your thoughts on the state of general practice with Pulse readers?  Well if so, now’s your chance to prove it! Pulse is running a summer writing competition to find a new blogger to entertain (or exasperate) readers. To apply, all you need to do is write a
The post Pulse Writing Competition: Could you be our next blogger? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bringing it all together: financial strategies that address health inequalities]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/bringing-it-all-together-financial-strategies-that-address-health-inequalities.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/bringing-it-all-together-financial-strategies-that-address-health-inequalities.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T15:33:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthcare Financial Management Association (HFMA) - This explainer sums up the HFMA’s work on health inequalities and explores how organisations can use financial strategies to address health inequalities. Explainer More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs report being targeted with abuse and violence amid racist rioting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883289</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-report-targeted-abuse-violence-amid-racist-rioting/article/1883289"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T14:44:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and practice staff have reported being targeted with abuse and violence in the ongoing wave of far-right civil unrest and rioting, the RCGP has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP urges vigilance as GPs ‘targeted’ in racist riots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151679</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/rcgp-urges-vigilance-as-gps-targeted-in-racist-riots/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T14:22:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and practice staff have been ‘targeted with abuse and violence’ during racist riots across the UK in recent days, the RCGP said while urging vigilance. In a statement published today, the college said it was ‘appalled’ at the ‘racist attacks’, and advised GP teams to ‘remain vigilant’ when travelling to and from work. Following
The post RCGP urges vigilance as GPs ‘targeted’ in racist riots appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barts Health launches ‘digital staff bank’ for over 4,000 medics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201327</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/barts-health-launches-digital-staff-bank-for-over-4000-medics/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T14:18:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Barts Health NHS Trust has launched a ‘digital staff bank’, enabling over 4,000 doctors in London to gain access to greater flexible working.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we scaled up user research in the NHS App at speed]]></title>
        <id>5cff1f83-a677-4a72-9990-bd90c5509386</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/design-matters/2024/how-we-scaled-up-user-research-in-the-nhs-app-at-speed"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T14:06:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tanja Galloway talks about the work of the NHS App user research team – and the challenges of supporting a fast-moving, inclusive national service. 


The NHS App recently achieved a significant milestone: most adults in England (34 million people) have now registered to use it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we scaled up user research in the NHS App at speed]]></title>
        <id>5cff1f83-a677-4a72-9990-bd90c5509386</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/design-matters/2024/how-we-scaled-up-user-research-in-the-nhs-app-at-speed"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T14:06:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tanja Galloway talks about the work of the NHS App user research team – and the challenges of supporting a fast-moving, inclusive national service. 


The NHS App recently achieved a significant milestone: most adults in England (34 million people) have now registered to use it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices begin collective action and warn patients of impact on services]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883209</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-begin-collective-action-warn-patients-impact-services/article/1883209"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices across England have begun to warn patients of the impact on services as they take part in collective action, explaining they are on patients' side and determined to secure better funding for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[North Tees and Hartlepool recognised after eObs cuts sepsis cases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201109</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/north-tees-and-hartlepool-recognised-after-eobs-cuts-sepsis-cases/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T12:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[North Tees and Hartlepool NHS Foundation Trust has been recognised by NHS England for its electronic observations and sepsis dashboard.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ARRS funding for GPs will be available in October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151667</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/arrs-funding-for-gps-will-be-available-in-october/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T11:29:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Funding to hire GPs under the Additional Roles Reimbursement Scheme (ARRS) will become available from October.  The Government announced last week that the ARRS will be expanded to include GPs, an ’emergency measure’ intended to allow practices to hire 1,000 more newly-qualified GPs this year. This expansion is backed by ring-fenced funding of £82m, and
The post ARRS funding for GPs will be available in October appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statement from Amanda Pritchard, NHS Chief Executive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250511</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/statement-from-amanda-pritchard-nhs-chief-executive/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T11:12:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had intended this message to focus mainly on thanking the many NHS colleagues who were involved in caring for those killed and injured in the horrendous attack in Southport last week  – the North West Ambulance Service (NWAS) crews who attended the scene, the receiving teams at Southport and Formby, Ormskirk, Alder Hey, Aintree, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs must supervise PA decisions immediately after each patient, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151654</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gps-must-supervise-pa-decisions-immediately-after-each-patient-says-bma/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T10:59:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP supervision of physician associates (PAs) must take place immediately after each patient and before they leave the surgery, according to the BMA.  In new guidance for GPs, which aims to ‘standardise’ the use of PAs in practices, the BMA has highlighted the importance of ‘contemporaneous’ and ‘co-located’ supervision. The union has also said PAs
The post GPs must supervise PA decisions immediately after each patient, says BMA appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GMC clarifies threshold for investigating doctors who protest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151625</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/gmc-clarifies-threshold-for-investigating-doctors-who-protest/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T10:09:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GMC has clarified that doctors have the ‘right to campaign’ but ‘must follow the law’ in new guidance on protests and political activism. Following the controversy surrounding GP Dr Sarah Benn, who was suspended for breaching a court order after attending a climate change protest, the regulator has set out how it deals with
The post GMC clarifies threshold for investigating doctors who protest appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action can stop GP burnout and make patients happier, says GP committee chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883186</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/collective-action-stop-gp-burnout-patients-happier-says-gp-committee-chair/article/1883186"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T10:04:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action will be 'painful', but adopting safe working limits and pushing back against unfunded work can help practices retain GPs and ultimately lead to improved patient satisfaction, the BMA England GP committee chair has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Hospital for Children launches virtual tour of neonatal unit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200669</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/royal-hospital-for-children-launches-virtual-tour-of-neonatal-unit/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T10:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Royal Hospital for Children in Glasgow has gone live with an immersive virtual tour of its neonatal intensive care unit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The power of prevention: boosting vaccine uptake for better outcomes]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/the-power-of-prevention-boosting-vaccine-uptake-for-better-outcomes.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/the-power-of-prevention-boosting-vaccine-uptake-for-better-outcomes.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T09:31:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reform - This briefing paper focuses on three broad factors involved in people's attitudes to vaccination — confidence, complacency and convenience — which influence uptake. Taking each in turn, it sets out practical steps for the new government that would help keep the UK protected against vaccine-preventable diseases, reducing unwarranted variation in health outcomes while freeing up valuable, limited resource...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patient safety must be central to EPR design and rollout says report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201247</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/patient-safety-must-be-central-to-epr-design-and-rollout-says-report/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-05T07:30:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patient safety must be central to the design, development, and rollout of EPR systems, a Patient Safety Learning report has stated.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What the 6% pay rise means for GP practice finances]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151637</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/practice-personal-finance/what-the-6-pay-rise-means-for-gp-practice-finances/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T15:25:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a busy week for general practice – along with the start of GP collective action and changes to the ARRS, the Government also made important commitments on doctors’ pay. Here, Eliza Parr looks at some of the questions around the promise of a GP pay rise Earlier this year, GPs in England roundly
The post What the 6% pay rise means for GP practice finances appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP collective action will have ‘detrimental effect’, says NHS England director]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151646</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gp-collective-action-will-have-detrimental-effect-says-nhs-england-director/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T15:04:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP collective action will have ‘a detrimental effect’ on services, NHS England’s director of primary care has stated. In an opinion piece for Pulse, Dr Amanda Doyle said that while she knows that GPs ‘would never intend to take action that would impact patients’, it is ‘hard to see’ how this action ‘will not have
The post GP collective action will have ‘detrimental effect’, says NHS England director appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Amanda Doyle: ‘We have ensured ring-fenced funding for GP recruitment’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151639</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/workforce/dr-amanda-doyle-we-have-ensured-ring-fenced-funding-for-gp-recruitment/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T15:01:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England’s director for primary care Dr Amanda Doyle on the Government’s decisions to include GPs in the additional roles reimbursement scheme and to accept the DDRB’s recommendation for a 6% pay uplift for all practice staff General practice has been under huge pressure in recent years, and I know that all of you will
The post Dr Amanda Doyle: ‘We have ensured ring-fenced funding for GP recruitment’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vine robots could transform cancer treatment, shows Leeds study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200757</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/vine-robots-could-transform-cancer-treatment-shows-leeds-study/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T14:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New robots that mimic creeping vine plants could transform cancer diagnosis and treatment, according to a study by University of Leeds.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP ARRS plan to start from October, NHS officials confirm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883102</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-arrs-plan-start-october-nhs-officials-confirm/article/1883102"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T13:52:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The extra £82m that is to be added to the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) to allow PCNs to recruit GPs will be available from October, NHS England has confirmed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NW London partnership leverages data to reduce child admissions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200743</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/nw-london-partnership-leverages-data-to-reduce-child-admissions/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T12:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A partnership between the North West London CAMHS PC and Real World Health has helped to reduce child admissions and time spent in hospital.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI in health care: what do the public and NHS staff think?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/ai-in-health-care-what-do-the-public-and-nhs-staff-think.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/ai-in-health-care-what-do-the-public-and-nhs-staff-think.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T11:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - To help understand public and staff attitudes towards the use of artificial intelligence (AI) in health care, the Health Foundation commissioned a survey, conducted in June and July 2024, of 7,201 nationally representative members of the public and 1,292 NHS staff members. It found that, on balance, support from both the public and NHS staff for...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hiring GPs through ARRS 'first step towards entirely salaried model']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883013</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/hiring-gps-arrs-first-step-towards-entirely-salaried-model/article/1883013"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T10:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plans to recruit GPs through the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) could be a first step towards an entirely salaried model of general practice, a prominent GP has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Masterclass: A complete GP’s guide to COPD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151225</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/respiratory/masterclass-a-complete-gps-guide-to-copd/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T10:44:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the next in our Masterclass series, Dr Andrew Whittamore, a GPSI in respiratory medicine and clinical lead at Asthma + Lung UK, explains the latest knowledge and best practice in the management of COPD in primary care.  This series showcases content from our Pulse Reference site, which supports GPs in making diagnoses. We are expanding this service to include
The post Masterclass: A complete GP’s guide to COPD appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[COVID-19 jabs for NHS staff to continue this autumn despite reduced campaign]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883070</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/covid-19-jabs-nhs-staff-continue-autumn-despite-reduced-campaign/article/1883070"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T10:34:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frontline NHS staff will continue to be offered COVID-19 jabs as part of this year's autumn vaccination campaign despite updated advice from expert advisers backing a more limited rollout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultation threshold for Pharmacy First payment reduced for August]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151511</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/consultation-threshold-for-pharmacy-first-payment-reduced-for-august/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T10:33:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Community pharmacies will only need to perform 15 Pharmacy First clinical pathway consultations in August to meet the minimum threshold, rather than the 20 originally set for the month. This comes as recent data has revealed that one in five community pharmacies participating in Pharmacy First in England failed to meet the minimum threshold of
The post Consultation threshold for Pharmacy First payment reduced for August appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The reality of, and potential for, digitally enabled care in the community]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/the-reality-of-and-potential-for-digitally-enabled-care-in-the-community.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/the-reality-of-and-potential-for-digitally-enabled-care-in-the-community.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T10:28:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The King's Fund - Could digital technology help move care closer to home? This long read explores how community services use digital technology and what the future could – and should – hold. Long read The King's Fund - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movers and Shakers news roundup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201197</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/movers-and-shakers-news-roundup-50/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T10:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Movers and Shakers roundup features the appointment of Duncan Burton as new chief nursing officer for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICBs told to ensure practices meet contract requirements during GP collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151609</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/icbs-told-to-ensure-practices-meet-contract-requirements-during-gp-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T09:54:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ICBs should make sure that GP practices are continuing to meet contractual requirements during collective action, NHS England has said. Yesterday, the BMA announced the results of its non-statutory ballot, which saw 98.3% of GP partners voting in favour of taking collective action from today, in protest against contractual terms and funding. GP practices will choose
The post ICBs told to ensure practices meet contract requirements during GP collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Government accepts advice on 2024 autumn Covid vaccine programme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/government-accepts-advice-on-2024-autumn-covid-vaccine-programme</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/government-accepts-advice-on-2024-autumn-covid-vaccine-programme"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T09:36:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minister Andrew Gwynne has accepted advice from the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Independent report: COVID-19 autumn 2024 vaccination programme: JCVI advice, 8 April 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/covid-19-autumn-2024-vaccination-programme-jcvi-advice-8-april-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/covid-19-autumn-2024-vaccination-programme-jcvi-advice-8-april-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T09:14:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Statement setting out the advice from the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation (JCVI) on the COVID-19 vaccination programme for autumn 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: Department of Health and Social Care prompt payment of suppliers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/department-of-health-prompt-payment-of-suppliers-data</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/department-of-health-prompt-payment-of-suppliers-data"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T08:35:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proportion of payments made within 5 and 30 working days.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: NHS injury costs recovery scheme: April 2024 to March 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-injury-costs-recovery-scheme-april-2024-to-march-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-injury-costs-recovery-scheme-april-2024-to-march-2025"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T07:57:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data on the funds collected by the Compensation Recovery Unit and funds paid to the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England says trusts must start using FDP within two years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201167</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/nhs-england-says-trusts-must-start-using-fdp-within-two-years/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T07:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has written to trusts asking them to confirm their plans for using the national Federated Data Platform, HSJ reports.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Preventive medicine in general practice - with Dr Adrian Hayter from the RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882967</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-preventive-medicine-general-practice-dr-adrian-hayter-rcgp/article/1882967"/>
        <updated>2024-08-02T07:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Dr Adrian Hayter, the Royal College of GPs medical director of clinical policy and a GP in Windsor, about the college’s new clinical priority - preventive medicine.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Health and Social Care Secretary visits hospital staff in Epping]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/health-and-social-care-secretary-visits-hospital-staff-in-epping</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/health-and-social-care-secretary-visits-hospital-staff-in-epping"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T16:15:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit was part of a series of planned engagements across regions in England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: workforce management information June 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-june-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-june-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T16:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reports on departmental staff numbers and costs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: workforce management information May 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-may-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-may-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T15:59:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reports on departmental staff numbers and costs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: workforce management information April 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-april-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-april-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T15:42:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reports on departmental staff numbers and costs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: workforce management information March 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-march-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-march-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T15:40:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reports on departmental staff numbers and costs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: workforce management information February 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-february-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-february-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T15:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reports on departmental staff numbers and costs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why shouldn’t this collective action be the norm?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151502</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/why-shouldnt-this-collective-action-be-the-norm/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T15:24:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Jaimie Kaffash questions the use of the term ‘collective action’ when GPs simply fulfil their contract If you are a little confused about the collective action beginning today, I don’t blame you. None of the measures breach the GP contract, and there are good reasons for this – GP partners simply can’t afford financial
The post Why shouldn’t this collective action be the norm? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wes Streeting wants to ‘reset relationship’ between GPs and the Government]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151613</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/health-secretary-says-he-wants-to-reset-relationships-between-gps-and-government/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T15:19:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The health secretary has said he wants ‘to reset the relationship between GPs and the Government’, in a letter sent to the profession today. Wes Streeting wrote to GPs today after the announcement that practices will be allowed to employ GPs as part of the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS), in the hope practices will
The post Wes Streeting wants to ‘reset relationship’ between GPs and the Government appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contract uplift and £82m ARRS plan 'first steps' to sustainable general practice, Streeting tells GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882982</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/contract-uplift-82m-arrs-plan-first-steps-sustainable-general-practice-streeting-tells-gps/article/1882982"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T14:36:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Backing a 6% pay uplift and plans to recruit 1,000 GPs by expanding the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) are 'simply the first steps' towards a more sustainable future for general practice, the health and social care secretary has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dementia commission adds high cholesterol and untreated vision loss to risk list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151597</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/dementia-commission-adds-high-cholesterol-and-untreated-vision-loss-to-risk-list/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T13:10:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[High cholesterol and untreated vision loss have been identified as new risk factors for dementia by a major new report. The Lancet’s third ‘commission’ on dementia, published yesterday, suggested that 45% of dementia cases could be prevented or delayed by tackling 14 risk factors starting in childhood.  A previous dementia commission in 2020 identified 12
The post Dementia commission adds high cholesterol and untreated vision loss to risk list appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4533 - Progress Software Releases Security Update for MOVEit Transfer]]></title>
        <id>e41703b6-10db-4154-a74f-001a22be6ece</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4533"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T13:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 An improper authentication vulnerability can lead to privilege escalation
 An improper authentication vulnerability can lead to privilege escalation
 Updated: 01 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wrightington, Wigan and Leigh FT deploys patient flow solution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200695</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/wrightington-wigan-and-leigh-ft-deploys-patient-flow-solution/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T12:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wrightington, Wigan and Leigh Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust has deployed Altera Digital Health’s patient flow solution.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why GPs are ready to press ahead with collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882949</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/why-gps-ready-press-ahead-collective-action/article/1882949"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T12:20:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are right to press ahead with collective action because plans to create GP jobs through the ARRS are only 'superficially attractive' and the 6% contract uplift is 'not enough', a Rebuild General Practice campaigner has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Maths may not stack up' on plan for 1,000 GP ARRS jobs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882951</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/maths-may-not-stack-up-plan-1000-gp-arrs-jobs/article/1882951"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T11:21:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An £82m bolt-on to the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) unveiled by the government may not deliver the 'more than 1,000' new GP jobs it claims unless recruits are paid below market rates, a specialist accountant has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Private GP provider allowed to keep APMS contracts despite ‘serious breach’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151563</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/private-gp-provider-allowed-to-keep-apms-contracts-despite-serious-breach/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T10:30:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A large private GP provider will be allowed to continue to run its nine practices in North West London despite having committed ‘a serious breach’ of its APMS contract. Earlier this year, three London ICBs announced that the successor to Operose Health had actioned an unauthorised ‘change of control’, after the HCRG Care Group – formerly
The post Private GP provider allowed to keep APMS contracts despite ‘serious breach’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200733</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-159/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T10:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Digital Health's Coffee Time Briefing includes Oxford Medical Simulation raising £9.78m to advance VR training in healthcare.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does collective action mean for GP practices?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882925</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/does-collective-action-mean-gp-practices/article/1882925"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T10:28:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPonline looks at the steps practices are being asked to take now that the profession in England has voted in favour of collective action.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS urges public to come forward for care during GP collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250354</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/nhs-urges-public-to-come-forward-for-care-during-gp-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T10:21:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS is asking the public to still come forward as usual for care during collective action by GP services which starts today (Thursday 1 August). GP services across England will begin collective action on Thursday 1 August for an indefinite period of time, and while there may be some disruption to services practices will […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CEPI and WHO urge broader research strategy for countries to prepare for the next pandemic]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:c4367ba0-fb4e-42ec-a9c9-169b93e51611</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/01-08-2024-cepi-and-who-urge-broader-research-strategy-for-countries-to-prepare-for-the-next-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T10:12:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI) and the World Health Organization (WHO) today called on researchers and governments to strengthen and accelerate global research to prepare for the next pandemic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health announces judges for Rewired Pitchfest 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200745</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-announces-judges-for-rewired-pitchfest-2025/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T10:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health has announced the judges for its annual Pitchfest competition for startups, which will take place at Rewired 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP partners vote in favour of taking collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151374</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/gp-partners-vote-in-favour-of-taking-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T09:50:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[England’s GP partners have voted in favour of taking part in collective action in protest against contractual terms and funding. The ballot, which closed on Monday (29 July), saw 98.3% of GP partners voting in favour and 1.7% voting against. In all, almost 8,500 GP partners voted – 67.7% of those eligible. The GPC has
The post GP partners vote in favour of taking collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Views of NHS website heat health advice almost triples as temperatures soar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250343</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/views-of-nhs-website-heat-health-advice-almost-triples-as-temperatures-soar/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T09:26:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visits to the heat exhaustion advice webpage on the NHS website have almost tripled in the past few days as temperatures surge in England. The UK recorded its hottest day of the year so far on Tuesday and yellow heat health alerts are in place for millions of people until Friday. Analysis by NHS England, which […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Official Statistics: Adult social care in England, monthly statistics: July 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-july-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-july-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T08:43:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Official statistics on a range of topics including occupancy and infection control measures in adult social care settings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs back collective action in landmark vote for general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882917</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-back-collective-action-landmark-vote-general-practice/article/1882917"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T08:41:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP partners have voted overwhelmingly in favour of collective action in a landmark BMA ballot that could see widespread adoption of safe working advice including capping daily appointments per GP in the coming days and weeks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult social care in England statistics: background quality and methodology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T08:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) puts together the data in its monthly reports.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Official Statistics: Adult social care in England, monthly statistics: August 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-august-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-august-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T08:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Official statistics on a range of topics including occupancy and infection control measures in adult social care settings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practices to be able to hire GPs under ARRS this year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151540</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/practices-to-be-able-to-hire-gps-under-arrs-this-year/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T08:08:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has added GPs to the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS), in the hope practices will be able to hire 1,000 more doctors this year. More to follow
The post Practices to be able to hire GPs under ARRS this year appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital tech is key to ‘neighbourhood health’, says The King’s Fund]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200667</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-tech-is-key-to-neighbourhood-health-says-the-kings-fund/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T07:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital technology is key to delivering the new government’s ambition of moving care closer to home, says a report from The King’s Fund.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government plans 1,000 more GP jobs this year with £82m ARRS expansion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882875</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/government-plans-1000-gp-jobs-year-82m-arrs-expansion/article/1882875"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 1,000 GP jobs will be created in 2024/25 through an £82m expansion of the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS), the government has said, in an emergency intervention to tackle the 'absurd' GP unemployment crisis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government to create 1,000 GP jobs this year with £82m ARRS expansion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882875</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/government-create-1000-gp-jobs-year-82m-arrs-expansion/article/1882875"/>
        <updated>2024-08-01T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 1,000 GP jobs will be created in 2024/25 through an £82m expansion of the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS), after the government announced an emergency intervention to tackle the 'absurd' GP unemployment crisis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First targeted treatment made available for hundreds of blood cancer patients on the NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250292</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/first-targeted-treatment-made-available-for-hundreds-of-blood-cancer-patients-on-the-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T23:01:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A take-at-home tablet which could be a ‘game-changer’ for hundreds of blood cancer patients is now available on the NHS in England. Patients in England with a form of blood cancer known as marginal zone lymphoma (MZL) can now be offered an additional treatment option which could halt the progression of their cancer and provide […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Over 1,000 more GPs to be recruited this year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/over-1000-more-gps-to-be-recruited-this-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/over-1000-more-gps-to-be-recruited-this-year"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T23:01:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government will recruit more than 1,000 newly qualified GPs thanks to action to remove red tape.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On World Breastfeeding Week, UNICEF and WHO call for equal access to breastfeeding support]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:3c642595-6151-42fc-b3bb-d7e9a7f6f14d</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/31-07-2024-on-world-breastfeeding-week--unicef-and-who-call-for-equal-access-to-breastfeeding-support"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T22:57:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the last 12 years, the number of infants under six months of age globally who are exclusively breastfed has increased by more than 10%. This means 48% of infants worldwide now benefit from this healthy start in life. It translates to hundreds of thousands of babies whose lives have been saved by breastfeeding.

While this significant leap brings us closer to the World Health Organization target of increasing exclusive breastfeeding to at least 50% by 2025, there are persistent challenges that must be addressed.

When mothers receive the support they need to breastfeed their babies, everyone benefits. Improving breastfeeding rates could save over 820 000 children’s lives each year, according to the latest available data. 
During this critical period of early growth and development, the a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA urges pause on implementation of Cass transgender child treatment advice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151526</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/bma-urges-pause-on-implementation-of-cass-transgender-child-treatment-advice/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T16:13:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has called for a pause to the implementation of the Cass review’s recommendations on treatment of transgender children. The doctors’ union intends to undertake its own evaluation of the the independent report following ‘concerns’ voiced by doctors and academics, which it expects to complete towards the end of the year. ‘In the meantime, the
The post BMA urges pause on implementation of Cass transgender child treatment advice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New death certification guidance hails ‘improved accuracy’ ahead of statutory launch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151491</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/new-death-certification-guidance-hails-improved-accuracy-ahead-of-statutory-launch/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T15:30:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new system requiring GPs to agree death certificates with a medical examiner has already ‘improved accuracy’ of recorded causes of death, ahead of its statutory implementation, NHS England has claimed. The process has been ‘supporting bereaved people and providing the public with greater safeguards’ through ‘consistent scrutiny’ of non-coronial deaths, the commissioner added in new guidance
The post New death certification guidance hails ‘improved accuracy’ ahead of statutory launch appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open consultation: Healthy Start eligibility for families who cannot access public funds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/healthy-start-eligibility-for-families-who-cannot-access-public-funds</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/healthy-start-eligibility-for-families-who-cannot-access-public-funds"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T14:02:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seeks views on whether eligibility for Healthy Start should be extended to include others who are prevented from accessing public funds due to immigration controls.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First, do some harm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151479</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/first-do-some-harm/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T14:02:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Copperfield considers the impact of industrial action on patients I’m writing this just before the result of the ballot on industrial action. And I’m going out on a limb here, but I reckon GPs will be in favour. There’s one thing I’m less clear on, though. Why, as D-day approaches, does the message to
The post First, do some harm appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Healthy Start extension: application guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/healthy-start-extension-application-guidance</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/healthy-start-extension-application-guidance"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T13:58:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out who is eligible to apply for the Healthy Start scheme under the extended criteria, and how to apply.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vine robots could transform cancer treatment, shows Leeds study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200757</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/vine-robots-could-transform-cancer-treatment-shows-leeds-study/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T12:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New robots that mimic creeping vine plants could transform cancer diagnosis and treatment, according to a study by University of Leeds.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Majority of NHS staff support use of AI, finds the Health Foundation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200701</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/majority-of-nhs-staff-support-use-of-ai-finds-the-health-foundation/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T12:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than three quarters of NHS staff (76%) support the use of AI to help with patient care, according to research by the Health Foundation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: Voluntary scheme aggregate net sales and payment information: May 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/voluntary-scheme-aggregate-net-sales-and-payment-information-may-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/voluntary-scheme-aggregate-net-sales-and-payment-information-may-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T12:12:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information on how the 2024 voluntary scheme for branded medicines pricing, access and growth (VPAG) is controlling spend on branded medicines in the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices incorporated in NHSE’s OPEL framework in one area]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151304</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/gp-practices-incorporated-in-nhses-opel-framework-in-one-area/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T11:08:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cornish GP practices have now been included in NHS England’s OPEL framework, in a move that the local LMC hopes will ‘raise the profile’ of pressures in general practice. Last year, Pulse revealed exclusively that NHS England is currently working towards incorporating general practice in the system used by hospitals to report when they are under pressure.
The post GP practices incorporated in NHSE’s OPEL framework in one area appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flo Health secures $200m investment to reach $1bn valuation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200841</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/flo-health-secures-200m-investment-to-reach-1bn-valuation/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T10:35:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flo Health, the number one downloaded women’s health app worldwide, has raised over $200 million in an investment from General Atlantic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['No guarantee' GP contract uplift will deliver promised 6%, accountants warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882739</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/no-guarantee-gp-contract-uplift-will-deliver-promised-6-accountants-warn/article/1882739"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are by no means guaranteed to see the 6% uplift promised by the government reflected in their pay packets, financial experts have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice closes following ‘bankruptcy order’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151440</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-practice-closes-following-bankruptcy-order/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T08:58:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP practice caring for 4,000 patients in the West Midlands has closed down following a bankruptcy order. Hawes Lane Surgery in Rowley Regis closed suddenly on Thursday last week. Pulse was told that ‘a bankruptcy order was made’ against the surgery and that Black Country ICB was informed that actions were taken to annul
The post GP practice closes following ‘bankruptcy order’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Child death overview panels: contacts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T08:31:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Contact details of the people in child death overview panels (CDOPs) who are responsible for receiving child death notifications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adoption of FDP ‘progressing at pace’, says NHS England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200691</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/adoption-of-fdp-progressing-at-pace-says-nhs-england/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T07:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adoption of the federated data platform (FDP) is “progressing at pace”, according to an announcement from NHS England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[India commits US$ 85 million to WHO Global Traditional Medicine Centre]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:432a1617-e2c5-4041-8b77-46838ced7106</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/31-07-2024-india-commits-usd-85-million-to-who-global-traditional-medicine-centre"/>
        <updated>2024-07-31T05:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WHO-India donor agreement is part of a US$ 250 million investment from India in support of the establishment of the WHO Global Centre of Traditional Medicine in 2022, which includes financial support for the workplan of the Centre, interim premises and a new building. This support will scale up WHO’s capacities on traditional medicine across technical divisions and regions in the spirit of global collaboration and solidarity. Part of this substantial contribution from the Government of India will also be included in WHO’s Investment Round to resource WHO’s core work during 2025–2028.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO and United Arab Emirates evacuate 85 patients from Gaza]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:9f0a5b6f-5160-48c2-958e-0ae6b8d1e0c6</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/30-07-2024-who-and-united-arab-emirates-evacuate-85-patients-from-gaza"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T17:38:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, 85 sick and severely injured patients from Gaza were evacuated to Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates (UAE), for specialized care. This extremely complex joint evacuation was supported by the the World Health Organization (WHO) in partnership with the Government of the UAE and other partners. This is the largest medical evacuation outside Gaza since October 2023.

“I am immensely grateful to the United Arab Emirates for evacuating sick and severely injured patients from Gaza and providing them with lifesaving medical care,” said Dr Hanan Balkhy, WHO Regional Director for the Eastern Mediterranean. “This initiative is a clear demonstration of the intra-regional solidarity that is urgently needed. Support to people in the Region must start from the Region. Thousands more inside Gaza remai…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devolved governments still to confirm 6% DDRB pay uplift for GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151453</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/devolved-governments-still-to-confirm-6-ddrb-pay-uplift-for-gps/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T16:17:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland are yet to receive confirmation from their respective governments on whether the 6% pay uplift recommended by the DDRB will be funded.  The Review Body on Doctors’ and Dentists’ Remuneration (DDRB) report, published yesterday, recommended a 6% pay increase for GPs in all of the four nations, and
The post Devolved governments still to confirm 6% DDRB pay uplift for GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GMC reminds doctors taking part in protests to 'follow the law']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882736</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gmc-reminds-doctors-taking-part-protests-follow-law/article/1882736"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T15:59:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GMC has warned doctors taking part in protests or activism of their duty to 'follow the law', in updated guidance that sets out how the regulator will approach cases where doctors receive a criminal conviction.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big questions: The impact of industrial action and Wes Streeting’s first few weeks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151446</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/big-questions/big-questions-the-impact-of-industrial-action-and-wes-streetings-first-few-weeks/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T15:03:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse summarises July’s talking points – what will the BMA ballot change, and what has the new health secretary done in his first month How will the BMA ballot change the landscape of general practice? Limbo. Purgatory. Inbetween. Precipice. Call it what you want, but we’re in it right now. The GPCE ballot on collective
The post Big questions: The impact of industrial action and Wes Streeting’s first few weeks appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UKHSA wants to increase hepatitis B awareness among GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151442</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/ukhsa-wants-to-increase-hepatitis-b-awareness-among-gps/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T14:35:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) is looking to increase awareness of hepatitis B among GPs and other healthcare professionals.  In a new report summarising England’s progress towards the World Health Organisation (WHO) elimination target for hepatitis B, UKHSA highlighted that over 50% of people living with the disease remain undiagnosed.  The data, which runs
The post UKHSA wants to increase hepatitis B awareness among GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Private provider keeps NHS GP services despite 'serious breach' of contracts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882628</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/private-provider-keeps-nhs-gp-services-despite-serious-breach-contracts/article/1882628"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A major private provider of NHS GP services will not have its practice contracts terminated despite a 'serious breach' of their terms, an ICB has confirmed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hypertension remote monitoring scheme reaches 100,000 patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200639</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/hypertension-remote-monitoring-scheme-reaches-100000-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T12:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 100,000 patients have used the ConnectMe remote monitoring scheme for hypertension management in Scotland, which launched in 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>DHI News Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200251</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-158/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T10:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This Coffee Time Briefing features NHS Humber Health Partnership launching a transformation project to reduce hospital stays and admissions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[North Cumbria Integrated Care NHS FT to roll out EPR in 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200597</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/north-cumbria-integrated-care-nhs-ft-to-roll-out-epr-in-2025/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T10:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[North Cumbria Integrated Care NHS Foundation Trust has announced that it plans to roll out an electronic patient record system in early 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>DHI News Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-sampling HPV kits could increase cervical screening uptake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151037</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/self-sampling-hpv-kits-could-increase-cervical-screening-uptake/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T09:54:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Offering self-test kits for cervical screening to be used in GP surgeries or at home could dramatically increase take up, NHS research has shown. The YouScreen trial which gave self-sampling kits to test for HPV to participants who were least six months overdue for their cervical screening found it could be an effective way to
The post Self-sampling HPV kits could increase cervical screening uptake appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the Month: What is wrong with this elderly woman with back pain?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151394</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/case-of-the-month-what-is-wrong-with-this-elderly-woman-with-back-pain/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T09:40:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest of our monthly series, Dr Henna Taimoor is asking readers to suggest what is the cause of this elderly woman’s  back pain, fever and right flank pain symptoms. Put your answers in the comments. Answers to be revealed on 13 August! This 73-year-old Asian female patient presents to you for the first
The post Case of the Month: What is wrong with this elderly woman with back pain? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thirty-seventh report 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/thirty-seventh-report-2024.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/thirty-seventh-report-2024.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T09:32:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Pay Review Body (NHSPRB) - This report sets out the NHSPRB’s analysis of evidence provided by relevant organisations and makes observations on the pay of NHS staff paid under Agenda for Change for 2024. Report More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fifty-second report 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/fifty-second-report-2024.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/fifty-second-report-2024.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T09:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Review Body on Doctors’ and Dentists’ Remuneration (DDRB) - This report sets out the DDRB’s recommendations for doctors’ and dentists’ pay in England, Scotland, Wales, and Northern Ireland. The DDRB provides independent advice on the pay of doctors and dentists in the NHS and HSC. Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forty-sixth annual report on senior salaries 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/forty-sixth-annual-report-on-senior-salaries-2024.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/forty-sixth-annual-report-on-senior-salaries-2024.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T09:09:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Review Body on Senior Salaries - This report sets out the SSRB’s analysis of evidence and makes recommendations on the remuneration of senior civil servants, senior officers in the armed forces, members of the judiciary, senior leaders in the NHS in England and chief police officers in England, Wales and Northern Ireland. Report More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DDRB’s 6% pay uplift recommendation for GP partners ‘not enough’, says GPC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151420</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/ddrb-recommends-6-pay-uplift-to-gp-partners-and-all-practice-staff/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T09:04:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The doctors’ pay review body has recommended a 6% uplift for all GPs, including both salaried and partners, and practice staff – but this is ‘not enough to address the erosion’ of general practice funding, the BMA’s GP committee has said. Yesterday, chancellor Rachel Reeves confirmed that the Government has accepted ‘in full’ the recommendations
The post DDRB’s 6% pay uplift recommendation for GP partners ‘not enough’, says GPC appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health at the heart of government: rebuilding the nation’s health through mission-driven government]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/health-at-the-heart-of-government-rebuilding-the-nations-health-through-mission-driven-government-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/health-at-the-heart-of-government-rebuilding-the-nations-health-through-mission-driven-government-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T08:48:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health Foundation - This briefing sets out practical and achievable solutions for rebuilding the health of the UK through mission-driven government. It is informed by our in-depth analysis on how government should operate and by insights and expertise from our expert panel. Briefing More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carer’s Allowance overpayments]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/carers-allowance-overpayments-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/carers-allowance-overpayments-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T08:36:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Carers UK - This report which brings together the experiences of 138 unpaid carers who have had a Carer’s Allowance overpayment. The report calls for swift action to prevent unpaid carers unwittingly building up huge debts after going over the earnings limit, which is causing financial hardship, anxiety and ill-health for unpaid carers. Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poor IT systems factored in CQC failings, says DHSC report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200599</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/poor-it-systems-a-factor-in-cqc-failings-says-dhsc-report/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T07:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Significant challenges with IT systems, most notably the provider portal, have contributed to failings at CQC, says DHSC report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs 'deeply disappointed' as government backs 6% uplift for general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882596</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-deeply-disappointed-government-backs-6-uplift-general-practice/article/1882596"/>
        <updated>2024-07-30T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government has backed a 6% overall uplift to GP contract funding for 2024/25 that doctors' leaders warn will leave GPs 'deeply disappointed' and will fail to stop practice closures.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Independent report: Review Body on Doctors’ and Dentists’ Remuneration 52nd Report: 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/review-body-on-doctors-and-dentists-remuneration-52nd-report-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/review-body-on-doctors-and-dentists-remuneration-52nd-report-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T17:48:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recommendations and observations from the Review Body on Doctors’ and Dentists’ Remuneration on doctors’ and dentists’ pay in England, Scotland, Wales, and Northern Ireland.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Independent report: Senior Salaries Review Body Report: 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/senior-salaries-review-body-report-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/senior-salaries-review-body-report-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T17:48:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recommendations from the Senior Salaries Review Body on the remuneration of senior staff in the public sector.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Fresh offer paves way to end junior doctor strikes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/fresh-offer-paves-way-to-end-junior-doctor-strikes</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/fresh-offer-paves-way-to-end-junior-doctor-strikes"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T16:51:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA will recommend members accept the offer following the negotiations, which could bring an end to 15 months of devastating strike action]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors offered 22.3% pay rise to end strike action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151391</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/junior-doctors-offered-22-3-pay-rise-to-end-strike-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T15:59:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA’s junior doctors committee will put a new Government offer to members which would increase pay by 22.3% over two years. Today, the union confirmed that following negotiations the new offer includes a backdated pay rise of 4.05% for 2023/24, which is on top of the existing increase of between 8.8% and 10.3%. For
The post Junior doctors offered 22.3% pay rise to end strike action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors offered 22.3% pay deal over two years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882576</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/junior-doctors-offered-223-pay-deal-two-years/article/1882576"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T15:43:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA is recommending junior doctors accept a new offer that would see them receive an average 22.3% pay increase over two years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4532 - Exploitation of Vulnerability CVE-2023-45249 in Acronis Cyber Infrastructure]]></title>
        <id>691596e6-69d2-4487-9224-8fe33b2a3c2a</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4532"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T15:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Critical vulnerability in Acronis Cyber Infrastructure (ACI) could be exploited to achieve remote code execution
 Critical vulnerability in Acronis Cyber Infrastructure (ACI) could be exploited to achieve remote code execution
 Updated: 29 Jul 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DDRB ‘recommends 6% pay rise’ for salaried GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151397</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/ddrb-recommends-6-pay-rise-for-salaried-gps/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T14:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The doctors’ pay review body has recommended a 6% pay uplift for salaried GPs this year, according to the BMA’s sessional GP committee chair. Chancellor Rachel Reeves is expected to address public sector pay uplifts in her statement to the House of Commons this afternoon. Ahead of this, BMA sessional GP committee chair Dr Mark
The post DDRB ‘recommends 6% pay rise’ for salaried GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4531 - Broadcom Releases Security Updates for VMware ESXi, vCenter Server, and Cloud Foundation Vulnerabilities]]></title>
        <id>11e7fe94-a89c-48b9-8e67-02ed2b67f4a9</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4531"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T14:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisory addresses three security vulnerabilities that could result in denial-of-service or authentication bypass
 Advisory addresses three security vulnerabilities that could result in DoS or authentication bypass
 Updated: 29 Jul 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn the lesson from vets: we cannot replace GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150700</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/katie-musgrave/learn-the-lesson-from-vets-we-cannot-replace-gps/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T14:01:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Katie Musgrave compares the veterinary system to general practice to reflect on the systematic replacement of GPs My best friend from primary school was the daughter of a vet. I loved visiting her house: she had a tank of terrapins in her bedroom; her family kept chickens; and they had multiple dogs and cats.
The post Learn the lesson from vets: we cannot replace GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: NHS cost recovery - overseas visitors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-cost-recovery-overseas-visitors</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-cost-recovery-overseas-visitors"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T13:38:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information for NHS bodies who need to make and recover hospital charges from overseas visitors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tavistock and Portman launches PEP in gender identity clinic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200287</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/tavistock-and-portman-to-launch-pep-for-gender-identity-clinic/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T12:30:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tavistock and Portman NHS Foundation Trust has announced the roll out of a patient engagement platform in its gender identity clinic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National training survey: 2024 results]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/national-training-survey-2024-results.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/national-training-survey-2024-results.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T12:16:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General Medical Council - The results of the GMC's national training survey, the largest annual insight into the training of doctors in the UK, show half of doctors whose roles include training junior colleagues are at high or moderate risk of burnout. The report warns that plans to boost the UK’s workforce by increasing medical school places will fail if...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Social work bursary information packs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/reforming-social-work-bursary-information-packs</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/reforming-social-work-bursary-information-packs"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T12:06:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information for higher education institutions (HEIs) and students on social work bursary arrangements.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patient harm linked to GP tech is ‘underreported’, says report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200547</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/patient-harm-linked-to-gp-tech-has-been-underreported-says-report/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T11:06:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patient safety incidents relating to the use of GP online consultation tools have been underreported, according to an HSSIB investigation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government urged to fund respiratory testing in GP practices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151310</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/government-urged-to-fund-respiratory-testing-in-gp-practices/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T10:56:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government should provide long-term funding for GP practices to offer testing for lung conditions, including spirometry and fractional exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO), a charity has said. Asthma+Lung UK also wants to see national diagnosis targets for lung conditions and for waiting lists to be halved by 2028.   It comes after a survey of 12,000
The post Government urged to fund respiratory testing in GP practices appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS leaders warn of ‘catastrophic’ impact of GP collective action on A&E as ballot closes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151379</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/nhs-leaders-warn-of-catastrophic-impact-of-gp-collective-action-on-ae-as-ballot-closes/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T10:54:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP collective action could have a ‘catastrophic’ impact on A&E and other services, NHS leaders have warned ahead of the ballot closing today.  The action, coordinated by the BMA’s GP committee, is expected to start on Thursday (1 August), depending on the results of a non-statutory ballot of GP partners closing today at midday.  As revealed by
The post NHS leaders warn of ‘catastrophic’ impact of GP collective action on A&E as ballot closes appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CQC inconsistency can give poorer practices better ratings than top performers, review warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882500</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/cqc-inconsistency-give-poorer-practices-better-ratings-top-performers-review-warns/article/1882500"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T10:43:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ratings awarded to GP practices by the CQC are inconsistent because the watchdog has failed to define clearly what good or outstanding care looks like - with providers warning that 'poorer quality' practices can receive better ratings than top-performing ones, a report commissioned by the government shows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP who burst into tears at work 'gobsmacked' by Wes Streeting response]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1882478</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-burst-tears-work-gobsmacked-wes-streeting-response/article/1882478"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T10:39:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who posted on social media about bursting into tears at work says he was 'gobsmacked' to receive a direct message of support from the health and social care secretary in response.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Productivity in the NHS: what’s getting in the way?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/productivity-in-the-nhs-whats-getting-in-the-way.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/productivity-in-the-nhs-whats-getting-in-the-way.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T10:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - This long read explores the many factors that may be affecting NHS productivity. It argues that reaching a consensus on the roots of the problem, working collaboratively in a psychologically safe environment, is vital if the health service is to use the resources that it has in the best possible way. Long read]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CQC ratings of GP practices ‘lack consistency’, review finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151365</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/cqc-ratings-of-gp-practices-lack-consistency-review-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T09:53:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is a ‘lack of consistency’ and transparency in CQC ratings of GP practices, a damning report has found.  An interim review into the effectiveness of the health and care regulator has highlighted serious issues with the way the CQC operates and rates providers, including low levels of inspections, a ‘lack of clinical expertise’ and
The post CQC ratings of GP practices ‘lack consistency’, review finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enabling integrated care systems to work better]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/enabling-integrated-care-systems-to-work-better-1.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/enabling-integrated-care-systems-to-work-better-1.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T09:40:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Government - One of NHS England's roles is to take some of the management of the NHS out of the Department of Health and Social Care. Since 2022 it has done this with the help of integrated care systems (ICSs). However senior officials in these bodies are still complaining about various forms of micromanagement. This short paper, based...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enabling integrated care systems to work better]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/enabling-integrated-care-systems-to-work-better.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/enabling-integrated-care-systems-to-work-better.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T09:40:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Government - One of NHS England's roles is to take some of the management of the NHS out of the Department of Health and Social Care. Since 2022 it has done this with the help of integrated care systems (ICSs). However senior officials in these bodies are still complaining about various forms of micromanagement. This short paper, based...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing public services: priorities for the new Labour government]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/fixing-public-services-priorities-for-the-new-labour-government.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/fixing-public-services-priorities-for-the-new-labour-government.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T09:17:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Government - This report looks at the most pressing issues facing the new Labour government in four key public services – the NHS, local government, schools and the criminal justice system – and the common problems that cut across them. It also analyses the implications of sticking with current spending plans, and makes recommendations for how the government...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[East Kent Hospitals pilots population health platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=200459</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/east-kent-hospitals-pilots-population-health-platform/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-29T07:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[East Kent Hospitals University NHS Foundation Trust has introduced a population health platform to reduce preoperative consultation times.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Independent report: NHS Pay Review Body Thirty-Seventh Report: 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-pay-review-body-thirty-seventh-report-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-pay-review-body-thirty-seventh-report-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-07-28T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recommendations from the NHS Pay Review Body on the pay of NHS staff paid on Agenda for Change terms and conditions in England, Wales and Northern Ireland.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adolescent girls face alarming rates of intimate partner violence]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5f785e41-94ee-49a4-9d23-f2ffa12bb7b4</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/29-07-2024-adolescent-girls-face-alarming-rates-of-intimate-partner-violence"/>
        <updated>2024-07-28T16:58:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among adolescent girls who have been in a relationship, nearly a quarter (24%) – close to 19 million – will have experienced physical and/or sexual intimate partner violence by the time they turn 20 years old, as highlighted by a new analysis from the World Health Organization (WHO) published today in The Lancet Child & Adolescent Health. Almost 1 in 6 (16%) experienced such violence in the past year. 
“Intimate partner violence is starting alarmingly early for millions of young women around the world,” said Dr Pascale Allotey, Director of WHO’s Sexual and Reproductive Health and Research Department. “Given that violence during these critical formative years can cause profound and lasting harms, it needs to be taken more seriously as a public health issue – with a focus on prevention and t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New initiative launched to advance mRNA vaccine development against human avian influenza (H5N1)]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:fbba0215-c05f-4ee9-964e-bceca46a474f</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/29-07-2024-new-initiative-launched-to-advance-mrna-vaccine-development-against-human-avian-influenza-(h5n1)"/>
        <updated>2024-07-28T16:41:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new project aiming to accelerate the development and accessibility of human avian influenza (H5N1) messenger RNA (mRNA) vaccine candidates for manufacturers in low- and middle-income countries has been launched today. The Argentinian manufacturer Sinergium Biotech will lead this effort leveraging the World Health Organization (WHO) and the Medicines Patent Pool (MPP) mRNA Technology Transfer Programme.
The mRNA Technology Transfer Programme, jointly developed by WHO and MPP, was launched in July 2021 with the aim to build capacity in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) for the development and production of mRNA-based vaccines. Sinergium Biotech, a partner in the mRNA Technology Transfer Programme, has developed candidate H5N1 vaccines and aims to establish proof-of-concept in precli…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS partners with Asda to put crucial mouth cancer symptoms on toothpaste and mouthwash]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250198</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/07/nhs-partners-with-asda-to-put-crucial-mouth-cancer-symptoms-on-toothpaste-and-mouthwash/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-26T23:01:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS and Asda are teaming up to provide vital advice on millions of toothpaste tubes and mouthwash bottles encouraging people to contact their GP or dentist if they notice any potential symptoms of mouth cancer. From this month, Asda’s own brand of oral hygiene products will now feature NHS advice in over 500 Asda […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>