<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html</id>
    <title>Industry Feed</title>
    <updated>2025-01-17T20:11:43.481Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs warned against using artificial intelligence without ICB approval]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157789</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gps-warned-against-using-artificial-intelligence-without-icb-approval/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T15:49:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices in one area have been warned against using artificial intelligence (AI) without seeking approval from their ICB first. The NHS Midlands and Lancashire information governance team said they have recently been contacted by ‘numerous different GP practices’ regarding the implementation of AI technology. It published new guidance on the topic, indicating some of
The post GPs warned against using artificial intelligence without ICB approval appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bowel cancer screening expansion completes with all over-50s now eligible]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157878</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/bowel-cancer-screening-expansion-completes-with-all-over-50s-now-eligible/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T15:40:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS has moved to the final stage of its rollout of bowel cancer screening by opening up testing kits to those over the age of 50 years. It means around 850,000 additional people in England a year will be eligible for the home FITs test with kits are sent out every two years by
The post Bowel cancer screening expansion completes with all over-50s now eligible appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2025 – Time for solutions not resolutions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157900</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/margaret-ikpoh/2025-time-for-solutions-not-resolutions/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T15:31:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Margaret Ikpoh on what solutions 2025 could bring for general practice The first week back in the New Year brought with all it the usual news. The rise of winter viruses, practices bursting at the seams and overwhelmed hospital corridors. Now it seems that these winter pressures have become perennial and just keep rolling
The post 2025 – Time for solutions not resolutions appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some PCNs yet to claim any ARRS GP funding, NHS England admits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902783</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/pcns-yet-claim-arrs-gp-funding-nhs-england-admits/article/1902783"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T14:20:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has issued a last-ditch bid to boost take-up of jobs through the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) amid fears the £82m scheme will fall short of recruiting 1,000 newly-qualified GPs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital health coaching platform Numan launches AI assistant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215565</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-health-coaching-platform-numan-launches-ai-assistant/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T13:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Numan is launching an AI Health Assistant aimed at bolstering the firm’s holistic approach to weight management through health coaching.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social capital 2025: the hidden wealth of nations]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/social-capital-2025-the-hidden-wealth-of-nations.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/social-capital-2025-the-hidden-wealth-of-nations.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T12:09:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demos - Social capital refers to the networks and trust that exist between people. This report makes the case for a greater focus on social capital in policy and practice. It argues that strengthening it will improve economic and social outcomes, improve health and wellbeing and reduce crime and antisocial behaviour. Report Demos - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should use ‘clinical judgment’ on child obesity safeguarding concerns, says NICE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157870</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-should-use-clinical-judgment-on-child-obesity-safeguarding-concerns-says-nice/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T12:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should use their ‘clinical judgement’ to decide when a child’s obesity becomes a safeguarding concern because of a ‘significant threat’ to their health and wellbeing, NICE has said in updated guidelines on overweight and obesity. The committee said that guidance was needed to help healthcare professionals balance the need for person-centred care with the
The post GPs should use ‘clinical judgment’ on child obesity safeguarding concerns, says NICE appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rise in women seeking abortion using ‘natural’ smartphone cycle tracking apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157880</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/rise-in-women-seeking-abortion-using-natural-smartphone-cycle-tracking-apps/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T11:42:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A ‘significant increase’ in the proportion of women having abortions using natural methods such as period tracking apps to prevent pregnancy could relate to problems accessing contraception, researchers have said. Women could also be choosing not to use hormonal contraception opting for alternative methods instead, they said. An analysis published in BMJ Sexual & Reproductive
The post Rise in women seeking abortion using ‘natural’ smartphone cycle tracking apps appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government’s plan for 18-week NHS waiting times: is it realistic?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/governments-plan-for-18-week-nhs-waiting-times-is-it-realistic.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/governments-plan-for-18-week-nhs-waiting-times-is-it-realistic.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T11:38:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - The government’s elective reform plan pledges to meet the NHS standard that 92% of patients should wait no longer than 18 weeks for treatment by the end of the parliament. This compares with current performance of just 59%. This analysis estimates that this will require the number of people being removed from the waiting list to...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors urged to diagnose obesity based on health risk rather than BMI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157861</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/doctors-urged-to-diagnose-obesity-based-on-health-risk-rather-than-bmi/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T11:16:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An international committee of experts has urged doctors to move away from relying on BMI in diagnosing obesity to take a more personalised approach to an individual’s actual health risk. A ‘radical overhaul’ that takes into account measures of body fat is needed to avoid both under and overdiagnosis of obesity, a Lancet Commission concluded.
The post Doctors urged to diagnose obesity based on health risk rather than BMI appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Orthopaedic Hospital pilots VitVio to boost surgical safety]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215557</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/royal-orthopaedic-hospital-pilots-vitvio-to-boost-surgical-safety/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T11:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Royal Orthopaedic Hospital NHS FT has launched a pilot with VitVio to enhance the safety and efficiency of surgical procedures.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pushing all GPs into substantive roles 'totally wrong' for general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902748</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/pushing-gps-substantive-roles-totally-wrong-general-practice/article/1902748"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T10:58:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Locum GPs bring substantial benefits to general practice and any drive to push them into substantive, permanent roles would be 'totally wrong' for the profession as a whole, a leading advocate of sessional GPs has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs called to give evidence on impact of medicines shortages]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902707</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-called-give-evidence-impact-medicines-shortages/article/1902707"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T09:55:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in England have been called to give evidence on the impact of medicines shortages, factors contributing to it and potential solutions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CPD: Casebook – head and neck swellings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157889</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-areas/ear-nose-throat-ophthamology/cpd-casebook-head-and-neck-swellings/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T09:54:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this case-based module, GP with Extended Role in ENT Dr Eason Sivayoham explains how to manage four cases involving presentations of head and neck swellings. Complete the module today on Pulse365 Learning objectivesThis case-based module will guide you through assessment, diagnosis and management of four presentations of head and neck swellings, including:• How to
The post CPD: Casebook – head and neck swellings appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movers and Shakers news roundup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215831</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/movers-and-shakers-news-roundup-56/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T08:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Movers and Shakers roundup includes John Quinn, chief information officer (CIO) at NHS England, announcing his departure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: How valuing locum GPs can maximise their benefit to the NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902607</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-valuing-locum-gps-maximise-benefit-nhs/article/1902607"/>
        <updated>2025-01-17T08:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Dr Richard Fieldhouse, chair of the National Association of Sessional GPs, about how the current jobs market is affecting locum GPs and what the NHS could do to make better use of locums]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP changes exam attempts policy in light of High Court ruling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157698</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/education-and-training/rcgp-changes-exam-attempts-policy-in-light-of-high-court-ruling/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T17:10:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP has changed its exam regulations in light of a High Court ruling last year which found its ‘attempts’ policy to be ‘unlawful’. Last month, the college said it has ‘formulated a new policy on examination attempts’ which now means it can ‘void’ previous attempts for candidates who receive a ‘late disability diagnosis’. The
The post RCGP changes exam attempts policy in light of High Court ruling appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP flu consultations up in past week but spread may have reached its peak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157875</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/gp-flu-consultations-up-in-past-week-but-spread-may-have-reached-its-peak/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T16:57:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP flu consultation rates increased once more in the past week but officials think spread of the infection may have reached a peak. Surveillance data shows a consultation rate of 23.1 per 100,000 in the week up to the 12 January compared with 20.6 per 100,000 the week before. But the UK Health Security Agency
The post GP flu consultations up in past week but spread may have reached its peak appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC register of board members' interests, 2024 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-register-of-board-members-interests-2024-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-register-of-board-members-interests-2024-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T16:39:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A register of the private interests declared by DHSC board members.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dilemmas in HRT: Getting the basics right]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157802</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/dilemmas-in-hrt-getting-the-basics-right/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T16:21:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the first of a three-part mini-series, Dr Toni Hazell discusses some key decisions that need to be made when a woman is started on HRT for the first time Who should start HRT, and when? HRT should be started when a woman presents with symptoms of the menopause (defined as >12 months since the
The post Dilemmas in HRT: Getting the basics right appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Annual assessment of integrated care boards 2023/24]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/annual-assessment-of-integrated-care-boards-202324.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/annual-assessment-of-integrated-care-boards-202324.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T13:51:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England - This report is a summary of the assessment of each ICB covering how effectively they have led their local NHS system and their contribution to each of the four core purposes of an integrated care system. It summarises an assessment of performance during the 2023/24 financial year and reflects NHS England’s views relating to that period only....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS trust chief exec Richard Mitchell confirmed for Rewired 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215643</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/nhs-trust-chief-exec-richard-mitchell-confirmed-for-rewired-2025/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T13:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Richard Mitchell, chief executive at University Hospitals of Leicester NHS Trust, is the latest speaker announced for Rewired 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO launches US$ 1.5 billion Health Emergency Appeal to tackle unprecedented global health crises]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:acb1ee43-7123-4ecd-af94-57be51cbd4e7</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/16-01-2025-who-launches-us-1.5-billion-health-emergency-appeal-to-tackle-unprecedented-global-health-crises"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T13:14:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conflict, climate change, epidemics, and displacement are converging to create an unparalleled global health crisis, with 305 million people in urgent need of humanitarian assistance in 2025. In response, the World Health Organization (WHO) is calling for US$ 1.5 billion for its 2025 Health Emergency Appeal (HEA), to support life-saving health interventions worldwide.
The appeal, launched today by WHO Director-General, Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, outlines the critical priorities and resources needed to address 42 ongoing health emergencies, including 17 Grade 3 crises – the most severe emergencies requiring the highest level of response. With health systems stretched to their limits and global financial resources dwindling, the US$ 1.5 billion are needed to help people facing the most d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the frontline of the UK’s corridor care crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/on-the-frontline-of-the-uks-corridor-care-crisis.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/on-the-frontline-of-the-uks-corridor-care-crisis.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T12:56:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Nursing - This report documents the experiences of more than 5,000 NHS nursing staff following a survey at the end of December 2024. Thousands of nursing staff responded, confirming corridor care is widespread across the UK. Almost 7 in 10 (66.8%) respondents to an RCN survey said they're delivering care in over-crowded or unsuitable places – such...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Legal challenge calling for GMC to set PA scope passes first High Court hurdle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157857</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/legal-challenge-calling-for-gmc-to-set-pa-scope-passes-first-high-court-hurdle/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T12:07:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A legal challenge against the GMC over its regulation of physician associates (PAs) – and specifically its refusal to set out a scope of practice – has passed its first hurdle at the High Court.  On Tuesday, a High Court judge granted Anaesthetists United (AU) ‘permission’ to proceed to a judicial review, stating that their
The post Legal challenge calling for GMC to set PA scope passes first High Court hurdle appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215689</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-35/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T11:30:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest news roundup includes new Beckman Coulter analysers for Croydon Hospital and a digital inclusion initiative for pregnant women.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Abortion: procedures for approval of independent providers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/update-to-procedures-for-the-approval-of-independent-sector-places-published</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/update-to-procedures-for-the-approval-of-independent-sector-places-published"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T11:18:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Procedures for approval of independent sector providers of treatment for termination of pregnancy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS SBS plans healthcare AI solutions framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215675</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/nhs-sbs-plans-healthcare-ai-solutions-framework/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T11:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Shared Business Services (NHS SBS) is planning the formation of a new framework agreement for AI solutions in healthcare.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CQC IT failure means 500 draft inspection reports currently ‘lost’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157851</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/cqc-it-failure-means-500-draft-inspection-reports-currently-lost/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T10:54:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[About 500 CQC reports are currently ‘stuck’ in the watchdog’s system and cannot be retrieved due to IT issues, MPs have been told. Yesterday CQC chief executive Sir Julian Hartley and chair Ian Dilks were questioned by the health and social care committee in light of the damning review into the regulator published last year. Sir Julian
The post CQC IT failure means 500 draft inspection reports currently ‘lost’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flu consultations in general practice hit highest point this winter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902560</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/flu-consultations-general-practice-hit-highest-point-winter/article/1902560"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T10:47:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flu consultations in general practice surged to a new high for the current winter season in week two of 2025, surveillance data show.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Green light for groundbreaking hearing aids]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/green-light-for-groundbreaking-hearing-aids</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/green-light-for-groundbreaking-hearing-aids"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T10:34:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fresh guidance will give businesses the green light to sell certain pioneering hearing aids]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitals ‘jampacked’ following busiest week for NHS this winter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=259141</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/01/hospitals-jampacked-following-busiest-week-for-nhs-this-winter/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T10:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week was the busiest yet for the NHS this winter, amid sky-high virus rates which have left hospitals ‘jampacked’ with patients. New data published today shows that more hospital beds were occupied last week (w/e 12 Jan) than at any point so far this winter (97,636), with 96% of adult general and acute hospital […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom W</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Official Statistics: Adult social care in England, monthly statistics: January 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-january-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-january-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T09:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Official statistics on a range of topics including occupancy and infection control measures in adult social care settings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult social care in England statistics: background quality and methodology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T09:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) puts together the data in its monthly reports.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC Government Major Projects Portfolio data, 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-government-major-projects-portfolio-data-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-government-major-projects-portfolio-data-2024"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T09:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) March 2024 Government Major Projects Portfolio data that supports the 2023-24 Infrastructure and Projects Authority (IPA) annual report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CQC says 500 inspection reports are stuck in IT platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215721</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/cqc-says-500-inspection-reports-are-stuck-in-it-platform/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T08:30:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Care Quality Commission (CQC) revealed that it has around 500 reports which are “stuck” in its IT platform and cannot be retrieved.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Policy paper: Hearing aids in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/hearing-aids-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/hearing-aids-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T08:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Policy statement setting out case studies for the sale of hearing aids in the UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of people at increased cancer risk identified by new NHS BRCA testing programme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=259113</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/01/hundreds-of-people-at-increased-cancer-risk-identified-by-new-nhs-brca-testing-programme/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-16T00:01:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of people with Jewish ancestry in England have been identified as being at increased risk of cancer and offered risk-reducing options, as part of a new NHS genetic testing programme. New data shows that over 25,000 free saliva test kits have now been requested and delivered as part of the NHS Jewish BRCA Testing […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom W</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: UK invests £5.5 million to tackle mpox in sub-Saharan Africa]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-invests-55-million-to-tackle-mpox-in-sub-saharan-africa</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-invests-55-million-to-tackle-mpox-in-sub-saharan-africa"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T17:18:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[£5.5 million to go towards vital research projects to tackle ongoing mpox outbreaks in DRC and neighbouring countries.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statement to Parliament: Health and Social Care Secretary's statement: winter 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/health-and-social-care-secretarys-statement-winter-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/health-and-social-care-secretarys-statement-winter-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T17:17:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health and Social Care Secretary made a statement to the House of Commons on winter pressures.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Repeated paracetamol use linked with severe complications in over-65s]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157640</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/repeated-paracetamol-use-linked-with-severe-complications-in-over-65s/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T16:29:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Repeated doses of paracetamol in older patients can lead to an increased risk of several severe complications, researchers have reported. An analysis of 20 years of GP data found an increased risk of gastrointestinal, cardiovascular and renal complications associated with regular use of the painkiller. The researchers from the University of Nottingham said the findings
The post Repeated paracetamol use linked with severe complications in over-65s appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Population need’ GP funding overhaul would cost just £333m, according to ICB modelling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157842</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/population-need-gp-funding-overhaul-would-cost-just-333m-according-to-icb-modelling/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T16:11:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing a new GP funding formula based on population need would cost just £333m in England, according to new modelling by two ICBs. Leicester, Leicestershire and Rutland ICB and Frimley ICB came up with new formulas to redistribute GP funding to address inequalities in the existing primary care funding model. The pilot run in Leicestershire
The post ‘Population need’ GP funding overhaul would cost just £333m, according to ICB modelling appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reform plan? No scan do]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157833</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/reform-plan-no-scan-do/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T14:33:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield considers the ‘scan-tastic’ future put forward by the Government’s elective reform plan So Sarah has gone. You know, Case Study Sarah of Streeting’s ‘elective reform plan’ who rapidly achieved iconic status for needing multiple contacts, a scan and an MDT to get a diagnosis of rhinitis? She’s been edited out – offlisted, probably for
The post Reform plan? No scan do appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robeauté raises £23m to develop rice-sized neurosurgical robots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215465</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/startup-raises-23m-to-develop-rice-sized-neurosurgical-robots/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T13:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Robeauté has raised $28m (£23m) to develop its microrobots which enter the brain to diagnose, treat and monitor neurological conditions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ADCS safeguarding pressures research – phase 9]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/adcs-safeguarding-pressures-research-phase-9.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/adcs-safeguarding-pressures-research-phase-9.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T12:02:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Association of Directors of Children’s Services - This research highlights changes in safeguarding activity which have not previously been seen, or not previously seen to this extent. One of the key themes was health challenges, from the impact of delayed access to assessment or treatment plans for parents and carers, particularly for alcohol and substance misuse, to growing concerns about...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: UK reciprocal healthcare agreements with non-EU countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/guidance/uk-reciprocal-healthcare-agreements-with-non-eu-countries</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/uk-reciprocal-healthcare-agreements-with-non-eu-countries"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T11:52:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How UK citizens or residents can get healthcare when visiting countries or territories outside the EU where the UK has reciprocal healthcare agreements.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE must urgently review potentially ‘distorting’ impact of ARRS, says report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157814</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/nhse-must-urgently-review-potentially-distorting-impact-of-arrs-says-report/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T11:43:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England should ‘urgently’ review the impact of the Additional Roles Reimbursement Scheme (ARRS) which could be ‘distorting’ staffing decisions, a new report has argued. The report, published by influential health think tank the Nuffield Trust yesterday, reviewed the expansion of ‘new’ roles such as physician associates, and called on NHSE to ‘openly’ outline governance
The post NHSE must urgently review potentially ‘distorting’ impact of ARRS, says report appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Bolton Hospital opens digital autopsy suite]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215467</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/royal-bolton-hospital-opens-digital-autopsy-suite/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T11:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Bolton Hospital is carrying out digital autopsies that reduce invasive post-mortems and release bodies back to families sooner.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CQC admits to backlog for looking into major issues of concern about NHS providers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157808</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/cqc-admits-to-backlog-for-looking-into-major-issues-of-concern-about-nhs-providers/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T10:52:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CQC has admitted to being significantly behind on reviews into major issues of concerns that have been raised about NHS providers. CQC chief executive Sir Julian Hartley was speaking in front of the health and social care committee this morning, in light of the damning review into the regulator published last year, prompting immediate
The post CQC admits to backlog for looking into major issues of concern about NHS providers appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs entitled to follow advice on PAs that could lead to redundancies, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902307</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-entitled-follow-advice-pas-lead-redundancies-says-bma/article/1902307"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T09:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices are entitled to follow advice from the BMA and RCGP on employing physician associates (PAs) and resulting restructuring of their workforce could lead to redundancies, the BMA has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Virtual rally' to tackle sessional GP unemployment crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902061</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/virtual-rally-tackle-sessional-gp-unemployment-crisis/article/1902061"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T08:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been urged to attend a ‘virtual rally’ on the sessional GP unemployment crisis and help the BMA ‘shape the direction’ of plans to address the job shortage for salaried and locum GPs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cera secures more than £123m to roll out AI-led home healthcare]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215337</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/cera-secures-more-than-123m-to-roll-out-ai-led-home-healthcare/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-15T08:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK health tech firm Cera has completed a transaction in excess of $150m (£123m) to further scale its AI-led home healthcare technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP staff quitting or considering quitting over cost of living, say practice managers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157775</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gp-staff-quitting-or-considering-quitting-over-cost-of-living-say-practice-managers/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T16:55:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Half of practice managers report that GP staff have quit their job or indicated they may need to leave their job as a result of the cost of living crisis, a survey has revealed. The survey of 540 respondents, by Pulse’s sister title Management in Practice, has highlighted the toll of financial pressures on practice
The post GP staff quitting or considering quitting over cost of living, say practice managers appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices in deprived areas should be ‘prioritised’ for funding, say researchers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157774</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-practices-in-deprived-areas-should-be-prioritised-for-funding-say-researchers/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T15:24:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices in deprived areas should be ‘prioritised for resource’ to reduce health inequalities, researchers have argued. A new study from the University of Glasgow found that supporting and resourcing ‘high-quality’ patient care in general practice ‘could be critical in efforts to reduce existing health inequalities’. The researchers said that policymakers should priorities and resource
The post GP practices in deprived areas should be ‘prioritised’ for funding, say researchers appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not your average practice: Caring for homeless populations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157624</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/not-your-average-practice/not-your-average-practice-caring-for-homeless-populations/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T15:19:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In our ‘Not your average practice’ series we speak to the GP practices with distinct patient demographics to find out how they run. The Doctor Hickey Surgery has been dedicated to treating the homeless population in Westminster for nearly 40 years. Maya Dhillon sat down with GP partner Dr Paul O’Reilly to talk about his experience of providing
The post Not your average practice: Caring for homeless populations appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mental Health Bill: House of Lords, Committee of the whole House, 14, 20, 22 and 27 January 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/mental-health-bill-house-of-lords-committee-of-the-whole-house-14-20-22-and-27-january-2025.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/mental-health-bill-house-of-lords-committee-of-the-whole-house-14-20-22-and-27-january-2025.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T13:55:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This briefing covers amendments tabled ahead of the Committee of the whole house up to and including 9 January 2025. Briefing More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Unplugged: The future of mental health technology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215201</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-health-unplugged-the-future-of-mental-health-technology/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T13:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This episode of Digital Health Unplugged features Holly Coole from the MHRA discussing the regulation of digital mental health technologies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mental health services: the NHS trust perspective]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/mental-health-services-the-nhs-trust-perspective.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/mental-health-services-the-nhs-trust-perspective.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T12:54:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This briefing provides an outline of mental health services in the NHS, the current levels of demand that NHS trusts are facing and what trusts need in order to deliver a more proactive and co-ordinated community-based model of mental health care. Briefing More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence (AI) in pharmacy]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/artificial-intelligence-ai-in-pharmacy-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/artificial-intelligence-ai-in-pharmacy-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T12:41:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Pharmaceutical Society (RPS) - This policy document outlines how artificial intelligence (AI) can be used to support pharmacy practice and improve patient care. Developed in consultation with RPS members, Expert Advisory Group members, Board members, multi-professional experts in digital technology and AI, and external stakeholders including the General Pharmaceutical Council, the policy highlights the challenges and opportunities AI presents...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roadshow report: together we can shape the future of pharmacy]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/roadshow-report-together-we-can-shape-the-future-of-pharmacy-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/roadshow-report-together-we-can-shape-the-future-of-pharmacy-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T12:36:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Pharmaceutical Society (RPS) - This report captures the conversations and questions that were a key part of 15 ‘roadshow’ events held across Great Britain in October and November to outline and discuss the RPS's proposals for change and ambition to become a Royal College. Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maintaining and retaining staff through a career coaching programme]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/maintaining-and-retaining-staff-through-a-career-coaching-programme-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/maintaining-and-retaining-staff-through-a-career-coaching-programme-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T12:26:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - Lincolnshire Integrated Care System (LICS) is made up of three local NHS trusts and a number of other health and social care partners and providers. One of its main workforce targets is to keep more employees working within the various organisations in the system and to support this aim a career coaching programme has been developed and...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215045</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-34/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T11:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest news roundup covers cleaning robots at South Tees Hospitals and a £10 million framework for data validation services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost half of children batted back to GP after CAMHS referral]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157636</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/almost-half-of-children-batted-back-to-gp-after-camhs-referral/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T10:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Children with high-level mental health needs are being left without specialist care, after almost half of referrals are rejected by NHS child and adolescent mental health services (CAMHS). In a trial set up to test a new online assessment tool within CAMHS, researchers were instead shocked to find that 44% of children and young people
The post Almost half of children batted back to GP after CAMHS referral appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sector pulse check: adult social care sector annual review]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/sector-pulse-check-adult-social-care-sector-annual-review-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/sector-pulse-check-adult-social-care-sector-annual-review-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T10:51:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Care England - This annual report, produced together with the learning disability charity Hft, analyses the financial health and workforce of adult social care, providing an important benchmark for the nature and scale of challenges facing the sector. The research highlights how the current approach to adult social care funding simply isn’t working; the sector remains in a sustained crisis....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS jabs tens of thousands more against flu than last winter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=259053</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/01/nhs-jabs-tens-of-thousands-more-against-flu-than-last-winter/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T10:44:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff have ramped up the flu vaccination campaign by jabbing almost a quarter of a million more people this winter compared to last winter. Services across the country have faced extreme pressures from one of the worst winters on record with 5,408 patients a day in hospital with flu in the first week of […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom W</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs criticise ICB for choosing to invest in hospital-based hub instead of practices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157756</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/nhs-structures/gps-criticise-icb-for-choosing-to-invest-in-hospital-based-hub-instead-of-practices/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T10:43:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An LMC has criticised plans by its local ICB to spend £315,000 a year on a new hospital-based primary care service instead of investing in local GP practices. Leicester, Leicestershire and Rutland (LLR) ICB is consulting on new proposals to implement a same-day access service – led by nurses – in a bid to ‘free
The post GPs criticise ICB for choosing to invest in hospital-based hub instead of practices appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government response to the House of Lords inquiry into preterm birth: reducing risks and improving lives]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/government-response-to-the-house-of-lords-inquiry-into-preterm-birth-reducing-risks-and-improving-li.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/government-response-to-the-house-of-lords-inquiry-into-preterm-birth-reducing-risks-and-improving-li.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T10:39:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Department of Health and Social Care - This document details the government's response to the recommendations made by the House of Lords report, Preterm birth: reducing risks and improving lives, and sets out the improvements the government is making to ensure everybody receives the care that they deserve. Paper More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Policy paper: Government response to the House of Lords inquiry into preterm birth: reducing risks and improving lives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/government-response-to-the-house-of-lords-inquiry-into-preterm-birth-reducing-risks-and-improving-lives</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/government-response-to-the-house-of-lords-inquiry-into-preterm-birth-reducing-risks-and-improving-lives"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T10:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Details the government's response to the recommendations made by the House of Lords Preterm Birth Committee report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In the balance: lessons for changing the mix of professions in NHS services]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/in-the-balance-lessons-for-changing-the-mix-of-professions-in-nhs-services.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/in-the-balance-lessons-for-changing-the-mix-of-professions-in-nhs-services.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T10:12:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - The NHS workforce has gone through shifts and rebalances of roles since the service began, driven by changing needs as much as financial constraints and staff shortages. In recent years there has been a rebalancing through expanding roles like nursing associates, advanced practitioners, physician associates and clinical pharmacists, and further growth of these roles is planned. This...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government fails to clarify stance on pharmacies delivering more routine jabs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901961</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/government-fails-clarify-stance-pharmacies-delivering-routine-jabs/article/1901961"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T09:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers have backed an expansion of the role of pharmacies in primary care but failed to clarify whether the government will allow them to deliver all routine and seasonal immunisations for adults and children alongside GP practices.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP changes exam re-sit policy for disabled GP registrars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902118</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/rcgp-changes-exam-re-sit-policy-disabled-gp-registrars/article/1902118"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T09:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Registrars who fail RCGP exams and are later diagnosed with a disability will be offered additional attempts and can have previous exam results voided after a change in college policy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government announces AI Action Plan including health data library]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215357</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/government-announces-ai-action-plan-including-health-data-library/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T08:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prime minister Keir Starmer has unveiled details of the government’s AI Opportunities Action Plan, which includes a National Data Library.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS rolls out lifesaving home testing for bowel cancer to over 50s]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=259013</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/01/nhs-rolls-out-lifesaving-home-testing-for-bowel-cancer-to-over-50s/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T00:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of thousands more people will be sent a home-testing kit that can help to detect signs of bowel cancer, as the NHS expands its lifesaving screening programme to those aged 50 in England. People aged 50 and 52 are now starting to automatically receive a home test kit every two years by post when […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs outnumbered almost 3:1 after 'stark' reshaping of workforce through ARRS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902141</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-outnumbered-almost-31-stark-reshaping-workforce-arrs/article/1902141"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T00:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are now outnumbered almost three to one by other clinical roles in general practice after a dramatic NHS-wide workforce shift that has been 'particularly stark' in GP practices, a report has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs outnumbered almost 3:1 after 'stark' reshaping of staff through ARRS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902141</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-outnumbered-almost-31-stark-reshaping-staff-arrs/article/1902141"/>
        <updated>2025-01-14T00:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are now outnumbered almost three to one by other clinical roles in general practice after a dramatic NHS-wide workforce shift that has been 'particularly stark' in GP practices, a report has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calls for GPs to offer PSA test to Black men from age of 45 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157642</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/renal-medicine-urology-mens-health/calls-for-gps-to-offer-psa-test-to-black-men-from-age-of-45-years/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T17:10:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should discuss PSA testing with Black men from the age of 45 years after figures show disproportionately high rates of late-stage prostate cancer diagnosis, a charity has said. Data from the National Prostate Cancer Audit shows that Black men have higher rates of stage 3 and 4 prostate cancer diagnoses than any other ethnic
The post Calls for GPs to offer PSA test to Black men from age of 45 years appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy: government response]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/pharmacy-government-response-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/pharmacy-government-response-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T16:38:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[House of Commons Health and Social Care Committee - In its report in May 2024, Pharmacy, the predecessor Health and Social Care Committee said that the government must urgently reform the funding framework for community pharmacy if more clinical services are to be delivered and increasing demands for medication are to be met. In this response, the government says that...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Total triage as an antidote to selfish patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157682</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/zoe-rog/total-triage-as-an-antidote-to-selfish-patients/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T15:34:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Zoe Rog on how her practice’s triage system has helped them regain a degree of control against selfish patients Although I enjoy the privilege of working closely with patients and for the most part experiencing the best of human nature, I do often find myself disappointed by the less laudable behaviour of some patients. 
The post Total triage as an antidote to selfish patients appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft confirmed as Rewired 2025 co-headline sponsor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215039</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/microsoft-confirmed-as-rewired-2025-co-headline-sponsor/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T13:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft has been confirmed as the co-headline sponsor of Digital Health Rewired 2025, the UK’s biggest and best digital health conference.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>DHI News Team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LMC special conference on GP protest ‘escalation’ to take place in March]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157748</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/lmcs-conferences/lmc-special-conference-on-gp-protest-escalation-to-take-place-in-march/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T13:18:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[England’s GP leaders will meet for a special conference in March to discuss next steps to escalate their protests following tax hikes and the recent contract offer from the Government. In November, LMC representatives declared that the Autumn Budget tax hikes will make NHS general practice unsustainable as a business model and called for a
The post LMC special conference on GP protest ‘escalation’ to take place in March appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: 2024 VPAG operational review: 25 November 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/2024-vpag-operational-review-25-november-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/2024-vpag-operational-review-25-november-2024"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T13:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minutes of a meeting held between the government, NHS England and ABPI about the 2024 voluntary scheme for branded medicines pricing, access and growth (VPAG).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA sets date for special LMC conference on stepping up industrial action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902079</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-sets-date-special-lmc-conference-stepping-industrial-action/article/1902079"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T12:08:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have set a date in March for a special conference of LMCs to debate whether general practice should step up industrial action.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of doctors received inaccurate pension savings statements for last year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157715</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/hundreds-of-doctors-received-inaccurate-pension-savings-statements-for-last-year/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T11:21:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors are being ‘failed’ by their pension scheme administrator, the BMA has warned, after hundreds received inaccurate pension savings statements.   The NHS Business Services Authority (NHSBSA) must urgently rectify ‘completely unacceptable’ errors in doctors’ pensions savings statements (PSS), and should report itself to the pensions regulator over the mistakes, according to the union. The
The post Hundreds of doctors received inaccurate pension savings statements for last year appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ageing in the fast and slow lane: examining geographic gaps in ageing]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/ageing-in-the-fast-and-slow-lane-examining-geographic-gaps-in-ageing.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/ageing-in-the-fast-and-slow-lane-examining-geographic-gaps-in-ageing.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T11:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Resolution Foundation - Like most countries, the UK is ageing – over the past five decades its median age has risen from 34 to 41. This deep demographic trend has all sorts of implications for public policy, not least the need to find greater resources to provide care for a growing elderly population. What is less well appreciated is that...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GMC worried ‘restrictive’ scopes could deter PA employment in GP practices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157718</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/gmc-worried-restrictive-scopes-could-deter-pa-employment-in-gp-practices/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T11:06:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GMC raised concerns about royal colleges ‘dissuading’ GP practices from employing physician associates (PAs) with their ‘restrictive’ scopes of practice. In response to draft RCGP’s guidance, which in its final version severely limited the tasks PAs can safely carry out, the GMC warned that it could ‘diminish the attractiveness of employing PAs in GP
The post GMC worried ‘restrictive’ scopes could deter PA employment in GP practices appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CBT-based app helps children self-manage anxiety through ‘quests’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215087</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/cbt-based-app-helps-children-self-manage-anxiety-through-quests/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T11:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A CBT-based mobile game designed to help children self-manage anxiety is now available across Herefordshire and Worcestershire.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of doctors 'let down' by inaccurate pension statements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1902040</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/hundreds-doctors-let-down-inaccurate-pension-statements/article/1902040"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T10:23:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of doctors have received inaccurate pension savings statements for 2023/24 from the NHS Business Services Authority (NHSBSA) - making it impossible for them to complete tax returns accurately by the end of this month, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complexity of modern general practice has undermined quality, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901855</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/complexity-modern-general-practice-undermined-quality-study-finds/article/1901855"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T09:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Measures introduced to support general practice – including greater use of remote consultations, digital triage and an expansion of additional roles – have had the 'unintended consequence' of compromising quality and increasing the risk of patient safety incidents, according to new research.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suppliers doubled on Digital Capability for Health framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215205</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/suppliers-doubled-on-digital-capability-for-health-framework/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-13T08:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Crown Commercial Service has included twice the number of suppliers in the latest version of its Digital Capability for Health framework.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Searches for NHS advice on childhood illnesses surge in 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258984</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/01/searches-for-nhs-advice-on-childhood-illnesses-surge-in-2024/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-11T00:01:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Online searches for NHS advice on common childhood illnesses surged in 2024, according to new figures compiled by NHS England. Five of the ten most visited health conditions on the NHS website last year mostly affect children, with three of them seeing significant increases compared to 2023. Visits to the hand, foot and mouth disease […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Future of PCNs ‘secure’ for 2025/26, NHS England tells GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157704</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/nhs-structures/future-of-pcns-secure-for-2025-26-nhs-england-tells-gps/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T15:57:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has reassured GP practices and ARRS staff that the future of PCNs is ‘secure’ for the next financial year. The commissioner clarified this during a webinar for GPs yesterday evening, after being told that some practices have had ARRS staff resigning because of ‘uncertainty’ about the future of PCNs until the new Network
The post Future of PCNs ‘secure’ for 2025/26, NHS England tells GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP handed 12-month prison sentence after climate change protest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901931</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-handed-12-month-prison-sentence-climate-change-protest/article/1901931"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T15:33:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP has received a 12-month prison sentence after damaging petrol pumps during a Just Stop Oil climate change protest.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why are GPs more prone to compassion fatigue?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157612</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/why-are-gps-more-prone-to-compassion-fatigue/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T15:22:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr John Holden, chief medical officer at MDDUS and former GP partner, explains why compassion fatigue is rife in general practice and what can be done to tackle it Exhausted. Rushing. Running late. The rinse and repeat daily routine for many GPs is not only a draining working environment – it can be a dangerous
The post Why are GPs more prone to compassion fatigue? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP workload concerns as chickenpox to become notifiable disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157687</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/gp-workload-concerns-as-chickenpox-to-become-notifiable-disease/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T15:04:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have raised concerns around an increase in workload as practices will have to report chickenpox cases to the UK Health Security Agency from April. Following a Government consultation to ensure that regulations ‘meet current surveillance needs’, eight additional infectious diseases, including chickenpox, will be added to the list of notifiable diseases once new legislation
The post GP workload concerns as chickenpox to become notifiable disease appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[£2m tech platform launched to simplify access to medical cannabis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215105</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/2m-tech-platform-launched-to-simplify-access-to-medical-cannabis/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T13:30:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Releaf has launched a £2 million proprietary tech platform to transform how patients access medical cannabis treatment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Families to receive £126 million in early years support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/families-to-receive-126-million-in-early-years-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/families-to-receive-126-million-in-early-years-support"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T11:48:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of parents and children across England will be able to give their child the best start in life thanks to a £126 million government funding boost.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government rejects call to make OTC medicines free to reduce GP pressure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157669</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/long-term-conditions-prescribing/government-rejects-call-to-make-otc-medicines-free-to-reduce-gp-pressure/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T11:27:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has rejected a call to make over-the-counter (OTC) medicines free of charge to reduce pressure on GPs.  In May last year, the previous Health and Social Care Committee recommended that OTC medication should become ‘free for people on low incomes, as part of the Pharmacy First scheme’.  The aim was to ‘avoid patients
The post Government rejects call to make OTC medicines free to reduce GP pressure appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Central patient ‘helpdesk’ and increased GP funding part of £205m ICB plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157634</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/nhs-structures/central-patient-helpdesk-and-increased-gp-funding-part-of-205m-icb-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T11:06:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Cambridgeshire and Peterborough ICB has unveiled further detail on its planned care model overhaul, including a central patiens ‘helpdesk’ and a shift of funding towards general practice. An updated draft plan said it will invest up to £205m into the radical overhaul, which will also see new neighbourhood hubs being introduced to bring together
The post Central patient ‘helpdesk’ and increased GP funding part of £205m ICB plan appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PocDoc app rolled out in West Yorkshire to screen for CVD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215051</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/pocdoc-app-to-be-rolled-out-in-west-yorkshire-to-screen-for-cvd/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T11:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PocDoc has partnered with the West Yorkshire Health and Care Partnership to roll out cardiovascular disease (CVD) health screenings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welsh government ‘deeply concerned’ over GP pay and bullying claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901722</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/welsh-government-deeply-concerned-gp-pay-bullying-claims/article/1901722"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T10:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Welsh government has said it is ‘deeply concerned’ over claims of bullying and non-payment of staff including GPs at practices linked to private provider eHarley Street, after concerns raised in the Senedd.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency preparedness, resilience and response concept of operations]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/emergency-preparedness-resilience-and-response-concept-of-operations.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/emergency-preparedness-resilience-and-response-concept-of-operations.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T10:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK Health Security Agency - This guidance sets out the UK Health Security Agency’s approach to systematically preparing for, responding to and recovering from health security incidents. These include: infectious diseases; pandemics; chemical, biological, radiological and nuclear events; extreme adverse weather events; business continuity challenges; and cyber security events. Guidance UK Health Security Agency - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: VPAS aggregate net sales and payment information: November 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/vpas-aggregate-net-sales-and-payment-information-november-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/vpas-aggregate-net-sales-and-payment-information-november-2024"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T09:30:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information on how the 2019 voluntary scheme for branded medicines pricing and access (VPAS) controlled spend on branded medicines in the NHS between 2019 and 2023.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CPD: Key questions on genetic lipid disorders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157644</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/cpd-key-questions-on-genetic-lipid-disorders/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Specialists in cardiovascular disease and lipid management Professor Ahmet Fuat, Dr Jaimini Cegla, Dr Tina Khan and Dr Mayur Patel discuss key features of familial hypercholesterolaemia (FH) and other genetic lipid disorders. To complete the full module and log 2 CPD points visit Pulse365. Learning objectives This module will enhance your understanding of genetic lipid
The post CPD: Key questions on genetic lipid disorders appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health’s monthly roundup of contracts and go lives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=215021</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-healths-monthly-roundup-of-contracts-and-go-lives-48/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T08:30:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest contracts features two Essex trusts announcing plans to deliver an Oracle Health electronic patient record (EPR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Will £889m save general practice - and how plans to cut NHS waits affect GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901687</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-will-889m-save-general-practice-plans-cut-nhs-waits-affect-gps/article/1901687"/>
        <updated>2025-01-10T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GPonline team discusses the key news stories affecting general practice including the government announcement about the GP contract for 2025/26 and the elective reform plan announced this week.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rural recruitment scheme criticised as only two new GPs hired]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157596</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/scotland/rural-recruitment-scheme-criticised-as-only-two-new-gps-hired/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T16:52:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Government scheme aimed at boosting doctor numbers in rural areas has been criticised as it resulted in only two new GPs being hired in Scotland. New figures presented to the Scottish Parliament revealed that out of 52 students who graduated from the first cohort of the Scottish Graduate Entry Medicine (ScotGEM), only 10 went
The post Rural recruitment scheme criticised as only two new GPs hired appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welsh Government ‘very concerned’ about GP company not paying locums]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157631</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/wales/welsh-government-very-concerned-about-gp-company-not-paying-locums/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T16:19:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Welsh Government is ‘very concerned’ about locums not being paid by a GP-led company, following complaints from politicians.  Last month, Pulse reported on several locum GPs who said they were owed thousands of pounds from eHarley Street, an England-based company which is owned by two GP partners and which helps to run nine practices
The post Welsh Government ‘very concerned’ about GP company not paying locums appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Supplementary information for pharmaceutical wholesalers on the Windsor Framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/supplementary-information-for-pharmaceutical-wholesalers-on-the-windsor-framework</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/supplementary-information-for-pharmaceutical-wholesalers-on-the-windsor-framework"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T15:48:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information for pharmaceutical wholesalers explaining the main changes the Windsor Framework introduces to the packaging for all medicines licensed in the UK, effective from 1 January 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Supplementary information for pharmacists and medicines procurers on the Windsor Framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/supplementary-information-for-pharmacists-and-medicines-procurers-on-the-windsor-framework</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/supplementary-information-for-pharmacists-and-medicines-procurers-on-the-windsor-framework"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T15:48:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information for pharmaceutical wholesalers explaining the main changes the Windsor Framework introduces to the packaging for all medicines licensed in the UK, effective from 1 January 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In charts: How is winter pressure affecting GP practices?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901783</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/charts-winter-pressure-affecting-gp-practices/infections-and-infestations/influenza/article/1901783"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T15:21:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A surge in flu cases this winter has piled extra pressure onto GP services already delivering record numbers of appointments. Explore the charts below to find out what RCGP surveillance data show about demand in general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How is winter pressure affecting GP practices?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901783</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/winter-pressure-affecting-gp-practices/infections-and-infestations/influenza/article/1901783"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T15:21:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A surge in flu cases this winter has piled extra pressure onto GP services already delivering record numbers of appointments. Explore the charts below to find out what RCGP surveillance data show about demand in general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once in a lifetime: Acromegaly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=153191</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/diabetes-endocrinology/once-in-a-lifetime-acromegaly/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T14:50:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Endocrinology specialist Dr Preethi Dissanayake discusses this uncommon presentation, in the latest in our series on conditions that GPs may only encounter once in their career What is it? Acromegaly is a rare pituitary endocrine disorder, characterized by excess Growth Hormone (GH) secretion and consequently, excess Insulin-like Growth Factor (IGF)-1 output from the liver. The prolonged
The post Once in a lifetime: Acromegaly appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health reveals full programme for Rewired 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214947</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-health-reveals-full-programme-for-rewired-2025/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T14:10:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The highly anticipated programme for Digital Health Rewired 2025, which takes place at NEC Birmingham on 18-19 March, has been published.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultation outcome: Changes to rules - the Care Quality Commission (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-rules-the-care-quality-commission-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-rules-the-care-quality-commission-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T13:37:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This consultation is about 3 changes we want to make to rules that the Care Quality Commission will check (CQC for short).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spike in flu driving extremely busy winter for GPs as NHS faces 'national emergency']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901718</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/spike-flu-driving-extremely-busy-winter-gps-nhs-faces-national-emergency/article/1901718"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T12:08:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice is facing an 'extremely busy winter' with consultations for flu-like illness well above the seasonal average, as doctors' leaders warned of a 'national emergency' for the NHS as a whole.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health secretary grilled on further GP redundancy claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157617</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/health-secretary-grilled-on-further-gp-redundancy-claims/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T11:58:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The health secretary has said he is ‘determined to fix’ general practice in response to concerns about GP practice redundancies.  A caller to Shelagh Fogarty‘s LBC radio show on Tuesday, who said she was a practice nurse from Leatherhead in Surrey, told Wes Streeting that she and ‘multiple GPs’ as well as ‘four receptionists’ had
The post Health secretary grilled on further GP redundancy claims appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214927</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-33/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T11:58:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's news roundup covers funding for an integrated housing and care technology project and research into using AI to help IVF success.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs can reject requests for input on private weight-loss jab prescriptions, say LMCs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157158</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-can-reject-requests-for-input-on-private-weight-loss-jab-prescriptions-say-lmcs/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T11:10:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders across the country are advising practices to push back on private providers requesting input for weight-loss jab prescriptions.  Advice from LMCs in Cornwall, Essex and Derbyshire revealed that GP practices are dealing with a rising number of requests from private providers seeking patient information to inform their prescribing of weight-loss medication such as
The post GPs can reject requests for input on private weight-loss jab prescriptions, say LMCs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deciphex raises £26m to expand pathology access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214829</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/deciphex-raises-26m-to-expand-pathology-access/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T11:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pathology software and services company Deciphex has closed its Series C financing, raising $32.3m to expand access to high-quality pathology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: DHSC public appointments: 2024 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-public-appointments-2024-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-public-appointments-2024-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T11:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Non-executive appointments to the Department of Health and Social Care's public bodies and committees from October 2024 to March 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Busiest year on record for emergency services as winter flu pressure rages on]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258867</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/01/busiest-year-on-record-for-emergency-services-as-winter-flu-pressure-rages-on/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T09:49:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff experienced the busiest year on record for A&E and ambulance services last year, new figures show today, as flu continues to pile pressure on hospitals into 2025. There was an average of 5,407 patients a day in hospital with flu last week, including 256 in critical care – 3.5 times higher than the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom W</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices face rising workload and complaints over weight loss jabs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901644</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-face-rising-workload-complaints-weight-loss-jabs/article/1901644"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T09:15:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and practice teams are facing extra workload and a rise in complaints from patients denied weight loss drugs on the NHS that they have previously obtained privately, the Institute of General Practice Managers (IGPM) has revealed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could drop collective action on advice and guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901645</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-drop-collective-action-advice-guidance/article/1901645"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T08:56:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could stop collective action on advice and guidance if it is fairly resourced under the 2025/26 contract, the BMA England GP committee chair has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online hub launched to help patients understand Lynch Syndrome]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214843</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/online-hub-launched-to-help-patients-understand-lynch-syndrome/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-09T08:30:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Airedale and Bradford hospitals have teamed together to create and launch a digital resource for patients on diagnosing Lynch Syndrome.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is £20 for A&G a good deal?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157601</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/is-20-for-ag-a-good-deal/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T16:15:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse editor Sofia Lind on the Government remunerating GPs £20 for A&G as part of its ‘elective reform plan’ It looks as though GPs across England will begin to be remunerated for the controversial practice of advice and guidance (A&G). This seems, on the face of it, like good news. Details of the offer are, as
The post Is £20 for A&G a good deal? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA may stand down A&G collective action if GPs ‘paid fairly’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157594</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/referrals/bma-may-stand-down-ag-collective-action-if-gps-paid-fairly/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T16:10:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA’s current advice for GPs to stop advice and guidance (A&G) may be ‘dropped’ from its collective action options following the announcement of a £20 per request payment. In a message to GPs, GP Committee England chair Dr Katie Bramall-Stainer said that resourcing for A&G is ‘a positive step’ and is the ‘first example’
The post BMA may stand down A&G collective action if GPs ‘paid fairly’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs affected by unemployment urged to attend BMA rally]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157564</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gps-affected-by-unemployment-urged-to-attend-bma-rally/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T14:58:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs affected by unemployment or underemployment have been urged to attend a ‘virtual rally’ organised by the BMA to look into the issue. BMA representatives will hear ‘first-hand experiences’ from sessional GPs who have struggled to find work, at an online event on 12 February. It comes after a BMA survey last year found that
The post GPs affected by unemployment urged to attend BMA rally appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practice staff and 'multiple GPs' made redundant, Wes Streeting told]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901577</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/practice-staff-multiple-gps-made-redundant-wes-streeting-told/article/1901577"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T14:04:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A practice nurse confronted health and social care secretary Wes Streeting over redundancies in general practice this week during a radio phone-in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI trial to enhance the precision of radiotherapy for prostate cancer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214811</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/ai-trial-to-enhance-the-precision-of-radiotherapy-for-prostate-cancer/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T13:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers at The Clatterbridge Cancer Centre NHS Foundation Trust are using AI to enhance the precision of radiotherapy for prostate cancer.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO prequalifies diagnostic test to support safer administration of P. vivax malaria treatments]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:d0fab7da-0ea3-44a2-8d8c-0e994d9db812</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/08-01-2025-who-prequalifies-diagnostic-test-to-support-safer-administration-of-p.-vivax-malaria-treatments"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T11:56:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 18 December 2024, the World Health Organization (WHO) prequalified the first diagnostic test for glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency which can help to safely deliver WHO-recommended treatments to prevent relapse of Plasmodium vivax (P. vivax) infection.
The prequalification of this G6PD diagnostic test marks a significant milestone in facilitating safe and effective P. vivax malaria treatment, reaffirming WHO’s dedication to ensuring equitable access to life-saving health solutions globally. Some 500 000 people die each year from malaria, most of them children.
The prequalification of this test immediately followed the prequalification, in early December, of two new tafenoquine products for anti-relapse treatment of P. vivax malaria, and these therapeutics were recommend…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A portrait of modern Britain: health - the public's priorities for the NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/a-portrait-of-modern-britain-health-the-publics-priorities-for-the-nhs.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/a-portrait-of-modern-britain-health-the-publics-priorities-for-the-nhs.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T11:44:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Policy Exchange - This report – based on polling of 2,000 representative Britons in 2024 – examines the perceptions of and priorities the British public have for the NHS. It found that the NHS providing services free at point of use was less of a priority to the public than ensuring access to a GP and treating major conditions. It...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sheffield Children’s implements ePMA in paediatric critical care unit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214603</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/sheffield-childrens-implements-epma-in-paediatric-critical-care-unit/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T11:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sheffield Children’s has rolled out System C's electronic prescribing and medicine administration system in its Paediatric Critical Care Unit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP given one-year prison sentence for damaging petrol pumps in climate protest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157574</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/gp-given-one-year-prison-sentence-for-damaging-petrol-pumps-in-climate-protest/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T10:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Bristol GP who took part in a climate protest damaging petrol pumps has been sentenced to 12 months in prison. Dr Patrick Hart was sentenced yesterday at Chelmsford Crown Court, after being found guilty of criminal damage on 29 October last year. In August 2022, with a group from the campaign Just Stop Oil,
The post GP given one-year prison sentence for damaging petrol pumps in climate protest appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts of self-harm or suicide a 'silent emergency' among GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901257</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/thoughts-self-harm-suicide-silent-emergency-among-gps/article/1901257"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T09:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One in five GPs say they have experienced thoughts of self-harm or suicide during their career as a healthcare professional, with the vast majority citing their job as a contributing factor, a survey has found.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make a positive impact on your clinical practice with a MIMS Learning webinar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901393</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/positive-impact-clinical-practice-mims-learning-webinar/article/1901393"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T08:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join a free evening webinar on Monday 13 January to understand more about how you can make a positive impact on your own clinical practice and that of your colleagues.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI tool trialled in Leeds that helps to identify atrial fibrillation risk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214727</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/ai-tool-trialled-in-leeds-that-helps-to-identify-atrial-fibrillation-risk/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-08T08:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A trial of an AI tool, conducted by Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, is identifying people at risk of developing atrial fibrillation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behind the headlines: Are there really more ‘failing’ GP practices than successful ones?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157552</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/behind-the-headlines/behind-the-headlines-are-there-more-failing-practices-than-successful-ones/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T15:58:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maya Dhillon looks at a Daily Mail article criticising the number of ‘failing’ GP practices following an analysis of CQC ratings and explores the figures being omitted from the headlines. A Daily Mail ‘exclusive’ has reported that millions of patients are receiving ‘sub-standard’ care at hundreds of failing GP surgeries. The analysis was carried out
The post Behind the headlines: Are there really more ‘failing’ GP practices than successful ones? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practice Tips: Exploring the role of non-GP partners in general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149733</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/practice-tips/practice-tips-exploring-the-role-of-non-gp-partners-in-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T15:56:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practice manager Mike Neville explains how non-GP partners can benefit practices As the healthcare landscape evolves, the question of whether non-GP professionals should become partners in GP practices has become increasingly pertinent. It is a complex question that does not have one single answer. I have been a partner in my practice for almost a
The post Practice Tips: Exploring the role of non-GP partners in general practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP's book offers children 'tips for life' - including how to survive a visit to the doctor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900822</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-book-offers-children-tips-life-including-survive-visit-doctor/article/1900822"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T15:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP has written a book to help children aged seven to 12 with issues including visits to the doctor or dentist, handling bullies, staying safe on the internet and making friends.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reforming elective care for patients]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/reforming-elective-care-for-patients-1.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/reforming-elective-care-for-patients-1.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T14:31:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - On 6 January 2025, the prime minister announced a new national plan published by NHS England (NHSE) setting out how the NHS will reform elective care for patients in England. This briefing highlights the key points from the plan and includes NHS Providers’ view and press statements. Briefing More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: DHSC group accounting manual 2024 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2024-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2024-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T13:59:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mandatory annual reports and accounts guidelines for the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) group bodies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients Know Best secures £6m to scale personal health record]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214695</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/patients-know-best-secures-6m-to-scale-personal-health-record/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T13:30:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients Know Best has secured £6 million in funding to scale its personal health record (PHR) platform in the UK and expand internationally.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[25% of patients changed medication following general practice-based pharmacogenetics trial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157547</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/25-of-patients-changed-medication-following-general-practice-based-pharmacogenetics-trial/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T12:20:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A pharmacogenetics pilot within general practice resulted in medicines changes for 25% of participating patients so far, Royal Pharmaceutical Society (RPS) conference attendees heard. Jessica Keen, pharmacy lead at the NHS North West Genomic Medicines Service Alliance, shared an update on the NHS England-funded Pharmacogenetics Roll Out – Gauging Response to Service (PROGRESS) study which
The post 25% of patients changed medication following general practice-based pharmacogenetics trial appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flu cases in general practice triple level a year ago]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901299</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/flu-cases-general-practice-triple-level-year-ago/infections-and-infestations/influenza/article/1901299"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T11:36:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP consultations for flu-like illness were almost three times higher in the final week of 2024 compared with the same week in 2023 as general practice saw a surge in seasonal workload amid a 'tidal wave of flu'.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214517</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-32/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T11:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Coffee Time Briefing covers a new online prescription service at Morrisons and a CBE for Milton Keynes CEO, Joe Harrison.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in several areas serve collective notice to ICBs on ‘unfunded work’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157535</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/gps-in-several-areas-serve-collective-notice-to-icbs-on-unfunded-work/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T11:26:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in several areas are coming together to serve notice to their ICBs on ‘unfunded work’ as part of collective action.  ICBs across the country have been warned that, unless funding improves, GPs will withdraw various services and shared care arrangements, including PSA monitoring, phlebotomy, ring pessaries and ECGs. LMC leaders told Pulse that serving
The post GPs in several areas serve collective notice to ICBs on ‘unfunded work’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maternity app and electronic health record to be rolled out in Wales]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214557</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/maternity-app-and-electronic-health-record-to-be-rolled-out-in-wales/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T11:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An electronic health record and app will be rolled out across Wales to enable mothers-to-be to access their full maternity records instantly.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kent and Essex to receive largest share of additional smoking cessation funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157473</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/kent-and-essex-to-receive-largest-share-of-additional-smoking-cessation-funding/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T10:56:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has confirmed how much additional funding each local authority will receive for smoking cessation services in 2025/26. The funding, which totals £70m per year, was announced in November 2023 as part of the previous government’s plans to create a smokefree generation. And the new Labour government has continued this intention, introducing a bill
The post Kent and Essex to receive largest share of additional smoking cessation funding appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices face 'great strain' if pharmacies close, RCGP warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901344</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-face-great-strain-pharmacies-close-rcgp-warns/article/1901344"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T10:18:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice will face a ‘greater strain’ if pharmacies close, the RCGP has said after nearly two in five pharmacy owners warned their businesses may not survive the winter without urgent financial support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understaffed GP practices 'not ready' to take on more work from hospitals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901313</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/understaffed-gp-practices-not-ready-work-hospitals/article/1901313"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most GPs say their practice doesn't have the staff to cope with government plans to shift more healthcare into the community, according to polling by a medico-legal organisation.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[John Quinn to leave NHS England CIO role]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214561</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/john-quinn-to-leave-nhs-england-cio-role/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-07T08:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[John Quinn, chief information officer (CIO) at NHS England, has announced he will leave the role at the end of March 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs instructed to help ambulance crews in bid to ease winter pressures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157506</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/gps-instructed-to-help-ambulance-crews-in-bid-to-ease-winter-pressures/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T15:51:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS leaders have directed hundreds of GP practices to find capacity for taking ‘urgent calls’ from the ambulance service to mitigate ‘unprecedented’ winter pressures.  NHS England’s East of England region wrote to all GP practices at the end of December to ‘ask for help’, warning that urgent and emergency care in the area is in
The post GPs instructed to help ambulance crews in bid to ease winter pressures appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The patients are revolting, or they should be]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157480</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/the-patients-are-revolting-or-they-should-be/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T15:05:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield considers how to mobilise patients for collective action I returned to the surgery after the seasonal break to be met by a terrifying howling and clanging. The sort of noise, in fact, you’d expect the nation’s GPs to make as they’re driven insane by their ongoing existential despair and the apparent failure of collective
The post The patients are revolting, or they should be appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Imperial College to go live with Netcall’s contact centre solution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214437</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/imperial-college-to-go-live-with-netcalls-contact-centre-solution/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T13:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imperial College Healthcare is to upgrade to Netcall’s cloud-based contact centre solution to improve patient engagement and productivity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Deal between NHS and independent sector to cut NHS waiting lists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/deal-between-nhs-and-independent-sector-to-cut-nhs-waiting-lists</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/deal-between-nhs-and-independent-sector-to-cut-nhs-waiting-lists"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T12:56:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New agreement struck between NHS and independent sector to help tackle waiting lists and give patients greater choice]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reforming elective care for patients]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/reforming-elective-care-for-patients.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/reforming-elective-care-for-patients.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T12:18:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England - This plan sets out how the NHS will reform elective care services and meet the 18 week referral to treatment standard by March 2029. The aim is that elective care will be increasingly personalised and digital, with a focus on improving experience and convenience, and empowering people with choice and control over when and where they will...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Power to patient as government sets out plan to cut waiting lists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/power-to-patient-as-government-sets-out-plan-to-cut-waiting-lists</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/power-to-patient-as-government-sets-out-plan-to-cut-waiting-lists"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T11:06:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will be offered a wider choice of providers and the process of booking treatments and appointments will be made as smooth as possible]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS App upgrades planned to help cut elective care waiting lists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214373</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/government-sets-out-nhs-app-upgrades-to-help-cut-waiting-lists/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T11:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government is upgrading the NHS App to enable patients to choose providers, book appointments and receive test results, all in one place.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should prioritise cancer testing in older men with tiredness, suggests study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157042</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/renal-medicine-urology-mens-health/gps-should-prioritise-cancer-testing-in-older-men-with-tiredness-suggests-study/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T10:26:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cancer should be at the forefront of GPs minds when older men present with tiredness, say researchers who did an analysis of the main reasons behind the symptom. A study of health records of almost three quarters of a million patients compared the most common diseases in those were did or did not present with
The post GPs should prioritise cancer testing in older men with tiredness, suggests study appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to be paid £20 per A&G request in bid to cut hospital waiting lists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157472</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gps-to-be-paid-20-per-ag-request-in-bid-to-cut-hospital-waiting-lists/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T10:12:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in England will be paid £20 for undertaking advice and guidance (A&G) with hospital specialists, as part of a bid to bring down the elective waiting list.  The Government said this will help prevent ‘unnecessary referrals’ with 800,000 more patients managed in primary rather than secondary care annually.  Prime Minister Keir Starmer has this
The post GPs to be paid £20 per A&G request in bid to cut hospital waiting lists appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: NHS general ophthalmic service fees and optical voucher values from April 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-general-ophthalmic-service-fees-and-optical-voucher-values-from-april-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-general-ophthalmic-service-fees-and-optical-voucher-values-from-april-2024"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T10:10:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Letter and directions setting out general ophthalmic services fees, payments, optical voucher values and hospital eye service charges from 1 April 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to be paid £20 per request in £80m advice and guidance plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901187</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-paid-20-per-request-80m-advice-guidance-plan/article/1901187"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T09:24:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs will be offered £20 per request submitted through advice and guidance under an £80m plan to almost double use of the system and cut 800,000 hospital referrals a year.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: PM sets out plan to end waiting list backlogs through millions more appointments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-sets-out-plan-to-end-waiting-list-backlogs-through-millions-more-appointments</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-sets-out-plan-to-end-waiting-list-backlogs-through-millions-more-appointments"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T09:04:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of patients will be able to access more appointments closer to home and get the treatment they need faster under a new plan to tackle hospital backlogs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government to develop NHS shared digital platform for medical info]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214351</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/government-to-develop-nhs-shared-digital-platform-for-medical-info/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-06T08:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government will develop a shared digital platform to allow up-to-date medical information to be shared between the NHS and care staff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government to set out roadmap to bring waiting times back to 18 weeks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901130</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/government-set-roadmap-bring-waiting-times-back-18-weeks/article/1901130"/>
        <updated>2025-01-05T00:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government plans to bring waiting times for hospital treatment down to 18 weeks by the end of the current parliament will be published this week, setting out a roadmap for tackling a major driver of workload in general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Major plan to cut waiting lists will see millions receive faster diagnosis and treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258612</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/01/major-plan-to-cut-waiting-lists-will-see-millions-receive-faster-diagnosis-and-treatment/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-04T09:43:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of thousands of patients will be able to get directly referred and booked in for tests, checks and scans by their GP for a range of conditions as part of a radical new plan set to be launched by the NHS and government next week. People with conditions such as breathlessness, asthma in children […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom W</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs report usual respiratory workload despite ‘skyrocketing’ flu in hospital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157461</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/gps-report-usual-respiratory-workload-despite-skyrocketing-flu-in-hospital/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T16:40:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs report ‘as expected’ levels of respiratory virus in the community despite hospital flu cases quadrupling in just one month.  NHS England warned this morning that flu cases have ‘continued to skyrocket’ with over 5,000 patients hospitalised with the virus at the end of last week.  This comes as the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA)
The post GPs report usual respiratory workload despite ‘skyrocketing’ flu in hospital appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should GP collective action become the new norm?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157443</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/david-turner/should-gp-collective-action-become-the-new-norm/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T14:46:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr David Turner considers whether various parts of GP collective action should become permanent in general practice At a recent GP meeting in my area we discussed what collective action different practices have taken. It soon became apparent that far from a temporary ceasing of an activity as a way of making a protest to
The post Should GP collective action become the new norm? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI to help patients with long-term conditions in North East London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214337</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/ai-to-help-patients-with-long-term-conditions-in-north-east-london/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T13:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of patients are benefitting from an NHS initiative that uses AI to better support those living with long-term health conditions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICBs told to put in place mitigation plans for pancreatic enzyme medicine shortages]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157437</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/renal-medicine-urology-mens-health/icbs-told-to-put-in-place-mitigation-plans-for-pancreatic-enzyme-medicine-shortages/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T12:51:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ICBs should put in place local mitigation plans to ensure patients are not left without pancreatic enzyme replacement therapies (PERT), amid shortages of the medicine. PERT, which is used in the treatment of pancreatic exocrine insufficiency such as in cystic fibrosis, pancreatic cancer and pancreatitis, has no clinical alternative. GPs have previously told Pulse that
The post ICBs told to put in place mitigation plans for pancreatic enzyme medicine shortages appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 80% of GPs faced verbal abuse from patients last year, finds survey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157433</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/special-investigations/gp-abuse/over-80-of-gps-faced-verbal-abuse-from-patients-last-year-finds-survey/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T12:14:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 80% of GPs experienced verbal abuse from patients in 2024, while a quarter were subjected to physical violence, a new survey has found. Worryingly, over a fifth of GPs also reported that they have endured thoughts of harming themselves due to work pressures. The medical defence organisation MDDUS recently conducted a survey of 1,855
The post Over 80% of GPs faced verbal abuse from patients last year, finds survey appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physician associate body preparing over 180 legal cases against GP practices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157426</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/physician-associate-body-preparing-over-180-legal-cases-against-gp-practices/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T11:49:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices could face legal action from physician associates (PAs), as an unofficial representative body revealed plans to take forward 184 individual employment claims. The organisation, United Medical Associate Professionals (UMAPs), claimed there have been around 200 PA redundancies from surgeries since October as a result of ‘discriminatory’ scope guidance produced by both the BMA
The post Physician associate body preparing over 180 legal cases against GP practices appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complete our fees survey for a chance to win £350 of John Lewis vouchers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901068</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/complete-fees-survey-chance-win-350-john-lewis-vouchers/article/1901068"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T11:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Take part in the GP Business survey of private and professional fees and you could be in with a chance of winning £350 of John Lewis vouchers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: New reforms and independent commission to transform social care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-reforms-and-independent-commission-to-transform-social-care</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-reforms-and-independent-commission-to-transform-social-care"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T11:18:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Immediate investment and reforms to improve adult social care, and Louise Casey appointed to head independent commission and build cross-party consensus.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pilot utilises tech to support digital access for kidney patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214315</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/pilot-utilises-tech-to-support-digital-access-for-kidney-patients/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T11:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A pilot by South Tyneside and Sunderland NHS Foundation Trust is utilising technology to support digital access for kidney patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: NHS injury costs recovery scheme: April 2024 to March 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-injury-costs-recovery-scheme-april-2024-to-march-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-injury-costs-recovery-scheme-april-2024-to-march-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T10:54:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data on the funds collected by the Compensation Recovery Unit and funds paid to the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs face 'postcode lottery' on enhanced service funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901062</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-face-postcode-lottery-enhanced-service-funding/article/1901062"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T10:08:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices across England face huge gaps in funding for locally-commissioned services, with up to three-fold variation in pay for the same work or practices delivering work for free that others receive tens of thousands a year for, experts have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital patients with flu quadrupled to over 5,000 ahead of New Year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258570</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/01/hospital-patients-with-flu-quadrupled-to-over-5000-ahead-of-new-year/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T10:06:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New NHS data covering the Christmas and New Year period shows flu cases have continued to skyrocket, with over 5,000 patients hospitalised with the virus at the end of last week. Last week (w/e 29 Dec) there were an average of 4,469 patients with flu in hospital each day – almost 3.5 times higher than […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Lothian launches AI physiotherapy clinic pilot for patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214279</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/nhs-lothian-launches-ai-physiotherapy-clinic-pilot-for-patients/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T08:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Lothian in Scotland has made an AI-powered physiotherapy clinic available to nearly one million patients as part of a large-scale pilot.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: General practice finance in the year ahead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1901015</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-general-practice-finance-year-ahead/article/1901015"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T07:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Dr Tommy Perkins and accountant Andy Pow from Medics Money about the year ahead for general practice finance and how practices can ensure their business is in good shape.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Two-tier' job risk as practice nurses join ARRS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900791</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/two-tier-job-risk-practice-nurses-join-arrs/article/1900791"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plans to add practice nurses to the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) risk creating a two-tier employment system and driving more staff into at-scale working, GPs and nursing leaders have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs recognised in 2025 New Year Honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157417</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gps-recognised-in-2025-new-year-honours/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T16:09:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Several GPs have been recognised for their achievements and contributions to healthcare in the King’s New Year Honours list.  A total of five GPs made the list for 2025, which ‘recognises the achievements and service of extraordinary people across the UK’. RCGP Wales chair Dr Rowena Christmas, who is also a GP principal at the
The post GPs recognised in 2025 New Year Honours appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the month: What’s causing this patient’s sudden-onset confusion and memory loss?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157294</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/neurology/case-of-the-month-whats-causing-this-patients-sudden-onset-confusion-and-memory-loss/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T14:22:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the next in our monthly quiz series, Dr Roger Henderson asks what might be the cause of this patient’s sudden-onset confusion and memory loss. Share your thoughts on the diagnosis in the comments below! A previously well 65-year-old woman attended the GP surgery as an emergency, having been brought there by her family. That
The post Case of the month: What’s causing this patient’s sudden-onset confusion and memory loss? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Counting what matters: how to classify, account and track spending for prevention]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/counting-what-matters-how-to-classify-account-and-track-spending-for-prevention.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/counting-what-matters-how-to-classify-account-and-track-spending-for-prevention.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T11:54:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demos - Demos has been making the case for a fundamental shift in the purpose of government away from firefighting in public services towards preventing problems arriving. However, this approach raises concerns about both the feasibility of measuring preventative spending accurately and appropriately but also that ring-fencing alone may not lead to the desired improvements in outcomes and value for...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local stop smoking services and support: funding allocations and methodology for 2025 to 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/local-stop-smoking-services-and-support-funding-allocations-and-methodology-for-2025-to-2026.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/01/local-stop-smoking-services-and-support-funding-allocations-and-methodology-for-2025-to-2026.html"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T11:38:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Department of Health and Social Care - The funding allocations document confirms the additional funding to local authorities for 2025 to 2026. It also outlines the methodology for making these allocations. This funding will be provided in addition to the current public health grant allocations. Guidance Department of Health and Social Care - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What do we know about the 2025/26 GP contract?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900935</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/know-2025-26-gp-contract/article/1900935"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T11:35:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government says an £889m funding boost to the GP contract for 2025/26 will 'liberate' GPs from bureaucracy and help create a neighbourhood NHS. But what will practices be asked to do under the contract?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost 40% of GP partners would consider becoming salaried ‘if offered the right deal’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=156991</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/almost-40-of-gp-partners-would-consider-becoming-salaried-if-offered-the-right-deal/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T11:34:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Almost 40% of GP partners across the UK would consider becoming salaried ‘if they were offered the right deal’, a Pulse survey has revealed. GPs told Pulse that lack of core contract funding, and uncertainty around the national insurance contributions hikes more recently, are contributing to partners considering going salaried. The recent survey results,
The post Almost 40% of GP partners would consider becoming salaried ‘if offered the right deal’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213771</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-31/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T11:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Coffee Time Briefing covers robotic-assisted surgery at Queen Elizabeth Hospital and funding for DeepLife's "digital twin" tech.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Stick together’ to ‘restore general practice as cornerstone of the NHS’, BMA chair tells GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157405</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/stick-together-to-restore-general-practice-as-cornerstone-of-the-nhs-bma-chair-tells-gps/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T11:11:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs must ‘stick together’ to help ‘restore general practice as the cornerstone of the NHS’, the BMA council chair has said. Professor Phil Banfield made the comments in a New Year’s message to doctors across the UK, adding that it will be up to GPs to determine if their governments’ contract offers are ‘good enough’.
The post ‘Stick together’ to ‘restore general practice as cornerstone of the NHS’, BMA chair tells GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Unplugged: Data and diversity in digital health]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213793</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/digital-health-unplugged-data-and-diversity-in-digital-health/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T11:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jordan Sollof is joined by Rachel Dunscombe, OpenEHR International chief executive to discuss data, women in digital health and Rewired 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs must continue promotion of folic acid in pregnancy after fortification of flour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157394</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/gps-must-continue-promotion-of-folic-acid-in-pregnancy-after-fortification-of-flour/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T10:33:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been urged to continue to promote the importance of folic acid supplementation in pregnancy after it is added to non-wholemeal flour from the end of 2026. The UK’s chief medical officers, chief midwifery officers and chief nursing officers have written to health professionals warning of the ‘risk’ that some women will stop taking
The post GPs must continue promotion of folic acid in pregnancy after fortification of flour appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs recognised in 2025 New Year Honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900930</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-recognised-2025-new-year-honours/article/1900930"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T09:56:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are among healthcare staff recognised in the 2025 New Year Honours list.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2025 predictions: Health tech suppliers on what’s in store]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213405</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/01/2025-predictions-health-tech-suppliers-on-whats-in-store/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T08:30:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health News asked suppliers to share their predictions about what lies ahead for the sector in 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Early cancer diagnosis in England reaches highest ever level]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258507</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/01/early-cancer-diagnosis-in-england-reaches-highest-ever-level/"/>
        <updated>2025-01-02T00:01:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The proportion of patients being diagnosed with cancer at an early stage in England has risen to its highest ever level, according to new NHS analysis.  Latest data on 13 of the most common cancers, such as breast, prostate and lung cancer, shows that nearly three in five patients are now being diagnosed at stages […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Healthy Start]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/healthy-start</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/healthy-start"/>
        <updated>2025-01-01T00:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthy Start is an NHS scheme that helps women who are pregnant or have young children and are receiving benefits, buy foods such as milk or fruit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS national medical director comments on latest winter pressures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258517</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/nhs-national-medical-director-comments-on-latest-winter-pressures/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-31T13:59:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS national medical director, Professor Sir Stephen Powis, said: “The winter flu season has not only hit the NHS early this year, but it is potentially on track to be one of the worst we have ever seen, as the ‘quad-demic’ continues to increase pressure across services. “Frontline NHS staff are currently under significant pressure […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Provisional list of NHS abortion clinics and hospitals in England, 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/provisional-list-of-nhs-abortion-clinics-and-hospitals-in-england-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/provisional-list-of-nhs-abortion-clinics-and-hospitals-in-england-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-12-31T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This publication contains a provisional list of NHS abortion clinics and hospitals in England as identified in a notification to the Chief Medical Officer in 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Provisional list of abortion clinics and hospitals in Wales, 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/provisional-list-of-abortion-clinics-and-hospitals-in-wales-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/provisional-list-of-abortion-clinics-and-hospitals-in-wales-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-12-31T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This publication contains a provisional list of abortion clinics and hospitals in Wales.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Independent clinics approved to carry out abortions in England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/clinics-authorised-to-carry-out-abortions</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/clinics-authorised-to-carry-out-abortions"/>
        <updated>2024-12-31T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information about independent clinics and hospitals that are approved to carry out abortions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2025 predictions: Digital Health Networks’ leaders look ahead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213429</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/2025-predictions-digital-health-networks-leaders-look-ahead/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-31T08:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We asked members of the Digital Health Networks for their thoughts on what lies ahead for the world of NHS digital and technology in 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 in review: The 10-year plan and neighbourhood teams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157241</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/special/end-of-year-reviews/2024-in-review-the-10-year-plan-and-neighbourhood-teams/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-31T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As 2024 draws to a close, Pulse looks at the big issues in general practice this year, such as Labour’s 10-year plan, the shift from ‘hospital to community’, and the focus on neighbourhood teams Less than a week into the role of health secretary, Wes Streeting tasked Lord Ara Darzi with an independent investigation into
The post 2024 in review: The 10-year plan and neighbourhood teams appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Record numbers complete NHS Couch to 5k app]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/record-numbers-complete-nhs-couch-to-5k-app</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/record-numbers-complete-nhs-couch-to-5k-app"/>
        <updated>2024-12-31T00:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The free running app has been downloaded over 7 million times since it launched in 2016, with 9.3 million NHS Couch to 5k runs started this year.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff among those recognised in 2025 New Year honours list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258495</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/nhs-staff-among-those-recognised-in-2025-new-year-honours-list/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-30T22:35:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nurses, doctors and surgeons are among dozens of NHS staff on the 2025 New Year Honour list, released today (Monday 30 December). The head of the NHS, Amanda Pritchard, praised the dedication of those recognised in what has again been another challenging year for the health service. This year staff have dealt with record levels of demand but also […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: New Year Honours 2025: Ambulance Service list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/new-year-honours-2025-ambulance-service-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/new-year-honours-2025-ambulance-service-list"/>
        <updated>2024-12-30T22:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recipients of The King's Ambulance Service Medal 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Milestone: COVID-19 five years ago]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:de1c6f88-8660-4274-b6f6-b08abbafa414</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/30-12-2024-milestone-covid-19-five-years-ago"/>
        <updated>2024-12-30T16:15:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Five years ago on 31 December 2019, WHO’s Country Office in China picked up a media statement by the Wuhan Municipal Health Commission from their website on cases of ‘viral pneumonia’ in Wuhan, China. In the weeks, months and years that unfolded after that, COVID-19 came to shape our lives and our world. 
At WHO, we went to work immediately as the new year dawned. WHO employees activated emergency systems on 1 January 2020, and informed the world on 4 January. By 9-12 January, WHO had published its first set of comprehensive guidance for countries, and on 13 January, we brought together partners to publish the blueprint of the first SARS-CoV-2 laboratory test. 
All along, we convened experts and ministries of health from around the world, gathered and analysed data, and shared what was reported, what we learned and what it meant for people. Read about WHO’s actions in this  interactive timeline. 
As we mark this milestone, let’s take a moment to honour the lives changed and lost, recognize those who are suffering from COVID-19 and long COVID, express gratitude to the health workers who sacrificed so much to care for us, and commit to learning from COVID-19 to build a healthier tomorrow. 
We continue to call on China to share data and access so we can understand the origins of COVID-19. This is a moral and scientific imperative. Without transparency, sharing, and cooperation among countries, the world cannot adequately prevent and prepare for future epidemics and pandemics. 
As we pose the question, “Is the world better prepared for the next pandemic than we were for COVID-19?” see WHO Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus’s response at a recent press conference: https://who.canto.global/b/SHEJL]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Local stop smoking services and support: funding for 2025 to 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/local-stop-smoking-services-and-support-funding-for-2025-to-2026</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/local-stop-smoking-services-and-support-funding-for-2025-to-2026"/>
        <updated>2024-12-30T09:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information about the additional funding of £70 million to local authorities in England for stop smoking services and support in 2025 to 2026.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 in review: The Budget and National Insurance tax hike]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157209</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/special/end-of-year-reviews/2024-in-review-the-budget-and-national-insurance-tax-hike/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-30T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As 2024 draws to a close, Pulse looks at the big issues in general practice this year, such as the announcement of a National Insurance tax hike for GPs in the Budget Ahead of the first Labour budget in 14 years, speculation was rife about what it might bring for general practice.  The BMA made
The post 2024 in review: The Budget and National Insurance tax hike appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Quit for a week and save a day, say health experts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/quit-for-a-week-and-save-a-day-say-health-experts</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/quit-for-a-week-and-save-a-day-say-health-experts"/>
        <updated>2024-12-30T00:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smokers who choose to quit on the 1 January could save a whole day of their life by 8 January, according to new research.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS prevents thousands of strokes, thanks to lifesaving drive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258482</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/nhs-prevents-thousands-of-strokes-thanks-to-lifesaving-drive/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-28T00:01:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Around one hundred people a month in England have avoided a stroke over the last year thanks to a lifesaving NHS rollout of blood thinning medication. Over the last year, one million people with Atrial Fibrillation (AF) – a condition that causes an irregular and often abnormally fast heartbeat – have been prescribed anticoagulant medication […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamal Adwan Hospital out of service following a raid yesterday and repeated attacks since October]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:06591993-c403-4c4d-ad0f-23f3779adc7c</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/28-12-2024-kamal-adwan-hospital-out-of-service-following-a-raid-today-and-repeated-attacks-since-october"/>
        <updated>2024-12-27T20:04:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO is appalled by yesterday’s raid on Kamal Adwan Hospital, which put the last major health facility in North Gaza out of service. The systematic dismantling of the health system and a siege for over 80 days on North Gaza puts the lives of the 75,000 Palestinians remaining in the area at risk.

Initial reports indicate that some areas of the hospital were burnt and severely damaged during the raid, including the laboratory, surgical unit, engineering and maintenance department, operations theatre, and the medical store. Earlier in the day, twelve patients and a female health staff were reportedly forced to evacuate to destroyed and non-functional Indonesian Hospital where it is not possible to provide any care, while the majority of the staff, stable patients and companions were moved to …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicines eligible for Northern Ireland MHRA Authorised Route]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route"/>
        <updated>2024-12-27T16:23:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out medicines that can be moved to Northern Ireland to meet patient need.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Tackles Problem Gambling Amid Growing Demand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258480</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/nhs-tackles-problem-gambling-amid-growing-demand-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-27T12:21:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS in England is facing an “uphill battle” with demand for gambling addiction help more than doubling since last year.  Referrals have gone up almost 130%, with almost 2,000 people referred to gambling clinics between April and September this year, compared to just over 800 in the same period last year. However to manage […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicine choices in opioid substitution treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicine-choices-in-opioid-substitution-treatment</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicine-choices-in-opioid-substitution-treatment"/>
        <updated>2024-12-27T09:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recommendations for prescribing methadone and buprenorphine to people in treatment for opioid dependence in England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 in review: The 2024/25 GP contract and collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157272</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/special/end-of-year-reviews/2024-in-review-the-2024-25-gp-contract-and-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-27T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As 2024 draws to a close, Pulse looks at the big issues in general practice this year, such as collective action over the 2024/25 GP contract. The year started out with the GPC announcing it would put the Government’s offer for the 2024/25 GP contract to a referendum of GPs, regardless of whether there was
The post 2024 in review: The 2024/25 GP contract and collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statement by Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General on the attack on the Sana'a airport, Yemen]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:aa704480-634f-4627-8278-ead3d0da2a07</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/26-12-2024-statement-by-dr-tedros-adhanom-ghebreyesus--who-director-general-on-the-attack-on-the-sana-a-airport--yemen"/>
        <updated>2024-12-26T18:01:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our mission to negotiate the release of the United Nations staff detainees and to assess the health and humanitarian situation in Yemen concluded today. 
We continue to call for the detainees' immediate release.  
As we were about to board our flight from Sana’a, about three hours ago (around 5 pm local time), the airport came under aerial bombardment.  One of our plane’s crew members was injured.  At least two people were reported killed at the airport.  
The air traffic control tower, the departure lounge — just a few meters from where we were — and the runway were damaged.  We will need to wait for the damage to the airport to be repaired before we can leave. 
My UN and WHO colleagues and I are safe. 
Our heartfelt condolences to the families whose loved ones lost their lives in the attack.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Tackles Problem Gambling Amid Growing Demand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258476</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/nhs-tackles-problem-gambling-amid-growing-demand/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-26T10:01:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS in England is facing an “uphill battle” with demand for gambling addiction help more than doubling since last year. Referrals have gone up almost 130%, with almost 2,000 people referred to gambling clinics between April and September this year, compared to just over 800 in the same period last year. However to manage […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>fraja</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: NHS cost recovery - overseas visitors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-cost-recovery-overseas-visitors</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-cost-recovery-overseas-visitors"/>
        <updated>2024-12-24T12:27:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information for NHS bodies who need to make and recover hospital charges from overseas visitors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultation outcome: changes to regulations relating to the Care Quality Commission]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/consultation-outcome-changes-to-regulations-relating-to-the-care-quality-commission.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/consultation-outcome-changes-to-regulations-relating-to-the-care-quality-commission.html"/>
        <updated>2024-12-24T12:09:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Department of Health and Social Care - This is the analysis by the Department of Health and Social Care of responses to their consultation to amend the Health and Social Act 2008 (Regulated Activities) Regulations 2014 (the ‘2014 regulations’). Respondents supported the amendment to remove the 2014 regulations’ expiry date of 31 March 2025 and instead review the regulations every...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Christmas Coffee Briefing 🎄]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213791</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/digital-health-christmas-coffee-briefing-%f0%9f%8e%84/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-24T11:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our Christmas Coffee Briefing features festive-themed news, including a story from NHS Highland about how virtual care can make a difference.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health’s 2024 Review: Top 5 podcasts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=212893</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/digital-healths-2024-review-top-5-podcasts/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-24T08:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health News takes a look at the five most listened to episodes of he Digital Health Unplugged podcast in 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Burnt Out’s 2025 preview for general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157218</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/dr-burnt-out/dr-burnt-outs-2025-preview-for-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-24T08:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Burnt Out takes a satirical look at what 2025 could have in store for general practice JanuaryNorth West London ICB suddenly halts funding to half of the area’s GP practices, and announces that they need to all urgently move to an empty repurposed storage warehouse along the edge of the North Circular Road which has been
The post Dr Burnt Out’s 2025 preview for general practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 in review: The rise of the physician associates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157180</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/special/end-of-year-reviews/2024-in-review-the-rise-of-the-physician-associates/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-24T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As 2024 draws to a close, Pulse looks at the big issues in general practice this year, such as the implementation and regulation of physician associates With physician associate (PA) regulation starting this month, its quite the task to remember how we ever got to this point at all. 2024 began with the legislation which
The post 2024 in review: The rise of the physician associates appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Booze, burns and bites top NHS Christmas health advice list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258383</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/booze-burns-and-bites-top-nhs-christmas-health-advice-list/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-24T00:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Booze, burns and bites are top of the list of NHS health advice being sought over Christmas. The NHS website’s information on alcohol, burns, rabies and animal bites showed the biggest increases in visits on Christmas Day and Boxing Day last year, newly released figures from NHS England show. Top of the list was advice […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Luxembourg and WHO sign two strategic agreements]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:d503ccdc-d0a3-4b19-9e3f-6047222e81ae</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/23-12-2024-luxembourg-and-who-sign-two-strategic-agreements"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T16:44:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Strategic Partnership Framework (SPF) with the Ministry of Development Cooperation and Humanitarian Affairs and multiyear agreement with the Ministry of Health and Social Safety was signed on 20 December 2024. By signing two new partnership agreements, Luxembourg reaffirmed its continued support for WHO to fulfill a shared mission to promote, provide and protect health.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Becoming a national leader in supporting the armed forces]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/becoming-a-national-leader-in-supporting-the-armed-forces.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/becoming-a-national-leader-in-supporting-the-armed-forces.html"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T16:17:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - East Lancashire Hospitals NHS Trust (ELHT) serves a diverse population over 1,211 square kilometres, operating five hospitals and various community services. Since signing the Armed Forces Covenant in 2017, ELHT has taken deliberate steps to support Reservists and the wider armed forces community. These efforts align with the trust’s values of providing safe, personal and effective care,...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS chief focuses on innovation and staff commitment in Christmas message]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258411</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/nhs-chief-focuses-on-innovation-and-staff-commitment-in-christmas-message/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T16:01:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The head of the NHS in England has praised staff for “working tirelessly” and “constantly innovating” to modernise care for patients in her Christmas message to health workers. Amanda Pritchard, Chief Executive of NHS England, spoke about how NHS innovations are improving care and providing better value for money during a visit to Sutton Health […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde launches health visiting app]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214037</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/nhs-greater-glasgow-and-clyde-launches-health-visiting-app/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T13:30:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde has launched a new app for parents of young children to bring together a host of health and wellbeing advice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How could Britain and the EU work together to improve health?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/how-could-britain-and-the-eu-work-together-to-improve-health.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/how-could-britain-and-the-eu-work-together-to-improve-health.html"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T11:48:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - Striking a somewhat different note from his predecessors, the Prime Minister recently pledged to “reset relationships” with the European Union. While the UK’s policy goals within this strengthened cooperation remain for now vague, there are several concrete measures in health and life sciences that could form part of an attempt to work more closely with the EU....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs report average of 30 patient contacts per day]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=156936</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/gps-report-average-of-30-patient-contacts-per-day/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T11:06:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are seeing an average of 31 patient contacts each day, which is down from the average of 37 reported last year. Pulse’s recent survey, which had 840 UK respondents, asked GPs how many patient contacts they have in a full day, with just over a third stating that they see between 26 and 30. 
The post GPs report average of 30 patient contacts per day appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Highland frees up capacity through waiting list validation app]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214057</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/nhs-highland-frees-up-capacity-through-waiting-list-validation-app/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T11:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Highland has avoided up to £1m of appointment costs by using a waiting list validation tool from Netcall.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most people support sharing personal health data to develop AI in NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157234</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/long-term-conditions-prescribing/most-people-support-sharing-personal-health-data-to-develop-ai-in-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T10:57:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three quarters (75%) of the public support sharing some of their personal health data to aid the development of AI systems in the NHS, a Health Foundation report has found. The research, published earlier this month, surveyed 7,201 people across the UK between June and July 2024 and found that 29% were happy for any of
The post Most people support sharing personal health data to develop AI in NHS appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dependency-forming drugs prescriptions fall but inequalities persist]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157230</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/dependency-forming-drugs-prescriptions-fall-but-inequalities-persist/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T10:28:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The total number of patients prescribed dependency-forming medications in England fell by more than 2,000 between June and September this year, latest figures have shown. But huge variation persists between the most and least deprived areas of the country, with 79.3% more patients being prescribed dependency-forming medications in the most deprived areas of the country compared
The post Dependency-forming drugs prescriptions fall but inequalities persist appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corporate report: DHSC register of senior civil servants' secondary paid employment, 2023 to 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-register-of-senior-civil-servants-secondary-paid-employment-2023-to-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-register-of-senior-civil-servants-secondary-paid-employment-2023-to-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T10:08:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Details of any paid or otherwise remunerated outside employment held by senior civil servants in the Department of Health and Social Care during the 2023 to 2024 financial year.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statement on the antigen composition of COVID-19 vaccines]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:250c132f-02eb-4098-9d0e-d23b45b60489</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/23-12-2024-statement-on-the-antigen-composition-of-covid-19-vaccines"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T10:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Key points: 


Vaccination remains an important public health countermeasure against COVID-19. As per the WHO Director General’s  standing recommendations for COVID-19, Member States are recommended to continue to offer COVID-19 vaccination based on the recommendations of the  WHO Strategic Advisory Group of Experts on Immunization (SAGE).
SARS-CoV-2 continues to circulate and evolve with important genetic and antigenic evolution of the spike protein since the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic.
The objective of an update to COVID-19 vaccine antigen composition is to enhance vaccine-induced immune responses to circulating SARS-CoV-2 variants.
The WHO TAG-CO-VAC advises retaining the use of a monovalent JN.1 lineage variant as the antigen in future formulations of COVID-19 vaccines.
In acco…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health’s 2024 Review: Top 10 news stories]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=212313</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/digital-healths-2024-review-top-10-news-stories/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T08:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health News has picked out the 10 stories that sparked the most conversations in the sector in 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS highlights dementia symptoms to look out for over Christmas as numbers diagnosed soar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258347</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/nhs-highlights-dementia-symptoms-to-look-out-for-over-christmas-as-numbers-diagnosed-soar/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-23T00:01:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As family and friends gather for the festive period, the NHS is highlighting the signs and symptoms of dementia to look out for in loved ones. Common early symptoms of dementia that may appear some time before an official medical diagnosis include: emotional changes such as irritability forgetfulness struggling to follow a conversation or find […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS warns of ‘bargain basement’ BBLs in run up to Christmas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258372</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/nhs-warns-of-bargain-basement-bbls-in-run-up-to-christmas/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-21T11:48:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[England’s top doctor is warning the public about the risk of ‘bargain-basement’ Brazilian Butt lifts, following a stream of deals being offered by overseas clinics in the run up to Christmas.  The NHS has seen clinics offering 25% discounts, all-inclusive packages including hotels and flights for under £3,000, as well as finance deals in a […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS chief urges public to “unwrap the NHS App” this Christmas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258318</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/nhs-chief-urges-public-to-unwrap-the-nhs-app-this-christmas/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-21T00:01:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS is encouraging people to gift their loved ones the NHS App this Christmas, so they can order prescriptions, manage appointments and check test results over the festive period. As the health service combats its busiest ever start to winter, the NHS wants to ensure that patients have easy access to care, amid a […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What will the Government proposals for the 2025/26 contract mean for GP practices?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157358</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/contract/what-will-the-government-proposals-for-the-2025-26-contract-mean-for-gp-practices/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T16:43:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This morning, the Government unveiled the very first few details of the next GP contract. Health secretary Wes Streeting wrote to the profession mentioning a £889m funding uplift and reiterating Labour’s commitment to ‘bring back the family doctor’. As the proposal is now with the BMA for consultation, Pulse’s Eliza Parr, Maya Dhillon and Anna
The post What will the Government proposals for the 2025/26 contract mean for GP practices? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is £889m the lifeline practices need to keep them afloat?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900684</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/889m-lifeline-practices-need-keep-afloat/article/1900684"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders say an £889m funding uplift in 2025/26 could be 'an important lifeline' that avoids redundancies and contract hand-backs in general practice - but warned that detail on how the money works will be key, and that a 'long road' lies ahead.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Music as medicine’ trialled for South Asian people with dementia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214023</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/music-as-medicine-trialled-for-south-asian-people-with-dementia/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T13:30:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MediMusic and Anglia Ruskin University have been awarded £183,682 to investigate how AI and music can help South Asian people with dementia.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rise in doctors reporting domestic abuse, charity reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900525</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/rise-doctors-reporting-domestic-abuse-charity-reveals/article/1900525"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T13:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rising numbers of doctors are seeking support after experiencing domestic abuse, but cases are often under-reported by clinicians for fear of professional repercussions, a doctors’ charity has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building health equity: the role of the property sector in improving health]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/building-health-equity-the-role-of-the-property-sector-in-improving-health.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/building-health-equity-the-role-of-the-property-sector-in-improving-health.html"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T12:19:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute of Health Equity - This review explains how the twin crises of health and housing can be tackled together, by promoting health equity. It lays out a way forward to enable the property sector and national and local governments to work in partnership and put health equity, wellbeing and environmental sustainability at the heart of how the UK builds...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: GP reforms to cut red tape and bring back family doctor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/gp-reforms-to-cut-red-tape-and-bring-back-family-doctor</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/gp-reforms-to-cut-red-tape-and-bring-back-family-doctor"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T11:57:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The measures are backed by the biggest boost to GP funding in years, an extra £889m on top of the existing budget for general practice]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preventive and proactive care: research report]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/preventive-and-proactive-care-research-report.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/preventive-and-proactive-care-research-report.html"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T11:53:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local Government Association - This research was commissioned by The Better Care Fund Support Programme to collect and synthesise existing publications and reports, related to local prevention or proactive targeted support initiatives which enable people to stay well, safe and independent at home for longer. The aim was to better understand what preventive and proactive care initiatives local areas have...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relationality in community engagement: its role in humanizing health and achieving quality integrated health services]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:7cc4939b-e7e9-4920-bfa3-598d22bedeb6</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/19-12-2024-relationality-in-community-engagement-its-role-in-humanizing-health-and-achieving-quality-integrated--health-services"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T11:44:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new report, entitled “Relationality in community engagement: its role in humanizing healthcare and achieving quality integrated health Services” has been developed in collaboration with the Qatar Foundation for Education, Science and Community Development (QF) and launched at the Seventh edition of the World Innovation Summit for Health (WISH) taking place in Doha on 13–14 November 2024.
In the aftermath of the COVID-19 pandemic, community engagement has further resurfaced as a necessary condition, and a shared responsibility within health systems, for emergency preparedness, response and recovery efforts in global public health. 
The new report introduces the background and current policy context for community engagement across different WHO regions. It presents an Integrated Change Fra…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only 8% of Pharmacy First patients are sent back to general practice, says NHSE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=155355</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/only-8-of-pharmacy-first-patients-are-sent-back-to-general-practice-says-nhse/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T11:41:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Only 8% of patients using the Pharmacy First service are referred back to their GP practice, NHS England has claimed. Under the service, GP practices can refer patients to community pharmacies for seven common conditions – including sore throats and ear infections – in a bid to ‘save up to 10 million general practice team
The post Only 8% of Pharmacy First patients are sent back to general practice, says NHSE appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicines that you cannot export from the UK or hoard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-that-cannot-be-parallel-exported-from-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-that-cannot-be-parallel-exported-from-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T11:33:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out medicines that cannot be exported from the UK or hoarded because they are needed for UK patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical Quizmas: What is causing Rudolph’s orange nose?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=156163</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/dermatology-and-wound-care/clinical-quizmas-what-is-causing-rudolphs-orange-nose/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T11:15:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Christmas is here and so is Rudolph! But he’s not looking like he usually does. What are the diagnoses in the finale of our Quizmas picture quiz series? Click the answer boxes to find out. Note: ChatGPT was used to assist in the creation of these images
The post Clinical Quizmas: What is causing Rudolph’s orange nose? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stephen Kinnock: New contract can liberate GPs to build a neighbourhood NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900657</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/stephen-kinnock-new-contract-liberate-gps-build-neighbourhood-nhs/article/1900657"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T11:07:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing for GPonline as the government unveiled an £889m general practice funding boost, primary care minister Stephen Kinnock says next year's contract will ease financial pressure on practices, strip away red tape and 'bring back the family doctor'.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recommendations published to tackle bias in medical AI tech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=214019</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/recommendations-published-to-tackle-bias-in-medical-ai-tech/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T11:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A set of recommendations has been published with the aim of reducing the risk of potential bias in AI for healthcare technologies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bridging the gap: a guide to making health inequalities a strategic priority for NHS leaders]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/bridging-the-gap-a-guide-to-making-health-inequalities-a-strategic-priority-for-nhs-leaders.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/bridging-the-gap-a-guide-to-making-health-inequalities-a-strategic-priority-for-nhs-leaders.html"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T10:23:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Physicians - This guidance provides actionable steps for tackling health inequity within health care delivery, emphasising the role clinicians and clinical leaders can play in addressing these longstanding disparities. It argues that tackling these disparities is essential to improving the nation’s health and reducing unnecessary pressures on health care services. It underscores that NHS leaders have a...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Care beyond beds: exploring alternatives to hospital-based mental health care]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/care-beyond-beds-exploring-alternatives-to-hospital-based-mental-health-care.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/12/care-beyond-beds-exploring-alternatives-to-hospital-based-mental-health-care.html"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T10:13:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Centre for Mental Health - According to this report, an overhaul of mental health care is needed to achieve the Government’s goal of shifting treatment from hospitals to communities. It finds that inpatient care is too often characterised by unsafe levels of bed occupancy, chronic staffing shortages and dilapidated facilities which risk re-traumatising patients. Black people, neurodivergent people and children...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government unveils first details of next GP contract including extra £889m]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157340</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/government-unveils-first-details-of-next-gp-contract-including-extra-889m/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T09:50:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has unveiled the first details of the next GP contract, including an extra £889m ‘on top of the existing budget’ for general practice. The proposals also include reducing the number of QOF targets from 76 to 44 and adding practice nurses to ARRS. The Government will consult on its proposals for the GP
The post Government unveils first details of next GP contract including extra £889m appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government unveils £889m GP funding boost for 2025/26]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900633</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/government-unveils-889m-gp-funding-boost-2025-26/article/1900633"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T09:33:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government will increase overall funding for general practice by £889m in 2025/26 in what it says is the 'biggest boost to GP funding in years'.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movers and Shakers news roundup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213933</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/movers-and-shakers-news-roundup-55/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T08:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest roundup features a new joint CEO of Chelsea and Westminster Hospital and The Hillingdon Hospitals NHS Foundation Trusts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: How the NHS can get the best from social prescribing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900466</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-nhs-best-social-prescribing/article/1900466"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T08:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Charlotte Osborn Forde and Dr Radha Modgil from the National Academy for Social Prescribing about the evidence that supports the use of social prescribing and how general practice - and the rest of the NHS - can get the best from social prescribing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter pressure surge for GPs as flu consultations pass epidemic threshold]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900524</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/winter-pressure-surge-gps-flu-consultations-pass-epidemic-threshold/infections-and-infestations/influenza/article/1900524"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP consultations for flu-like illness rose by 42% in the week to 15 December, reflecting a spike in workload in general practice as NHS leaders warned that hospitals had been 'flooded' with cases in an early surge of illness before Christmas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practice manager to pay back £44,000 after theft left GP facing panic attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1900448</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/practice-manager-pay-back-44000-theft-left-gp-facing-panic-attacks/article/1900448"/>
        <updated>2024-12-20T07:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A former practice manager has been ordered to pay back £44,000 after stealing more than £300,000 from the surgery she once worked for, leaving it facing 'substantial financial risk', staff fearing for their jobs and one GP partner experiencing panic attacks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England among countries experiencing steepest rise in bowel cancer in under-50s]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157044</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cancer/england-among-countries-experiencing-steepest-rise-in-bowel-cancer-in-under-50s/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T17:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rates of bowel cancer in the under-50s have been rising around the world, with England seeing one of the fastest increases, new research has found. Data up to 2017 for 50 countries shows that the incidence of early-onset colorectal cancer rose in 27 of them, with the greatest annual increases seen in New Zealand (4%),
The post England among countries experiencing steepest rise in bowel cancer in under-50s appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs told to stop ‘subsidising’ minor surgery as part of collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=156323</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gps-told-to-stop-subsidising-minor-surgery-as-part-of-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T17:20:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been told to stop providing minor surgery as part of collective action, after one LMC calculated that underfunding means practices are ‘subsidising’ the NHS by up to £43 for each procedure. Leicestershire, Leicester and Rutland LMC said it negotiated an uplift in funding for the service with the ICB last year, since it
The post GPs told to stop ‘subsidising’ minor surgery as part of collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lebanon: soaring needs for trauma treatment and rehabilitation]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:4455b1b9-4f69-472e-8381-5c867b65d67c</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/20-12-2024-lebanon--soaring-needs-for-trauma-treatment-and-rehabilitation"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T14:49:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ceasefire and the cessation of hostilities took effect on 27 November, offering temporary relief for the millions of civilians caught in the conflict in Lebanon. But Lebanon’s suffering did not end amid staggering unmet health needs. Bordering Syria and Israel, Lebanon’s overburdened health system is reeling from the impacts of an economic crisis, political deadlock, refugee crisis and now war. 
The country is host to 1.5 million Syrian refugees: inevitably, events in Syria impact Lebanon and WHO operations. Syrian nationals are entering Lebanon at the same time as Syrian refugees are returning to Syria from Lebanon.
"An already decimated health system remarkably withstood this latest storm, but it has been further weakened. The challenges are complex and call for specialized, sustaine…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All I want for 2025 is some common sense]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157267</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/all-i-want-for-2025-is-some-common-sense/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T14:37:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Sofia Lind reflects on the year and puts forward her wish for what 2025 might bring general practice This last year brought a new Government to oversee general practice contracts and funding, however as I write this end-of-year editorial it remains to be seen whether that is good or bad for practices. Health secretary Wes Streeting
The post All I want for 2025 is some common sense appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assisted living suites used to train health and care students in Kent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213865</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/assisted-living-suites-used-to-train-health-and-care-students-in-kent/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T13:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health and social care students and NHS employees will be trained on using smart technology in assisted living suites at North Kent College.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corporate report: Business critical models for Department of Health and Social Care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/business-critical-models-for-department-of-health-and-social-care</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/business-critical-models-for-department-of-health-and-social-care"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T13:29:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A list of the main analytical models used by the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) and its arm's length bodies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213593</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-30/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T11:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Coffee Time Briefing includes updates on the Synnovis strike action and insights from the National Data Guardian 2023-2024 report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs told to stop providing ADHD care to children due to ‘capacity issues’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157264</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gps-told-to-stop-providing-adhd-care-to-children-due-to-capacity-issues/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T11:18:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GPs should withdraw care for children with ADHD due to ‘capacity issues’, and as a way of pressuring the ICB into commissioning a specialist service, a group of LMCs has recommended.  North and South Essex LMCs chief executive Dr Brian Balmer told Pulse that practices are not currently paid to provide this care, and
The post GPs told to stop providing ADHD care to children due to ‘capacity issues’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medtech startup SleepCogni raises £300,000 for insomnia care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213959</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/medtech-startup-sleepcogni-raises-300000-for-insomnia-care/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T11:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sheffield-based insomnia medtech firm SleepCogni has raised £300,000, bringing its total funding to £3.9m.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult social care outcomes framework: handbook of definitions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-outcomes-framework-handbook-of-definitions</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-outcomes-framework-handbook-of-definitions"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T11:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out the technical detail of each adult social care outcomes framework (ASCOF) measure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Biggest investment into hospices in a generation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/biggest-investment-into-hospices-in-a-generation</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/biggest-investment-into-hospices-in-a-generation"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T10:33:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[£100 million boost for adult and children’s hospices and £26 million to support children and young people’s hospices.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter pressure builds as no sign of ‘festive flu’ letting up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=258238</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/12/winter-pressure-builds-as-no-sign-of-festive-flu-letting-up/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T10:05:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flu cases in hospital have already surpassed last year’s peak as festive infections “flood” hospitals early this winter. Latest weekly figures published today show one in 18 hospital beds are being taken up or closed by a festive bug, with 2,504 beds alone being taken up by flu patients – an increase of almost half on […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Latest report on child asthma deaths highlights stark impact of deprivation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=157037</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/latest-report-on-child-asthma-deaths-highlights-stark-impact-of-deprivation/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T09:40:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Children from the most deprived areas are four times more likely to die from an asthma attack, a charity has warned. Asthma + Lung UK called on the Government to take ‘urgent action’ to prevent child asthma deaths including tackling poor housing conditions and air pollution. It comes as the National Child Mortality Database Report
The post Latest report on child asthma deaths highlights stark impact of deprivation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Closed consultation: Our plan to improve the lives of people with ME/CFS (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/our-plan-to-improve-the-lives-of-people-with-mecfs-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/our-plan-to-improve-the-lives-of-people-with-mecfs-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T09:32:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government has written a plan to support people who live with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultation outcome: Improving the experiences of people with ME/CFS: interim delivery plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/improving-the-experiences-of-people-with-mecfs-interim-delivery-plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/improving-the-experiences-of-people-with-mecfs-interim-delivery-plan"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T09:31:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're seeking your views on an interim delivery plan to improve the experiences and outcomes of people with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical Quizmas: What is causing these patients’ long faces?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=156156</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/clinical-quizmas-what-is-causing-these-patients-long-faces/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T09:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a bit of fun in the lead-up to Christmas we are asking if you can help diagnose some seasonal ailments in our Quizmas picture quiz. What are the diagnoses for the festive patients below? Click the answer boxes to find out. Note: ChatGPT was used to assist in the creation of these images
The post Clinical Quizmas: What is causing these patients’ long faces? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moorfields Eye Hospital selects MEDITECH Expanse EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=213855</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/12/moorfields-eye-hospital-selects-meditech-expanse-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-12-19T08:30:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moorfields Eye Hospital NHS Foundation Trust is to implement MEDITECH’s Expanse electronic patient record in its 20 locations around London.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4542 - Veeam Releases September 2024 Security Bulletin]]></title>
        <id>85825aaa-e2f2-4a84-a65c-6988f7db87fa</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4542"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T15:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security bulletin addresses critical severity vulnerabilities affecting Backup & Replication, One, Server Provider Console, and other Veeam product lines
 Security bulletin addresses critical severity vulnerabilities affecting Backup & Replication, One, Server Provider Console, and other Veeam product lines
 Updated: 05 Sep 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4541 - Zyxel Releases Multiple Security Advisories]]></title>
        <id>e5f08660-ed81-435d-a34c-0dc21ea1cf25</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4541"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T14:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisories address vulnerabilities in Zyxel firewalls, APs, extenders, and security router devices
 Advisories address vulnerabilities in Zyxel firewalls, APs, extenders, and security router devices
 Updated: 04 Sep 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4540 - Fortra Releases Security Advisories for FileCatalyst Workflow]]></title>
        <id>18401ee8-6a00-412f-89b8-05ea56eb9a97</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4540"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T15:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisories address two vulnerabilities, one rated as critical and the other as high severity
 Advisories address two vulnerabilities, one rated as critical and the other as high severity
 Updated: 28 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4539 - Google Releases Security Updates for Chrome]]></title>
        <id>74ab7663-66c2-40c7-acbf-7c60ea2baa00</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4539"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security update includes one exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome
 Security update includes one exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome
 Updated: 22 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4537 - Microsoft Releases August 2024 Security Updates]]></title>
        <id>109955e9-5dd3-4129-8431-57e20b76a8c4</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4537"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products fix 90 vulnerabilities, including ten zero-day vulnerabilities
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products fix 90 vulnerabilities, including ten zero-day vulnerabilities
 Updated: 14 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4538 - Adobe Releases Security Updates for Acrobat and Reader]]></title>
        <id>f23828e8-5b9e-4a50-942d-224ccd27ffaa</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4538"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Successful exploitation of the critical vulnerabilities could lead to ACE or privilege escalation
 Successful exploitation of the critical vulnerabilities could lead to ACE or privilege escalation
 Updated: 14 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4536 - SAP Releases Security Update for BusinessObjects]]></title>
        <id>63eb5ba8-c97f-4427-9353-262e32dc8d76</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4536"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T11:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Successful exploitation could lead to full system compromise
 Successful exploitation could lead to full system compromise
 Updated: 14 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4535 - Roundcube Releases Security Updates for Webmail]]></title>
        <id>004b7f6c-b964-430f-bb6a-c3f6ec8eb34a</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4535"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T13:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Updates address three vulnerabilities that could lead to theft of emails and contacts
 Updates address three vulnerabilities that could lead to theft of emails and contacts
 Updated: 08 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>