<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html</id>
    <title>Industry Feed</title>
    <updated>2024-09-08T04:12:22.745Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great North Run set to inspire thousands to take up running with NHS couch to 5K]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=252360</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/09/great-north-run-set-to-inspire-thousands-to-take-up-running-with-nhs-couch-to-5k/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T23:01:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[National running events like the London Marathon and Great North Run inspire thousands of armchair viewers to get healthy, according to new figures released by the NHS today. Visits to the NHS couch to 5K webpage are expected to rise significantly this weekend as the Great North Run takes place in Newcastle. Analysis by NHS […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA safe working handbook offers practices blueprint to step up collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1887582</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-safe-working-handbook-offers-practices-blueprint-step-collective-action/article/1887582"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T15:59:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices have been handed a blueprint to step up collective action after the BMA published a handbook spelling out how to implement its safe working advice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behind the headlines: GPs and 10 minute appointments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=153045</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/behind-the-headlines/behind-the-headlines-gps-and-10-minute-appointments/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T15:29:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse scrutinises a headline by the Daily Mail saying that GPs are ‘putting patients at risk’ by ‘rushing’ them with 10 minute appointments. Another day, another Daily Mail headline attacking GPs. This week, the issue at hand is patients being put at risk by GPs rushing them out in 10-minute appointments. The data comes from
The post Behind the headlines: GPs and 10 minute appointments appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs face patchy shared-care arrangements for ADHD, researchers warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152933</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gps-face-patchy-shared-care-arrangements-for-adhd-researchers-warn/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T15:19:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Regional variation on shared-care arrangements for ADHD medicine prescribing must be addressed to ensure equitable access, say researchers. A survey of 750 people from across the country, including commissioners, healthcare professionals and people with lived experience of ADHD has highlighted specific challenges that GPs face in prescribing medication. Reporting in the British Journal of General
The post GPs face patchy shared-care arrangements for ADHD, researchers warn appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA advises GP practices to ‘cease’ all non-contractual work and limit appointments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=153041</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/2024-25-gp-contract/bma-advises-gp-practices-to-cease-all-non-contractual-work-and-limit-appointments/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T14:31:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has published ‘safe-working guidance’ for GP practices which it said would lead to a ‘fall’ in appointment availability and some patients having to be seen elsewhere. The advice includes ‘ceasing’ ‘all non-contractual work’ and ‘diverting’ resources ‘to core services’. The BMA’s GP Committee for England said this comes as ‘GPs and practices are
The post BMA advises GP practices to ‘cease’ all non-contractual work and limit appointments appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[News story: Paul Corrigan appointed by the government to help shape health plans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/paul-corrigan-appointed-by-the-government-to-help-shape-health-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/paul-corrigan-appointed-by-the-government-to-help-shape-health-plans"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T14:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paul Corrigan brings extensive sector experience and will work on emerging policy to support the government on successfully delivering better health services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult Social Care Learning and Development Support Scheme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-learning-and-development-support-scheme</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-learning-and-development-support-scheme"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T12:51:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information for adult social care employers in England on learning and development support for the financial year 2024 to 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full-fibre radio network to help prevent loss of life on UK’s coastline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203979</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/full-fibre-radio-network-to-help-prevent-loss-of-life-on-uks-coastline/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T12:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Maritime and Coastguard Agency has launched a £175 million search and rescue radio network to prevent loss of life on the coast and at sea.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VR project aims to improve mental health for homeless]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203415</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/vr-project-aims-to-improve-mental-health-for-homeless/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T12:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A virtual reality initiative has been launched to help homeless people improve their mental health  and prepare for independent living.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virtual ward company Doccla secures £35m in Series B funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204625</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/virtual-ward-company-doccla-secures-35m-in-series-b-funding/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T10:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Virtual ward and remote monitoring technology provider Doccla has announced that it has secured £35 million in Series B funding.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs told not to sign contract variation notice during NHSE dispute]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152892</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/2024-25-gp-contract/gps-told-not-to-sign-contract-variation-notice-during-nhse-dispute/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T09:55:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been advised not to sign a recent variation notice to their terms in protest against NHS England’s imposition of this year’s contract. A number of LMCs shared a message saying that GP practices may ‘at any time, but particularly during collective action’ opt not to sign the variation notice, which was recently published
The post GPs told not to sign contract variation notice during NHSE dispute appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From left behind to leading the way: a blueprint for transforming child health services in England]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/from-left-behind-to-leading-the-way-a-blueprint-for-transforming-child-health-services-in-england.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/from-left-behind-to-leading-the-way-a-blueprint-for-transforming-child-health-services-in-england.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T09:53:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Paediatrics and Child Health - This report finds that children are waiting longer than adults to access health care, paediatric services are not recovering at the same rates as adult services, and there is a growing gap between demand and capacity. This has coincided with an unprecedented increased demand for children’s health services, which is forecast to...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS chief signs pledge to support armed forces and veterans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=252352</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/09/nhs-chief-signs-pledge-to-support-armed-forces-and-veterans/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T09:38:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The chief executive of the NHS has signed a public pledge to people in the armed forces and their families to ensure they get the support they need from local health services. Amanda Pritchard signed the Armed Forces Covenant on behalf of NHS England at the Royal Hospital in Chelsea yesterday (Thursday 5 September 2024). […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National rollout for advice and guidance LES could be worth £130m a year to GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1887322</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/national-rollout-advice-guidance-les-worth-130m-year-gps/article/1887322"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T09:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices across England could earn around £130m a year from advice and guidance if a locally-agreed deal in part of Yorkshire was rolled out nationwide, GPonline can reveal.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical language used after pregnancy loss adds to trauma, researchers warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152948</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/clinical-language-used-after-pregnancy-loss-adds-to-trauma-researchers-warn/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T09:01:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The language used by healthcare professionals to describe pregnancy loss exacerbates the grief and trauma experienced by some individuals, a report has concluded. A team from University College London has developed a set of recommendations to guide healthcare professionals when interacting with those experiencing pregnancy loss. The guidance is based on a study of 290
The post Clinical language used after pregnancy loss adds to trauma, researchers warn appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MHRA warns men taking valproate to use contraception over small risk to children]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=153021</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/mhra-warns-men-taking-valproate-to-use-contraception-over-small-risk-to-children/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T08:49:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK medicines regulator has warned that men taking valproate and their partners should use effective contraception, because of a small increased risk of harm to children if the drug is used by a father at conception. Healthcare professionals should inform male patients about this ‘newly identified risk’ at their next routine treatment review and
The post MHRA warns men taking valproate to use contraception over small risk to children appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DigitalHealth.London reveals latest Accelerator programme cohort]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204619</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/digitalhealth-london-reveals-latest-accelerator-programme-cohort/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T07:30:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DigitalHealth.London has announced the latest 17 digital health companies selected for its accelerator programme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: How much are GPs earning, AI doctors, GP exam ruling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1887390</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-gps-earning-ai-doctors-gp-exam-ruling/article/1887390"/>
        <updated>2024-09-06T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In our regular news review the GPonline team discusses the latest data on GP earnings and expenses, a recent report on AI in the NHS and a High Court ruling on RCGP exam resists.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4542 - Veeam Releases September 2024 Security Bulletin]]></title>
        <id>85825aaa-e2f2-4a84-a65c-6988f7db87fa</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4542"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T15:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security bulletin addresses critical severity vulnerabilities affecting Backup & Replication, One, Server Provider Console, and other Veeam product lines
 Security bulletin addresses critical severity vulnerabilities affecting Backup & Replication, One, Server Provider Console, and other Veeam product lines
 Updated: 05 Sep 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical conundrum: An incidental finding of calcified coronary arteries on lung cancer screening]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152938</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/clinical-conundrum-an-incidental-finding-of-calcified-coronary-arteries-on-lung-cancer-screening/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T15:18:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the next of our series, GP Dr Matthew Molloy considers this hypothetical case of a man with a finding of calcified coronary arteries after lung cancer screening You see a 62-year-old man who has recently undergone a CT scan, having been identified as high risk for lung cancer as part of the new lung
The post Clinical conundrum: An incidental finding of calcified coronary arteries on lung cancer screening appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spotting the early signs of burnout: A guide for GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152926</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/spotting-the-early-signs-of-burnout-a-guide-for-gps/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T15:16:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical psychologist Dr Matt Slavin on the early symptoms of burnout that GPs should keep an eye out for, and how to tackle them ‘I was running on fumes but not even aware of it,’ David* shared in our final session, reflecting on his experience of burnout. ‘I was just putting one foot in front
The post Spotting the early signs of burnout: A guide for GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Concerns over go live date for Northampton maternity service EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204555</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/concerns-over-go-live-date-for-northampton-maternity-service-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T12:37:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lack of implementation date for a maternity EPR at Northampton General Hospital poses “potential operational risks”, a board report says.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘High-performing’ GP practice to be taken over by private provider]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152907</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/high-performing-gp-practice-to-be-taken-over-by-private-provider/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T10:48:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A ‘high-performing’ practice in Cambridge is to be taken over by a private provider after its GP partners handed back their contract due to ‘increasing financial difficulties’. Earlier this year, East Barnwell Health Centre’s four GP partners were forced to make the ‘devastating’ decision to hand back the contract for their training practice, and told
The post ‘High-performing’ GP practice to be taken over by private provider appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winners and losers from the GP funding uplift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152901</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/practice-personal-finance/winners-and-losers-from-the-gp-funding-uplift/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T10:40:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP funding in England has this month seen an injection of £311m to help practices pass on pay rises to staff – but many may struggle to do so. Here, Eliza Parr looks at this year’s ‘winners and losers’. In July, the Government accepted the recommendations of the Review Body on Doctors’ and Dentists’ Remuneration
The post Winners and losers from the GP funding uplift appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203969</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-169/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T10:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s Coffee Time Briefing covers adaptive brain stimulation for Parkinson’s disease and a £400m investment in UK clinical trials.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency steroid kits should be provided routinely in adrenal insufficiency, says NICE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152739</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/diabetes-endocrinology/emergency-steroid-kits-should-be-provided-routinely-in-adrenal-insufficiency-says-nice/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T10:17:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People with adrenal insufficiency should be issued with emergency kits containing steroid injections to avoid hospital admission, NICE has recommended. Two or three kits should be provided to people with primary and secondary adrenal insufficiency containing an intramuscular hydrocortisone injection, syringes and needles and easy to understand instructions. Training should also be provided to patients,
The post Emergency steroid kits should be provided routinely in adrenal insufficiency, says NICE appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to launch ePMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204417</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/cwm-taf-morgannwg-university-health-board-to-launch-epma/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T10:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board has selected Nervecentre to deliver an electronic prescribing and medicines administration system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National Shortlist of Exceptional NHS Staff Announced]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=252204</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/09/national-shortlist-of-exceptional-nhs-staff-announced/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T09:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, the NHS has announced its 2024 NHS Parliamentary Awards shortlist. The shortlisted staff, who have gone above and beyond in pursuit of excellence, will now advance to the final stage of the awards. The winners in each of the ten categories will be announced at the award ceremony in Westminster on Monday, 14 October 2024. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs face collective action penalty under 'discriminatory' ICB rule, warns LMC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1887074</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-face-collective-action-penalty-discriminatory-icb-rule-warns-lmc/article/1887074"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices taking part in collective action could be penalised by 'discriminatory' ICB rules on locally-commissioned services, an LMC has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Official Statistics: Adult social care in England, monthly statistics: September 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-september-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-september-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Official statistics on a range of topics including occupancy and infection control measures in adult social care settings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Innovate UK U-turns on funding for female tech founders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204499</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/innovate-uk-u-turns-on-funding-for-female-tech-founders/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-05T07:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Innovate UK has reversed its decision to slash 50% of grants for the ‘Women in Innovation’ awards, following a campaign by female founders.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First ever drug approved for NHS patients with life-threatening genetic, tumour-causing disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=252170</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/09/first-ever-drug-approved-for-nhs-patients-with-life-threatening-genetic-tumour-causing-disease/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T23:01:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS patients in England with a rare genetic disease that causes tumours in major organs, including the brain and spine, can now benefit from the first-ever therapy which could shrink their tumours to help them avoid high-risk surgery. In clinical trials of belzutifan, 95% of patients did not experience any growth in their tumours in […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First phase of polio campaign concludes successfully in Gaza]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:7b8e058f-b03f-4620-880d-34bc7e81df11</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/04-09-2024-first-phase-of-polio-campaign-concludes-successfully-in-gaza"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T20:42:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 187 000 children under ten years of age were vaccinated with novel oral polio vaccine type 2 (nOPV2) in central Gaza during the first phase of a two-round polio vaccination campaign, conducted between 1–3 September 2024. Vaccination coverage in this phase exceeded the initial estimated target of 157 000 children due to population movement towards central Gaza, and expanded coverage in areas outside the humanitarian pause zone.  

To ensure no child is missed in this area, polio vaccination will continue at four large health facilities in central Gaza over the next few days. Vaccine doses have been supplied to these sites to meet any additional needs. 

“It has been extremely encouraging to see thousands of children being able to access polio vaccines, with the support of their resilie…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Haemophilus influenzae type b (Hib): revised recommendations for the prevention of secondary cases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/haemophilus-influenzae-type-b-hib-revised-recommendations-for-the-prevention-of-secondary-cases</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/haemophilus-influenzae-type-b-hib-revised-recommendations-for-the-prevention-of-secondary-cases"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T16:44:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[These guidelines on the prevention of secondary cases have been developed following a review of the epidemiology of invasive Hib disease.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police called after threatening calls to health centre]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1887193</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/police-called-threatening-calls-health-centre/article/1887193"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T15:50:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police were called to a health centre this week after it received phone calls threatening staff and property, with a man later arrested.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs warned against using AI for complaint responses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152893</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/gps-warned-against-using-ai-for-complaint-responses/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T15:25:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should avoid using AI for complaint responses due to the risk of ‘inaccuracy’ or ‘insincerity’, a medical defence organisation has warned.  The Medical Defence Union (MDU) has put out guidance this week which said that ‘some doctors are turning to artificial intelligence programs’ such as ChatGPT to ‘draft complaint responses for them’.  But the
The post GPs warned against using AI for complaint responses appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Popular GP practice set for takeover by large provider on APMS contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1887186</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/popular-gp-practice-set-takeover-large-provider-apms-contract/article/1887186"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T15:17:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A popular and successful training practice whose partners were forced to hand back their contract earlier this year will be taken over by a large provider under an APMS contract from October.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO launches global framework for understanding the origins of new or re-emerging pathogens]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:7a5bf437-d5f8-4719-bcf7-93cfb1b04e8e</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/04-09-2024-who-launches-global-framework-for-understanding-the-origins-of-new-or-re-emerging-pathogens"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T15:02:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the support of the Scientific Advisory Group for the Origins of Novel Pathogens (SAGO), the World Health Organization (WHO) has published a global framework to help Member States comprehensively investigate the origins of new and re-emerging pathogens. While there are a number of tools available for investigating infectious disease outbreaks, this is the first unified, structured approach to investigating the origins of a novel pathogen. This framework aims to fill that gap by providing a comprehensive set of scientific investigations and studies. It is the first version of a “how-to” guide that will be updated as and when needed, based on feedback from users.
As each outbreak and pandemic demonstrates, human and animal health is threatened by the increasing risk of the emergence of k…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4541 - Zyxel Releases Multiple Security Advisories]]></title>
        <id>e5f08660-ed81-435d-a34c-0dc21ea1cf25</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4541"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T14:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisories address vulnerabilities in Zyxel firewalls, APs, extenders, and security router devices
 Advisories address vulnerabilities in Zyxel firewalls, APs, extenders, and security router devices
 Updated: 04 Sep 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Those two doctors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152868</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/those-two-doctors/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T14:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Offering up his own take on Pulse’s writing competition, editor Jaimie Kaffash reflects on the two doctors that left a lasting impact on him I’ve just finished my first read of the entries for the writing competition. The response was fantastic, and I genuinely enjoyed reading all of them – whether it was about That
The post Those two doctors appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former Operose GP practices set for contract retender following ‘serious breach’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152873</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/former-operose-gp-practices-set-for-contract-retender-following-serious-breach/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T14:02:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A London ICB has decided to launch a retender process for a number of NHS GP contracts – formerly run by a subsidiary of Operose Health – which had been subject to a ‘serious breach’. North Central London ICB has now decided that the APMS contracts for the five GP practices in London operated by
The post Former Operose GP practices set for contract retender following ‘serious breach’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital NHS Health Checks to be piloted at three councils in 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204415</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/digital-nhs-health-checks-to-be-piloted-at-three-councils-in-2025/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T12:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital NHS Health Checks to identify risk of cardiovascular disease will be piloted in three councils in England before nationwide rollout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just living and coping: the cost-of-living crisis and the nation’s mental health]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/just-living-and-coping-the-cost-of-living-crisis-and-the-nations-mental-health.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/just-living-and-coping-the-cost-of-living-crisis-and-the-nations-mental-health.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T11:03:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Centre for Mental Health - The cost-of-living crisis has had a profound impact on people with mental health problems, with many struggling to get by day-to-day at the expense of their health. This report draws together research commissioned by Mind to explore the impact of the cost-of-living crisis. The Centre’s researchers heard from 500 people across England and Wales, many...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Ionising Radiation (Medical Exposure) Regulations 2017: guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ionising-radiation-medical-exposure-regulations-2017-guidance</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/ionising-radiation-medical-exposure-regulations-2017-guidance"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T11:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance on the Ionising Radiation (Medical Exposure) Regulations 2017 for employers and health professionals who carry out medical radiological procedures.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new fiscal model to deliver prevention]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/a-new-fiscal-model-to-deliver-prevention.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/a-new-fiscal-model-to-deliver-prevention.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T10:49:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Blair Institute for Global Change - This paper argues for the introduction of a national health insurance model in the UK to support a mission-led approach to growth and health, provide stability and predictability to health budgets, and fix a system that has been funded by short-sighted investments to plug short-term gaps. It argues that by formally and fiscally...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data show marked increase in annual cholera deaths]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:6db7eeb4-b0a8-4e30-8f78-8af936d11919</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/04-09-2024-data-show-marked-increase-in-annual-cholera-deaths"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T10:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) has published global cholera statistics for 2023, showing an increase in cases and deaths.  
The number of reported cholera cases increased by 13% and deaths by 71% in 2023 compared to 2022. Over 4000 people died last year from a disease that is preventable and easily treatable. 
Forty-five countries reported cases, an increase from 44 the previous year and 35 in 2021. Thirty-eight per cent of the reported cases were among children under five years of age.  
Cholera is an acute intestinal infection spread through contaminated food and water. Communities with limited access to sanitation are most affected. 
Conflict, climate change, inadequate safe water and sanitation, poverty, underdevelopment, and population displacement due to emerging and re-emerging…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy Pressures Survey 2024: funding and profitability report]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/pharmacy-pressures-survey-2024-funding-and-profitability-report.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/pharmacy-pressures-survey-2024-funding-and-profitability-report.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T10:27:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Community Pharmacy England - This report confirms the severe financial pressures putting community pharmacies at risk of closure, threatening patient care and access to services across England. Spiralling costs and workload coupled with a 30% funding cut in real terms since 2015 mean too many pharmacies are struggling to stay afloat. Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI tool can identify patients at risk of heart-related deaths]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204213</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/ai-tool-can-identify-patients-at-risk-of-heart-related-deaths/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T10:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An AI algorithm can identify those at highest risk of conditions leading to heart-related death, according to researchers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five GP contracts put out to tender after 'serious breach' by private provider]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1887088</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/five-gp-contracts-put-tender-serious-breach-private-provider/article/1887088"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T09:32:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Five GP practice contracts held by a major private provider will be opened to new bidders after a 'serious breach' of their terms, NHS officials have confirmed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Republic of Korea and WHO discuss joint priorities, challenges and trends around global health]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5c8b0528-cdb0-4a02-b86c-91e1c6b1b572</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/29-08-2024-the-republic-of-korea-and-who-discuss-joint-priorities--challenges-and-trends-around-global-health"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T09:19:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) and the Republic of Korea have a long-standing partnership spanning over 75 years. As a result of their fruitful collaboration, there has been significant progress in health and development all around the world. The Republic of Korea has gone from being a donor-recipient country to a donor-country and is now a leader in global health and playing a critical role on the world stage.
Dr Catharina Boehme, Assistant Director-General for External Relations and Governance (WHO) and Dr Hye-Jin Kim, Deputy Minister for Planning and Coordination (Ministry of Health and Welfare, Republic of Korea), together with counterparts from WHO and the Government of the Republic of Korea.
To further strengthen this partnership and our commitment to working jointly to address …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS launches £1.5bn tender to provide computer hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204393</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/nhs-launches-1-5bn-tender-to-provide-computer-hardware/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-04T07:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS has launched a joint procurement worth up to £1.5 billion for suppliers to provide a variety of computer hardware.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Number of GP practices fell by 20% in a decade, researchers find]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152826</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/number-of-gp-practices-fell-by-20-in-a-decade-researchers-find/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T22:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The number of GP practices in England fell by 20% in a decade, while average list size expanded by 40%, a new study has found. The analysis, published in BMJ Open, found that between 2013 and 2023, the number of practices fell from 8,044 to 6,419 – an average loss of 178 practices per year.
The post Number of GP practices fell by 20% in a decade, researchers find appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General practice 'at tipping point' as GPs per patient drop 15% in a decade]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1887038</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-practice-at-tipping-point-gps-per-patient-drop-15-decade/article/1887038"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T22:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice in England is at a 'tipping point' - with GPs per 1,000 patients down 15% and the number of practices reduced by a fifth over the past 10 years, a study shows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practices set to register thousands of early-release prisoners over coming weeks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1887049</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/practices-set-register-thousands-early-release-prisoners-coming-weeks/article/1887049"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T16:26:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice has been told to prepare to register around 5,500 prisoners set for early release from prison over the next two months as part of a government drive to tackle prison overcrowding.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A guide to the new medical examiner system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152819</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/a-guide-to-the-new-medical-examiner-system/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T15:03:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the new medical examiner system starting next week, Dr Grant Ingrams explains what this means for GPs and how they can prepare From 9 September the processes to be followed after death of a patient are undergoing the greatest shake up since the Births and Deaths Registration Act 1953 – including the introduction of
The post A guide to the new medical examiner system appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sexual and reproductive health competency framework for nurses caring for women in prison]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/-sexual-and-reproductive-health-competency-framework-for-nurses-caring-for-women-in-prison-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/-sexual-and-reproductive-health-competency-framework-for-nurses-caring-for-women-in-prison-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T15:02:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Nursing - This competencies framework has been developed for nurses, midwives, and those supporting nursing teams, who provide sexual and reproductive health care to women in prison. It takes account of nursing teams who may have limited experience caring for pregnant women. Framework More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England sets out virtual ward requirements to ‘reduce variation’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152840</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/nhs-england-sets-out-virtual-ward-requirements-to-reduce-variation/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T14:45:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has set out comprehensive guidance on virtual wards in order to reduce the ‘variation’ which resulted from their ‘rapid expansion’.  Earlier this year, NHSE committed to further expanding the use of virtual wards following an evaluation in the South East region which showed more than £10m savings.  A new ‘operational framework’ has now
The post NHS England sets out virtual ward requirements to ‘reduce variation’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs told to prepare to register early-release prisoners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152816</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/gps-told-to-prepare-to-register-early-release-prisoners/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T13:18:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has called on GPs to support the early release of prisoners under a new Government scheme.  The Ministry of Justice scheme is designed to help tackle prison capacity issues, and eligible prisoners will be released in England between 10 September and 22 October.  Yesterday, NHS England wrote to GP practices asking for their
The post GPs told to prepare to register early-release prisoners appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: NHS injury costs recovery scheme: April 2024 to March 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-injury-costs-recovery-scheme-april-2024-to-march-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-injury-costs-recovery-scheme-april-2024-to-march-2025"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T12:54:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data on the funds collected by the Compensation Recovery Unit and funds paid to the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England to adopt new cyber security framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204301</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/nhs-england-to-adopt-new-cyber-security-framework/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T12:30:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The National Data Guardian and NHS England have announced a new cyber resilience framework for health and social care organisations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time to care: findings from a nationally representative survey of experiences at the end of life in England and Wales]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/time-to-care-findings-from-a-nationally-representative-survey-of-experiences-at-the-end-of-life-in-e.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/time-to-care-findings-from-a-nationally-representative-survey-of-experiences-at-the-end-of-life-in-e.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T11:31:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marie Curie - This report sets out the findings from a national post-bereavement survey, the QUALYCARE survey, conducted in 2023 across England and Wales. The aim was to describe the outcomes, experiences, and use of care services by people affected by dying, death, and bereavement in England and Wales. The report reveals that in England and Wales one in three...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203939</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-168/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T10:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing covers a raft of new rehab technologies at Nottingham University Hospitals, plus a new health app for women]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203939</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T10:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing covers a raft of new rehab technologies at Nottingham University Hospitals, plus a new health app for women]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Unplugged: Taking a stand against racism in digital health]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204119</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/digital-health-unplugged-taking-a-stand-against-racism-in-digital-health/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T10:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tammy Lovell is joined on Digital Health Unplugged by the founders of the Equity Charter to discuss how to tackle racism in digital health.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the Month – what’s underlying this unusual case of persistent diarrhoea?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152486</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/case-of-the-month-whats-underlying-this-unusual-case-of-persistent-diarrhoea/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T09:47:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest in our monthly series, Dr Nicolas Alexander asks readers to suggest what’s causing persistent diarrhoea in this otherwise well woman. Put your answers in the comments. You see a 34-year-old female patient with a two-week history of diarrhoea, which she explains started suddenly a few days after returning from holiday in Switzerland.
The post Case of the Month – what’s underlying this unusual case of persistent diarrhoea? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs unable to meet end-of-life care demands, charity warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152805</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gps-unable-to-meet-end-of-life-care-demands-charity-warns/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T09:34:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure on GP services has resulted in an inability to meet the needs of patients at the end of their life, a report has warned. The findings from a nationally-representative survey of people affected by dying, death and bereavement in England and Wales, run by end-of-life charity Marie Curie, revealed that many respondents ‘felt support
The post GPs unable to meet end-of-life care demands, charity warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action to accelerate as BMA unveils safe working guidance handbook]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886933</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/collective-action-accelerate-bma-unveils-safe-working-guidance-handbook/article/1886933"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T09:27:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action in general practice will 'ramp up' as the BMA publishes a safe working guidance handbook next week, the union's England GP committee chair has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New global guidance aims to curb antibiotic pollution from manufacturing]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:4e355564-dbfa-4ade-8d49-b5e357cbcc8f</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/03-09-2024-new-global-guidance-aims-to-curb-antibiotic-pollution-from-manufacturing"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T07:46:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) has published its first-ever guidance on antibiotic pollution from manufacturing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“No specific plans to add social care to the DMA”, says NHSE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204173</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/no-specific-plans-to-add-social-care-to-the-dma-says-nhse/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-03T07:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has said there are no plans to add social care to the Digital Maturity Assessment (DMA) in 2025, despite calls for its inclusion.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients have fewer but longer GP consultations, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152795</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/consultations/patients-have-fewer-but-longer-gp-consultations-study-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T23:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients have fewer but longer consultations with their GP, a new study of over 500 million anonymised electronic health records has found. The study published in the British Journal of General Practice found that the number of times a year that a patient had a consultation with their GP – face to face or by
The post Patients have fewer but longer GP consultations, study finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP workload per patient surged by 50% in past 20 years, study reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886889</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-workload-per-patient-surged-50-past-20-years-study-reveals/article/1886889"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T23:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP workload per patient rose by nearly 50% between 2005 and 2019 according to a study that sheds new light on rising pressure on general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UNICEF issues emergency tender to secure mpox vaccines for crisis-hit countries in collaboration with Africa CDC, Gavi and WHO]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:7c777e47-6193-44d3-81da-69e707c7efe6</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/31-08-2024-unicef-issues-emergency-tender-to-secure-mpox-vaccines-for-crisis-hit-countries-in-collaboration-with-africa-cdc--gavi-and-who"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T19:56:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UNICEF today announced that it has issued an emergency tender for the procurement of mpox vaccines. Vaccines can play a critical role in containing the mpox outbreak which was declared a public health emergency by both the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC) and the World Health Organization (WHO).
The UNICEF tender is issued to help secure mpox vaccines for the hardest hit countries in collaboration with Africa CDC, Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, WHO, the Pan American Health Organization and other partners. This collaboration to increase access and timely allocation also includes working together to facilitate donations of vaccines from existing stockpiles in high-income countries with the aim of containing the ongoing transmission of mpox.
Under the emergency tend…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Code of practice for the international recruitment of health and social care personnel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/code-of-practice-for-the-international-recruitment-of-health-and-social-care-personnel</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/code-of-practice-for-the-international-recruitment-of-health-and-social-care-personnel"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T16:14:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out the principles and best practice benchmarks health and social care employers and recruitment agencies must follow to ensure effective, ethical international recruitment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CPD: An introduction to genetic haemochromatosis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152765</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/cpd-an-introduction-to-genetic-haemochromatosis/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T16:01:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs Dr Susan Hancock and Dr Doug Jenkinson and ANP Diogo Gomes provide an overview of genetic haemochromatosis, including how timely diagnosis can support early intervention and optimal management Module summary Genetic haemochromatosis (GH) is a relatively common but under-diagnosed condition. Due to the generic nature of early symptoms, the condition can be missed, misdiagnosed
The post CPD: An introduction to genetic haemochromatosis appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will Generation Z save the NHS?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152598</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/will-generation-z-save-the-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T15:31:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Seema Haider on whether or not the newest generation of doctors will break the patterns of general practice, and change the face of the NHS Recently I met up with my medical school friends and, as expected, the NHS was high on the agenda. As we reminisced about our experiences of training, recurrent themes
The post Will Generation Z save the NHS? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: ministerial gifts, hospitality, travel and meetings, January to March 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-ministerial-gifts-hospitality-travel-and-meetings-january-to-march-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-ministerial-gifts-hospitality-travel-and-meetings-january-to-march-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T15:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data on gifts that ministers gave and received, their external meetings and any overseas travel.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: senior officials’ business expenses, hospitality and meetings, January to March 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-senior-officials-business-expenses-hospitality-and-meetings-january-to-march-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-senior-officials-business-expenses-hospitality-and-meetings-january-to-march-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T15:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All data on senior officials’ business expenses, external meetings and hospitality.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: special advisers' gifts, hospitality and meetings, January to March 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-special-advisers-gifts-hospitality-and-meetings-january-to-march-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-special-advisers-gifts-hospitality-and-meetings-january-to-march-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T15:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data on gifts and hospitality received by special advisers, and meetings they attended with senior media figures.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices refusing call data handover ‘risk contract breach’, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152737</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gp-practices-refusing-call-data-handover-risk-contract-breach-bma-warns/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T13:48:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices cannot refuse to provide NHS England with their patient call data next month as this would ‘risk breaching their contract’, the BMA has warned. The 2024/25 GP contract was amended to require practices to provide digital telephony data on eight metrics through a national data extraction from October, for use by NHS England, ICBs and
The post GP practices refusing call data handover ‘risk contract breach’, BMA warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes to winter fuel payments put pensioners at risk, warns RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886878</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/changes-winter-fuel-payments-put-pensioners-risk-warns-rcgp/article/1886878"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T13:42:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New restrictions on winter fuel payments will leave thousands of pensioners at risk of developing illness from cold and damp conditions and add to GP workload, the RCGP has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Website launched to support people with undiagnosed gut issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203245</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/website-launches-to-support-diagnosis-and-people-with-gut-issues/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T12:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A website has been launched by healthcare organisations and charities to provide answers and diagnosis for gut problems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Priorities for the NHS workforce: the NHS trust perspective]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/priorities-for-the-nhs-workforce-the-nhs-trust-perspective.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/priorities-for-the-nhs-workforce-the-nhs-trust-perspective.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T11:20:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This briefing provides an overview of the following areas of NHS workforce policy: building an NHS fit for the future; pay; and culture and staff wellbeing. Briefing More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Community diagnostic centres: guidance for planning, design and implementation]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/community-diagnostic-centres-guidance-for-planning-design-and-implementation-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/community-diagnostic-centres-guidance-for-planning-design-and-implementation-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T11:10:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England - The national Community Diagnostic Centre (CDC) Programme is now in its third year and has approved 170 CDC sites across England. This guidance sets out next steps and best practice for systems on developing CDCs, including sections on commissioning, governance, engagement, regulatory and accreditation requirements, digital connectivity, workforce and pathway development. Guidance More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Same day emegency care: service specification]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/same-day-emegency-care-service-specification.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/same-day-emegency-care-service-specification.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T11:07:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England - Same day emergency care (SDEC) allows specialists, where appropriate, to assess, diagnose and treat patients on the same day of arrival who would otherwise have been admitted to hospital. This specification defines what should be delivered as part of the SDEC service. It includes links to reference documents and metrics for measurement (the desired outcomes and outputs)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is the use of privately funded health care on the rise?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/is-the-use-of-privately-funded-health-care-on-the-rise.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/is-the-use-of-privately-funded-health-care-on-the-rise.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T10:58:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This analysis explores trends in attitudes, activity and spending on privately funded health care. Where possible, it draws on data covering the whole of the UK, but some data sources exclude Northern Ireland or cover England only. While there may be some distinctive regional trends at play, The Health Foundation believes the findings generally hold true...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bupa launches ‘Netflix-style’ GP subscription service starting at £200 a year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152743</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/bupa-launches-netflix-style-gp-subscription-service-starting-at-200-a-year/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T10:57:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Private healthcare provider Bupa has announced a new ‘Netflix-style’ GP subscription service starting at around £200 a year. The company is offering a remote same-day GP appointment service for £16.99 a month. Those wanting the option of face-to-face appointments can sign up for £21.66 a month. Both models, which are only available to over-18s, offer
The post Bupa launches ‘Netflix-style’ GP subscription service starting at £200 a year appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diabetes drugs found to lower risk of dementia in large analysis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152741</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/diabetes-endocrinology/diabetes-drugs-found-to-lower-risk-of-dementia-in-large-analysis/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T10:23:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A class of drugs used to treat type 2 diabetes have been shown to be associated with a reduced risk of dementia, say researchers. Analysis of a large database of people aged 40-69 with type 2 diabetes found a 35% reduced risk of dementia associated with use of sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) compared with dipeptidyl peptidase-DPP-4
The post Diabetes drugs found to lower risk of dementia in large analysis appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The impact of hardship on primary schools and primary and community healthcare]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/the-impact-of-hardship-on-primary-schools-and-primary-and-community-healthcare.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/09/the-impact-of-hardship-on-primary-schools-and-primary-and-community-healthcare.html"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T10:08:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joseph Rowntree Foundation - This report investigates the impact hardship is having on the delivery of services in primary schools and primary and community healthcare setting such as GP surgeries. It finds hardship is adding demand, pressure, workload and stress in these public services. JRF states that an urgent action plan to tackle hardship is needed to lighten their load....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Derby Hospital adopts cloud-based telephony platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203957</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/royal-derby-hospital-adopts-cloud-based-telephony-platform/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T10:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[University Hospitals of Derby and Burton NHS Foundation Trust has partnered with Cinos to modernise its unified communications platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practices downsize to smaller PCN to sharpen localised, preventative care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886508</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/practices-downsize-smaller-pcn-sharpen-localised-preventative-care/article/1886508"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three GP practices have downsized to a smaller PCN because they believe it can help them deliver more preventative and patient-focused care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Birmingham and Solihull ICB launches digital social prescribing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203911</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/09/birmingham-and-solihull-icb-launches-digital-social-prescribing/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T07:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A digital social prescribing system has been launched across Birmingham and Solihull ICB to address growing demand for mental health support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices 'struggling to stay afloat' despite £311m contract boost]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886721</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-struggling-stay-afloat-despite-311m-contract-boost/article/1886721"/>
        <updated>2024-09-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices across England are struggling to stay afloat in the face of rising costs, the BMA has warned, as the government revealed new detail on an extra £311m in core funding as part of this year's contract uplift.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Landmark Moment As NHS Kicks Off First Ever RSV Jab Rollout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251944</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/09/landmark-moment-as-nhs-kicks-off-first-ever-rsv-jab-rollout/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T23:02:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS has started vaccinating people against Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV), for the first time in its history. RSV, a leading cause of infant mortality around the world, is a common cause of coughs and colds but can lead to severe lung infections like pneumonia and infant bronchiolitis, which are highly dangerous to older people and young children. As […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blood pressure checks at the dentist and optician to catch those at risk of heart attacks and strokes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251940</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/09/blood-pressure-checks-at-the-dentist-and-optician-to-catch-those-at-risk-of-heart-attacks-and-strokes/"/>
        <updated>2024-09-01T23:01:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS is trialling blood pressure checks at dentist and optometry appointments to help find people at hidden risks of stroke or heart attacks. The scheme which will be up and running in the coming months follows the success of NHS community pharmacy blood pressure checks, which has delivered more than a million checks in […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP partners saw 17% real-terms cut to income in one year, NHS figures reveal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152745</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-partners-saw-17-real-terms-cut-to-income-in-one-year-nhs-figures-reveal/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T15:35:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP partners and principals saw a 17% real-terms drop in income in one year, new official data has shown.  NHS data on GP earnings for 2022/23, published yesterday, showed that the average contractor income stood at £140,200. In cash terms, this is a drop of £13,200 (8.6%) on the previous year, but when adjusted for
The post GP partners saw 17% real-terms cut to income in one year, NHS figures reveal appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs need more support to manage rise in food allergies, say researchers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152678</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/gps-need-more-support-to-manage-rise-in-food-allergies-say-researchers/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T15:34:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs need urgent support and training to care for people with food allergies, according to researchers who found that numbers have doubled since 2008. An analysis published in The Lancet Public Health said the largest rise had been seen in young children but the reasons behind the trend were not clear. In a study of
The post GPs need more support to manage rise in food allergies, say researchers appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big questions: BMA-Government relations and what can GPs expect from CQC inspections?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152722</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/big-questions/big-questions-bma-government-relations-and-what-can-gps-expect-from-cqc-inspections/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T15:24:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse takes on August’s talking points – what is the relationship between the Government and BMA after a month of collective action, and what does the CQC’s latest announcement actually mean? What are relations like between the BMA and the Government? It was reiterated by the BMA in the run up to collective action that
The post Big questions: BMA-Government relations and what can GPs expect from CQC inspections? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile numbers of NHS staff compromised in cyber incident]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=204027</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/mobile-numbers-of-nhs-staff-compromised-in-cyber-incident/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T12:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile numbers of NHS staff have been compromised in a data breach at a software supplier which serves seven Scottish health boards.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New digital NHS Health Check to be trialled from early next year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152718</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/new-digital-nhs-health-check-to-be-trialled-from-early-next-year/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T11:32:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new digital version of the NHS Health Check will be piloted in selected areas early next year, the Government has announced. The Department of Health and Social Care has revealed today that a digital health check will be ‘ready for testing’ in early 2025, and will be available via the NHS App for patients
The post New digital NHS Health Check to be trialled from early next year appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA and RCGP condemn ‘unacceptable’ posters placed outside GP practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152697</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/bma-and-rcgp-condemn-unacceptable-posters-placed-outside-gp-practice/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T10:52:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have spoken out against ‘totally unacceptable’ abuse faced by a practice in Northern Ireland, after posters criticising GP access appeared outside the surgery overnight.   The Police Service of Northern Ireland told Pulse it was called to reports of posters being stuck on the Lisnaskea Health Centre building earlier this week, and that
The post BMA and RCGP condemn ‘unacceptable’ posters placed outside GP practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suicide rates highest seen in 25 years, official figures show]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152714</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/suicide-rates-highest-seen-in-25-years-official-figures-show/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T10:16:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Suicide should be treated as a public health crisis, a charity has warned after figures from the Office for National Statistics showed the highest rate since 1999. Official figures show there were 6,069 suicides registered in England and Wales in 2023, compared with 5,642 the previous year. It equates to 11.4 deaths per 100,000 people
The post Suicide rates highest seen in 25 years, official figures show appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacies in England to start issuing NHS electronic prescriptions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203995</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/more-than-200-pharmacies-in-england-to-start-issuing-nhs-electronic-prescriptions/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T10:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 200 pharmacies in England can now begin issuing prescriptions using the CLEO SOLO electronic prescribing system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices miss out on thousands of pounds in funding for care home patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886608</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-miss-thousands-pounds-funding-care-home-patients/article/1886608"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T09:25:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ICBs should help practices recoup thousands of pounds in funding they have missed out on for patients on their lists who live in care homes, an organisation representing practice managers has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP contract uplift detail confirmed in updated statement of financial entitlement]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886620</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-contract-uplift-detail-confirmed-updated-statement-financial-entitlement/article/1886620"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T08:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government has confirmed a 7.4% uplift to GP practices' global sum payments for 2024/25 and 6% increases to other elements of funding in an updated GMS contract statement of financial entitlement (SFE).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CPD: Key questions on diverticular disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152576</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/cpd-key-questions-on-diverticular-disease/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T08:45:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP specialist in gastroenterology Dr Kevin Barrett answers questions on the aetiology of diverticular disease and how it should be diagnosed and managed in primary care Learning objectives This module will enhance your understanding of: Q1. How common is diverticular disease? A. Diverticula are pouch-like protrusions of the mucosal wall of the gastrointestinal tract in
The post CPD: Key questions on diverticular disease appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statutory guidance: General Medical Services Statement of Financial Entitlements Directions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/general-medical-services-statement-of-financial-entitlements-directions</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/general-medical-services-statement-of-financial-entitlements-directions"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T08:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Directions for the NHS from the Secretary of State for Health and Social Care relating to payments for primary medical services contractors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movers and Shakers news roundup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203955</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/movers-and-shakers-news-roundup-51/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-30T07:30:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Movers and Shakers roundup includes a new interim chief nurse for NHS England's East of England regional team.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mirrors in leisure centres across the country to reflect important NHS reminder]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251900</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/mirrors-in-leisure-centres-across-the-country-to-reflect-important-nhs-reminder/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T23:01:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS messages prompting gym-goers to look out for potential signs of cancer will appear in the changing rooms of hundreds of Better leisure centres this summer. Stickers reminding people to check themselves regularly are set to feature on mirrors in more than 240 leisure centres run by Better, the UK’s largest leisure charitable social enterprise. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Over 130,000 people to benefit from life-saving health checks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/over-130000-people-to-benefit-from-life-saving-health-checks</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/over-130000-people-to-benefit-from-life-saving-health-checks"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T23:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 130,000 people across the country will be better protected from diseases such as heart disease, kidney disease and diabetes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO urges rapid access to mpox diagnostic tests, invites manufacturers to emergency review]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:9fdce8d4-82e5-439b-a66a-7ccd1bee3ada</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/29-08-2024-who-urges-rapid-access-to-mpox-diagnostic-tests--invites-manufacturers-to-emergency-review"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T16:47:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO has asked manufacturers of mpox in vitro diagnostics (IVDs) to submit an expression of interest for Emergency Use Listing (EUL). WHO has been in ongoing discussions with manufacturers about the need for effective diagnostics, particularly in low-income settings. The request for EUL expressions of interest by manufacturers is the latest development in these discussions.
Testing is key for people to get treatment and care as early as possible and prevent further spread. Since 2022, WHO has delivered around 150 000 diagnostic tests for mpox globally, of which over a quarter have gone to countries in the African Region. In the coming weeks, WHO will deliver another 30 000 tests to African countries. 
With as many as 1000 suspected cases reported in the Democratic Republic of the Congo alon…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices ‘lost tens of thousands of pounds’ due to care home patients underpayment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152708</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-practices-lost-tens-of-thousands-of-pounds-due-to-care-home-patients-underpayment/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T15:45:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices across the UK have been losing ‘tens of thousands’ of pounds due to a discrepancy in data that has led to a ‘chronic underpayment’ for care home patients, practice managers have revealed. The Institute of General Practice Management (IGPM) has said the problem is ‘widespread’, affecting surgeries in all nations and 70% of
The post GP practices ‘lost tens of thousands of pounds’ due to care home patients underpayment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices urged to share data with BMA to measure ‘impact of collective action’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152698</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/gp-practices-urged-to-share-data-with-bma-to-measure-impact-of-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T15:11:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices have been encouraged to share data with the BMA on how they are taking part in collective action every week. The union’s GP committee is collecting weekly data on GP participation in collective action, which it intends to use to ‘measure the impact’ of the action, and as a ‘lobbying tool’ with NHS
The post GP practices urged to share data with BMA to measure ‘impact of collective action’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: business appointment rules advice, January to March 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-business-appointment-rules-advice-january-to-march-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-business-appointment-rules-advice-january-to-march-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summaries of advice given under the business appointment rules to applicants at SCS2 and SCS1 level and equivalents.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update on the mpox outbreak – what GPs need to know]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152680</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/update-on-the-mpox-outbreak-what-gps-need-to-know/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T12:54:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP Dr Toni Hazell provides an update on the global mpox outbreak and explains current advice on identifying and managing suspected cases in the community Introduction and epidemiology Mpox is an infectious disease caused by the monkeypox virus (MPXV). The first human case was in 1970 in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), and
The post Update on the mpox outbreak – what GPs need to know appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Software powers hub and spoke dispensing at pharmacy group]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203549</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/software-powers-hub-and-spoke-dispensing-at-pharmacy-group/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T12:30:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy hub and spoke specialists Centred Solutions have supported Peak Pharmacy group to implement a dispensing hub.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real-terms GP partner income fell 17% in 2022/23, official data reveal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886524</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/real-terms-gp-partner-income-fell-17-2022-23-official-data-reveal/article/1886524"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T12:30:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Real-terms income before tax for GP partners in England slumped by 17% in 2022/23 according to official data published just weeks after the government backed a 6% pay uplift for the current financial year.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: NHS Choice Framework - what choices are available to you in your NHS care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/the-nhs-choice-framework</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/the-nhs-choice-framework"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T10:51:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out patients’ rights to choice in healthcare, where to find information to help choose, and how to complain if choice is not offered.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS leaders should stress importance of taking breaks to boost morale]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152515</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/nhs-leaders-should-stress-importance-of-taking-breaks-to-boost-morale/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T10:44:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The importance of rest and self-care should be clearly communicated and modelled ‘by leaders at every level’ in the NHS, an influential think-tank has said. Fair pay, quick resolution of industrial disputes and ring-fenced funding for staff mental health services are among 10 recommendations by the King’s Fund to tackle the NHS workforce crisis. In
The post NHS leaders should stress importance of taking breaks to boost morale appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Professor Kamila Hawthorne: ‘GP employment paradox must be resolved’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152640</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/professor-kamila-hawthorne-gp-employment-paradox-must-be-resolved/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T10:31:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP chair Professor Kamila Hawthorne on the damning state of the workforce for new GPs When GPs and patients are both frustrated with long waits for appointments that are too short, we should be welcoming newly qualified GPs into the workforce with open arms. But our latest polling has found the reality is very different.   Our survey
The post Professor Kamila Hawthorne: ‘GP employment paradox must be resolved’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Half of GP trainees about to qualify still looking for work, RCGP survey finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152654</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/exclusive-half-of-gp-trainees-about-to-qualify-still-looking-for-work-rcgp-survey-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T10:15:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Half of the GP trainees qualifying this summer are still looking for work, with over one third struggling to find an ‘appropriate role’, a new RCGP survey has found.  ST3 GP trainees taking part in the poll told the college that they feel ‘completely broken and demoralised’ due to the current job market, and
The post Exclusive: Half of GP trainees about to qualify still looking for work, RCGP survey finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI could speed skin cancer diagnosis, finds NHSE report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203771</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/ai-could-speed-skin-cancer-diagnosis-finds-nhse-report/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T10:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The use of autonomous AI could improve effectiveness and reducing wait times for skin cancer pathways, according to an NHS England report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review of NHS trust strategies for addressing health inequalities]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/review-of-nhs-trust-strategies-for-addressing-health-inequalities.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/review-of-nhs-trust-strategies-for-addressing-health-inequalities.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T09:50:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This review sets out the key components of a successful trust strategy for reducing health inequalities. It is based on desk-based research into a selection of published trust strategy documents and follow-up interviews to better understand the extent to which action on health inequalities has been prioritised. Briefing NHS Providers - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice facing ‘hostile atmosphere’ after campaign of harassment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886456</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practice-facing-hostile-atmosphere-campaign-harassment/article/1886456"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T09:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have condemned a campaign of harassment against a practice in Northern Ireland - warning that online abuse and posters placed on its premises had created a 'hostile atmosphere' for staff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid and South Essex selects SYNLAB for £900m pathology contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203803</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/mid-and-south-essex-selects-synlab-for-900m-pathology-contract/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-29T07:30:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mid and South Essex NHS FT has chosen SYNLAB as its pathology supplier, despite a cyber attack which caused disruption to services in London.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP partner income to rise 3% or less at nearly half of practices as uplift falls short]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886419</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-partner-income-rise-3-less-nearly-half-practices-uplift-falls-short/article/1886419"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T15:42:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP partner income will rise by 3% or less at nearly half of practices in England in 2024/25 - falling well short of the uplift promised by the government, figures from specialist accountants suggest.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4540 - Fortra Releases Security Advisories for FileCatalyst Workflow]]></title>
        <id>18401ee8-6a00-412f-89b8-05ea56eb9a97</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4540"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T15:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisories address two vulnerabilities, one rated as critical and the other as high severity
 Advisories address two vulnerabilities, one rated as critical and the other as high severity
 Updated: 28 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More patients face worsening health due to long hospital waiting lists, CQC survey suggests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152644</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/more-patients-face-worsening-health-due-to-long-hospital-waiting-lists-cqc-survey-suggests/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T15:24:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 40% of patients feel their health deteriorated while waiting to be admitted to hospital, a new survey has found.  The CQC’s annual survey, which received more than 63,500 responses, found that patient satisfaction with hospital services is largely unchanged since 2022, but remains ‘significantly worse than pre-pandemic’.  There is a ‘continued frustration’ at
The post More patients face worsening health due to long hospital waiting lists, CQC survey suggests appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A GP in Gaza: Delivering care in disaster zones]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152545</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/a-gp-in-gaza-delivering-care-in-disaster-zones/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T14:51:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Locum GP Dr Hareen De Silva shares his experience of working in areas of conflict, including Syria, Ukraine, Iraq and, most recently Gaza. I’m often asked what a GP actually does in disaster zones. When people think of places of conflict, they picture emergency medicine – and understandably so. The first time I applied for
The post A GP in Gaza: Delivering care in disaster zones appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices encouraged to sign up for NHSE ‘improvement programme’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152639</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-practices-encouraged-to-sign-up-for-nhse-improvement-programme/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T13:47:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Free support to help practices make the changes set out in the primary care recovery plan is to end, with GP surgeries being told they have ‘one final opportunity’ to sign up for help this September. The latest primary care bulletin from NHS England said any practices wanting to access the free support from specialists
The post GP practices encouraged to sign up for NHSE ‘improvement programme’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Without a safety net: the impact of no recourse to public funds on internationally educated nursing staff]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/without-a-safety-net-the-impact-of-no-recourse-to-public-funds-on-internationally-educated-nursing-s.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/without-a-safety-net-the-impact-of-no-recourse-to-public-funds-on-internationally-educated-nursing-s.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T13:42:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Nursing - This report finds that two thirds of migrant nursing staff are considering leaving the UK due to cost of living pressures. It also highlights the impact of ‘no recourse to public funds’ (NRPF), a rule that denies migrants on temporary visas, such as the Health and Care Worker visa, access to benefits. Migrant nursing staff...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Listening to the stories of women who have experienced child removal due to drug and alcohol use]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/listening-to-the-stories-of-women-who-have-experienced-child-removal-due-to-drug-and-alcohol-use.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/listening-to-the-stories-of-women-who-have-experienced-child-removal-due-to-drug-and-alcohol-use.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T13:19:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maternal Mental Health Alliance - This report, written in collaboration with REFORM, shares the stories of three women with experience of drug addiction during pregnancy and the early days of motherhood. It aims to shine a light on their experiences and centre their views on what is needed to improve the journey for others in a similar situation. The main...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dunscombe and Martins announced as Rewired 2025 keynotes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203581</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/dunscombe-and-martins-announced-as-rewired-2025-keynotes/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T12:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Professor Rachel Dunscombe and Professor Henrique Martins have been named as keynote speakers at Digital Health Rewired 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP exam policy ruled ‘unlawful’ in ‘landmark’ High Court case]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152621</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/education-and-training/rcgp-exam-policy-ruled-unlawful-in-landmark-high-court-case/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T11:19:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP’s exam policy puts some disabled GP trainees at a disadvantage and is ‘unlawful’, the High Court has ruled in a ‘landmark’ judgment. Dr Marwa Karmakar, a GP trainee who was supported by the BMA, brought legal action against the RCGP’s policy to disallow re-sits for trainees who received a ‘late diagnosis of a
The post RCGP exam policy ruled ‘unlawful’ in ‘landmark’ High Court case appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England excludes GPs from cheaper medicines deal due to ‘confidentiality concerns’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152280</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/nhs-england-excludes-gps-from-cheaper-medicines-deal-due-to-confidentiality-concerns/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T10:55:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been excluded from an agreement to access cheaper medicines due to concerns about ‘sharing confidential information’ with primary care, NHS England has said.  In a letter published last week, NHS England laid out its position on which providers can access the ‘Medicines procurement and supply chain’ (MPSC) framework, which offers ‘confidential’ prices on
The post NHS England excludes GPs from cheaper medicines deal due to ‘confidentiality concerns’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A local diagnosis: learning the lessons of Community Diagnostic Centres]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-local-diagnosis-learning-the-lessons-of-community-diagnostic-centres.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-local-diagnosis-learning-the-lessons-of-community-diagnostic-centres.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T10:26:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthwatch England - A Community Diagnostic Centre is a place where people can go for planned (elective) diagnostic care. Before Community Diagnostic Centres were established, most of these tests were performed in acute hospital settings — the same place where people needing emergency tests would go. This research looks at people's experiences of using Community Diagnostic Centres and lessons for...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: UK secures £400 million investment to boost clinical trials]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-secures-400-million-investment-to-boost-clinical-trials</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-secures-400-million-investment-to-boost-clinical-trials"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T10:04:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World-first public-private collaboration launched to kickstart economic growth and build an NHS fit for the future.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Libraries in England to promote the NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203681</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/libraries-in-england-to-promote-the-nhs-app/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T10:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has announced plans to work with libraries to help more people access online health services and use the NHS App.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO and International Paralympic Committee team up to highlight power of assistive technology at Paris 2024 Paralympics]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:b1383f1c-132a-4ceb-b44b-21ba51d8dee9</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/28-08-2024-who-and-international-paralympic-committee-team-up-to-highlight-power-of-assistive-technology-at-paris-2024-paralympics"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T08:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) and International Paralympic Committee (IPC) are joining forces to highlight the transformative impact of assistive technology on sports during the Paris 2024 Paralympic Games. The  "Equipped for equity" campaign emphasizes the crucial role of assistive technology for Paralympic athletes to advocate for concerted global action to improve access to these essential health products.
Throughout the Games, WHO and IPC will leverage the Paralympics platform to share messages and information focused on the importance of assistive technology, how athletes use it, and why universal access is essential. Examples of assistive technology used by Paralympians include: running blades, wheelchairs, and release braces in archery.
The “Equipped for equity” campaign will …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Landmark legal ruling overturns exam resits rule for disabled GP registrars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886329</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/landmark-legal-ruling-overturns-exam-resits-rule-disabled-gp-registrars/article/1886329"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T08:48:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP registrars with a disability could be offered additional attempts at crucial exams after a landmark High Court ruling found that current limits on resits are 'irrational'.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA urges ban on disposable and ‘non-tobacco flavoured’ vapes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152607</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/bma-urges-ban-on-disposable-and-non-tobacco-flavoured-vapes/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T08:37:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has called for a ban on all disposable and ‘non-tobacco’ flavoured vapes in a bid to stop the ‘epidemic’ of vaping.  A new report by the doctors’ union has set out a series of ‘bold actions’ for the Government to take to ‘stem the trend of increased vaping’, particularly among children and young
The post BMA urges ban on disposable and ‘non-tobacco flavoured’ vapes appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pitchfest finalist Little Journey launches app at Walsall hospital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203459</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/pitchfest-finalist-little-journey-launches-app-at-walsall-hospital/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-28T07:30:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An app from Pitchfest finalist, Little Journey has gone live at Walsall Manor Hospital to help young patients prepare for hospital stays.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fourteen African countries, key partners unite to provide critical resources for health in WHO’s first-ever Investment Round]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:f1eab9e9-8e5a-447d-9c89-4b87631a6f1a</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/27-08-2024-fourteen-african-countries--key-partners-unite-to-provide-critical-resources-for-health-in-who-s-first-ever-investment-round"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T19:45:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In an unprecedented show of unity in support of the World Health Organization, 14 African countries and many partners pledged over US$ 45 million to the WHO Investment Round, a three-month-old initiative aimed at generating sustainable financing for the organization at the center of the global health architecture.  The commitments were made during the World Health Organization (WHO) Regional Committee for Africa, with heads of state and government from across the continent underscoring the importance of investing in global health and ensuring a strong WHO. 
“I thank our African Region Member States for actively supporting WHO’s first Investment Round to mobilize predictable and flexible resources needed for our core work over the next four years,” said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Di…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[They’ll screen and screen until I’m sick]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152380</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/screening-at-the-top-of-my-lungs/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T15:52:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield on the impending workload dump that awaits GPs with Targeted Lung Health Checks Oh dear. That 25/day patient contact limit we’re, ahem, all collectively working to isn’t going to stretch very far. Because pretty soon it’s going to be filled with fallout from the NHS’s latest Big Clinical Idea, which is the Targeted (also
The post They’ll screen and screen until I’m sick appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men’s health: the lives of men in our communities]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/mens-health-the-lives-of-men-in-our-communities.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/mens-health-the-lives-of-men-in-our-communities.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T15:42:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local Government Association (LGA) - This report finds that men in England are facing “a silent health crisis”, dying nearly four years earlier than women, while suffering disproportionately higher rates of cancers, heart disease and type 2 diabetes. The report highlights severe inequalities, with men in deprived areas living up to 10 years less than their affluent counterparts and facing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs can continue prescribing puberty blockers in some cases, NHS England says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152590</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gps-can-continue-prescribing-puberty-blockers-in-some-cases-nhs-england-says/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T15:40:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs can continue prescribing puberty blockers for some children and young people if they ‘feel competent to do so’, NHS England has said in new advice.  It comes as the Government has recently extended the legal ban on private prescribing of puberty blockers, which was first introduced in May under the Conservatives, until 26 November.
The post GPs can continue prescribing puberty blockers in some cases, NHS England says appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI technology halves GP practice’s 8am telephone calls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884720</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/ai-technology-halves-gp-practices-8am-telephone-calls/article/1884720"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP practice has seen its 8am telephone rush halved after introducing AI triaging technology - supporting a move to 15-minute appointments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England partners with libraries to encourage use of NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152597</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/nhs-england-partners-with-libraries-to-encourage-use-of-nhs-app/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T14:08:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Library staff across England will help people access online health services, as part of a new NHS England scheme to increase the use of the NHS App. The commissioner said that work is already underway in a number of libraries across England to support people to get started with the NHS App, and that the
The post NHS England partners with libraries to encourage use of NHS App appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virtual wards operational framework]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/virtual-wards-operational-framework-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/virtual-wards-operational-framework-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T13:12:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England - This framework supports consistency across the NHS and the relevant goals in line with the Year 2 urgent and emergency care (UEC) recovery plan and the 2024/25 priorities and operational planning guidance: maintaining virtual ward capacity and optimising occupancy so it is consistently above 80%. Framework More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic children’s observation system rolled out in Shropshire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203523</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/electronic-childrens-observation-system-rolled-out-in-shropshire/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T12:30:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An electronic children’s observation system has been rolled out at Shropshire’s two acute hospitals to improve the care of young people.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What community health providers are doing to recruit and keep the staff they need]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-community-health-providers-are-doing-to-recruit-and-keep-the-staff-they-need.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-community-health-providers-are-doing-to-recruit-and-keep-the-staff-they-need.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T11:21:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This briefing from NHS Provider's Community Network showcases the work of four community providers that are innovating to improve recruitment and retention at a local level. Briefing]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New BMA Scotland GP committee chair demands 'fresh approach' to revive general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886190</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/new-bma-scotland-gp-committee-chair-demands-fresh-approach-revive-general-practice/article/1886190"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T11:21:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Midlothian GP Dr Iain Morrison has named restoring 'pride for our work' in general practice as a top priority after being elected chair of BMA Scotland's GP committee.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP pension queries delayed amid surge in retirement applications]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886182</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-pension-queries-delayed-amid-surge-retirement-applications/article/1886182"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T11:10:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are facing longer-than-usual waits for pension estimates or payments when they retire, the NHS Business Services Authority (NHSBSA) has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public health funding]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/public-health-funding-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/public-health-funding-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T10:35:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Association of Directors of Public Health (ADPH) - This briefing presents the public health funding landscape across the UK, including ADPH’s recommendations for how public health funding can be reformed to ensure people can live healthier, happier and more productive lives. Briefing More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203395</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-166/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T10:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Coffee Time Briefing includes new scanning tech at Royal Free Hospital and a report linking EPR design to nurse burnout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LMC tries to ‘pre-empt’ negative patient reaction to GP call data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151937</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/lmc-tries-to-pre-empt-negative-patient-reaction-to-gp-call-data/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T10:12:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are concerned about the ‘potential negative impact’ on patients’ perceptions should their digital telephony data be released to the public. Sheffield LMC said it received GP concerns about the impact on patients of data that will be collected from practices’ digital telephony after October. The 2024/25 GP contract was amended to require practices to provide
The post LMC tries to ‘pre-empt’ negative patient reaction to GP call data appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-dose psilocybin may be effective in treating depression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152484</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/high-dose-psilocybin-may-be-effective-in-treating-depression/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T10:10:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[High doses of psilocybin – the psychedelic ingredient in magic mushrooms – appear to have a similar effect on depressive symptoms as an antidepressant, according to a meta-analysis of the evidence. But some of the promise of psychedelic treatment for depression may have been overestimated due to issues with trial design, the results suggest. The
The post High-dose psilocybin may be effective in treating depression appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[West London Children’s Healthcare uses tool for safe prescribing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203457</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/west-london-childrens-healthcare-uses-tool-for-safe-prescribing/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T10:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[West London Children’s Healthcare has deployed a clinical decision support tool to safeguard prescribing for young patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS 111 extended to mental health crisis support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203511</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/nhs-111-extended-to-mental-health-crisis-support/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T07:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients experiencing a mental health crisis can now access support through calling 111, the NHS England has announced.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs face rising pressure as patients deteriorate during long waits for hospital care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886026</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-face-rising-pressure-patients-deteriorate-during-long-waits-hospital-care/article/1886026"/>
        <updated>2024-08-27T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices face rising pressure because growing numbers of patients are seeing their health deteriorate during long waits for hospital treatment, a CQC survey shows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS 111 offering crisis mental health support for the first time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251666</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/nhs-111-offering-crisis-mental-health-support-for-the-first-time/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-26T23:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of patients experiencing a mental health crisis can now benefit from support through 111, the NHS has announced today. The change means the NHS in England is one of the first countries in the world to offer access to a 24/7 full package of mental health crisis support through one single phone line. People […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS 111 to offer mental health crisis support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152553</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/nhs-111-to-offer-mental-health-crisis-support/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-26T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS 111 will now provide direct support to patients experiencing a mental health crisis, NHS England has announced. The service expansion announced today means that patients can now call 111, select the mental health option and speak to a mental health professional if they are in a crisis. NHS staff will then guide them through
The post NHS 111 to offer mental health crisis support appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global strategic preparedness and response plan launched by WHO to contain mpox outbreak]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:2db2adec-e75b-4c1d-ab16-19be762fdb0f</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/26-08-2024-global-strategic-preparedness-and-response-plan-launched-by-who-to-contain-mpox-outbreak"/>
        <updated>2024-08-26T10:33:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today launched a global  Strategic Preparedness and Response Plan to stop outbreaks of human-to-human transmission of mpox through coordinated global, regional, and national efforts. This follows the declaration of a public health emergency of international concern by the WHO Director-General on 14 August.
The current plan is subject to inputs by Member States, who were briefed on the plan on Friday, 23 August.
The plan covers the six-month period of September 2024-February 2025, envisioning a US$135 million funding need for the response by WHO, Member States, partners including Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC), communities, and researchers, among others.
A funding appeal for what WHO needs to deliver on the plan will be lau…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Libraries supporting more people to use NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251738</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/libraries-supporting-more-people-to-use-nhs-app/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-25T23:01:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS has today announced a new partnership with libraries across England to help more people access online health services and use the NHS App. The scheme, in partnership with The National Health Literacy Partnership, will officially launch in October – with NHS England contacting public libraries and NHS libraries in the coming weeks to […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workload dump impacting GP ability to provide safe care, LMC warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152564</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/workload-dump-impacting-gp-ability-to-provide-safe-care-lmc-warns/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T15:08:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Workload dump is impacting London GP practices’ ability to deliver safe patient care, the local LMC has warned. London-wide LMC said that the number of practices whose ability to deliver safe patient care is being impacted by workload shift ‘remains high’, and that 76% are ‘unable to absorb’ that additional workload. Of 247 practices taking
The post Workload dump impacting GP ability to provide safe care, LMC warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Abortion statistics: protocol for the release of personal data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/abortion-statistics-protocol-for-the-release-of-personal-data</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/abortion-statistics-protocol-for-the-release-of-personal-data"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T14:44:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to apply for the release of and use confidential abortion data for scientific research purposes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Checker: New collective action, Musk to take over GP services and all-new Zardi centres]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152468</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/pulse-checker/pulse-checker/pulse-checker-new-collective-action-musk-to-take-over-gp-services-and-all-new-zardi-centres/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T14:38:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Checker returns with its not-entirely-serious take on the month’s events. None of these news stories are true (to the best of our knowledge) BMA suggests ‘talking at slightly lower volume’ as next form of collective action The BMA’s GP Committee England have added new forms of collective action for GPs to undertake, including speaking
The post Pulse Checker: New collective action, Musk to take over GP services and all-new Zardi centres appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Independent report: NHS Pay Review Body Thirty-Seventh Report: 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-pay-review-body-thirty-seventh-report-2024</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-pay-review-body-thirty-seventh-report-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T14:32:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recommendations from the NHS Pay Review Body on the pay of NHS staff paid on Agenda for Change terms and conditions in England, Wales and Northern Ireland.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drones can successfully fly blood packs, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203289</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/drones-can-successfully-fly-blood-packs-study-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T12:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Drones can be used as a safe mode of transport for delivering blood packs, according to a study run by NHS Blood and Transplant.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government extends puberty blocker ban until end of November]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152540</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/government-extends-puberty-blocker-ban-until-end-of-november/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T11:33:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has renewed a temporary ban on private prescribing of puberty blockers which was introduced under the Conservatives.  Last month, health secretary Wes Streeting said he is ‘defending’ the emergency ban, which was being challenged at the High court by transgender rights activists.  It was brought in by former health secretary Victoria Atkins in
The post Government extends puberty blocker ban until end of November appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs still face blood testing disruption two months after cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152534</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gps-still-face-blood-testing-disruption-two-months-after-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T11:03:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices continue to face disruption following a major cyber attack on a pathology lab over two months ago. The latest NHS update has revealed that GP practices in three out of six south east London boroughs are yet to return to usual blood testing services.  At the start of June, Synnovis, a provider of
The post GPs still face blood testing disruption two months after cyber attack appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research suggests link between semaglutide and suicidal thoughts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152461</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/research-suggests-link-between-semaglutide-and-suicidal-thoughts/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T11:01:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have found an apparent disproportional risk of suicidal thoughts with semaglutide compared with other diabetes drugs. A study based on a World Health Organisation global database of adverse drug reactions found while cases were very rare patients were significantly more likely to report suicidal thoughts while taking semaglutide compared to other medication. The increased
The post Research suggests link between semaglutide and suicidal thoughts appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alzheimer’s treatment gets MHRA approval, but is too costly for the NHS says NICE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886023</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/alzheimers-treatment-gets-mhra-approval-costly-nhs-says-nice/article/1886023"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T10:21:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lecanemab has been shown to slow down progression of Alzheimer's disease - but the benefits are too small to justify the costs, NICE has concluded in draft guidance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England signs digital urgent and emergency care contracts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203467</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/nhs-england-signs-digital-urgent-and-emergency-care-contracts/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T10:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has signed two contracts to support the digital transformation of urgent and emergency care, totalling £86 million in value.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England releases guidance to GP practices in wake of racist riots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885061</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-england-releases-guidance-gp-practices-wake-racist-riots/article/1885061"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has written to GP practices offering advice on how to support staff in the wake of the recent racist riots that swept the country.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England releases guidance to GP practice in wake of racist riots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885061</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-england-releases-guidance-gp-practice-wake-racist-riots/article/1885061"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has written to GP practices offering advice on how to support staff in the wake of the recent racist riots that swept the country.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feeling the pressure: what the 2023 Commonwealth Fund survey reveals about the state of the UK health system]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/feeling-the-pressure-what-the-2023-commonwealth-fund-survey-reveals-about-the-state-of-the-uk-health.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/feeling-the-pressure-what-the-2023-commonwealth-fund-survey-reveals-about-the-state-of-the-uk-health.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T09:05:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This report found that the UK’s performance on hospital-based care is consistently near the bottom in a public survey of 10 high income countries. The analysis of the 2023 Commonwealth Fund survey highlights key areas where the UK performs poorly, particularly on long waits for specialist care, lack of access to out-of-hours care and affordability for...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fifth of patients have long COVID at some GP practices in north of England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1886002</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/fifth-patients-long-covid-gp-practices-north-england/article/1886002"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T08:53:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One in five patients at some GP practices in northern England are living with long COVID - driving up workload particularly in practices serving deprived populations, a report reveals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking the next step for working carers: introducing a new right to paid Carer’s Leave]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/taking-the-next-step-for-working-carers-introducing-a-new-right-to-paid-carers-leave.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/taking-the-next-step-for-working-carers-introducing-a-new-right-to-paid-carers-leave.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T08:26:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Carers UK - This report argues that introducing paid Carer’s Leave could boost productivity, whilst improving millions of workers’ lives. It estimates that it would cost the Government between £5.5 million to £32 million annually, if the statutory right to five days of unpaid Carer’s Leave for all employees with unpaid caring responsibilities was turned into paid Carer’s Leave. In...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[North London Mental Health Partnership goes live with PHR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203361</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/north-london-mental-health-partnership-goes-live-with-phr/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-23T07:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[North London Mental Health Partnership (NLMHP) has gone live with a personal health record from Patients Know Best.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 actions the government can take to improve NHS working conditions]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/10-actions-the-government-can-take-to-improve-nhs-working-conditions.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/10-actions-the-government-can-take-to-improve-nhs-working-conditions.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T16:24:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The King's Fund - The workforce crisis is at the heart of many of the challenges facing the NHS in England. This briefing outlines early actions the government can take to enable NHS staff and leaders to deliver the highest possible quality of care in the coming months. Briefing The King's Fund - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Join a discussion on health inequalities in women in a free MIMS Learning webinar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885957</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/join-discussion-health-inequalities-women-free-mims-learning-webinar/article/1885957"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T16:07:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join an expert panel – menopause specialist Dr Louise Newson, consultant gynaecologist Mr Abdelmageed Abdelrahman and GPwSI gynaecology Dr Anita Sharma – for a free MIMS Learning webinar on health inequalities faced by women, and how healthcare professionals can support patients at 7pm on Tuesday, 10 September 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA and Capita in disagreement over thousands of ‘missing’ GP pension records]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152481</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/bma-and-capita-in-disagreement-over-thousands-of-missing-gp-pension-records/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T15:48:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of GPs in England are experiencing significant issues with their pension records due to ‘maladministration’ by Capita, the BMA has claimed. According to BMA, ‘one of the biggest challenges’ that GPs face is out of date and inaccurate pension records, with ‘missing years’ of pensions data ‘due to mismanagement of pension records’ – which
The post BMA and Capita in disagreement over thousands of ‘missing’ GP pension records appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fighting for general practice: the key to a net zero health service]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151104</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/fighting-for-general-practice-the-key-to-a-net-zero-health-service/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T15:06:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Emma Radcliffe on how general practice can be used to green the NHS I have devoted a large part of the past 20 years of my life endeavouring to provide high quality health care to the community I work in: Tower Hamlets in East London. However, my mind and working life has been increasingly
The post Fighting for general practice: the key to a net zero health service appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[News story: Puberty blockers temporary ban extended]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/puberty-blockers-temporary-ban-extended</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/puberty-blockers-temporary-ban-extended"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:56:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Temporary ban on prescription and supply of puberty blockers extended.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA’s Scottish GP Committee elects new chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152465</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/scotland/bmas-scottish-gp-committee-elects-new-chair/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:39:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An LMC leader and GP partner has been elected as the new chair of the BMA’s GP committee for Scotland. Dr Iain Morrison, who has been Lothian LMC’s chair since October 2020, will succeed Dr Andrew Buist who is stepping down after six years in the role. In a message to members, Dr Morrison, who
The post BMA’s Scottish GP Committee elects new chair appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Menopause and HRT: Myths and facts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152373</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/menopause-and-hrt-myths-and-facts/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:25:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest of our series exploring some common misconceptions about conditions seen in general practice, GP Dr Toni Hazell debunks some myths about the menopause and HIV – and explains some perhaps less well known facts Myths 1. The menopause always presents with hot flushes and night sweats The menopause occurs at the average
The post Menopause and HRT: Myths and facts appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4539 - Google Releases Security Updates for Chrome]]></title>
        <id>74ab7663-66c2-40c7-acbf-7c60ea2baa00</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4539"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T14:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security update includes one exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome
 Security update includes one exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome
 Updated: 22 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hull hospital to trial video triage to assess stroke patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203159</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/hull-hospitals-to-trial-pre-hospital-video-triage-for-stroke-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T12:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hull University Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust has announced plans to trial a pre-hospital video triage scheme for stroke patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203223</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-165/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T10:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing covers Walsall Healthcare's first digital nurse role, rehab robots and a maternity EPR at East and North Herts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203223</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T10:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing covers Walsall Healthcare's first digital nurse role, rehab robots and a maternity EPR at East and North Herts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England statement on Alzheimer’s treatment lecanemab: Thursday 22 August 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251594</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/nhs-england-statement-on-alzheimers-treatment-lecanemab/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T10:18:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In response to the MHRA and NICE decisions on lecanemab, Professor Sir Stephen Powis, NHS National Medical Director, said: “The NHS now awaits a final decision from the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence that will look at the clinical benefits and cost-effectiveness of lecanemab and determine if it should be routinely offered by the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Yorkshire trusts select Nervecentre as preferred EPR supplier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203299</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/two-yorkshire-trusts-select-nervecentre-as-preferred-epr-supplier/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T10:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[York and Scarborough Teaching Hospitals and Harrogate and District NHS FT have selected Nervecentre as their preferred EPR supplier.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ARRS GPs could be hired under 'less favourable terms', BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885850</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/arrs-gps-hired-less-favourable-terms-bma-warns/article/1885850"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T09:41:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs employed through the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) may be offered employment benefits such as holiday and sick pay below the level required under the BMA salaried GP model contract, the union has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NICE rules Alzheimer’s-slowing drug lecanemab too expensive for NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152447</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/nice-rules-alzheimers-slowing-drug-lecanemab-too-expensive-for-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T09:32:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK medicines regulator has approved lecanemab – the first drug shown to slow cognitive decline in patients in the early stages of Alzheimer’s – but NICE said it was too costly for the NHS. NICE’s draft guidance, published today, has been put out for a four-week consultation after the committee concluded the benefits of
The post NICE rules Alzheimer’s-slowing drug lecanemab too expensive for NHS appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England and Medical Schools Council to join forces to manage the Specialised Foundation Programme recruitment process for 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251520</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/specialised-foundation-programme-recruitment-process-for-2025/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T09:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England and the Medical Schools Council have launched a new partnership that will give students the opportunity to apply directly to medical schools for certain Specialised Foundation Programmes in England. The Specialised Foundation Programme has been created to offer medical school graduates the opportunity to develop skills in research, teaching and leadership alongside their […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultation outcome: Standard adult ready-to-drink oral nutritional supplements: ACBS policy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oral-nutritional-supplements-acbs-policy</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oral-nutritional-supplements-acbs-policy"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T08:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We want your views on changes being proposed to Advisory Committee on Borderline Substances (ACBS) policy about standard adult ready-to-drink oral nutritional supplements listed in part XV of the Drug Tariff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK worst on hospital waits but best on GP access, 10-country survey shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152437</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/uk-worst-on-hospital-waits-but-best-on-gp-access-10-country-survey-shows/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T08:21:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK general practice has been shown to perform well on access and speed of getting an appointment, in a large survey across 10 high-income countries. A report from the Health Foundation said 97% of respondents in the UK said they had regular access to a GP with only the Netherlands scoring higher. On getting an
The post UK worst on hospital waits but best on GP access, 10-country survey shows appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs facing extra pressure as seven pharmacies a week close down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885657</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-facing-extra-pressure-seven-pharmacies-week-close-down/article/1885657"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T08:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy closures are adding to pressure on general practice and threaten to undermine patient care, GP leaders have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Betsi Cadwaladr University Health Board to roll out ePMA in 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203339</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/betsi-cadwaladr-university-health-board-to-roll-out-epma-in-2026/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-22T07:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Betsi Cadwaladr University Health Board has partnered with Better to deliver an electronic prescribing and medicines administration system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK healthcare 'near bottom of the pack' compared with similar countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885805</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/uk-healthcare-near-bottom-pack-compared-similar-countries/article/1885805"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients' experience of healthcare in the UK is 'near the bottom of the pack' compared with other developed nations despite relatively strong performance on rapid access to a GP, analysis of a major international survey reveals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health board forced to apologise to patients ‘left out’ of GP catchment area]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152414</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/wales/health-board-forced-to-apologise-to-patients-left-out-of-gp-catchment-area/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T15:53:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Welsh health board was forced to apologise after a ‘discrepancy’ in GP practice boundaries meant patients could not access GP services. Betsi Cadwaladr University Health Board told Pulse that it was aware that ‘a small number of residents’ in Saltney Ferry, Flintshire, ‘had issues’ accessing GP services’ due to a discrepancy relating to practice
The post Health board forced to apologise to patients ‘left out’ of GP catchment area appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA warns GPs taking collective action not to plug service gaps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152390</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/bma-warns-gps-taking-collective-action-not-to-plug-service-gaps/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T14:52:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has warned GP practices against plugging gaps in local services which have arisen as a result of collective action. The union’s GP Committee for England has issued additional guidance for LMCs and practices, in light of collective action which began earlier this month, after taking legal advice. It said that although legally only
The post BMA warns GPs taking collective action not to plug service gaps appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I actually have sympathy with Streeting over his ARRS plans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152393</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/i-actually-have-sympathy-with-streeting-over-his-arrs-plans/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T14:24:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Jaimie Kaffash reflects on the health secretary’s plans to include GPs in the ARRS I do not expect to say these words too often: I have sympathy for Wes Streeting. Not in general, but specifically with regards to his plan to put GPs in the additional roles reimbursement scheme. Now, quick declaration of interest
The post I actually have sympathy with Streeting over his ARRS plans appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Milton Keynes University Hospital trials Dora AI assistant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203121</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/milton-keynes-university-hospital-trials-dora-ai-assistant/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T12:30:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Milton Keynes University Hospital is trialling a conversational AI assistant in its ophthalmology department.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHSC insists GP contract uplift should cover partners, salaried GPs and other staff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885741</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/dhsc-insists-gp-contract-uplift-cover-partners-salaried-gps-staff/article/1885741"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T10:22:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government officials have insisted that the 2024/25 GP contract uplift is intended to deliver a 6% pay increase for partners as well as for salaried GPs and other practice staff - despite warnings that it will fall short.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Falls prevention app helps reduce care home ambulance call-outs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203157</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/falls-prevention-app-helps-reduce-care-home-ambulance-call-outs/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T10:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A falls prevention app has been adopted by 37 care homes in Greater Manchester after trials led to a 57% reduction in ambulance call-outs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA urges Streeting to give GP ARRS funding directly to practices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152381</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/bma-urges-streeting-to-give-gp-arrs-funding-directly-to-practices/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T09:58:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ARRS funding to hire GPs must be provided to practices directly rather than to PCNs, the BMA has demanded in a letter to the health secretary. At the beginning of this month, the Government agreed to fund the ARRS with an extra £82m to allow PCNs to hire GPs, with this funding intended cover the
The post BMA urges Streeting to give GP ARRS funding directly to practices appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking about adversity, trauma and resilience: recommendations from FrameWorks UK]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/talking-about-adversity-trauma-and-resilience-recommendations-from-frameworks-uk.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/talking-about-adversity-trauma-and-resilience-recommendations-from-frameworks-uk.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T09:52:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Association of Directors of Public Health (ADPH) - Earlier this year, ADPH invited FrameWorks UK to present a set of evidence-based recommendations to Directors of Public Health and other public health professionals to enable them to better explain the causes and impact of adversity, trauma and resilience in infants, children and young people to policy makers and the wider public....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI will never be a replacement for a highly-qualified GP, warns RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885715</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/ai-will-replacement-highly-qualified-gp-warns-rcgp/article/1885715"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T09:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence (AI) should never be considered a replacement for a highly-qualified GP, the RCGP has warned - but the college said it would welcome the chance to help develop AI-driven health analytics to support the profession.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government pauses work on ‘major conditions’ strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152332</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/government-pauses-work-on-major-conditions-strategy/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T08:36:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A plan to tackle six major health conditions has been put on pause by the new Government, a health minister has confirmed. The previous Government wanted to set out a strategy to tackle the conditions contributing to England’s ‘burden of disease’, with then health secretary Steve Barclay saying that ‘for too long our healthcare services
The post Government pauses work on ‘major conditions’ strategy appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Humber Teaching NHS FT deploys patient communication platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203013</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/humber-teaching-nhs-ft-deploys-patient-communication-platform/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-21T07:30:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Humber Teaching NHS Foundation Trust has signed a three-year contract with Accurx for a patient communication platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE urging GPs to streamline patient SMS practices to avoid fraud]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152371</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/nhse-urging-gps-to-streamline-patient-sms-practices-to-avoid-fraud/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T16:05:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices and other NHS providers are being requested to exclusively use ‘NHSNoReply’ and block other variations by 5 November 2024, the latest primary care bulletin has said. The National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC) is updating guidance to reduce the number of SMS SenderID variations, ensuring they reflect the service consumed and minimising the risk
The post NHSE urging GPs to streamline patient SMS practices to avoid fraud appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in devolved nations still waiting for 6% pay rise confirmation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152363</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gps-in-devolved-nations-still-waiting-for-6-pay-rise-confirmation/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T15:44:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices in the devolved nations are still in the dark about how the 6% pay uplift will be allocated by their governments.  At the end of July, the Review Body on Doctors’ and Dentists’ Remuneration (DDRB) recommended a 6% pay increase for GPs in all of the four nations.  Last week, an internal BMA
The post GPs in devolved nations still waiting for 6% pay rise confirmation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing the NHS for the AI era: a digital health record for every citizen]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/preparing-the-nhs-for-the-ai-era-a-digital-health-record-for-every-citizen.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/preparing-the-nhs-for-the-ai-era-a-digital-health-record-for-every-citizen.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T14:55:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Blair Institute for Global Change - This report proposes a digital health record (DHR) to drive improvements to health and care, and ensure that the NHS is ready for the artificial-intelligence era. Each person’s DHR would be the “single source of truth” for their health and care data – data that currently sit in silos across hospitals, GP practices,...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We need to be better at reaching out to burnt out colleagues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152324</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/dr-burnt-out/we-need-to-be-better-at-reaching-out-to-burnt-out-colleagues/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T14:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[True to his name, Dr Burnt Out reflects on how GPs can offer support to colleagues suffering from burn out and exhaustion  Sadly, we live in a health care system, and more specifically a primary care environment, where there is currently an epidemic of work-related stress and burnout. Doctors become seriously unwell due to work
The post We need to be better at reaching out to burnt out colleagues appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A call for change: tackling inequalities in access to mental health support for children with social work involvement and those living in poverty]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-call-for-change-tackling-inequalities-in-access-to-mental-health-support-for-children-with-social-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-call-for-change-tackling-inequalities-in-access-to-mental-health-support-for-children-with-social-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T13:47:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[National Children's Bureau - This report finds children with social work involvement for current concerns are more likely to be rejected by NHS mental health services compared to their peers. The research, undertaken with Cambridge University, found overall, children from the most deprived areas are twice as likely to be rejected than those from the least deprived areas. Report Press...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Networks launches council for clinical safety officers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202801</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-networks-launches-council-for-clinical-safety-officers/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T12:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Digital Health Networks Clinical Safety Officer (CSO) Council has been launched for CSOs to share knowledge, experience and best practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New GP contract should build care around 250,000-patient populations, says think tank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885659</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/new-gp-contract-build-care-around-250000-patient-populations-says-think-tank/article/1885659"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:57:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS primary care should be reorganised around populations of around 250,000 patients under a new GP contract that ignores geographical areas, according to an influential think tank.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speediatrics: Can you solve this quick case of a child’s rash?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151863</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/paediatrics/speediatrics-can-you-solve-this-quick-case-of-a-child-s-rash/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:20:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new series, Pulse clinical adviser Dr Keith Hopcroft poses some quick quizzes around paediatric care. We kick off with the case of a child with atopic eczema
The post Speediatrics: Can you solve this quick case of a child’s rash? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dev Support</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices should be scaled up to 250k-patient lists, says Tony Blair think tank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152311</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/gp-practices-should-be-scaled-up-to-250k-patient-lists-says-tony-blair-think-tank/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:18:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Blair’s think tank has put forward a new vision of primary care with ‘far fewer groups of GP practices’ and 250,000-patient lists.  In a report published yesterday, the Tony Blair Institute (TBI) also urged the Government to implement a ‘digital health record’ for every citizen, which would replace the GP record, by 2029. The
The post GP practices should be scaled up to 250k-patient lists, says Tony Blair think tank appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP given three-month suspension after M25 climate protest conviction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885593</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-given-three-month-suspension-m25-climate-protest-conviction/article/1885593"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:05:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who was jailed twice after taking part in an M25 climate change protest has been suspended for three months from the GMC register.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP given three-month GMC suspension after M25 climate protest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885593</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-given-three-month-gmc-suspension-m25-climate-protest/article/1885593"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T11:05:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who was jailed twice after taking part in an M25 climate change protest has been suspended for three months from the GMC register.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202707</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-164/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T10:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health's latest Coffee Time Briefing includes Sussex's new £2 million robot surgeon and an AI study on pressure ulcers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202707</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T10:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health's latest Coffee Time Briefing includes Sussex's new £2 million robot surgeon and an AI study on pressure ulcers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blair Institute calls for crash programme of digital health records]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203155</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/blair-institute-calls-for-crash-programme-of-digital-health-records/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T10:27:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tony Blair Institute for Global Change has proposed a programme to create digital health records for all UK citizens within five years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Hoeksma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Women smoking during pregnancy at record low thanks to NHS support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251449</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/women-smoking-during-pregnancy-at-record-low-thanks-to-nhs-support/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T10:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smoking rates among mums-to-be are at an all-time low thanks to support from NHS teams. This year also saw the biggest annual fall in smoking during pregnancy since records began, meaning 6,000 fewer pregnant women smoked when compared to the previous 12 months, protecting thousands of babies from potential harm. NHS England is working to […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bring in AI doctors and strip GP practices of sole data controller role, says Blair think tank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885581</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bring-ai-doctors-strip-gp-practices-sole-data-controller-role-says-blair-think-tank/article/1885581"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T09:32:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government should strip GPs of their role as sole data controllers of patient records and bring in 'AI doctors' to support decisions about care as part of a major NHS digital overhaul, an influential think tank has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What can integrated care systems in England learn from the devolved nations?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-can-integrated-care-systems-in-england-learn-from-the-devolved-nations.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-can-integrated-care-systems-in-england-learn-from-the-devolved-nations.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T09:15:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - Approaches to integrating health and care services to improve efficiency and meet population needs have varied across the United Kingdom’s four devolved nations. Given the differences in approach to integration across the four nations, the NHS Confederation, supported by Novartis, has developed this resource to showcase both examples of good practice and lessons learned in Wales, Scotland...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Realising the potential of primary care provider collaboratives]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/realising-the-potential-of-primary-care-provider-collaboratives-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/realising-the-potential-of-primary-care-provider-collaboratives-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T09:03:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - The new Labour government has set out an intention to move care closer to home with a shift of resources to primary and community care. This report highlights the role of primary care provider collaboratives in supporting transformation. The report – informed by interviews with 20 leaders in collaboratives and two roundtables with wider partners, including integrated...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telephony system reduces missed GP appointments in Birmingham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=203011</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/telephony-system-reduces-missed-gp-appointments-in-birmingham/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-20T07:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A ‘check and cancel’ appointment solution at Hall Green Health GP practice in Birmingham has helped save patient and staff time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LMC sets out list of ‘workload dump’ requests GPs should decline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151154</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/lmc-sets-out-list-of-workload-dump-requests-gps-should-decline/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T16:24:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have set out a comprehensive list of requests GPs should ‘decline’ and send back to hospitals, in a bid to tackle workload dump. A new document produced by Humberside LMCs summarised the ‘most common interface workload transfer’ from other providers to GP practices, as well as their recommended response. The LMCs have argued
The post LMC sets out list of ‘workload dump’ requests GPs should decline appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unleashing health and prosperity throughout Britain]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/unleashing-health-and-prosperity-throughout-britain-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/unleashing-health-and-prosperity-throughout-britain-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T15:53:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - While a theoretical understanding of the links between health and wealth is increasingly recognised, the practical elements of what makes it work on the ground are less evidenced. Based on engagement with five local areas in England and Wales, this paper puts forward a set principles that have proven to aid successful social and economic development: making...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An overview of the National Minimum Wage]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/an-overview-of-the-national-minimum-wage.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/an-overview-of-the-national-minimum-wage.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T15:37:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - This guide provides an overview of the National Minimum Wage (NMW), sets out how to calculate the NMW, and frequently asked questions (FAQs). Guide More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consultant doctors and dentists pay progression system guidance for employers]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/consultant-doctors-and-dentists-pay-progression-system-guidance-for-employers.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/consultant-doctors-and-dentists-pay-progression-system-guidance-for-employers.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T15:29:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - The 2024 amendments to the 2003 consultant contract introduced provisions to move to a new pay structure supported by a new pay progression system. This guidance is produced in association with the British Medical Association (BMA) and the Hospital Consultants and Specialists Association (HCSA). Guidance More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA urges GP registrars to vote ‘yes’ to Government pay offer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152275</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/bma-urges-gp-registrars-to-vote-yes-to-government-pay-offer/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T14:53:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has urged GP registrars to vote in favour of accepting a pay offer made by the Government to junior doctors in England. The union’s GP registrars committee has recommended that members vote to accept the offer, which would increase pay by 22.3% over two years, in a referendum of more than sixty thousand
The post BMA urges GP registrars to vote ‘yes’ to Government pay offer appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How females are disproportionately affected by the employment crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152090</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/how-females-are-disproportionately-affected-by-the-employment-crisis/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T14:28:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Seema Pattni considers the impact of the employment crisis on female GPs ‘Both my job offers have fallen through. I’m really panicking. I’m stuck in limbo trying to decide what to do.’ These are the words of a female GP who I spoke to recently.  The employment crisis in general practice is rife and
The post How females are disproportionately affected by the employment crisis appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) Emergency Committee regarding the upsurge of mpox 2024]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:08be502f-4acd-4af5-8b03-4e9fd9971151</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/19-08-2024-first-meeting-of-the-international-health-regulations-(2005)-emergency-committee-regarding-the-upsurge-of-mpox-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T14:21:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Director-General of the World Health Organization (WHO), having concurred with the advice offered by the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR or Regulations)  Emergency Committee regarding the upsurge of mpox 2024 during its first meeting, held on 14 August 2024, has determined, on the same date, that the ongoing upsurge of mpox in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) and in a growing number of countries in Africa constitutes a public health emergency of international concern (PHEIC) under the provisions of the Regulations. The communication of the Director-General regarding the determination of the above-mentioned PHEIC on 14 August 2024 is available  here.
The Director-General is hereby transmitting the report of the first meeting of the IHR Emergency Committee regardin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA urges junior doctors to back pay offer as referendum opens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885532</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-urges-junior-doctors-back-pay-offer-referendum-opens/article/1885532"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T13:44:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A BMA referendum on a new pay deal for junior doctors including GP registrars has opened, with doctors' leaders urging the profession to back the pay offer and bring an end to long-running strike action.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Portsmouth Hospitals expands digital patient communications]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202643</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/portsmouth-hospitals-expands-digital-patient-communications/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T12:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Portsmouth Hospitals has expanded digital patient communications through a new patient portal, waiting list validation and digital letters.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[M25 climate protest GP suspended for three months]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152251</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/m25-climate-protest-gp-suspended-for-three-months/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T11:18:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who took part in a climate protest blocking the M25 motorway will be suspended for three months, a medical practitioners’ tribunal has decided. The Medical Practitioners Tribunal Service (MPTS) hearing, which concluded last week, examined allegations that Dr Diana Warner had breached a court order by protesting on the M25 in 2021 and
The post M25 climate protest GP suspended for three months appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NICE recommends additional treatment for uterine fibroids]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152174</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/nice-recommends-additional-treatment-for-uterine-fibroids/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T10:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As many as 30,000 women could benefit from a new treatment to manage uterine fibroids, the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) has estimated. Linzagolix, a GnRH antagonist, has been recommended as a longer term treatment – more than six months – for people with moderate to severe symptoms. It follows two clinical
The post NICE recommends additional treatment for uterine fibroids appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Bolton Hospital deploys Miya patient flow system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202793</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/royal-bolton-hospital-deploys-miya-patient-flow-system/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T10:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bolton NHS Foundation Trust has deployed a new patient flow system from Alcidion to boost bed availability at Royal Bolton Hospital.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Care into the Future]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/we-care-into-the-future-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/we-care-into-the-future-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T09:06:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - Introduced for the first time in July 2019, the We Care into the Future interactive careers event aims to inspire young people in the Doncaster and Bassetlaw area, by challenging their perceptions around the career opportunities available across health and care. Case study]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice staff faced Islamophobic death threat during riots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885420</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practice-staff-faced-islamophobic-death-threat-during-riots/article/1885420"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T08:58:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP practice was forced to shut its doors after a man threatened to kill a member of staff at the height of Islamophobic and racist rioting earlier this month, GPonline has learned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northumbria Healthcare goes live with CLEO SOLO EPS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202731</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/northumbria-healthcare-goes-live-with-cleo-solo-eps/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-19T07:30:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northumbria Healthcare NHS Foundation Trust has gone live with the CLEO SOLO electronic prescription system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What you don’t know about… S2 funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151519</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/what-you-dont-know-about/what-you-dont-know-about-s2-funding/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T14:17:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest instalment of our series looking at policies, funding pots and new initiatives that may have slipped your notice, Dr Lucy Douglas investigates the S2 funding route and why GPs may want to recommend it to patients What is S2 funding? The Planned Treatment Scheme (S2 funding route) entitles eligible patients to NHS funding
The post What you don’t know about… S2 funding appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs told to set up mpox isolation procedures and check PPE stocks in light of new variant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152211</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/gps-told-to-set-up-mpox-isolation-procedures-and-check-ppe-stocks-in-light-of-new-variant/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T13:53:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices have been told to set up isolation procedures and check PPE stocks, as concerns grow around a new more fatal version of mpox. The Clade 1b mpox variant (MPXV) has been spreading rapidly across parts of central and East Africa since first being discovered in September last year, killing 537 people in the
The post GPs told to set up mpox isolation procedures and check PPE stocks in light of new variant appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delivering with dignity: a framework for strengthening commissioning and provision of healthcare services for people seeking asylum]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/delivering-with-dignity-a-framework-for-strengthening-commissioning-and-provision-of-healthcare-serv.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/delivering-with-dignity-a-framework-for-strengthening-commissioning-and-provision-of-healthcare-serv.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T13:48:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British Red Cross - This report finds that people seeking asylum in England often have complex health needs and yet face barriers to accessing timely, quality, and appropriate health care. It sets out a framework of good practice to remove these barriers and ensure people can access the health care that they are entitled to. Report British Red Cross -...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy concerns raised over trust’s AI data-sharing deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202923</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/privacy-concerns-raised-over-trusts-ai-data-sharing-deal/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T12:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A privacy campaign group has raised concerns over a data sharing agreement between the Royal National Orthopaedic Hospital and an AI startup.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New RSV vaccination programme could cut GP consultations by 35,000]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152162</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/new-rsv-vaccination-programme-could-cut-gp-consultations-by-35000/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T12:18:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new RSV vaccination programme due to start in September could prevent 20,000 GP consultations for poorly babies, public health experts predict. The analysis by the UKHSA and London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine also suggests the vaccine could prevent 5,000 hospitalisations in infants in England and Wales. The analysis which assumes 60% uptake
The post New RSV vaccination programme could cut GP consultations by 35,000 appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice advised to break up or hand back contract as new premises delayed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152199</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/premises/gp-practice-advised-to-break-up-or-hand-back-contract-as-new-premises-delayed/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T11:03:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive A good-rated GP practice at risk of having no premises from October was ‘shell-shocked’ at being advised by its ICB it could ‘hand back the contract’.  Another option suggested was to work from a range of different other practices while awaiting new premises. St James Medical Practice in Walthamstow, run by a father and
The post GP practice advised to break up or hand back contract as new premises delayed appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Humanitarian pauses vital for critical polio vaccination campaign in the Gaza Strip]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:ca556dce-263d-4d3e-8e10-c4fba6da0256</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/16-08-2024-humanitarian-pauses-vital-for-critical-polio-vaccination-campaign-in-the-gaza-strip"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T10:20:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two rounds of a polio vaccination campaign are expected to be launched at the end of August and September 2024 across the Gaza Strip to prevent the spread of circulating variant type 2 poliovirus (cVDPV2).  
WHO and UNICEF request all parties to the conflict to implement humanitarian pauses in the Gaza Strip for seven days to allow for two rounds of vaccination campaigns to take place. These pauses in fighting would allow children and families to safely reach health facilities and community outreach workers to get to children who cannot access health facilities for polio vaccination. Without the humanitarian pauses, the delivery of the campaign will not be possible. 
During each round of the campaign, the Palestinian Ministry of Health (MoH), in collaboration with the World Health Organiza…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jersey’s EPR plans delayed by ‘patchy WiFi’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202739</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/jerseys-epr-plans-delayed-by-patchy-wifi/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T10:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plans to update Jersey’s electronic patient record (EPR) system have been delayed owing to WiFi issues, according to an annual report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rise in GP practices participating in research studies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152196</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/diabetes-endocrinology/rise-in-gp-practices-participating-in-research-studies/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T09:49:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s been an increase in the number of GP practices taking part in health research, new data has revealed. The growth has allowed more patients to participate in local clinical trials used to develop new treatments. Fresh data has shown during 2023/24 more than half of all GP practices in England (56%) took part in
The post Rise in GP practices participating in research studies appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flu and Covid vaccination campaign to run from 3 October to 20 December]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152179</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/flu-and-covid-vaccination-campaign-to-run-from-3-october-to-20-december/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T09:34:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should vaccinate eligible groups against flu and Covid between 3 October and 20 December, NHS England has said in its latest update. NHSE announced in March that the flu vaccination programme would be moved from September to October this year in order to maximise vaccine effectiveness, with Covid vaccination to commence at the same
The post Flu and Covid vaccination campaign to run from 3 October to 20 December appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man jailed after GP practice break in and laptop thefts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885141</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/man-jailed-gp-practice-break-laptop-thefts/article/1885141"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T07:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man has been jailed for four months after pleading guilty to breaking into a GP practice and stealing laptops.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health’s monthly roundup of contracts and go lives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202767</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-healths-monthly-roundup-of-contracts-and-go-lives-43/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T07:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This latest roundup includes Northampton General Hospital signing a 10-year Nervecentre electronic patient record (EPR) contract.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: GP contract uplift, will ARRS GP jobs work, plus GP working hours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885232</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-gp-contract-uplift-will-arrs-gp-jobs-work-plus-gp-working-hours/article/1885232"/>
        <updated>2024-08-16T07:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GPonline team discusses what the uplift to this year's GP contract in England means for GP practices, GP pay and staff salaries, plans to add GPs to the ARRS and the number of hours GPs work.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once in a lifetime: Acoustic neuromas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151940</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/neurology/acoustic-neuromas/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T15:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mr Gerard Kelly, consultant ENT and skull base surgeon at Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust, outlines this unusual presentation in the latest in our series of conditions that GPs may expect to encounter once in a lifetime What is it? An acoustic neuroma (more correctly termed a vestibular schwannoma) is a benign (non-cancerous) tumour that
The post Once in a lifetime: Acoustic neuromas appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public health warning over rising rates of antibiotic-resistant gonorrhoea]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152150</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/sexual-health/public-health-warning-over-rising-rates-of-antibiotic-resistant-gonorrhoea/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T15:19:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public health officials are warning of a concerning rise in antibiotic-resistant gonorrhoea infections in England. Data from the UK Health Security Agency shows there have been 15 new confirmed cases of ceftriaxone-resistant Neisseria gonorrhoeae between June 2022 and May 2024. This includes five cases which were extensively drug-resistant to first and second line antibiotics as
The post Public health warning over rising rates of antibiotic-resistant gonorrhoea appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finance Diary: How GPs can make the most out of childcare funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150935</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/finance-diary/finance-diary-how-gps-can-make-the-most-out-of-childcare-funding/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T15:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mazars client director Lisa Pennington shares how GPs can check their eligibility to childcare funding and what measures can be taken to maximise access Many parents who work in primary care either as GP partners, salaried GPs or staff members want to continue working after having a child, but childcare costs can be prohibitive. To
The post Finance Diary: How GPs can make the most out of childcare funding appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Damp and mould: understanding and addressing the health risks for rented housing providers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/damp-and-mould-understanding-and-addressing-the-health-risks-for-rented-housing-providers</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/damp-and-mould-understanding-and-addressing-the-health-risks-for-rented-housing-providers"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T14:32:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This guidance delivers on the government’s commitment in response to the Coroner’s 'prevention of future deaths' report on the death of 2-year-old Awaab Ishak due to mould in the home.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP team climbing Three Peaks to raise money for suicide prevention]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151995</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gp-team-climbing-three-peaks-to-raise-money-for-suicide-prevention/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T13:26:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A team of GPs is climbing the National Three Peaks to raise money for suicide prevention among doctors.  Over the next week, a group of five GPs, six consultants and three dentists will climb Ben Nevis in Scotland, Scafell Pike in England and Snowdon in Wales to raise money for Doctors in Distress. The group
The post GP team climbing Three Peaks to raise money for suicide prevention appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Millions to get protected ahead of winter in NHS vaccine rollout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251227</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/millions-to-get-protected-ahead-of-winter-in-nhs-vaccine-rollout/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T12:52:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of children and adults across England will be offered their flu, COVID-19 and respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) vaccinations as the NHS sets out plans for protection ahead of winter. The vaccines provide vital protection to keep people from developing serious illnesses and ending up in hospital during busy winter months. This year, based on […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kootenai Health cyber attack impacts 464,000 patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202669</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/kootenai-health-cyber-attack-impacts-464000-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T12:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US healthcare provider Kootenai Health has revealed that data belonging to 464,000 patients has been compromised following a cyber attack.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA spells out scale of GP crisis in Darzi review evidence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885233</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-spells-scale-gp-crisis-darzi-review-evidence/article/1885233"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T11:34:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demand for GP services has outstripped supply, with underfunding driving practice closures and a growing gap between the workforce and numbers of patients that has undermined continuity of care, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs need to be 'alert' to new mpox strain, warns UKHSA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885219</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-need-alert-new-mpox-strain-warns-ukhsa/article/1885219"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:55:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs need to be ‘alert’ to the possibility of clade 1b mpox infection if a patient has a link to a country listed with confirmed or possible cases, the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202413</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-163/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Coffee Time Briefing includes Leeds Teaching Hospitals trialling an app to remotely monitor heart rhythm disorders in patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP review submissions warn Darzi over loss of care continuity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152137</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gp-review-submissions-warn-darzi-over-loss-of-care-continuity/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:27:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lord Darzi has been warned by GP leaders of risks to continuity of care, insufficient funding, and rising workload dump, in his Government review of the NHS. Last month, health secretary Wes Streeting revealed that Professor Lord Ara Darzi will lead an ‘independent investigation’ into the state of the NHS, in one of his first
The post GP review submissions warn Darzi over loss of care continuity appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UKHSA updates mpox guidance for doctors amid global health alert]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152135</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/ukhsa-updates-mpox-guidance-for-doctors-amid-global-health-alert/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:09:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) has updated its guidance to advise doctors to be aware of a new more fatal variant of mpox, currently spreading in parts of central and East Africa. The UKHSA warning, issued today, comes after the World Health Organisation declared mpox a public health emergency yesterday. There are particular concerns
The post UKHSA updates mpox guidance for doctors amid global health alert appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share of £32m AI funding to speed up prescription deliveries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202575</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/share-of-32m-ai-funding-to-speed-up-prescription-deliveries/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T10:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A project to speed up NHS prescription deliveries using AI algorithms is to receive a share of £32 million in UK government funding.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Child death overview panels: contacts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T09:09:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Contact details of the people in child death overview panels (CDOPs) who are responsible for receiving child death notifications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newly-qualified GPs could be 'driven away' by ARRS jobs plan, warns BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885120</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/newly-qualified-gps-driven-away-arrs-jobs-plan-warns-bma/article/1885120"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Newly-qualified GPs could be 'driven away' from the NHS under plans to create jobs through the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) - while experienced GPs struggling to find work risk being left out in the cold, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexarad closes £11.2m growth round for radiology platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202587</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/hexarad-closes-11-2m-funding-round-for-radiology-platform/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-15T07:30:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Radiology platform Hexarad has announced the closure of a €13 million (£11.2m) growth round with reinvestment from existing shareholders.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UKHSA warns of 'concerning rise' in antibiotic-resistant gonorrhoea cases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885111</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/ukhsa-warns-concerning-rise-antibiotic-resistant-gonorrhoea-cases/sexual-health/article/1885111"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T23:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) has warned that a 'concerning rise' in antiobiotic-resistant gonorrhoea cases in England could lead to the infection becoming untreatable in future.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO Director-General declares mpox outbreak a public health emergency of international concern]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:3a74b31d-9848-4fad-9518-86d377493cc6</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/14-08-2024-who-director-general-declares-mpox-outbreak-a-public-health-emergency-of-international-concern"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T18:55:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus has determined that the upsurge of mpox in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) and a growing number of countries in Africa constitutes a public health emergency of international concern (PHEIC) under the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR).
Dr Tedros’s declaration came on the advice of an IHR Emergency Committee of independent experts who met earlier in the day to review data presented by experts from WHO and affected countries. The Committee informed the Director-General that it considers the upsurge of mpox to be a PHEIC, with potential to spread further across countries in Africa and possibly outside the continent.
The Director-General will share the report of the Committee’s meeting and, based on the advice of the Comm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take ‘robust’ stance on racism in GP practices, NHSE advises partners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152121</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/special-investigations/gp-abuse/take-robust-stance-on-racism-in-gp-practices-nhse-advises-partners/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T15:32:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has published new guidance for GP practices on how to handle racist incidents, whether from patients or colleagues, in the wake of ‘civil unrest’ across the country. This includes taking a ‘robust’ disciplinary approach to staff involved in racist behaviour outside of work, as well as ensuring staff know what to do if
The post Take ‘robust’ stance on racism in GP practices, NHSE advises partners appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Changes to the death certification process]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/changes-to-the-death-certification-process</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/changes-to-the-death-certification-process"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T15:28:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the death certification process in England and Wales will change from 9 September 2024, including the introduction of medical examiners.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action means goodwill games are over]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152079</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/collective-action-means-goodwill-games-are-over/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T14:27:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Copperfield on why over half of England’s GP practices have not started taking collective action I found myself getting nostalgic watching the Paris Olympics, and not just for my days as a professional break-dancer. It reminded me of London 2012 and going misty-eyed at the children bouncing on NHS beds in Danny Boyle’s opening
The post Collective action means goodwill games are over appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Find help and support if you have long COVID]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/guidance/find-help-and-support-if-you-have-long-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/find-help-and-support-if-you-have-long-covid"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you have long COVID there is a range of support available.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Six NHS hospitals now fully live with NPIC digital pathology system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202493</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/six-nhs-hospitals-now-fully-live-with-npic-digital-pathology-system/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six NHS hospitals in the North of England have gone live with "digitised pathology departments" underpinned by the National Pathology Imaging Co-operative.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4537 - Microsoft Releases August 2024 Security Updates]]></title>
        <id>109955e9-5dd3-4129-8431-57e20b76a8c4</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4537"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products fix 90 vulnerabilities, including ten zero-day vulnerabilities
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products fix 90 vulnerabilities, including ten zero-day vulnerabilities
 Updated: 14 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4538 - Adobe Releases Security Updates for Acrobat and Reader]]></title>
        <id>f23828e8-5b9e-4a50-942d-224ccd27ffaa</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4538"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T12:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Successful exploitation of the critical vulnerabilities could lead to ACE or privilege escalation
 Successful exploitation of the critical vulnerabilities could lead to ACE or privilege escalation
 Updated: 14 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4536 - SAP Releases Security Update for BusinessObjects]]></title>
        <id>63eb5ba8-c97f-4427-9353-262e32dc8d76</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4536"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T11:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Successful exploitation could lead to full system compromise
 Successful exploitation could lead to full system compromise
 Updated: 14 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicines eligible for Northern Ireland MHRA Authorised Route]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T11:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out medicines that can be moved to Northern Ireland to meet patient need.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish GP practices funded to target ‘lost’ patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152110</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/scotland/scottish-gp-practices-funded-to-target-lost-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T11:01:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices in Scotland engaging with patients ‘lost’ to the system but who have the greatest need have been given an additional £1m of funds for 2024/25, following the scheme’s success last year. The Scottish government launched a programme called Inclusion Health Action in General Practice (IHAGP) in 2023 to address health inequalities in disadvantaged areas,
The post Scottish GP practices funded to target ‘lost’ patients appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA warns GPs 'now is not the time to waver' over collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1885081</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-warns-gps-now-not-time-waver-collective-action/article/1885081"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T10:43:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BMA GP leaders have urged the profession to 'push on with collective action' after revealing that global sum payments to practices will rise by 7.4% in 2024/25.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England signposts upcoming £18m health and justice EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202431</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/nhs-england-signposts-upcoming-18m-health-and-justice-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T10:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has issued a pre-procurement notice for an £18 million EPR to capture health data in the justice system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Q&A: What we know so far about GP collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152081</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/contract/qa-what-we-know-so-far-about-gp-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T09:52:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action is the big story in general practice in England this summer. But, despite the headlines, there’s been no ‘big bang’ moment – instead, we’re seeing a slow but steady change to the way general practice works. Eliza Parr looks at what the action means for GP practices. Please note, this article will be
The post Q&A: What we know so far about GP collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DrDoctor steps into mental health support with Maia acquisition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202347</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/drdoctor-steps-into-mental-health-support-with-maia-acquisition/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-14T07:30:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DrDoctor has made its first foray into the mental health and community support space after acquiring personal health record platform, Maia.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: How is collective action affecting general practice so far?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152003</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/practice-personal-finance/analysis-how-is-collective-action-affecting-general-practice-so-far/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:58:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following Pulse’s snapshot survey on collective action, we analyse the full set of data to see what it tells us about the current climate and what could happen next Ever since NHS England’s imposed 2024/25 contract for general practice was rejected by 99% of GPs in a BMA referendum, we have been slowly walking along
The post Analysis: How is collective action affecting general practice so far? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: New MCCD: check that your organisation is on the distribution list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/new-mccd-check-that-your-organisation-is-on-the-distribution-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/new-mccd-check-that-your-organisation-is-on-the-distribution-list"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:57:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Current list of organisations that will receive the new medical certificate of cause of death (MCCD), which must be used from 9 September 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Receiving the new medical certificate of cause of death (MCCD)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/guidance/receiving-the-new-medical-certificate-of-cause-of-death-mccd</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/receiving-the-new-medical-certificate-of-cause-of-death-mccd"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:56:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to get the new MCCD if your organisation uses the current MCCD.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ARRS pay rises will be ‘unfunded cost pressure’ for PCNs, claims BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152051</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/arrs-pay-rises-will-be-unfunded-cost-pressure-for-pcns-claims-bma/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:40:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pay uplifts for Additional Roles Reimbursement Scheme (ARRS) staff will be an ‘unfunded cost pressure’ for PCNs, according to the BMA. An internal BMA letter to GPC England members, sent yesterday and seen by Pulse, has clarified how pay rises recommended by the independent pay review bodies will be implemented. At the end of last
The post ARRS pay rises will be ‘unfunded cost pressure’ for PCNs, claims BMA appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contract uplift won't deliver promised 6% pay rise for GP partners, accountant warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884980</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/contract-uplift-wont-deliver-promised-6-pay-rise-gp-partners-accountant-warns/article/1884980"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T15:01:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Half of GPs are unlikely to see the 6% pay rise promised by the government because a 7.4% uplift to global sum funding in 2024/25 - confirmed this week by the BMA - will not cover a pay increase on that level for partners on top of salaried GPs and other staff, an accountant has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global sum will rise by 7.4% to fund pay uplift for GPs and staff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=152027</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/global-sum-will-rise-by-7-4-to-fund-pay-uplift-for-gps-and-staff/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T14:25:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government will increase the global sum by a total of 7.4% for 2024/25 in order to fund GP and practice staff pay rises worth 6%. An internal BMA letter to GPC England members, sent yesterday and seen by Pulse, said that this ‘aggregate’ rise will incorporate the 2.7% global sum uplift already awarded in
The post Global sum will rise by 7.4% to fund pay uplift for GPs and staff appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open consultation: Changes to rules - the Care Quality Commission (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-rules-the-care-quality-commission-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-rules-the-care-quality-commission-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T13:50:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This consultation is about 3 changes we want to make to rules that the Care Quality Commission will check (CQC for short).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global sum to rise 7.4% in 2024/25 as final detail of GP contract revealed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884911</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/global-sum-rise-74-2024-25-final-detail-gp-contract-revealed/article/1884911"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T12:59:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global sum payments to GP practices will rise by 7.4% in 2024/25 compared with the previous financial year, the BMA England GP committee has revealed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[East and North Herts first UK trust to select Dedalus ORBIS U EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202363</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/east-and-north-herts-first-uk-trust-to-select-dedalus-orbis-u-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T12:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[East and North Hertfordshire NHS Trust has become the first trust in the UK to adopt the Dedalus ORBIS U electronic patient record (EPR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult Social Work Apprenticeship Fund]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-work-apprenticeship-fund</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-work-apprenticeship-fund"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T11:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information about the Adult Social Work Apprenticeship Fund, introduced by the previous government to increase social worker capacity in adult social care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collective action plans must be put in writing to salaried and locum GPs, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884890</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/collective-action-plans-put-writing-salaried-locum-gps-says-bma/article/1884890"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T10:57:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP partners have been urged to tell salaried and locum GPs in writing if measures they take as part of collective action will significantly change employees' working day.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs with burnout already resilient and need better support, research shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151046</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gps-with-burnout-already-resilient-and-need-better-support-research-shows/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T10:32:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs who have suffered burnout do not lack resilience and need organisational support to help reduce and manage their distress, a study has found. Research based on in-depth interviews with those who had experienced burnout presented at the Society for Academic Primary Care annual conference in Bristol last month concluded that these were ‘highly motivated,
The post GPs with burnout already resilient and need better support, research shows appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201861</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-162/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T10:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Coffee Time Briefing includes a report on digital skills barriers and a new AI model for FHIR health data interoperability.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TPP awarded Sussex Community NHS EPR contract extension]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=202147</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/tpp-awarded-sussex-community-nhs-epr-contract-extension/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T09:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sussex Community NHS Foundation Trust has awarded a 10-year contract extension for an EPR system from TPP, worth almost £6.3 million.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP contract uplift will not cover 6% pay rise for all practices, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884871</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-contract-uplift-will-not-cover-6-pay-rise-practices-bma-warns/article/1884871"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T09:19:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some practices will not receive enough funding through the increased 2024/25 GP contract uplift to pass on a full 6% pay uplift to salaried GPs and other staff, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP contract uplift won't cover 6% pay rise for all practices, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884871</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-contract-uplift-wont-cover-6-pay-rise-practices-bma-warns/article/1884871"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T09:19:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some practices will not receive enough funding through the increased 2024/25 GP contract uplift to pass on a full 6% pay uplift to salaried GPs and other staff, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost half of England’s GP practices have started taking collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151971</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/almost-half-of-englands-gp-practices-have-started-taking-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T08:08:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Almost half (46%) of England’s GP practices are taking some form of collective action, with one in five putting a limit on the number of patients they see in a day, a Pulse survey has revealed. The snapshot survey of 283 GP partners from different practices – representing 5% of the practices in England
The post Almost half of England’s GP practices have started taking collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Viewpoint: Is Stockholm syndrome the real reason GPs won't give up the partnership model?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884604</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/viewpoint-stockholm-syndrome-real-reason-gps-wont-give-partnership-model/article/1884604"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GP partnership model is a sacred cow that the profession is unwilling to relinquish, but a system that leaves GPs facing the pressures of running a small business on a shoestring alongside intense clinical work seems like a recipe for burnout. Maybe it's time for a rethink, says former GP partner Dr Tom Riddington.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RSV vaccination could prevent 5,000 infant hospitalisations a year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884859</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/rsv-vaccination-prevent-5000-infant-hospitalisations-year/article/1884859"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T07:45:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RSV vaccination programme for pregnant women, which is due to start from September, could prevent 5,000 infant hospitalisations a year, health officials have said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man handed suspended jail term for threats of violence at GP practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884802</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/man-handed-suspended-jail-term-threats-violence-gp-practice/article/1884802"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T07:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man has received an 18-month suspended prison sentence after pleading guilty to offences including threatening behaviour and threatening to damage property at a GP practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Shrewsbury Hospitals opens new ‘nuclear’ gamma camera]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201903</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/royal-shrewsbury-hospitals-opens-new-nuclear-gamma-camera/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-13T07:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first patients have been scanned a new, £3.6m gamma camera at The Shrewsbury and Telford NHS Hospital Trust.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Health and Social Care Secretary Responds to CQC Review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/health-and-social-care-secretary-responds-to-cqc-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/health-and-social-care-secretary-responds-to-cqc-review"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T23:01:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health and Social Care Secretary Wes Streeting responds to the Care Quality Commission's report outlining failings in Valdo Calocane's care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders raise ‘grave concerns’ with national PCN pilot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151960</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/gp-leaders-raise-grave-concerns-with-national-pcn-pilot/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T16:20:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have raised ‘grave concerns’ with a new national PCN pilot which puts ‘excessive’ conditions on practices. The BMA GP Committee England and a group of LMCs have highlighted several issues with NHS England’s plan, including its potential to worsen health inequalities and the requirements to share income data.  In June, Pulse reported on
The post GP leaders raise ‘grave concerns’ with national PCN pilot appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New GP model pilots could trap practices in PCN DES, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1884825</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/new-gp-model-pilots-trap-practices-pcn-des-says-bma/article/1884825"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practices that join test sites piloting new models of general practice could be 'unable to opt-out of the PCN DES' for several years even if it becomes far more onerous, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England statement on collective action: Monday 12 August 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=251040</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/nhs-england-statement-on-collective-action-monday-12-august-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T15:57:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Amanda Doyle, NHS National Director for Primary Care and Community Services said: “As some practices continue collective action, it is vital that patients continue to come forward for care in the usual ways – practices remain open and services are still running. “We will be monitoring the impacts of this action to ensure practices […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Communication Breakdown: ‘I’m making a complaint!’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151517</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/communication-breakdown-station/communication-breakdown-im-making-a-complaint/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T15:47:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new series Dr Ed Pooley, GP and communication expert, shares his knowledge with readers having difficulties with colleagues and patients in the workplace. In this first instalment, he tackles the age-old question – what do you do when threatened with a complaint? Dear Dr Pooley  How should I respond if a patient says,
The post Communication Breakdown: ‘I’m making a complaint!’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designated prescribing practitioners: a national conversation for community pharmacy]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/designated-prescribing-practitioners-a-national-conversation-for-community-pharmacy.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/designated-prescribing-practitioners-a-national-conversation-for-community-pharmacy.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T14:51:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Pharmaceutical Society - This report (published together with the National Pharmacy Association) examines the challenges in accessing designated prescribing practitioners (DPPs) in community pharmacy in England. The report is the outcome of a multi-professional roundtable event in June 2024 and proposes further solutions and collaborative actions to build on the current work to support pharmacists and trainees in securing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statutory guidance: Care Act 2014: supporting implementation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/care-act-statutory-guidance</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/care-act-statutory-guidance"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T13:45:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Support for local authorities to carry out the implementation for part 1 of the Care Act 2014.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: Department of Health and Social Care information asset register]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/department-of-health-and-social-care-information-asset-register</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/department-of-health-and-social-care-information-asset-register"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T12:33:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This register lists personal and non-personal information assets held by DHSC in the UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Teaching Hospitals to trial laser-activated antimicrobial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201933</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/leeds-teaching-hospitals-to-trial-laser-activated-antimicrobial/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T12:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Teaching Hospitals is to begin trials of a new laser-activated antimicrobial in an effort to cut post-surgery infections.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and frontline staff eligible for autumn Covid boosters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151956</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/gps-and-frontline-staff-eligible-for-autumn-covid-boosters/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T10:55:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and all other patient-facing practice staff will be encouraged to take up a free Covid-19 booster vaccination through the national programme this autumn. In terms of patients, ‘all those aged 65 or over, all those in care homes for older people, and those aged 6 months or over who are in a clinical risk
The post GPs and frontline staff eligible for autumn Covid boosters appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The state of medical education and practice in the UK: workplace experiences 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/the-state-of-medical-education-and-practice-in-the-uk-workplace-experiences-2024-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/the-state-of-medical-education-and-practice-in-the-uk-workplace-experiences-2024-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T10:51:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General Medical Council (GMC) - This report is based on report evidence from the GMC's annual survey of thousands of doctors, supported by in-depth interviews and other research. It includes data and insights, to highlight where action needs to be taken to address workplace pressures and help retain doctors across all four countries of the UK. The report found that...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salaried and locum GPs must take partner lead on collective action, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151923</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/salaried-and-locum-gps-must-take-partner-lead-on-collective-action-bma-warns/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T10:08:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Salaried and locum GPs need to follow the lead of their employing partners on collective action, the BMA has warned in new guidance. Collective action began this month following a ballot result in which 98% of GP partners voted in favour, with actions including capping patient contacts at 25 per day and stopping engagement with
The post Salaried and locum GPs must take partner lead on collective action, BMA warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What can the new government learn from other countries’ attempts to reform pay in social care?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-can-the-new-government-learn-from-other-countries-attempts-to-reform-pay-in-social-care.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/what-can-the-new-government-learn-from-other-countries-attempts-to-reform-pay-in-social-care.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:48:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - This long read looks at the lessons England might learn from other countries when it comes to reforming pay for care workers, and the key principles to consider in any pay reform. Long read]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government urged to take action as clinical negligence costs continue to rise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=151928</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/government-urged-to-take-action-as-clinical-negligence-costs-continue-to-rise/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:47:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A medical defence organisation has written to the health secretary demanding urgent action to address the cost of clinical negligence to the NHS. The Medical Defence Union (MDU) said it continues to have concerns about the total cost that clinical negligence litigation poses to healthcare in the UK. The organisation has seen a ‘steady increase’
The post Government urged to take action as clinical negligence costs continue to rise appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are taking ‘collective action’: what does that mean?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/gps-are-taking-collective-action-what-does-that-mean.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/gps-are-taking-collective-action-what-does-that-mean.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:47:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - After GP partners voted on 1 August for collective action, this explainer describes what’s behind the dispute, the action that GPs plan to take, and what it might mean for patients and the government. Explainer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advice and guidance should be a DES worth millions to general practice, says BMA GP chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883319</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/advice-guidance-des-worth-millions-general-practice-says-bma-gp-chair/article/1883319"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:12:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advice and guidance is effectively 'shifting outpatients onto general practice' and should be commissioned as a multi-million pound directed enhanced service, the BMA England GP committee chair has suggested.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP who spent £40,000 to save her practice 'deserves refund']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883346</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-spent-40000-save-practice-deserves-refund/article/1883346"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who forked out £40,000 of her own money to stop her practice being handed to another provider should be fully reimbursed by the NHS, a campaigner has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP who spent £40,000 to save her practice 'deserves NHS refund']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1883346</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-spent-40000-save-practice-deserves-nhs-refund/article/1883346"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who forked out £40,000 of her own money to stop her practice being handed to another provider should be fully reimbursed by the NHS, a campaigner has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A pivotal moment for regulation: regulation and oversight survey 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-pivotal-moment-for-regulation-regulation-and-oversight-survey-2024.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/08/a-pivotal-moment-for-regulation-regulation-and-oversight-survey-2024.html"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T08:53:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This report details the findings of the latest NHS Providers' member survey, focusing on trust leaders’ views and experience of regulation during 2023/24. The report finds that trusts are experiencing intense pressures against a backdrop of 'unrealistic' regulatory demands. Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alder Hey goes live with Meditech Expanse EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=201791</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/08/alder-hey-goes-live-with-meditech-expanse-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-12T07:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alder Hey has become the second NHS trust to go live the Meditech Expanse electronic patient record system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS chief nurse urges students to consider healthcare careers through clearing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=250964</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/08/nhs-chief-nurse-urges-students-to-consider-healthcare-careers-through-clearing/"/>
        <updated>2024-08-11T23:01:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The university clearing system is a great gateway into the NHS, health bosses are reminding would-be graduates and career-changers. As thousands of students nervously await their A-level results on Thursday (15 August), the NHS is launching a campaign to highlight the many healthcare career options available through UCAS clearing. Students reconsidering their choices after receiving […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4535 - Roundcube Releases Security Updates for Webmail]]></title>
        <id>004b7f6c-b964-430f-bb6a-c3f6ec8eb34a</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4535"/>
        <updated>2024-08-08T13:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Updates address three vulnerabilities that could lead to theft of emails and contacts
 Updates address three vulnerabilities that could lead to theft of emails and contacts
 Updated: 08 Aug 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>