<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html</id>
    <title>Industry Feed</title>
    <updated>2025-07-06T10:13:39.066Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[At a glance: All the headlines from the 10-year health plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163472</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/special-investigations/10-year-health-plan/at-a-glance-all-the-headlines-from-the-10-year-health-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T14:43:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has released its plan for how the NHS in England will be reformed over the next decade. Here are the major headlines Partnership model alternative The Government will introduce two new contracts aimed at enabling GPs to work across larger geographies, as an alternative’ to the traditional GP partnership model. The first of
The post At a glance: All the headlines from the 10-year health plan appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Single patient record’ to become available via NHS App by 2028]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163466</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/single-patient-record-to-become-available-via-nhs-app-by-2028/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T13:27:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS will introduce a ‘single patient record’ (SPR) available on the NHS App by 2028, bringing a patient’s medical records and other relevant information into one place. This will make patients’ data visible to clinicians across different care settings, according to the Government’s 10-year plan published yesterday. It will introduce new legislation placing a
The post ‘Single patient record’ to become available via NHS App by 2028 appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 10-Year Plan signals the end of the GP partnership model as we know it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163465</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/the-10-year-plan-signals-the-end-of-the-gp-partnership-model-as-we-know-it/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T13:21:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Sofia Lind on what the Government’s wide-ranging NHS remodel plans will mean for the future of GP partnerships The Government’s new 10-Year Plan is billed as a bold reset for the NHS – and general practice is at the centre of the upheaval. But behind the language of opportunity lies a quiet certainty: this signals the
The post The 10-Year Plan signals the end of the GP partnership model as we know it appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS to overhaul mandatory learning and prioritise UK medical graduates for specialty training]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924448</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-overhaul-mandatory-learning-prioritise-uk-medical-graduates-specialty-training/article/1924448"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T13:13:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government will 'completely reform' mandatory training requirements by next April and prioritise UK medical graduates for foundation and specialist training, the 10-year plan has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Policy paper: Adult social care and the cost of inaction: government response to the HSCC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-and-the-cost-of-inaction-government-response-to-the-hscc</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-and-the-cost-of-inaction-government-response-to-the-hscc"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T12:58:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government response to the recommendations made by the Health and Social Care Committee (HSCC) in their report on adult social care and the cost of inaction.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Streeting promises up to 300 neighbourhood health centres by 2035]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924445</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/streeting-promises-300-neighbourhood-health-centres-2035/article/1924445"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T12:53:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Up to 300 neighbourhood health centres could be built by the end of the 10-year health plan cycle - with as many as 50 up and running by the end of the current parliament, the government has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VR improves patient experience at Leeds Children’s Hospital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231301</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/vr-improves-patient-experience-at-leeds-childrens-hospital/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T12:30:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Virtual reality technology at Leeds Children's Hospital is enabling young patients to undergo medical procedures without general anaesthetic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitals could take on contracts where GPs ‘are not stepping up’, says NHSE lead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163444</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/hospitals-could-take-on-contracts-where-gps-are-not-stepping-up-says-nhse-lead/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T11:03:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital trusts will be invited to take on new contracts for neighbourhood services where GPs ‘are not stepping up’, NHS England’s primary care director has said. Dr Amanda Doyle was speaking at an NHS England webinar on the 10-year plan last night, where she answered questions from GPs about the two new contracts which will
The post Hospitals could take on contracts where GPs ‘are not stepping up’, says NHSE lead appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New AI warning system to prompt ‘rapid response’ CQC inspections]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163389</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/new-ai-warning-system-to-prompt-rapid-response-cqc-inspections/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T10:50:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CQC will carry out ‘rapid response inspections’ of healthcare providers based on prompts from a new AI-led ‘warning system’. This forms part of the Government’s 10-year NHS plan, published yesterday, which said CQC will move to a ‘more data-led regulatory model’. A new AI-powered early warning system will monitor real-time data to flag safety issues.
The post New AI warning system to prompt ‘rapid response’ CQC inspections appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harry Hetherington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Claire Fuller: Why the NHS is rolling out at-scale alternatives to the GP contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924419</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/dr-claire-fuller-why-nhs-rolling-at-scale-alternatives-gp-contract/article/1924419"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T10:19:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing for GPonline, NHS England co-national medical director (primary care) Dr Claire Fuller says general practice is at the 'nexus' of government plans for the health service - but that reform is crucial and GPs must get on board.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA warns GP online consultation changes may cause waiting lists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=233353</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/bma-warns-gp-online-consultation-changes-may-cause-waiting-lists/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T10:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BMA leaders have warned that making GP practices keep online tools open all day will risk a spike in workload and could create waiting lists.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland GPs vote in favour of ‘unprecedented’ collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163433</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/northern-ireland-gps-vote-in-favour-of-unprecedented-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T09:47:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in Northern Ireland have voted in favour of taking collective action, following this year’s first-ever contract imposition. The BMA said that 98.7% of those who took part in a referendum voted ‘yes’ to collective action that will see GP practices across the country take the ‘unprecedented’ step of withdrawing some unfunded and non-contractual services
The post Northern Ireland GPs vote in favour of ‘unprecedented’ collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland GPs vote for collective action after imposed contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924414</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/northern-ireland-gps-vote-collective-action-imposed-contract/article/1924414"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T09:21:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in Northern Ireland have voted overwhelmingly for collective action to push for better funding, just weeks after the government imposed a contract rejected by the profession.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does the 10 year plan mean for digital?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=233779</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/what-does-the-10-year-plan-mean-for-digital/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T07:30:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health takes a look at the government’s 10 year health plan for the NHS, which includes new tools for the NHS App, such as My Health.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Understanding the financial pressures facing general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924329</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-understanding-financial-pressures-facing-general-practice/article/1924329"/>
        <updated>2025-07-04T07:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Lizzy Lloyd, chair of AISMA, the Association of Independent Specialist Medical Accountants, and a partner at the accountancy firm Larking Gowen, about GP practice finance and NHS pensions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CPD: Key questions on asthma diagnosis and management]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162717</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/respiratory/cpd-key-questions-on-asthma-diagnosis-and-management/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T16:35:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP respiratory specialist Dr Fiona Mosgrove discusses current recommended practice in the diagnosis and management of asthma, including appropriate diagnostic steps, use of eosinophil counts, the principles of recommended treatment regimens and use of fractional exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO) in monitoring. Complete the full module on Pulse 365 today. Learning objectives This module will enhance
The post CPD: Key questions on asthma diagnosis and management appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government to support AI tools rollout in GP practices over the next two years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163383</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/government-to-support-ai-tools-rollout-in-gp-practices-over-the-next-two-years/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T16:05:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government will support the rollout of artificial intelligence (AI) transcribing tools in GP practices over the next two years, in a bid to save clinicians’ time, its 10-year plan for the NHS has said.  The plan, which was released this morning, used figures from ‘local trials’ that showed ambientvoice technology (AVT) saved one to
The post Government to support AI tools rollout in GP practices over the next two years appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harry Hetherington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cardiology, mental health and respiratory to form part of major A&G expansion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163378</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/dermatology-and-wound-care/cardiology-mental-health-and-respiratory-to-form-part-of-major-ag-expansion/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T14:52:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advice and guidance (A&G) will be expanded to more specialties, with a focus in the next few years on ophthalmology, cardiology, respiratory medicine and mental health. This forms part of plans to ‘end outpatient care as we know it’, the Government said in today’s NHS 10-year plan. The plan will see outpatient services significantly redesigned
The post Cardiology, mental health and respiratory to form part of major A&G expansion appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Majority of complex patients to have personalised care plan within two years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163372</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/majority-of-complex-patients-to-have-personalised-care-plan-within-two-years/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T14:14:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost all patients with complex needs will have a personalised care plan in place within two years under targets set out in the NHS 10-year plan. By 2027, a new standard will ensure 95% of people with complex care needs will have a personalised and agreed plan in place covering both their treatment and holistic
The post Majority of complex patients to have personalised care plan within two years appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs will face legal duty to share data for NHS single patient record]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924310</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-will-face-legal-duty-share-data-nhs-single-patient-record/article/1924310"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T13:56:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government will introduce a new legal duty that will require GP practices and other NHS providers to make patient data available in a new ‘single patient record’, the 10-year plan has revealed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First areas for neighbourhood health centre rollout revealed in 10-year plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924302</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/first-areas-neighbourhood-health-centre-rollout-revealed-10-year-plan/article/1924302"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T13:21:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deprived areas with the lowest life expectancy will be the first targets for neighbourhood health centre (NHC) rollout, the government's 10-year health plan reveals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fit for the Future: Health and Social Care Secretary's statement]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/fit-for-the-future-health-and-social-care-secretarys-statement</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/fit-for-the-future-health-and-social-care-secretarys-statement"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T13:03:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wes Streeting, Secretary of State for Health and Social Care, made an oral statement announcing Fit for the Future: 10 Year Health Plan for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital health sector reacts to NHS 10 year health plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=233733</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/digital-health-sector-reacts-to-nhs-10-year-health-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T12:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Think tanks and suppliers from within the digital health sector have given their reactions to the government's 10 year health plan.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS app will become a 'doctor in your pocket', says Streeting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924286</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-app-will-become-doctor-pocket-says-streeting/article/1924286"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T11:43:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A major overhaul of the NHS app, including the introduction of a new 'My NHS GP' AI tool which will provide patients who need non-urgent care with instant advice, will become 'a doctor in your pocket', the health and social care secretary has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS app upgrade to include AI GP service, 10-year plan reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924286</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-app-upgrade-include-ai-gp-service-10-year-plan-reveals/article/1924286"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T11:43:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new tool in the NHS app - ‘My NHS GP’ - will use AI technology to provide patients who need non-urgent care with instant advice about their health problems, the 10-year health plan has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readout on WHO participation in global nuclear emergency exercise]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:e97ae234-ec32-4d24-a849-f7b48b6c575b</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/03-07-2025-readout-on-who-participation-in-global-nuclear-emergency-exercise"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T11:25:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 25 June, the World Health Organization (WHO) concluded its participation in a 36-hour nuclear emergency exercise organized by the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA).
The exercise was part of the IAEA’s Level 3 Convention Exercise (ConvEx-3), the highest and most complex level of its emergency exercises. These large-scale exercises are conducted every three to five years to test emergency preparedness and response capacities and identify areas in need of improvement. The last ConvEx-3 exercise took place in 2021 in cooperation with the United Arab Emirates.
The exercise involved more than 75 countries and 10 international organizations and was based on a simulated accident at a nuclear power plant in Romania, resulting in the release of significant amounts of radioactive material.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10-year NHS plan unveils 'alternative' to GP partnership model]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924291</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/10-year-nhs-plan-unveils-alternative-gp-partnership-model/article/1924291"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T11:22:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two new forms of GP contract will be introduced from 2026 as an 'alternative' to the traditional GP partnership model - and could be handed to hospital trusts, the government's 10-year health plan reveals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two new GP contracts to support care across larger areas, says NHS 10-year plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163348</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/two-new-gp-contracts-to-support-care-across-larger-areas-says-nhs-10-year-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T10:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government will introduce two new contracts aimed at enabling GPs to work across larger geographies, according to its long-awaited 10-year plan for the NHS. Set to roll out early next year, the new contracts will offer ‘an alternative’ to the traditional GP partnership model, the document released this morning confirmed, and will also be
The post Two new GP contracts to support care across larger areas, says NHS 10-year plan appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing healthcare easy as online banking with revamped NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/managing-healthcare-easy-as-online-banking-with-revamped-nhs-app</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/managing-healthcare-easy-as-online-banking-with-revamped-nhs-app"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T10:54:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS App to become complete digital front door to NHS, where patients book appointments, manage medicines, and view data]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232365</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-83/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T10:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This Coffee Time Briefing includes STADA's Health Report 2025 and its findings on trust in AI and a partnership for Brainomix and 3DR Labs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Live reaction to the Government’s 10-year health plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163334</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/breaking-news/live-reaction-to-the-governments-10-year-health-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T10:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government’s long-awaited 10-year health plan was published today. We will be featuring all the reaction to this news from the BMA to grassroots GPs. This will be constantly updated. If you would like to send in your reaction, email editor@pulsetoday.co.uk BMA GP committee chair Dr Katie Bramall:  ‘Whilst the Government’s acknowledgment of the need to focus
The post Live reaction to the Government’s 10-year health plan appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NICE welcomes the equal treatment of health tech with medicines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=233351</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/nice-welcomes-the-equal-treatment-of-health-tech-with-medicines/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T10:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NICE has welcomed the inclusion of a rules-Based pathway for medical technologies in the government's upcoming NHS 10 year health plan.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top ten advice and guidance requests in respiratory medicine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163338</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/respiratory/top-ten-advice-and-guidance-requests-in-respiratory-medicine/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T09:58:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continuing our series sharing expert insights on common advice and guidance (A&G) requests in key specialties, consultant in respiratory medicine Dr Himender Makker highlights ten typical examples of requests to a respiratory A&G service and explains how these should be managed Note all requests are hypothetical cases developed for illustrative purposes 1. This 68-year-old male
The post Top ten advice and guidance requests in respiratory medicine appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Policy paper: 10 Year Health Plan for England: fit for the future]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/10-year-health-plan-for-england-fit-for-the-future</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/10-year-health-plan-for-england-fit-for-the-future"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T09:50:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out the government’s 10 Year Health Plan for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Policy paper: 10 Year Health Plan for England: fit for the future (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/10-year-health-plan-for-england-fit-for-the-future-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/10-year-health-plan-for-england-fit-for-the-future-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T09:50:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 Year Health Plan for England says how we will fix the problems in the NHS to make it better for everyone.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult social care in England statistics: background quality and methodology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T08:41:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) puts together the data in its monthly reports.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Official Statistics: Adult social care in England, monthly statistics: July 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-july-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-july-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T08:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Official statistics on a range of topics including occupancy and infection control measures in adult social care settings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS will be ‘digital by default’ under 10 year health plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=233633</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/nhs-will-be-digital-by-default-under-10-year-health-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-03T07:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer will launch the government’s 10 year health plan today by setting out plans for the NHS to be ‘digital by default’.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most outpatient care in community in 10 years, says long-awaited Government plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163307</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/most-outpatient-care-in-community-in-10-years-says-long-awaited-government-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T21:33:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government will lay out plans to move ‘the majority of outpatient care’ outside of hospitals and into the community by 2035, as part of its 10-year plan for the NHS. Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer will finally launch the plan tomorrow (Thursday), pledging to ‘bring the NHS closer to home’ with new neighbourhood ‘health
The post Most outpatient care in community in 10 years, says long-awaited Government plan appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10-year plan promises at-scale GP contracts and 'new era' neighbourhood NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924153</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/10-year-plan-promises-at-scale-gp-contracts-new-era-neighbourhood-nhs/article/1924153"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T21:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New GP contracts will push practices to deliver services at scale, while millions more patients receive care outside hospital in 'neighbourhood health centres' housing GPs, social care staff, pharmacists and dentists under the government's 10-year health plan.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10-year plan: Positive step or 'death knell' for general practice?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924201</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/10-year-plan-positive-step-death-knell-general-practice/article/1924201"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T21:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have welcomed elements of the government's 10-year health plan, but highlighted a failure to focus on improvements to existing services and a lack of clarity over funding - while campaigners labelled the proposals 'the death knell for general practice as we know it'.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PM launches new era for NHS with easier care in neighbourhoods]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-launches-new-era-for-nhs-with-easier-care-in-neighbourhoods</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/pm-launches-new-era-for-nhs-with-easier-care-in-neighbourhoods"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Prime Minister launches a new era for the NHS, bringing more easily accessible care closer to home.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your experiences and potentially win £1,000]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163325</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-life/tell-us-about-your-experiences-and-potentially-win-1000/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T16:23:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We want to hear from GPs across the UK. The new Pulse survey covers topics as diverse as patient access, weight loss drugs and botched overseas surgery. It is open to all GPs in the UK. By taking our survey, you will also be entered into a prize draw for £1,000, alongside respondents to surveys
The post Tell us about your experiences and potentially win £1,000 appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital failed to flag ‘serious or unexpected’ radiology reports to GPs due to IT fault]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163311</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cancer/hospital-failed-to-flag-serious-or-unexpected-radiology-reports-to-gps-due-to-it-fault/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T16:15:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive A hospital trust has failed to flag ‘serious or unexpected’ radiology findings to local GPs due to an IT fault, Pulse can reveal. Hull University Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust’s (HUTH) told Pulse that a ‘technical issue’ meant that some radiology reports containing information which GPs needed to act on were not flagged to practices.
The post Hospital failed to flag ‘serious or unexpected’ radiology reports to GPs due to IT fault  appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harry Hetherington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO launches bold push to raise health taxes and save millions of lives]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:4417cc61-cfeb-422f-99be-d538942ed4ac</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/02-07-2025-who-launches-bold-push-to-raise-health-taxes-and-save-millions-of-lives"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T15:35:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today has launched a major new initiative urging countries to raise real prices on tobacco, alcohol, and sugary drinks by at least 50% by 2035 through health taxes in a move designed to curb chronic diseases and generate critical public revenue. The “3 by 35” Initiative comes at a time when health systems are under enormous strain from rising noncommunicable diseases (NCDs), shrinking development aid and growing public debt.
The consumption of tobacco, alcohol, and sugary drinks are fueling the NCD epidemic. NCDs, including heart disease, cancer, and diabetes, account for over 75% of all deaths worldwide. A recent report shows that a one-time 50% price increase on these products could prevent 50 million premature deaths over the next 50 years.
“Health ta…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turn conflict into growth with a free MIMS Learning webinar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924164</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/turn-conflict-growth-free-mims-learning-webinar/article/1924164"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T14:39:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join a free MIMS Learning webinar on Tuesday 15 July at 7pm.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult Social Care Learning and Development Support Scheme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-learning-and-development-support-scheme</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-learning-and-development-support-scheme"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T14:03:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information for adult social care employers in England on learning and development support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve fallen shorts of expectation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163287</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/ive-fallen-shorts-of-expectation/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T13:26:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield on the trials and tribulations of consulting in shorts during the recent heatwave As some of you may have noticed, it’s been rather warm lately. The blogger’s curse means that by the time you read this, we’ll all be wrapped up in scarves and parkas again. But the fact is that I practise in
The post I’ve fallen shorts of expectation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lifeyear raises £2.4m for remote patient management platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232015</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/lifeyear-raises-2-4m-to-launch-remote-patient-management-platform/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T12:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lifeyear has raised €2.8 million (£2.4m) to launch its remote patient management platform in the UK to deliver at-home cardiovascular care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two GP premises-owning firms could combine in £1.8bn deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163257</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/premises/two-gp-premises-owning-firms-could-combine-in-1-8bn-deal/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T11:11:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two major corporate owners of GP premises in England could combine under a proposed £1.8bn deal. Primary Health Properties (PHP) has announced a cash and shares offer worth £1.79bn which would see it combine with Assura in a REIT (Real Estate Investment Trust). PHP owns 516 primary healthcare facilities valued at £2.8bn, while Assura’s 603
The post Two GP premises-owning firms could combine in £1.8bn deal appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harry Hetherington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pregnant patients received ‘inappropriate’ medication due to pharmacy coding errors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163286</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/pregnant-patients-received-inappropriate-medication-due-to-pharmacy-coding-errors/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T11:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GP practices have been asked to review records after pregnant patients at some pharmacies were ‘incorrectly coded’, receiving ‘inappropriate supplies’ of medications as a result. NHS England undertook an investigation into the recording of pregnancy status in the Optum PharmOutcomes IT system for the Pharmacy Contraception and Pharmacy First Services, after receiving incident reports.
The post Pregnant patients received ‘inappropriate’ medication due to pharmacy coding errors appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP News Update: GPs must ‘step up’ to shape neighbourhoods, LES cuts fears, GP premises]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924075</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-news-update-gps-step-up-shape-neighbourhoods-les-cuts-fears-gp-premises/article/1924075"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T10:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Catch up quickly with our weekly round-up of key news stories for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Unplugged: Rethinking EPR procurement and optimisation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232371</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/digital-health-unplugged-rethinking-epr-procurement-and-optimisation/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T10:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jordan Sollof is joined by Mark Hutchinson of Altera to discuss EPR procurement, optimisation and delivering tangible benefits.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is blended learning and how could it change GP training?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1919146</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/blended-learning-change-gp-training/article/1919146"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T09:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have raised concerns that an NHS England pilot of ‘blended learning’ for GP registrars risks diluting the quality of training doctors receive.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHSC to launch ‘innovator passport’ to accelerate tech adoption]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=233213</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/dhsc-to-launch-innovator-passport-to-accelerate-tech-adoption/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T07:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An ‘innovator passport’ will be introduced to allow technology that has been assessed by one NHS organisation to be rolled out to others.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government begins hunt for private premises investment ahead of 10-year plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924049</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/government-begins-hunt-private-premises-investment-ahead-10-year-plan/article/1924049"/>
        <updated>2025-07-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government officials have taken the first step towards appointing private sector partners to develop new primary care premises - in a move that could underpin plans to deliver 'neighbourhood health centres in every community' as part of the forthcoming 10-year health plan.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Innovator passports’ set to accelerate cutting-edge NHS care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/innovator-passports-set-to-accelerate-cutting-edge-nhs-care</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/innovator-passports-set-to-accelerate-cutting-edge-nhs-care"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T23:15:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New 'innovator passport' will slash red tape so cutting-edge tech can be rolled out across the NHS quicker under the 10 Year Health Plan.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New ICB model poses ‘existential threat’ to independent GP practices, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163274</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/nhs-structures/new-icb-model-poses-existential-threat-to-independent-gp-practices-bma-warns/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T15:35:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plans to transfer some ICB functions to neighbourhood teams pose an ‘existential threat’ to GPs as independent contractors, the BMA has warned. Under a draft blueprint unveiled earlier this year, ICBs could soon hand some of their existing functions over to the new neighbourhood teams. But the BMA’s GP committee said the draft new model
The post New ICB model poses ‘existential threat’ to independent GP practices, BMA warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is it really all good in the hood for GPs?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163207</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/margaret-ikpoh/is-it-really-all-good-in-the-hood-for-gps/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T15:24:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of the Government’s 10-year plan, Dr Margaret Ikpoh questions the role and implementation of neighbourhood services, and what this could mean for GPs As we all await with bated breath for the Government to unveil its 10-year healthcare plan, a renewed focus on ‘neighbourhood services‘ is taking centre stage. These locally rooted models aim
The post Is it really all good in the hood for GPs? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Champix relaunched for smoking cessation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1924025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/champix-relaunched-smoking-cessation/article/1924025"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T15:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smoking cessation drug Champix is being reintroduced for UK prescribing after steps to address concerns that it contained unacceptable levels of a potentially carcinogenic impurity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pitchfest finalist MediShout secures £6.6m Series A funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=233125</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/pitchfest-finalist-medishout-secures-6-6m-series-a-funding/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T12:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former Pitchfest finalist MediShout has raised $9 million (£6.6m) in Series A funding to accelerate expansion across Europe and the US.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS 10-year plan ‘will prioritise UK medical graduates for speciality training’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163264</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/nhs-10-year-plan-will-prioritise-uk-medical-graduates-for-speciality-training/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T11:19:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The upcoming 10-year plan for the NHS will reportedly pledge to prioritise UK medical graduates – and other doctors who have worked in the NHS ‘for a significant period’ – for foundation and specialty training. The Government will commit to hiring no more than one in 10 NHS recruits from overseas in order to create
The post NHS 10-year plan ‘will prioritise UK medical graduates for speciality training’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harry Hetherington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231599</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-81/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T10:30:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition includes a closer look at concerns on the UK's approach to regulating AI in healthcare and digital support for unpaid carers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4678 - Google Releases Security Updates for Chrome]]></title>
        <id>cd978396-23ca-466d-a154-2031ecd232cb</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4678"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T10:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security update addresses an exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome where an attacker could perform perform arbitrary read/write
 Security update addresses an exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome where an attacker could perform perform arbitrary read/write
 Updated: 01 Jul 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could bulk-warn patients about GLP-1 contraception interaction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163165</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/diabetes-endocrinology/gps-could-bulk-warn-patients-about-glp-1-contraception-interaction/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T09:51:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could bulk-warn patients about the risk of GLP-1 weight-loss drug injections potentially making their hormonal contraception less effective, it has been suggested. Advice from the BMA set out ahead of the phased rollout of tirzepatide for weight loss for some patients on the NHS flagged that women wishing to start a GLPI-1 agonist for
The post GPs could bulk-warn patients about GLP-1 contraception interaction appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICB mergers could slash locally-commissioned GP services, LMCs fear]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923656</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/icb-mergers-slash-locally-commissioned-gp-services-lmcs-fear/article/1923656"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T08:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plans to merge ICBs into larger 'clusters' could lead to cuts in local enhanced service (LES) funding as managers look to equalise spending across newly-formed organisations, LMCs have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cost of NI patient record system rises to £360m]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231901</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/07/expected-cost-of-ni-patient-record-system-rises-to-360m/"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T07:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cost of the encompass digital records system for Northern Irish health trusts is now expected to reach £360m.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opening online access 'floodgate' risks waiting lists for GP care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923911</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/opening-online-access-floodgate-risks-waiting-lists-gp-care/article/1923911"/>
        <updated>2025-07-01T07:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices could be forced to use waiting lists to manage demand when rules around online consultation tools change later this year, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government to ‘rapidly’ explore private investment in GP infrastructure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163241</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/premises/government-to-rapidly-explore-private-investment-in-gp-infrastructure/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T15:47:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government will explore private investment in primary and community health infrastructure, a strategy paper has revealed. The Public Private Partnership (PPP) model has not been used by central Government since 2018, but a new 10-year infrastructure strategy proposed reintroducing the model for taxpayer-funded projects ‘in very limited circumstances where they could represent value for
The post Government to ‘rapidly’ explore private investment in GP infrastructure appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes to DHSC group accounting manual 2025 to 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2025-to-2026</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/changes-to-dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2025-to-2026"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T15:21:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This consultation seeks views on the DHSC group accounting manual that applies to DHSC bodies for their annual reports and accounts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: DHSC group accounting manual 2025 to 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2025-to-2026</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2025-to-2026"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T15:19:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mandatory annual reports and accounts guidelines for the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) group bodies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suriname certified malaria-free by WHO]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:2a7cb79c-aa0b-47d8-ba70-f3ef64558506</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/30-06-2025-suriname-certified-malaria-free-by-who"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T14:59:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, Suriname became the first country in the Amazon region to receive malaria-free certification from the World Health Organization (WHO). This historic milestone follows nearly 70 years of commitment by the government and people of Suriname to eliminate the disease across its vast rainforests and diverse communities.
“WHO congratulates Suriname on this remarkable achievement,” said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General. “This certification is a powerful affirmation of the principle that everyone—regardless of nationality, background, or migration status—deserves universal access to malaria diagnosis and treatment. Suriname’s steadfast commitment to health equity serves as an inspiration to all countries striving for a malaria-free future.”
With today’s announcement, a tot…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of NHS quangos to be scrapped as part of 10-year plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163249</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/nhs-structures/hundreds-of-nhs-quangos-to-be-scrapped-as-part-of-10-year-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T14:46:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A number for NHS quangos will be scrapped to cut ‘wasteful spending’ as part of the upcoming 10-year plan, the Government has announced. It will abolish 201 NHS organisations, bodies and entities, including Healthwatch England, Health Services Safety Investigations Body and the National Guardian’s Office. The Government will also close Commissioning Support Units, set up
The post Hundreds of NHS quangos to be scrapped as part of 10-year plan appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI system to identify unsafe care ‘before it becomes a tragedy’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=233069</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/ai-system-to-identify-unsafe-care-before-it-becomes-a-tragedy/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T12:40:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An AI early warning system is being developed, as part of the 10 year health plan, to automatically identify safety concerns across the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beyond sleepless nights: managing chronic insomnia in adults in primary care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921118</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/beyond-sleepless-nights-managing-chronic-insomnia-adults-primary-care/article/1921118"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join us for this MIMS Learning webinar series focusing on chronic insomnia, initiated and funded by Idorsia Pharmaceuticals UK Ltd and and intended for UK healthcare professionals only.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Concerning acceleration’ in drug-resistant gonorrhoea ahead of vaccine programme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162488</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/sexual-health/concerning-acceleration-in-drug-resistant-gonorrhoea-ahead-of-vaccine-programme/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T10:20:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public health officials have warned of a ‘concerning acceleration’ in cases of antibiotic-resistant gonorrhoea in England. A report from the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) found that while diagnoses of gonorrhoea dropped by 16% overall in 2024, those resistant to ceftriaxone were being detected more frequently. This includes 14 cases reported in the first five
The post ‘Concerning acceleration’ in drug-resistant gonorrhoea ahead of vaccine programme appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS 10-year plan must commit to increasing GP investment each year, says RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163238</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/nhs-10-year-plan-must-commit-to-increasing-gp-investment-each-year-says-rcgp/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T10:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP has called for a ‘primary care investment standard’ to be included in the upcoming NHS 10-year plan, ensuring that the Government and ICBs increase their spending on general practice each year. To fulfil the Government’s ambition to ‘shift care from hospitals into the community’, the college warned that a ‘significant uplift’ in primary
The post NHS 10-year plan must commit to increasing GP investment each year, says RCGP appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All-female line-up of Digital Health advisory panel chairs elected]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232551</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/all-female-line-up-of-digital-health-advisory-panel-chairs-elected/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T10:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An all-female line-up of Digital Health Networks advisory panel chairs has been elected for the first time.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs must 'step up' to avoid being sidelined under 10-year NHS plan, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923741</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-step-up-avoid-sidelined-10-year-nhs-plan-says-bma/article/1923741"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T09:45:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice risks being sidelined unless the profession forms 'provider collaboratives' and positions itself to lead the shift to a neighbourhood NHS under the government's 10-year health plan, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS 10 year health plan: What do we know so far?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232733</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/the-nhs-10-year-health-plan-what-do-we-know-so-far/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T07:30:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the publication of the 10 year health plan approaches, Digital Health News editor Tammy Lovell takes a look at what we know so far.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IMG GPs fear joblessness and deportation, GP leader warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923070</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/img-gps-fear-joblessness-deportation-gp-leader-warns/article/1923070"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[International medical graduate (IMG) registrars and newly-qualified GPs fear deportation and are grappling with their mental health as they struggle to find work and secure visas, a GP registrar leader has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social connection linked to improved heath and reduced risk of early death]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:e4a1d323-ec31-4b0b-ad6b-de3b84d8ae70</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/30-06-2025-social-connection-linked-to-improved-heath-and-reduced-risk-of-early-death"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T06:43:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) Commission on Social Connection has released its global report revealing that 1 in 6 people worldwide is affected by loneliness, with significant impacts on health and well-being. Loneliness is linked to an estimated 100 deaths every hour—more than 871 000 deaths annually. Strong social connections can lead to better health and longer life, the report says.

“In this Report, we pull back the curtain on loneliness and isolation as a defining challenge of our time. Our Commission lays out a road map for how we can build more connected lives and underscores the profound impact this can have on health, educational, and economic outcomes,” said Dr Vivek Murthy, Co-chair of the WHO Commission on Social Connection, and former Surgeon General of the United State…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World-first AI system to warn of NHS patient safety concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/world-first-ai-system-to-warn-of-nhs-patient-safety-concerns</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/world-first-ai-system-to-warn-of-nhs-patient-safety-concerns"/>
        <updated>2025-06-30T04:35:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pioneering AI technology will be developed to scan NHS systems to flag safety issues in real time and trigger crucial inspections earlier]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Healthy food revolution to tackle obesity epidemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/healthy-food-revolution-to-tackle-obesity-epidemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/healthy-food-revolution-to-tackle-obesity-epidemic"/>
        <updated>2025-06-29T05:43:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New healthy food standard will see big businesses promoting healthier food and drink]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI will lead GPs up the garden path to oblivion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163125</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/ai-will-lead-gps-up-the-garden-path-to-oblivion/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T15:40:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield pits AI against GPs to see what the future may hold for the profession Welcome to this week’s clinical case. A conifer develops lots of persistent web-like material over its leaves. What would be your differential? You should be thinking spider mites, spiders or fungus, right? So what if I told you there is
The post AI will lead GPs up the garden path to oblivion appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Mounjaro mismatch – patient expectation versus GP reality]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163182</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/the-mounjaro-mismatch-patient-expectation-versus-gp-reality/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T14:53:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emma Wilkinson speaks to GPs across England as they raise the alarm over a chaotic rollout of weight-loss drug Mounjaro on the NHS this week All week, patients have arrived expecting access to tirzepatide (Mounjaro), only to find services are not in place and practices have been told not to prescribe. Since Pulse first reported
The post The Mounjaro mismatch – patient expectation versus GP reality appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UKHSA provides update on Nimbus Covid variant spread]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163161</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/ukhsa-provides-update-on-nimbus-covid-variant-spread/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T14:24:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK public health officials have issued an update about the new Covid variant that appears to be spreading internationally. The UK Health Security Agency said the NB.1.8.1 variant – sometimes known as Nimbus – had been detected in small numbers in the UK to date. It has been declared as a variant that is being
The post UKHSA provides update on Nimbus Covid variant spread appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO Scientific advisory group issues report on origins of COVID-19]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:aa058e2a-7385-43a4-968a-b61a1b44c741</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/27-06-2025-who-scientific-advisory-group-issues-report-on-origins-of-covid-19"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T13:18:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The WHO Scientific Advisory Group for the Origins of Novel Pathogens (SAGO), a panel of 27 independent, international, multidisciplinary experts, today published its report on the origins of SARS-CoV-2, the virus responsible for the COVID-19 pandemic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicines eligible for Northern Ireland MHRA Authorised Route]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T12:54:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out medicines that can be moved to Northern Ireland to meet patient need.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS App could offer AI-driven mental health support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232573</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhs-app-could-offer-ai-driven-mental-health-support/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T12:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will get better access to mental health support through the NHS App under the NHS 10 year health plan, the DHSC has announced.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wide variation in repeat prescription lengths across England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163189</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/wide-variation-in-repeat-prescription-lengths-across-england/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T11:05:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is a wide variation in repeat prescription lengths by GP practices across England, researchers have found. Their report published in the British Journal of General Practice (BJGP) focused on prescriptions issued for five common routine medications – ramipril, atorvastatin, simvastatin, levothyroxine and amlodipine – between 2018 and 2019. Doctors are asked to select ‘clinically
The post Wide variation in repeat prescription lengths across England appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paying GPs for performance does not bring lasting clinical improvements, finds study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163154</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/paying-gps-for-performance-does-not-bring-lasting-clinical-improvements-finds-study/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T10:52:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The introduction of QOF did not drive lasting change, say researchers who found that GP pay for performance is not a ‘magic bullet’ to improving quality. A systematic review of studies done on the impact of QOF found that in the first year it did drive up quality of care as recorded on GP systems.
The post Paying GPs for performance does not bring lasting clinical improvements, finds study appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lifeyear raises £2.4m to launch remote patient management platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232015</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/lifeyear-raises-2-4m-to-launch-remote-patient-management-platform/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T10:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lifeyear has raised €2.8 million (£2.4m) to launch its remote patient management platform in the UK to deliver at-home cardiovascular care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland’s ‘Digital Front Door’ app launch ‘may be underwhelming’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232243</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/scotlands-digital-front-door-app-launch-may-be-underwhelming/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T10:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland's version of the NHS App will only be available to dermatology patients in one area initially, the government has confirmed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitals must not define neighbourhood NHS, GP leader warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923517</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/hospitals-not-define-neighbourhood-nhs-gp-leader-warns/article/1923517"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T07:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital trusts must not end up defining how neighbourhoods take shape, a leading GP has warned, ahead of the publication of the government's 10-year plan for the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK joins global network for the safe use of AI in healthcare]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232137</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/uk-joins-global-network-for-the-safe-use-of-ai-in-healthcare/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T07:30:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK has become the first country to join a new global network of health regulators focused on the safe use of AI in healthcare.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Shaping the future for GPs in London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923524</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-shaping-future-gps-london/article/1923524"/>
        <updated>2025-06-27T06:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Dr Lisa Harrod-Rothwell, chief executive of Londonwide LMCs, about the key challenges facing practices in the capital and how the move to neighbourhood working could affect them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost to mental health services from thousands of extra staff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/boost-to-mental-health-services-from-thousands-of-extra-staff</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/boost-to-mental-health-services-from-thousands-of-extra-staff"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T23:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Latest data shows 6,700 more mental health workers have been recruited towards government’s 8,500 target.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4675 - Cisco Releases Security Advisory Affecting Cisco Identity Service Engine]]></title>
        <id>2d13d5c1-a001-45c8-be6c-edb17a7c7ba5</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4675"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisory addresses two critical severity vulnerabilities in Cisco Identity Service Engine which could lead to remote code execution
 Advisory addresses two critical severity vulnerabilities in Cisco Identity Service Engine which could lead to remote code execution
 Updated: 26 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact assessment: Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill: equality impact assessment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/terminally-ill-adults-end-of-life-bill-equality-impact-assessment</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/terminally-ill-adults-end-of-life-bill-equality-impact-assessment"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:24:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The equality impact assessment presents the impacts of the Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact assessment: Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill: ECHR memorandum]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/terminally-ill-adults-end-of-life-bill-echr-memorandum</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/terminally-ill-adults-end-of-life-bill-echr-memorandum"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:24:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Memorandum on the European Convention on Human Rights (ECHR) relating to the Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact assessment: Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill: impact assessment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/terminally-ill-adults-end-of-life-bill-impact-assessment</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/terminally-ill-adults-end-of-life-bill-impact-assessment"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:24:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The impact assessment presents the impacts of the Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland GPs enter ‘formal dispute’ with Government over underfunding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163166</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/scotland/scotland-gps-enter-formal-dispute-with-government-over-underfunding/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:08:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA in Scotland has moved into ‘formal dispute’ with the Government over years of underfunding. Today the union’s Scottish GP committee wrote to cabinet secretary for health Neil Gray and informed him they have entered formal dispute with Scottish Government. It comes after Scottish LMCs representatives voted in favour of balloting the profession on industrial
The post Scotland GPs enter ‘formal dispute’ with Government over underfunding appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4674 - Active Exploitation of Zero-Day Vulnerability CVE-2025-6543 in NetScaler ADC and NetScaler Gateway]]></title>
        <id>9b5e9142-dfb9-4fe5-b749-f8aa4fadedf7</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4674"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: High
 Citrix has released a security advisory to address exploited vulnerability CVE-2025-6543 that could lead to unintended control flow or a denial-of-service condition.
 Citrix has released a security advisory to address exploited vulnerability CVE-2025-6543 that could lead to unintended control flow or a denial-of-service condition.
 Updated: 26 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: special advisers' gifts, hospitality and meetings, January to March 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-special-advisers-gifts-hospitality-and-meetings-january-to-march-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-special-advisers-gifts-hospitality-and-meetings-january-to-march-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data on gifts and hospitality received by special advisers, and meetings they attended with senior media figures.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: senior officials’ business expenses, hospitality and meetings, January to March 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-senior-officials-business-expenses-hospitality-and-meetings-january-to-march-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-senior-officials-business-expenses-hospitality-and-meetings-january-to-march-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All data on senior officials’ business expenses, external meetings and hospitality.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: ministerial travel and meetings, January to March 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-ministerial-travel-and-meetings-january-to-march-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-ministerial-travel-and-meetings-january-to-march-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data on ministers' external meetings and any overseas travel.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: business appointment rules advice, January to March 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-business-appointment-rules-advice-january-to-march-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-business-appointment-rules-advice-january-to-march-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T15:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summaries of advice given under the business appointment rules to applicants at SCS2 and SCS1 level and equivalents.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs urged to be vigilant to pancreatitis in patients taking weight-loss drugs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163158</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-urged-to-be-vigilant-to-pancreatitis-in-patients-taking-weight-loss-drugs/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T14:56:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been urged to be vigilant to signs of acute pancreatitis in patients who are taking GLP-1 weight-loss drugs. A team of academics have issued guidance for GPs on how to manage patients – including those who may be privately accessing weight-loss medicines. Among the recommendations – from researchers at King’s College London and
The post GPs urged to be vigilant to pancreatitis in patients taking weight-loss drugs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the month – answers: Did you get the diagnosis in this child who ‘can’t shake off a bug’?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163059</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/case-of-the-month-answers-did-you-get-the-diagnosis-in-child-who-cant-shake-off-a-bug/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T14:04:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest in our series, Dr David Capehorn asked what might be the underlying cause in a child who is withdrawn and lethargic several weeks after apparent gastroenteritis. Did you get the diagnosis? Answer revealed below! Note details of the case have been changed to protect individuals’ identities A pale-looking five-year-old is brought into
The post Case of the month – answers: Did you get the diagnosis in this child who ‘can’t shake off a bug’? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Independent mental capacity advocates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/independent-mental-capacity-advocates</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/independent-mental-capacity-advocates"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T13:02:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People who lack mental capacity can be helped to express their views by an independent mental capacity advocate service.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI tool will launch on NHS App to help tackle health inequalities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232357</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhs-app-ai-tool-planned-to-tackle-health-inequalities/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T12:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An AI tool will be added to the NHS App to help tackle health inequalities, as part of measures under the 10 year health plan.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advice accepted on autumn 2025 COVID-19 vaccination programme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/advice-accepted-on-autumn-2025-covid-19-vaccination-programme</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/advice-accepted-on-autumn-2025-covid-19-vaccination-programme"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T11:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government has accepted advice from the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation (JCVI) for the autumn 2025 COVID-19 vaccination programme]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs told they will not be paid for shifts after private company went into administration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163131</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/urgent-care/gps-told-they-will-not-be-paid-for-shifts-after-private-company-went-into-administration/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T10:57:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Sessional GPs who worked for a private company providing out-of-hours and NHS 111 services have been told they will not be paid for shifts completed last month, after the company went into administration. Totally PLC, the parent company for Vocare, recently entered administration and at the beginning of this month was taken over by
The post GPs told they will not be paid for shifts after private company went into administration appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231561</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-82/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T10:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This morning's edition of Coffee Time includes the world's first tech-enabled contraception and the launch of Genomics' Health Insights tool.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patient death linked to cyber attack on NHS pathology provider]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232249</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/patient-dies-as-a-result-of-cyber-attack-on-nhs-pathology-provider/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T10:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first patient death linked to the cyber attack last year on NHS pathology system provider Synnovis has been confirmed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once in a lifetime: Mycosis fungoides]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163037</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/dermatology-and-wound-care/once-in-a-lifetime-mycosis-fungoides/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T09:58:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continuing our series on conditions GPs may only encounter once in their career, GP dermatology specialist Dr Anna Trigell explains how not to miss a case of mycosis fungoides What is it? Contrary to the name, it is not anything to do with a fungal infection. The alternative term primary cutaneous T-cell lymphoma is more
The post Once in a lifetime: Mycosis fungoides appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS App to get AI feature to guide questions during GP consultations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163134</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/nhs-app-to-get-ai-feature-to-guide-questions-during-gp-consultations/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T09:35:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS App will get an AI feature that will allow patients to discuss their health issues and help guide their GP consultations. Patients will be able to access more information about their healthcare including choosing where they are treated, health secretary Wes Streeting announced today. The upgraded version of the NHS App will help
The post NHS App to get AI feature to guide questions during GP consultations appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Independent report: Patient Safety Commissioner annual report 2024 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/patient-safety-commissioner-annual-report-2024-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/patient-safety-commissioner-annual-report-2024-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T09:18:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patient Safety Commissioner annual report for the financial year 2024 to 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New BMA chair promises to end 'exploitation' of doctors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923422</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/new-bma-chair-promises-end-exploitation-doctors/article/1923422"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T09:18:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anaesthetic consultant Dr Tom Dolphin has been elected chair of the BMA - and promised to end 'exploitation and erosion' of the medical profession.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health and Social Care Secretary speech on health inequalities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/health-and-social-care-secretary-speech-on-health-inequalities</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/health-and-social-care-secretary-speech-on-health-inequalities"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T09:16:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wes Streeting spoke at Blackpool Football club on reducing health inequalities.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England approves new clinical IT system for general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163128</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/nhs-england-approves-new-clinical-it-system-for-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T08:10:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new IT system for general practice has been approved by NHS England, the commissioner has announced today. The new core clinical GP IT system created by Medicus Health is already live in ‘four early-adopting sites’, serving over 42,000 patients in total, and will now available to practices across the country, NHS England said today. The
The post NHS England approves new clinical IT system for general practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE approves Medicus Health EPR system for primary care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=232201</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhse-approves-medicus-health-epr-system-for-primary-care/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-26T07:30:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has introduced the first new core IT system for GP practices across England in 25 years under the Tech Innovation Framework.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['New generation' IT system approved for rollout to GP practices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923366</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/new-generation-system-approved-rollout-gp-practices/article/1923366"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T23:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first of a 'new generation' of GP IT systems has been approved for rollout to practices - with more expected to become available over the coming months, NHS England has announced.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS approves new IT system for GPs to help transform care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268599</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-approves-new-it-system-for-gps-to-help-transform-care/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T23:01:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices across England can now access new technology with the introduction of the first new core IT system for 25 years. As part of reforms to increase competition and innovation in the market, NHS England has approved the first of a new generation of electronic patient record systems for GPs – with more suppliers […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS App overhaul will break down barriers to healthcare and reduce inequalities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nhs-app-overhaul-will-break-down-barriers-to-healthcare-and-reduce-inequalities</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nhs-app-overhaul-will-break-down-barriers-to-healthcare-and-reduce-inequalities"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T17:03:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS App will be transformed so it gives every patient information, choice and control of their own healthcare.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs caught in the middle of a muddled tirzepatide rollout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163085</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-caught-in-the-middle-of-a-muddled-tirzepatide-rollout/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T13:16:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Sofia Lind questions the lack of planning, support and infrastructure for GPs among the rollout of tirzepatide in primary care This week marks the start of the tirzepatide rollout in primary care. It’s a significant milestone for a drug that could transform the treatment of obesity. But while the clinical potential is clear, the
The post GPs caught in the middle of a muddled tirzepatide rollout appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK medical graduates should be prioritised for GP training posts, BMA says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923321</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/uk-medical-graduates-prioritised-gp-training-posts-bma-says/article/1923321"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T12:56:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK medical graduates should be prioritised ahead of overseas recruits for GP training posts, doctors' leaders have said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP News Update: GP funding overhaul, tirzepatide complaint fears, GP premises investment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923268</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-news-update-gp-funding-overhaul-tirzepatide-complaint-fears-gp-premises-investment/article/1923268"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T12:37:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Catch up quickly with our weekly round-up of key news stories for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guy’s and St Thomas’ to launch open source intranet platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231725</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/guys-and-st-thomas-to-launch-open-source-intranet-platform/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T12:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust has announced plans to implement a new intranet system in partnership with Torchbox Public.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energy access has improved, yet international financial support still needed to boost progress and address disparities]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:e8d6912a-b3e8-477e-ac64-b2a70692f3e3</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/25-06-2025-energy-access-has-improved--yet-international-financial-support-still-needed-to-boost-progress-and-address-disparities"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T12:04:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tracking SDG 7: The Energy Progress Report 2025 finds that almost 92% of the world’s population now has basic access to electricity. Although this is an improvement since 2022, which saw the number of people without basic access decrease for the first time in a decade, over 666 million people remain without access, indicating that the current rate is insufficient to reach universal access by 2030. Clean cooking access is progressing but below the rates of progress seen in the 2010s, as efforts remain hobbled by setbacks during the Covid-19 pandemic, following energy price shocks, and debt crises.
Released today, the latest edition of the annual report that tracks progress towards Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) 7 highlights the role of distributed renewable energy (a combination of mini…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One in eight in senior NHS staff from black and minority ethnic backgrounds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268577</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/one-in-eight-in-senior-nhs-staff-from-black-and-minority-ethnic-backgrounds/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T11:23:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One in eight senior managers in the NHS are from black and minority ethnic (BME) backgrounds, according to new figures published today. The 2024 NHS Workforce Race Equality Standard (WRES) report showed that 12.7% of staff at very senior manager level are from these backgrounds – up from one in nine (11.2%) in 2023. Overall, this marks […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doctor leaders vote to ‘prioritise’ UK medical graduates for training posts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163109</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/doctor-leaders-vote-to-prioritise-uk-medical-graduates-for-training-posts/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T11:13:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctor leaders have backed a proposal to prioritise UK medical school graduates over international medical graduates (IMGs) for training posts. BMA leaders voted in favour of a motion to guarantee all UK medical school graduates a foundation programme post for all future recruitment cycles, as well as offering UK graduates specialty training posts first. At
The post Doctor leaders vote to ‘prioritise’ UK medical graduates for training posts appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Combination finerenone and empagliflozin superior in CKD with diabetes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162651</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/renal-medicine-urology-mens-health/combination-finerenone-and-empagliflozin-superior-in-ckd-with-diabetes/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T10:29:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients with both chronic kidney disease (CKD) and type 2 diabetes may benefit from initial therapy with finerenone and empagliflozin together, US researchers have concluded. The combination of the non-steroidal mineralocorticoid receptor antagonist (MRA) and the sodium–glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitor (SLGT2) led to a greater reduction in the urinary albumin-to-creatinine ratio than either treatment alone. An
The post Combination finerenone and empagliflozin superior in CKD with diabetes appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Landmark plan to rebuild NHS in working class communities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/landmark-plan-to-rebuild-nhs-in-working-class-communities</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/landmark-plan-to-rebuild-nhs-in-working-class-communities"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T10:10:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10 Year Health Plan will set out how the government plans to tackle inequalities in people’s health through fundamental reforms to our health system]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Wales expands digital toolkit for diabetes management]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231631</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhs-wales-expands-digital-toolkit-for-diabetes-management/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T10:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three diabetes apps have been made available across Wales to complement a government face-to-face programme.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs told they cannot prescribe Mounjaro as several ICBs fail to finalise service in time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163090</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-told-they-cannot-prescribe-mounjaro-as-several-icbs-fail-to-finalise-service-in-time/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T09:59:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP in many parts of England are having explain to eligible patients that tirzepatide (Mounjaro) cannot be prescribed in primary care yet, despite the NICE deadline having now passed. Commissioning guidance stated that tirzepatide for weight loss must be implemented in primary care by Monday this week (23 June), but several ICBs have told practices that
The post GPs told they cannot prescribe Mounjaro as several ICBs fail to finalise service in time appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soliton IT and xWave partner to improve NHS radiology workflow]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231741</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/soliton-it-and-xwave-partner-to-improve-nhs-radiology-workflow/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T07:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Soliton IT and xWave Technologies have joined forces to integrate their solutions and improve NHS radiology workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10-year NHS plan will promise 'major changes' to GP funding formula]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923195</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/10-year-nhs-plan-will-promise-major-changes-gp-funding-formula/article/1923195"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T23:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government will promise 'major changes to how GP funding is distributed' as part of its imminent 10-year health plan, with reforms targeting underfunding and GP shortages in deprived areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carr-Hill GP funding formula review announced as part of 10-year NHS plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163072</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/carr-hill-gp-funding-formula-review-announced-as-part-of-10-year-nhs-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The upcoming 10-year plan for health will include a review of the Carr-Hill formula for GP funding, so that ‘working-class areas’ receive their ‘fair share of resources’, the Government has said. Health secretary Wes Streeting will announce ‘major changes’ to how GP funding is distributed to ‘help working class communities and coastal areas’ during a
The post Carr-Hill GP funding formula review announced as part of 10-year NHS plan appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Investing in general practice – if not now, when?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162744</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/katie-musgrave/investing-in-general-practice-if-not-now-when/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T15:52:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anticipating another glossy NHS strategy as the 10-year-plan looms, Dr Katie Musgrave asks: If this isn’t the time to properly invest in general practice, then when is? At the NHS Confederation conference earlier this month, NHSE primary care director Amanda Doyle said the 10-year-plan for the NHS will be ‘GP-centric’ – while stressing this would not
The post Investing in general practice – if not now, when? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10-year plan to introduce HPV self-sampling for ‘under-screened’ women]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163045</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/10-year-plan-to-introduce-hpv-self-sampling-for-under-screened-women/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T15:35:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Under-screened women will be offered HPV self-sampling kits to detect cervical cancer as part of the Government’s upcoming 10-year health plan. The home-testing kits will be sent to women across England who have missed their invite to the cervical screening programme. The initiative aims to make care more convenient and support the shift from treatment
The post 10-year plan to introduce HPV self-sampling for ‘under-screened’ women appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacy First uptake falling short of expectations, says Kinnock]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163075</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/dermatology-and-wound-care/pharmacy-first-uptake-falling-short-of-expectations-says-kinnock/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T15:17:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Primary care minister Stephen Kinnock has said that take-up of Pharmacy First is not where the Government ‘would like it to be’. As a result, the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) is looking at options to increase awareness of the scheme and to ‘free up pharmacists to be able to operate at the
The post Pharmacy First uptake falling short of expectations, says Kinnock appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Immigration reform risks new barrier to NHS jobs for IMG GPs, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922674</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/immigration-reform-risks-new-barrier-nhs-jobs-img-gps-says-bma/article/1922674"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T14:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plans to extend the qualifying period for indefinite leave to remain in the UK to 10 years could make it even harder for international medical graduate (IMG) GPs to find NHS jobs, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MHRA AI Airlock regulatory sandbox receives £1m investment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231873</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/mhra-ai-airlock-regulatory-sandbox-receives-1m-investment/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T12:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency’s (MHRA) AI airlock programme has received £1 million in funding.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 60% of GPs ‘unsatisfied’ with Government’s handling of general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162957</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/over-60-of-gps-unsatisfied-with-governments-handling-of-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T10:36:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Over 60% of GPs are ‘unsatisfied’ with the Government’s handing of general practice, a new Pulse survey has found. The poll of 667 GPs found that 30.58% are ‘quite unsatisfied’ and 32.83% are ‘very unsatisfied’ with Labour’s handling of issues surrounding general practice. In response to these results, the Department of Health and Social
The post Over 60% of GPs ‘unsatisfied’ with Government’s handling of general practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230961</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-80/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T10:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Coffee Time includes investment for Imperial-startup Flomark and the launch of Aneira Health - a platform for women.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA demands GMC chief executive’s resignation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163023</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/bma-demands-gmc-chief-executives-resignation/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T10:26:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has demanded the resignation of the GMC’s chief executive and a ‘performance review’ of the regulator’s current senior management team. At their annual representative meeting (ARM) in Liverpool today, BMA leaders called on the union to set out ‘a vision for a reformed GMC’ or for a new ‘alternative regulator’, and to lobby
The post BMA demands GMC chief executive’s resignation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DHSC to roll out national maternity dashboard to address failings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231973</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/dhsc-to-roll-out-national-maternity-dashboard-to-address-failings/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T10:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Department of Health and Social Care will roll out a national maternity dashboard, as part of measures to address failings in care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: DHSC group accounting manual 2024 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2024-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-group-accounting-manual-2024-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T09:50:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mandatory annual reports and accounts guidelines for the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) group bodies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs fear wave of complaints over tirzepatide rollout in primary care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1923087</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-fear-wave-complaints-tirzepatide-rollout-primary-care/article/1923087"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T08:57:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs fear a wave of complaints from patients hoping to access the weight-loss drug tirzepatide in primary care - amid warnings that many practices will be unable to offer it until weeks or months after a widely-publicised deadline.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home testing kits for lifesaving checks against cervical cancer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/home-testing-kits-for-lifesaving-checks-against-cervical-cancer</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/home-testing-kits-for-lifesaving-checks-against-cervical-cancer"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T08:29:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government to offer home-testing kits as part of the cervical screening programme under its upcoming 10 Year Health Plan.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[East Cheshire and Mid Cheshire trusts launch joint EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231425</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/east-cheshire-and-mid-cheshire-trusts-launch-joint-epr/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-24T07:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[East Cheshire NHS Trust and Mid Cheshire Hospitals NHS Foundation trust have gone live with a joint electronic patient record (EPR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA leaders back GPs declining to prescribe specialist medication]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163010</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/bma-leaders-back-gps-declining-to-prescribe-specialist-medication/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T15:28:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctor leaders have voted in support of GPs declining to prescribe specialist medication in certain circumstances, including if initiated by non-prescribers, and demanded electronic prescribing is rolled out across the UK. At their annual representative meeting (ARM) in Liverpool today, BMA leaders passed a motion arguing that requests from secondary care clinicians asking GPs to
The post BMA leaders back GPs declining to prescribe specialist medication appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tobacco control efforts protect 6.1 billion people – WHO’s new report]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:ed95873b-68f2-4cb9-b4c1-ebce9f8edfab</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/23-06-2025-tobacco-control-efforts-protect-6.1-billion-people-who-s-new-report"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T14:19:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today released its report on the Global Tobacco Epidemic 2025 at the World Conference on Tobacco Control in Dublin, warning that action is needed to maintain and accelerate progress in tobacco control as rising industry interference challenges tobacco policies and control efforts.
The report focuses on the six proven WHO MPOWER tobacco control measures to reduce tobacco use, which claims over 7 million lives a year:

Monitoring tobacco use and prevention policies;
Protecting people from tobacco smoke with smoke-free air legislation;
Offering help to quit tobacco use;
Warning about the dangers of tobacco with pack labels and mass media;
Enforcing bans on tobacco advertising, promotion and sponsorship; and
Raising taxes on tobacco.

Since 2007, 155 countri…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients Know Best launches nationwide GP data integration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231731</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/patients-know-best-launches-nation-wide-gp-data-integration/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T12:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients Know Best (PKB) has launched GP data integration across England within its single patient record platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK warning over high levels of typhoid and malaria linked to travel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162637</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/uk-warning-over-high-levels-of-typhoid-and-malaria-linked-to-travel/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T11:55:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK public health officials have warned of a record high in reports of typhoid and paratyphoid fever associated with travel. Cases in 2024 jumped up 8% to 702 – the highest annual figure recorded to date, the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) said. It comes amidst a raft of health warnings as people prepare to
The post UK warning over high levels of typhoid and malaria linked to travel appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Heather Ryan: How my own GLP-1 journey has reshaped patient consultations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=158639</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/dr-heather-ryan-how-my-own-glp-1-journey-has-reshaped-patient-consultations/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T11:43:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Heather Ryan shares her weight-loss journey as a GP using GLP-1 medication as primary care prescribing of tirzepatide for obesity begins this week Conflicts of interest declared: Dr Ryan co-owns a private GP clinic where her husband, but not herself, provides weight-loss services. She is also a member of the Nestle Nutrition Paediatric Advisory
The post Dr Heather Ryan: How my own GLP-1 journey has reshaped patient consultations appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National insurance costs threaten viability of GP practices, doctors warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922935</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/national-insurance-costs-threaten-viability-gp-practices-doctors-warn/article/1922935"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T11:29:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Increased employer national insurance costs that took effect from April threaten the viability of GP practices across the UK, doctors' leaders have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health and Social Care Secretary speech at RCOG World Congress]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/health-and-social-care-secretary-speech-at-rcog-world-congress</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/health-and-social-care-secretary-speech-at-rcog-world-congress"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T11:18:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health and Social Care Secretary Wes Streeting spoke at RCOG World Congress, announcing a national investigation into maternity and neonatal services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ADHD services should move to primary care, NHS taskforce recommends]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162965</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/adhd-services-should-move-to-primary-care-nhs-taskforce-recommends/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T10:44:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS’s official taskforce into ADHD has recommended that general practice takes a greater role in management of the condition, similar to diabetes care. The first report from the taskforce, commissioned by NHS England last year, recommends a shift to ‘accessible, regulated and generalist models of care in the community, including primary care and other
The post ADHD services should move to primary care, NHS taskforce recommends appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA calls for GMC to be replaced with new regulator ‘for doctors only’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162967</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/bma-calls-for-gmc-to-be-replaced-with-new-regulator-for-doctors-only/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T10:26:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has called for a new professional regulator for doctors, arguing that the GMC is failing to support doctors and patient safety. In a speech at the BMA annual representative meeting (ARM) in Liverpool this morning, council chair Professor Philip Banfield warned that the GMC’s approach to regulating physician associates (PAs) has led to
The post BMA calls for GMC to be replaced with new regulator ‘for doctors only’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers call for stronger regulation of period tracking apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231483</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/researchers-call-for-stronger-regulation-of-period-tracking-apps/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have warned that period tracking apps may compromise users’ privacy and reproductive autonomy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National maternity investigation launched to drive improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/national-maternity-investigation-launched-to-drive-improvements</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/national-maternity-investigation-launched-to-drive-improvements"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T09:16:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The rapid national investigation into NHS maternity and neonatal services will provide truth to families suffering harm and urgently improve care and safety.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA demands new medical regulator to replace 'failing' GMC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922908</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-demands-new-medical-regulator-replace-failing-gmc/article/1922908"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T09:08:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has called for the creation of a new medical regulator, warning that the GMC is failing to protect patients and support doctors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Introducing new medicines in the NHS in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/introducing-new-medicines-in-the-nhs-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/introducing-new-medicines-in-the-nhs-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T08:45:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A pathway summarising the processes pharmaceutical companies should follow when preparing to launch new products in the UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research: WorkWell Pilots Evaluation Feasibility Study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/workwell-pilots-evaluation-feasibility-study</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/workwell-pilots-evaluation-feasibility-study"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T08:30:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An assessment of feasibility of evaluation options for the WorkWell pilot programme programme]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherwood Forest selects Nervecentre as preferred EPR supplier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231475</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/sherwood-forest-selects-nervecentre-as-preferred-epr-supplier/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T07:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sherwood Forest Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust has selected Nervecentre as its preferred electronic patient record (EPR) supplier.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS web visits to heat exhaustion advice surge by nearly 200 per cent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268424</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-web-visits-to-heat-exhaustion-advice-surge-by-nearly-200/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T20:14:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visits to the heat exhaustion advice on the NHS website have increased by 198 pre cent as temperatures rise across England.  There have been 31,524 visits to the heat exhaustion and heatstroke web page in the 48 hours since a heat-health alert was introduced across most of England at midday on Wednesday, compared to 10,578 visits […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors warn assisted dying must not become 'core GP work' after Commons vote]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922798</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/doctors-warn-assisted-dying-not-become-core-gp-work-commons-vote/article/1922798"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T15:32:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have warned that assisted dying should never 'be deemed core GP work' after MPs backed the Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill at its third reading in the House of Commons.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: DHSC public appointments: 2025 to 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-public-appointments-2025-to-2026</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-public-appointments-2025-to-2026"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T15:04:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Non-executive appointments to the Department of Health and Social Care's public bodies and committees from April 2025 to March 2026.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Checker: Out-of-work GPs to be hired as physician associates’ assistants (PAAs)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162702</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/pulse-checker/pulse-checker-out-of-work-gps-to-be-hired-as-physician-associates-assistants-paas/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T14:53:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Checker returns with its not-entirely-serious take on the month’s events. None of these stories are true (to the best of our knowledge) Ministers announce ‘Physician Associate’s Associate’ role to combat GP unemployment Out-of-work GPs will be able to apply for new jobs supporting the growing number of physician associates in general practice, under new
The post Pulse Checker: Out-of-work GPs to be hired as physician associates’ assistants (PAAs) appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most people think GPs ‘do not work hard enough’, ‘disheartening’ survey finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162907</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/most-people-think-gps-do-not-work-hard-enough-disheartening-survey-finds/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T14:48:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most people think GPs do not work hard enough, a nationally representative poll of attitudes towards general practice has revealed. In the survey commissioned by a specialist accountancy firm, which involved 2,000 people, only 23% said they believed GPs work hard enough. It also found just 31% of respondents think GPs should receive more support
The post Most people think GPs ‘do not work hard enough’, ‘disheartening’ survey finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New training code published for GPs on learning disability and autism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162890</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/new-training-code-published-for-gps-on-learning-disability-and-autism/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T14:29:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has published a new code of practice to ensure consistency of training for health and social care providers looking after people with a learning disability or autism. It sets out the standards that any CQC-registered provider, including GP practices, will have to meet to be compliant with the law. The new code also
The post New training code published for GPs on learning disability and autism appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MPs back assisted dying bill in final Commons reading]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162939</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/mps-back-assisted-dying-bill-in-final-commons-reading/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T13:43:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs have voted to support the assisted dying bill in its final reading in the House of Commons today, following hours of debate. The draft legislation, which would allow terminally ill adults to end their lives, was initially backed by MPs in a vote in November and has gone through committee and report stages, with MPs debating amendments
The post MPs back assisted dying bill in final Commons reading appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VR improves patient experience at Leeds Children’s Hospital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231301</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/vr-improves-patient-experience-at-leeds-childrens-hospital/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T12:30:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Virtual reality technology at Leeds Children's Hospital is enabling young patients to undergo medical procedures without general anaesthetic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medway launches digital platform to help scale virtual hospital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231275</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/medway-launches-digital-platform-to-help-scale-virtual-hospital/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T12:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Medway NHS Foundation Trust has implemented a new digital platform as part of its strategy to scale its virtual hospital initiative.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England responds to ADHD Taskforce interim report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268418</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-england-responds-to-adhd-taskforce-interim-report/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T11:20:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An independent taskforce set up to tackle challenges in attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) care has published its interim report and recommendations today (Friday 20 June 2025). The report describes that the rates of recognised ADHD in England are lower than the expected prevalence and stresses the need for timely access to needs-based support. To […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only half of overseas doctors who moved to the UK say their expectations have been met]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162917</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/only-half-of-overseas-doctors-who-moved-to-the-uk-say-their-expectations-have-been-met/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T10:45:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Only half of doctors who qualified overseas and moved to the UK said that their expectations had been met, according to new research published by the GMC. Those unsatisfied with the move blamed heavy workload, stress and a poor work-life balance. The research, commissioned by the GMC, surveyed over 3,000 doctors between June and August
The post Only half of overseas doctors who moved to the UK say their expectations have been met appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speediatrics: What’s causing this infant’s widespread and intensely itchy rash?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162871</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/paediatrics/speediatrics-whats-causing-this-infants-widespread-and-intensely-itchy-rash/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T10:32:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next in our series of quick quizzes in paediatric care asks – what is the likely diagnosis in this case of a persistent, widespread and intensely itchy rash? AI was used to assist in creation of this article, with thorough review by our medical advisors before publication
The post Speediatrics: What’s causing this infant’s widespread and intensely itchy rash? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices told to appoint trained officer before using AI transcription tools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162878</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gp-practices-told-to-appoint-trained-officer-before-using-ai-transcription-tools/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T10:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GP practices have been advised to appoint a ‘clinical safety officer’ (CSO) who has two days’ training before using any medical transcription tools – amid confusion around new NHS England guidance. A letter issued earlier this month by NHS England further developed its guidance on the use of ambient voice technology (AVT) – the
The post GP practices told to appoint trained officer before using AI transcription tools appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA warns GPs on the ‘substantial’ risks of AI scribing tools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231437</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/bma-warns-gps-on-the-substantial-risks-of-ai-scribing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The British Medical Association has advised that GPs should pause the use of AI scribing tools unless they have carried out safety checks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bradford Teaching Hospitals launches virtual access guides]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230973</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/bradford-teaching-hospitals-launches-virtual-access-guides/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T07:30:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bradford Teaching Hospitals, in partnership with AccessAble, has launched virtual access guides for visitors to Bradford Royal Infirmary.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government explores private funding for GP infrastructure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922628</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/government-explores-private-funding-gp-infrastructure/article/1922628"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government proposals to pay for new primary care infrastructure through public-private partnerships have sparked 'serious concerns' among GP leaders.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: What do we know about the 10-year NHS plan?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922605</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-know-10-year-nhs-plan/article/1922605"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T06:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GPonline team discusses the spending review and looks at what the government's 10-year health plan might say about general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA sets out GP advice on Mounjaro prescribing due to launch next week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162898</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/bma-sets-out-gp-advice-on-mounjaro-prescribing-due-to-launch-next-week/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T15:18:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has set out advice for the time and costs for GPs in setting up locally commissioned services to provide tirzepatide (Mounjaro) weight loss injections on the NHS. NICE interim commissioning guidance states that tirzepatide for weight loss must be implemented in primary care by 23 June 2025. ICBs have been tasked with getting
The post BMA sets out GP advice on Mounjaro prescribing due to launch next week appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ice slush drinks not suitable for children under seven, FSA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162888</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/ice-slush-drinks-not-suitable-for-children-under-seven-fsa-warns/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T14:51:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Food Standards Agency (FSA) has updated its advice that slush ice drinks containing glycerol are not suitable for children under seven. It follows research in the Archives of Diseases in Childhood earlier this year reporting 21 cases of children aged between two and seven years in the UK and Ireland who needed hospital treatment
The post Ice slush drinks not suitable for children under seven, FSA warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4673 - BeyondTrust Releases Security Advisory for Remote Support & Privileged Remote Access]]></title>
        <id>f723a117-4242-40fb-b12a-7e8f916edf65</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4673"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 A critical vulnerability in BeyondTrust remote access tools could lead to code injection
 A critical vulnerability in BeyondTrust remote access tools could lead to code injection
 Updated: 19 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Care for those with learning disabilities or autistic people]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/care-for-those-with-learning-disabilities-or-autistic-people</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/care-for-those-with-learning-disabilities-or-autistic-people"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:40:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New guidance published today will provide a boost in the quality of care for people with a learning disability or autistic people]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men's Health Strategy for England: call for evidence in British Sign Language]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence-in-british-sign-language</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence-in-british-sign-language"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We want to hear your views and ideas about men's health issues. Your ideas will help the government to make a Men's Health Strategy for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men's Health Strategy for England: call for evidence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:04:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This call for evidence is seeking the views of the public, as well as health and social care professionals, academics, employers and stakeholder organisations to inform a Men’s Health Strategy for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men's Health Strategy for England: call for evidence (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We want to hear your views and ideas about men's health issues. Your ideas will help the government to make a Men's Health Strategy for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New data laws will make life easier for British people, cutting life admin, easing traffic and speeding up roadworks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-data-laws-will-make-life-easier-for-british-people-cutting-life-admin-easing-traffic-and-speeding-up-roadworks</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-data-laws-will-make-life-easier-for-british-people-cutting-life-admin-easing-traffic-and-speeding-up-roadworks"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T12:34:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British people will benefit from new laws which will make their day-to-day lives easier – from slashing grocery bills and cutting traffic jams to speeding up NHS diagnoses – as the government delivers on manifesto commitments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two national keynotes complete Summer Schools 2025 line-up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231563</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/two-national-keynotes-complete-summer-schools-2025-line-up/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T12:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two national keynotes have been added to the Digital Health Summer Schools 2025 conference programme, which has been published in full today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England publishes contractual GP ‘patient charter’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162861</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/nhs-england-publishes-contractual-gp-patient-charter/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T11:23:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has published the ‘patient charter’ which GP practices will need to display on their website, setting out the standard of care they are contracted to provide. As part of the GP contract changes for 2025/26, practices will be required to publish a ‘publicly accessible document’, which sets out ‘in black and white’ what
The post NHS England publishes contractual GP ‘patient charter’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical conundrum: Patient with treatment-resistant depression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162852</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/clinical-conundrum-patient-with-treatment-resistant-depression/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:53:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP and mental health specialist Dr Emma Nash explores the management options for a young adult male patient with recurrent depression that has not responded to three different medications and who is concerned about his drinking A 28-year-old man with a history of depression attends for follow up. He has suffered recurrent depression since his
The post Clinical conundrum: Patient with treatment-resistant depression appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230337</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-79/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Coffee Time includes PKB's contract to provide a single patient ecord (SPR) system to the state government of Lagos.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oliver McGowan draft code of practice (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oliver-mcgowan-draft-code-of-practice-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oliver-mcgowan-draft-code-of-practice-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We want to know if you think the guidance for training on learning disability and autism is good enough. This guidance is called a code of practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Policy paper: Explanatory memorandum on the Oliver McGowan code of practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/explanatory-memorandum-on-the-oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/explanatory-memorandum-on-the-oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explanatory memorandum to Parliament about the Oliver McGowan code of practice on statutory learning disability and autism training.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Oliver McGowan code of practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out standards for training on learning disability and autism for Care Quality Commission (CQC)-registered health and social care providers and their staff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Oliver McGowan code of practice (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance about the training on learning disability and autism that health and care staff must do if they work in services registered with CQC in England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oliver McGowan draft code of practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oliver-mcgowan-draft-code-of-practice</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oliver-mcgowan-draft-code-of-practice"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This consultation considers the draft code and if it gives CQC registered providers the guidance needed to meet the legislative requirement to ensure all staff receive learning disability and autism training appropriate to their role.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA ‘increasingly’ seeing non-GPs appointed as training programme supervisors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162841</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/education-and-training/bma-increasingly-seeing-non-gps-appointed-as-training-programme-supervisors/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:26:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive The BMA has raised concerns about the growing shortage of GP trainers and warned it is ‘increasingly’ seeing non-GPs appointed as training programme directors and supervisors. The union’s GP registrars committee said there are concerns that non-GPs are increasingly becoming involved in overseeing some aspects of GP training, including allied health professionals ‘who have
The post BMA ‘increasingly’ seeing non-GPs appointed as training programme supervisors appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs left to pick up pieces from ‘harmful’ filler and botox procedures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162822</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/dermatology-and-wound-care/gps-left-to-pick-up-pieces-from-harmful-filler-and-botox-procedures/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:18:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The national consumer watchdog has called on the Government to urgently regulate harmful aesthetic procedures such as botox and fillers, which leave GPs picking up the pieces. The Chartered Trading Standards Institute (CTSI), which promotes fair trading practices and protects consumers, issued a warning saying unregulated aesthetic procedures – such as fat injections, Brazilian Butt
The post GPs left to pick up pieces from ‘harmful’ filler and botox procedures appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NICE says another no to Alzheimer’s drugs in final draft guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162845</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/nice-says-another-no-to-alzheimers-drugs-in-final-draft-guidance/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:13:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NICE has once again rejected new drugs for early Alzheimer’s disease because the costs are too great to justify the small benefits. An independent committee had reviewed new evidence submitted as part of an ongoing consultation process but said it did not change their position on whether donanemab and lecanemab should be made available on
The post NICE says another no to Alzheimer’s drugs in final draft guidance appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 9,000 robotic surgeries completed at North Bristol NHS Trust]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231385</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/over-9000-robotic-surgeries-completed-at-north-bristol-nhs-trust/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 9,000 robotic surgeries have been completed to date at North Bristol NHS Trust, as the use of the technology across the NHS increases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crackdown urged as half of GPs see patients injured by aesthetic procedures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922533</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/crackdown-urged-half-gps-patients-injured-aesthetic-procedures/article/1922533"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T09:38:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have backed a crackdown on unregulated aesthetic procedures after polling by a medico-legal organisation found nearly half have treated patients injured by procedures such as botox, liposuction or dermal fillers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England unveils GP contract patient charter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922507</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-england-unveils-gp-contract-patient-charter/article/1922507"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T08:47:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has published a 'patient charter' outlining standards patients can expect from their GP practice, which practices will be required to publish on their website as part of this year's GP contract.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England unveils GP patient charter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922507</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-england-unveils-gp-patient-charter/article/1922507"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T08:47:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has published a 'patient charter' outlining standards patients can expect from their GP practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Care Alliance to roll out eDMS in partnership with Hyland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230945</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/northern-care-alliance-to-roll-out-edms-in-partnership-with-hyland/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T07:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Northern Care Alliance NHS Foundation Trust is rolling out an electronic document management system (eDMS) in partnership with Hyland.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO issues first global guideline to improve pregnancy care for women with sickle cell disease]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5966cd79-a116-4ae1-b70e-d274656f90ff</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/19-06-2025-who-issues-first-global-guideline-to-improve-pregnancy-care-for-women-with-sickle-cell-disease"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T05:01:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today released its first-ever global guideline on the management of sickle cell disease (SCD) during pregnancy, addressing a critical and growing health challenge that can have life-threatening consequences for both women and babies.
SCD is a group of inherited blood disorders characterized by abnormally shaped red blood cells that resemble crescents or sickles. These cells can block blood flow, causing severe anaemia, episodes of severe pain, recurrent infections, as well as medical emergencies like strokes, sepsis or organ failures.
Health risks associated with SCD intensify during pregnancy, due to heightened demands on the body’s oxygen and nutrient supply. Women with SCD face a 4- to 11-fold higher likelihood of maternal death than those without. Th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders welcome ‘long overdue’ change in abortion law]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162825</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/gp-leaders-welcome-long-overdue-change-in-abortion-law/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T16:13:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP and BMA have welcomed the ‘long overdue’ changes of abortion laws in England and Wales following a vote in Parliament yesterday. MPs voted to ‘decriminalise’ abortion in an amendment to the Government’s Crime and Policing Bill, ensuring that women who have an abortion outside of the legal framework no longer face the threat
The post GP leaders welcome ‘long overdue’ change in abortion law appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Form: Child death reviews: forms for reporting child deaths]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-reviews-forms-for-reporting-child-deaths</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-reviews-forms-for-reporting-child-deaths"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T15:37:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forms to help child death overview panels (CDOPs) assess the causes of a child’s death as part of the child death review process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4762 - Proof-of-Concept Exploit Released for Pre-Auth RCE Chain in Sitecore Experience Platform]]></title>
        <id>751f97b8-6d15-46c7-9e31-dfb808de4e56</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4672"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T15:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security researchers have released a technical writeup which, with minimal modification, serves as a proof-of-concept exploit that could allow unauthenticated remote attackers to execute arbitrary code 
 Security researchers have released a technical writeup which, with minimal modification, serves as a proof-of-concept exploit that could allow unauthenticated remote attackers to execute arbitrary code 
 Updated: 18 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs need more than three strikes before we’re out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162812</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/gps-need-more-than-three-strikes-before-were-out/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T15:24:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield reflects on the impact of eponymous laws from grieving families on GPs, after NHS England’s primary care director spoke in favour of ‘Jess’s Law’ Another day, another eponymous law. This time, it’s Jess’s Law, the primary care version of Martha’s Rule. And that, in case you’ve forgotten, is NHSE’s guarantee that patients under hospital
The post GPs need more than three strikes before we’re out appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activist GP Dr Sarah Benn suspended for a further 12 months]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162817</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/activist-gp-dr-sarah-benn-suspended-for-a-further-12-months/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T14:31:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A retired GP who was suspended from the medical register after taking part in climate change protests should be suspended for a further 12 months, a tribunal has decided. Dr Sarah Benn, who took part in climate change protests at a Warwickshire oil terminal in 2022, was referred to the Medical Practitioners Tribunal Service (MPTS) for
The post Activist GP Dr Sarah Benn suspended for a further 12 months appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Pressure ulcers: how to safeguard adults]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/pressure-ulcers-how-to-safeguard-adults</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/pressure-ulcers-how-to-safeguard-adults"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T13:31:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to respond to individuals at risk of developing pressure ulcers, prevent harm where they occur and raise a safeguarding concern.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physiotherapy platform Phio goes live at 11 NHS organisations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231225</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/physiotherapy-platform-phio-goes-live-at-11-nhs-organisations/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T12:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eleven NHS organisations, including three primary care networks, have deployed Phio, a musculoskeletal triage and rehabilitation technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to chair ‘localities’ as part of ICB move to neighbourhood model]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162654</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/nhs-structures/gps-to-chair-localities-as-part-of-icb-move-to-neighbourhood-model/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T11:32:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GPs in Birmingham will be in charge of chairing health partnerships looking after 250,000 to 300,000 people, known as ‘localities’, as part of a move to a neighbourhood health service model. Birmingham and Solihull ICB has published its plans to roll out a neighbourhood health service model, which include splitting the area into six
The post GPs to chair ‘localities’ as part of ICB move to neighbourhood model appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP News Update: GPs ‘could run hospitals’, AI scribes, practices on the brink]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922387</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-news-update-gps-could-run-hospitals-ai-scribes-practices-brink/article/1922387"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T11:23:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Catch up quickly with our weekly round-up of key news stories for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4671 - Veeam Releases Security Updates for Backup & Replication and Windows Agent]]></title>
        <id>6d3619b8-976d-418e-88fc-7acd49c862fc</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4671"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T10:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security bulletin addresses critical severity vulnerabilities that could allow for remote code execution and privilege escalation
 Security bulletin addresses critical severity vulnerabilities that could allow for remote code execution and privilege escalation
 Updated: 18 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pitchfest 2022 winner CardMedic secures £411k Innovate UK grant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231135</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/pitchfest-2022-winner-cardmedic-secures-411k-innovate-uk-grant/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T10:00:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Pitchfest winner CardMedic has secured £411,000 from Innovate UK’s SMART grant programme for its healthcare language app.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICB boosts GP funding as NHS reforms take shape]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922365</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/icb-boosts-gp-funding-nhs-reforms-shape/article/1922365"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T09:14:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS leaders in Nottinghamshire have increased local enhanced services (LES) funding for GP practices and set out plans for a large-scale 'GP provider collaborative' to take on services moved out of hospital, as health service reforms begin to take shape.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public favours tiered system of access for single patient record]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230987</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/public-favours-tiered-system-of-access-for-single-patient-record/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T07:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The public believe that not all health professionals should have full access to a single patient record, according to research by NHSE.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS launches drive to catch one of the most lethal cancers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268215</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-launches-drive-to-catch-one-of-the-most-lethal-cancers/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of GP practices will comb patient records to offer urgent tests to people most at risk of pancreatic cancer, one of the deadliest forms of the disease. GP teams will scour online patients records to identify people over 60 who have the key early warning signs of pancreatic cancer including being recently diagnosed with […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom W</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs asked to case find pancreatic cancer via patient records]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162803</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cancer/gps-asked-to-case-find-pancreatic-cancer-via-patient-records/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS has launched a pilot scheme which will see GP practices asked to help identify patients most at risk of pancreatic cancer.  GPs will be asked to go through patient records to flag people over the age of 60 who have the early warning signs of pancreatic cancer. This includes being recently diagnosed with
The post GPs asked to case find pancreatic cancer via patient records appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of GP practices join pancreatic cancer early detection plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922173</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/hundreds-gp-practices-join-pancreatic-cancer-early-detection-plan/article/1922173"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 300 GP practices have joined a scheme to boost early detection of pancreatic cancer by checking patient records for warning signs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Professor Gillian Leng: ‘There’s nothing that says PAs are 100% safe in primary care’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162780</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/big-interviews/professor-gillian-leng-theres-nothing-that-says-pas-are-100-safe-in-primary-care/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T15:58:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a relaunch of Pulse’s ‘Big Interview’ series, editor Sofia Lind speaks to Professor Gillian Leng, leader of the Government’s review into physician associates (PAs). Commissioned by the health secretary in November, Professor Leng’s review has seen her engage with over 1,000 people to look into the safety and effectiveness of PAs in the workforce.
The post Professor Gillian Leng: ‘There’s nothing that says PAs are 100% safe in primary care’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 160 sessional GPs currently ‘seeking work’ in Scotland alone]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162789</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/nearly-160-sessional-gps-currently-seeking-work-in-scotland-alone/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T15:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 160 full-time equivalent salaried and locum GPs in Scotland are currently ‘seeking work’, a new BMA survey has revealed. The poll found that nearly half of GPs (44.58%) in Scotland say the future of their practice is ‘precarious’ or ‘not sustainable’, up 10% since 2023, and that many GPs are struggling to cope with
The post Nearly 160 sessional GPs currently ‘seeking work’ in Scotland alone appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4670 - Citrix Releases Security Updates for NetScaler ADC and NetScaler Gateway]]></title>
        <id>9d8eab47-cf8e-4dfc-8227-92dc9356cf96</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4670"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T15:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisory addresses two vulnerabilities that could lead to unauthorised access and memory overload
 Advisory addresses two vulnerabilities that could lead to unauthorised access and memory overload
 Updated: 17 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First keynote speakers announced for Digital Health Rewired 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231247</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/brotherton-and-power-first-keynotes-confirmed-for-rewired-2026/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T12:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Brotherton and Rachel Power have been confirmed as the first keynotes for Digital Health Rewired 2026.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO calls for global expansion of midwifery models of care]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5623bd5d-9728-4121-bb2f-8cddb1c9d292</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/18-06-2025-who-calls-for-global-expansion-of-midwifery-models-of-care"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T11:29:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today released new guidance to help countries adopt and expand midwifery models of care - where midwives serve as the main care provider for women and babies throughout pregnancy, childbirth, and the postnatal period.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CQC primary care inspector awarded high honour by King]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162781</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/cqc-primary-care-inspector-awarded-high-honour-by-king/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T10:43:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who was recently appointed as the new CQC chief inspector of primary care has been recognised in the 2025 King’s Birthday Honours list. Professor Bola Owolabi, a GP and director of inequalities at NHS England, was awarded a CBE ‘for her services to reducing health inequalities’.  She is currently director of the National
The post CQC primary care inspector awarded high honour by King appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230299</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-78/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T10:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Coffee Time includes the launch of a digital reminder service for medication intake and the UK's AI regulation under scrutiny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Partners must ensure career progression for younger GP colleagues, says primary care lead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162768</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/partners-must-ensure-career-progression-for-younger-gp-colleagues-says-primary-care-lead/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T10:21:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is incumbent on GP partners to provide their younger, salaried GPs with a career structure outside partnerships, NHS England’s primary care director has said. Speaking at the NHS Confederation conference in Manchester last week, Dr Amanda Doyle told delegates that the ‘new generation of GPs don’t want to become a partner at 29’. She
The post Partners must ensure career progression for younger GP colleagues, says primary care lead appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Central London Community Healthcare goes live in NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231041</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/central-london-community-healthcare-goes-live-in-nhs-app/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T10:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Central London Community Healthcare NHS Trust has launched a pilot which enables patients to view their appointments in the NHS App.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs advised to stop using AI scribes without key assurances]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922151</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-advised-stop-using-ai-scribes-without-key-assurances/article/1922151"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T08:55:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should pause use of AI scribing tools unless they have carried out data protection and safety checks and sought assurances that products meet NHS standards, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ground robots to join London’s NHS drone delivery network]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231289</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/ground-robots-to-join-londons-nhs-drone-delivery-network/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T07:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Autonomous ground delivery robots are planned to join the drone delivery network in London to deliver NHS supplies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The WHO Hub in Berlin: driving innovation to make the world safer from health threats]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:0e359b28-f5f3-4192-bdf6-02da28df08ff</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/17-06-2025-the-who-hub-in-berlin-driving-innovation-to-make-the-world-safer-from-health-threats"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T15:41:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building on lessons learned from the COVID-19 pandemic, the WHO Hub for Pandemic and Epidemic Intelligence in Berlin leverages innovative tools and collaborations for more effective disease surveillance worldwide. Just over three years after its inauguration, the Hub now supports over 150 countries in detecting health threats more effectively and rapidly. The Hub’s latest annual report highlights the growing impact of this work and provides key insights into progress made in 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physician associates introduced to NHS ‘without a clear vision’, says review lead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162742</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/physician-associates-introduced-to-nhs-without-a-clear-vision-says-review-lead/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T15:33:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Physician associates (PAs) were introduced into the NHS ‘without clear vision’ and workforce planning, the leader of the independent review has said. During an interview at Pulse LIVE Birmingham last week, Professor Gillian Leng suggested the rollout of PAs could have been handled better. Professor Leng, who is the former CEO of NICE, is
The post Physician associates introduced to NHS ‘without a clear vision’, says review lead appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-term desogestrel associated with small increased risk of meningioma]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162643</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/long-term-desogestrel-associated-with-small-increased-risk-of-meningioma/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T15:24:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Long-term use of the progestogen-only desogestrel contraceptive pill is linked to small increased brain tumour risk, researchers have concluded. However, the study of more than 92,000 patients found the risk was much lower than some other progestogens and disappeared one year after stopping treatment. The French researchers noted that prolonged use of several progestogens had
The post Long-term desogestrel associated with small increased risk of meningioma appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Physician associate review lead Professor Gillian Leng; and how GPs should manage antidepressant withdrawal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162667</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/pulse-in-focus/podcast-physician-associates-review-lead-professor-gillian-leng-and-how-gps-should-manage-antidepressant-withdrawal/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T14:50:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next episode of Pulse in Focus: The Podcast for GPs is live and available wherever you get your podcasts from. Editor Sofia Lind and features assistant Maya Dhillon reflect on Sofia’s interview with Professor Gillian Leng – leader of the Government-commissioned review into PAs – at Pulse LIVE Birmingham last week. Ahead of the
The post Podcast: Physician associate review lead Professor Gillian Leng; and how GPs should manage antidepressant withdrawal appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Half of GPs in Scotland say their practice is 'on the brink']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922057</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/half-gps-scotland-say-practice-on-brink/article/1922057"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T13:16:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly half of GPs in Scotland say their practice is at risk and that they are struggling to cope - but practices can't afford to hire scores of qualified GPs desperate for more work, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perci Health raises £3m to scale AI-powered virtual cancer clinic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230915</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/perci-health-raises-3m-to-scale-ai-powered-virtual-cancer-clinic/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T12:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Perci Health has raised £3m in its latest funding round supporting it to scale its AI-powered, multidisciplinary cancer care care clinic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over a third of GPs see patient health adversely affected by low literacy every week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162681</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/over-a-third-of-gps-see-patient-health-adversely-affected-by-low-literacy-every-week/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T10:44:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Over a third of GPs (37%) see patients whose health is adversely affected by low literacy every week, a Pulse survey has revealed. A poll of 731 GPs – conducted in conjunction with Channel 5 – found that every day 9% encounter patients having adverse health effects as a direct result of low literacy
The post Over a third of GPs see patient health adversely affected by low literacy every week appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS App feature will enable patients to sign up for clinical trials]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231181</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhs-app-feature-will-enable-patients-to-sign-up-for-clinical-trials/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T10:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will be able to browse and sign up to clinical trials via the NHS App, the Department of Health and Care (DHSC) has announced.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS App to match patients with clinical trials under 10-year health plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162701</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/nhs-app-to-match-patients-with-clinical-trials-under-10-year-health-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T09:49:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will be able to register for clinical trials via the NHS App under new Government plans to revive the UK’s struggling research sector and speed up access to new treatments. The initiative, part of the forthcoming 10-year health plan, aims to significantly reduce trial set-up times, increase public participation in research, and boost the
The post NHS App to match patients with clinical trials under 10-year health plan appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS 10-year plan 'make or break' for general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921951</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-10-year-plan-make-break-general-practice/article/1921951"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T09:43:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have urged the government to commit explicitly to a new contract for general practice in the upcoming 10-year NHS plan - warning that the government's health service blueprint will be 'make or break' for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS image bank of how conditions appear on different skin tones launched]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162696</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/nhs-image-bank-of-how-conditions-appear-on-different-skin-tones-launched/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T09:26:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A free NHS-funded image library showing how diseases appear on a range of skin tones has now been made live. GPs and other healthcare professionals can search through the bank of more than 3,000 high-resolution images to help them recognise signs of disease and illness. The Reframe initiative was funded by NHS England and led
The post NHS image bank of how conditions appear on different skin tones launched appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs recognised in King's birthday honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921931</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-recognised-kings-birthday-honours/article/1921931"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T08:11:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are among those who have been recognised in the King's birthday honours.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Reciprocal healthcare privacy notice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/reciprocal-healthcare-privacy-notice</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/reciprocal-healthcare-privacy-notice"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T07:57:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out how DHSC and NHSBSA collect and use personal information as part of the process of providing reciprocal healthcare.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overhaul of medical device regulations in UK takes effect]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231101</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/overhaul-of-medical-device-regulations-in-uk-takes-effect/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T07:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency’s (MHRA) has announced a major overhaul of how medical devices are regulated.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unprecedented boost for clinical trials under 10 Year Health Plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/unprecedented-boost-for-clinical-trials-under-10-year-health-plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/unprecedented-boost-for-clinical-trials-under-10-year-health-plan"/>
        <updated>2025-06-15T23:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions will take part in clinical trials under the 10 Year Health Plan which will speed up clinical research.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Responders to Southport attack among NHS staff receiving King’s Birthday Honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268077</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/responders-to-southport-attack-among-nhs-staff-receiving-kings-birthday-honours/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T21:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff involved in the response to the Southport knife attack are among those being recognised in the 2025 King’s Birthday Honours list, released today (Friday 13 June). Sir Jim Mackey, Chief Executive at NHS England, said the awards highlight the “incredible dedication and commitment” of those who responded to the attack in July 2024. Paul […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: Birthday Honours 2025: Ambulance Service list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/birthday-honours-2025-ambulance-service-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/birthday-honours-2025-ambulance-service-list"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T21:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recipients of the King's Ambulance Service Medal 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blue-sky thinking is great, but not if it fails to reach the grassroots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162683</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/blue-sky-thinking-is-great-but-not-if-it-fails-to-reach-the-grassroots/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T15:56:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse editor-in-chief Jaimie Kaffash tells the tale of his trip to the land of NHS managers, also known as NHS Confed Expo, where he encounters a lot of blue-sky thinking I can’t speak NHS Manager. Despite living in the locality/neighbourhood/place since starting at Pulse in 2012, I never picked up the lingo. Sure, I know
The post Blue-sky thinking is great, but not if it fails to reach the grassroots appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spain strengthens global health leadership with increased support to WHO]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:573441db-70f2-40e5-9f18-0e8091831dec</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/13-06-2025-spain-strengthens-global-health-leadership-with-increased-support-to-who"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T15:52:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Spanish Agency for International Development Cooperation (AECID) and the World Health Organization (WHO) today signed a new agreement and contribution of €5.25 million to support key WHO initiative.
“Spain has long been a close and steadfast partner to WHO and global health," said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General. "We thank Spain for its increased flexible funding of our work, in doing so helping WHO be stronger and more independent and allowing us to deliver the services that countries and communities need from us.”
This year, Spain’s commitment to global health entered a new chapter as it returned to the WHO Executive Board for the 2025–2028 term, nearly two decades since its last membership. This renewed engagement is supported by the country’s new Global Health Strategy, launched on 27 May 2025.
This is underscored by today’s signing of a new agreement between Spain and WHO and a growing collaboration between both partners. At the heart of this effort is the Spanish Agency for International Development Cooperation (AECID), under the leadership of Mr Antón Leis; AECID has significantly stepped up flexible and strategic funding for WHO activities.
AECID's €5.25 million contribution to WHO is part of a broader €60 million pledge announced by Prime Minister Pedro Sánchez in November 2024. Spain’s multi-year commitment also includes support for critical health programmes in countries such as Jordan, Mali, and Sudan, as well as other global initiatives. 
Looking forward, Spain will host the 4th International Conference on Financing for Development (FFD4) in Seville, 30 June–3 July 2025, where it aims to elevate health financing as a core development priority. A high-level special event – co-sponsored by WHO and featuring leaders from global health, finance, and academia – will call for bold action through the “Health financing for a safe and sustainable economy: towards Seville health financing agenda for action.”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate protest GP’s fitness to practise ‘remains impaired’, tribunal rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162677</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/climate-protest-gps-fitness-to-practise-remains-impaired-tribunal-rules/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T15:07:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A tribunal has ruled that the fitness to practise of Dr Sarah Benn – a retired GP who was suspended after taking part in climate change protests – remains impaired. Dr Sarah Benn, who took part in climate change protests at a Warwickshire oil terminal in 2022, was referred to the Medical Practitioners Tribunal Service
The post Climate protest GP’s fitness to practise ‘remains impaired’, tribunal rules appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alzheimer’s Society Accelerator selects two dementia innovations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230471</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/alzheimers-society-accelerator-selects-two-dementia-innovations/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T12:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An app that monitors changes in dementia symptoms and a device that tracks dehydration are partners in the Alzheimer’s Society’s Accelerator.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS primary care lead supportive of GP ‘three strikes and refer’ rule]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162662</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/nhs-primary-care-lead-supportive-of-gp-three-strikes-and-refer-rule/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T11:26:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England’s clinical director of primary care has spoken out in support of a proposed ‘three strikes and escalate’ law, which would generate an automatic patient review after the third contact with their GP surgery about a specific symptom or condition. Speaking at the NHS Confederation conference in Manchester this week, Dr Claire Fuller said
The post NHS primary care lead supportive of GP ‘three strikes and refer’ rule appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4669 - Active Exploitation of Critical RCE Vulnerability in Wazuh]]></title>
        <id>5cd2fb60-7bf6-45d6-8598-18b3ac9b7af6</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4669"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T11:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 CVE-2025-24016 could allow a remote, authenticated attacker to execute arbitrary Python code on the Wazuh server
 CVE-2025-24016 could allow a remote, authenticated attacker to execute arbitrary Python code on the Wazuh server
 Updated: 13 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New endometriosis training programme ‘boosted GP knowledge’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162647</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/new-endometriosis-training-programme-boosted-gp-knowledge/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T10:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new training programme in Wales is helping GPs to recognise the symptoms of endometriosis earlier, the Welsh Government says. The Endometriosis in Primary Care programme has led to a 43% improvement in knowledge of the condition among the GPs who have taken part so far. It is one of a range of training programmes
The post New endometriosis training programme ‘boosted GP knowledge’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs can now refer contaminated blood-affected patients for psychological treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162639</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gps-can-now-refer-contaminated-blood-affected-patients-for-psychological-treatment/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T10:12:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients across England who were affected and infected by the contaminated blood scandal will now have access to bespoke psychological treatment. The Infected Blood Psychological Service first opened last September after a recommendation from the interim inquiry but was rolled out in phases. Those eligible for the service also include bereaved partners, parents, children, and
The post GPs can now refer contaminated blood-affected patients for psychological treatment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital and community to take over from hospitals, says Streeting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231011</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-and-community-to-take-over-from-hospitals-says-streeting/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T08:45:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS 10 year health plan will see digital, remote and neighbourhood care, taking over much of the role of hospitals, said Wes Streeting.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doccla teams with Gophr for same-day delivery of medical devices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230237</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/doccla-teams-with-gophr-for-same-day-delivery-of-medical-devices/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T07:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A partnership between Doccla and Gophr is supporting the rapid deployment of medical devices to patients and hospital sites to ensure vulnerable patients receive vital medical equipment promptly.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General practice must be 'cornerstone of neighbourhood NHS']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921657</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-practice-cornerstone-neighbourhood-nhs/article/1921657"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T06:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A neighbourhood NHS should involve all services in a local area that could help people manage their health and wellbeing better, founded on the 'cornerstone' of general practice, a leading GP has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: How does general practice fit into a neighbourhood NHS?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921582</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-does-general-practice-fit-neighbourhood-nhs/article/1921582"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T06:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Dr Caroline Taylor, chair of the National Association of Primary Care and a GP in Calderdale, West Yorkshire, about how neighbourhood working benefits patients, GPs and practices - and how it could help the NHS shift its focus towards prevention.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS first in world to roll out new ‘trojan horse’ therapy for blood cancer patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267982</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-first-in-world-to-roll-out-new-trojan-horse-therapy-for-blood-cancer-patients/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T23:01:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS in England will be the first health system in the world to roll-out a ‘trojan horse’ targeted therapy for blood cancer patients which could halt the disease’s progression by nearly three times as long as existing treatments.  Around 1,500 patients a year with multiple myeloma – an incurable cancer of the bone marrow […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sickle cell patients to get better treatment after £9m boost]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/sickle-cell-patients-to-get-better-treatment-after-9m-boost</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/sickle-cell-patients-to-get-better-treatment-after-9m-boost"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients living with rare blood disorders to benefit from increased access to treatment and availability of services, thanks to £9 million investment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing menstrual disorders in young women – key points for GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162528</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/managing-menstrual-disorders-in-young-women-key-points-for-gps/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T16:13:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the next in our series showcasing Pulse 365 Live and Virtual presentations, Dr Shona Biggart explains the key take-home messages for GPs in management of menstrual disorders in adolescent and young adult women Dysmenorrhoea and menorrhagia – early recognition and intervention Dysmenorrhoea affects approximately one in three women and is frequently undertreated. Primary dysmenorrhoea
The post Managing menstrual disorders in young women – key points for GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we have learned about retiring APIs]]></title>
        <id>13f419d4-1d3b-4957-b1c9-14ddae00dacc</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/tech-talk/2023/what-we-have-learned-about-retiring-apis"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T15:55:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Business analyst Matthew Firth gives an update on what NHS Digital has been doing to progress the API ‘sunsetting’ strategy to retire some of our APIs over the last year. 


Last year we published our blog ‘What happens when we ‘sunset’ our APIs?’ in which Munish Jokhani explained how we actively deprecate (where we advise of our intention to retire the API while retaining all existing service levels) and retire our APIs, and the effect this had on developers. By working with our suppliers and engaging them early in the process, we found that we were able to agree and align the retirement dates so that we met our suppliers’ requirements.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does good look like for APIs?]]></title>
        <id>7c853843-4b2d-4150-b4b4-dcbbcc648efb</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/tech-talk/2023/what-does-good-look-like-for-apis"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T15:54:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matthew Firth describes our best practice policies around APIs – and how the most important one is not about the technical aspects of the work.


For the past 3 years, we have been on a mission to make integration easier within the NHS for people building healthcare technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our vision for a new model of NHS care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/our-vision-for-a-new-model-of-nhs-care</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/our-vision-for-a-new-model-of-nhs-care"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T15:28:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health and Social Care Secretary spoke at NHS ConfedExpo 2025 in Manchester.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England GPs to call women for cervical screening every five years instead of three]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162633</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/england-gps-to-call-women-for-cervical-screening-every-five-years-instead-of-three/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T14:31:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS in England is changing cervical cancer screening intervals from three to five years for women aged 25 to 49 years who have a negative HPV test. From July, the changes will also mean that individuals whose sample indicates the presence of HPV or who have a recent history of HPV will continue to
The post England GPs to call women for cervical screening every five years instead of three appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse hosting free women’s health online event for GPs on Tuesday]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162582</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/pulse-hosting-free-womens-health-online-event-for-gps-on-tuesday/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T14:21:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are invited to a free virtual conference held by Pulse 365 on women’s health on Tuesday 17 June. The event, worth five CPD hours, is one of Pulse 365’s ‘spotlight conferences’ which give GPs the opportunity to hear from experts in particular clinical areas. The conference agenda will feature discussions on hormonal shifts and
The post Pulse hosting free women’s health online event for GPs on Tuesday appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could run 'run local hospitals,' says Wes Streeting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921646</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-run-run-local-hospitals-says-wes-streeting/article/1921646"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T14:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should be able to run hospitals - but acute trusts could also take on primary care services as integration blurs traditional boundaries between parts of the NHS, the health and social care secretary has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs ‘should run local hospitals’ as part of NHS reform, says health secretary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162620</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/gps-should-run-local-hospitals-as-part-of-nhs-reform-says-health-secretary/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T13:05:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs ‘should be able to run local hospitals’ as part of a radical reform of the NHS, the health secretary has said.   During a speech at NHS Confederation Expo conference this afternoon, Wes Streeting said the NHS ‘should not be bound by traditional expectations of how services should be arranged’. He argued that acute
The post GPs ‘should run local hospitals’ as part of NHS reform, says health secretary appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Herefordshire and Worcestershire Health and Care rolls out Rio EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230753</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/herefordshire-and-worcestershire-health-and-care-rolls-out-rio-epr/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T12:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Herefordshire and Worcestershire Health and Care NHS Trust has rolled out the Access Rio electronic patient record (EPR) system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spending review allocations ‘will make or break general practice’, says GPC chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162618</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/spending-review-allocations-will-make-or-break-general-practice-says-gpc-chair/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T11:23:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS budget allocations following the Government’s spending review ‘will make or break general practice’, the BMA’s GP committee chair has said. Yesterday the chancellor specified GP training as a priority investment area while announcing a £29bn funding boost for the NHS until the end of this Parliament. According to the Treasury announcement, ‘thousands more GPs’
The post Spending review allocations ‘will make or break general practice’, says GPC chair appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4668 - Mitel Releases Security Advisory for MiCollab]]></title>
        <id>1dac23da-abc7-4af7-a408-82275eccd554</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4668"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T10:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Critical path traversal vulnerability could allow a remote unauthenticated attacker to perform unauthorised administrative actions
 Critical path traversal vulnerability could allow a remote unauthenticated attacker to perform unauthorised administrative actions
 Updated: 12 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs criticised by coroner for ‘not understanding’ medical examiner process]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162182</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-criticised-by-coroner-for-not-understanding-medical-examiner-process/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T10:46:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A London coroner has criticised GPs for ‘not understanding’ the medical examiner process and for making unnecessary death referrals. At a pre-inquest hearing for the death of a 94-year-old woman, senior coroner for east London Graeme Irvine said that the frequency with which doctors offer a cause of death ‘has declined considerably’ and that communications
The post GPs criticised by coroner for ‘not understanding’ medical examiner process appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229509</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-76/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T10:30:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's news roundup covers new interpreting systems in Walsall and pioneering virtual mental healthcare in Cambridgeshire and Peterborough.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE creating national population health management tool for FDP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230867</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhse-creating-national-population-health-management-tool-for-fdp/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T10:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE is working with NHS Frimley ICB to create a population health management tool which will run on the federated data platform (FDP).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS waiting list hits two-year low as staff work to ‘turn the tide’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267951</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-waiting-list-hits-two-year-low-as-staff-work-to-turn-the-tide/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T09:23:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS waiting list has fallen to its lowest level in two years, the first April drop since 2008*, as health chiefs hailed staff for continuing to tackle demand and drive progress for patients. New data published today shows that the NHS waiting list has fallen to 7.39 million, down from 7.42 million – the first time […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EMIS and SystmOne dominance of GP IT a 'barrier to change', says government advisor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921528</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/emis-systmone-dominance-gp-barrier-change-says-government-advisor/article/1921528"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T08:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A senior government health advisor has blasted the EMIS and SystmOne 'duopoly' in GP IT system provision as a 'barrier to change' and warned that he is actively pushing for more competition.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital health sector reacts to ‘record’ investment in NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230815</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-sector-reacts-to-record-investment-in-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T07:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The digital health sector has reacted to the government's Spending Review, which included up to £10bn of investment in tech for the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘GP-centric’ 10-year plan ‘won’t come with big bag of money’, says NHS England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162609</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-centric-10-year-plan-wont-come-with-big-bag-of-money-says-nhs-england/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T15:53:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government’s upcoming 10-year plan for health will be ‘GP-centric’, but will not include huge shifts of funding from secondary to primary care immediately, NHS England’s director for primary care and community services has said. Speaking at the NHS Confederation conference in Manchester today, Dr Amanda Doyle said that she believes that the future for
The post ‘GP-centric’ 10-year plan ‘won’t come with big bag of money’, says NHS England appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['GP-centric' 10-year NHS plan will protect partnerships]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921502</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-centric-10-year-nhs-plan-will-protect-partnerships/article/1921502"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T14:57:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The upcoming 10-year NHS plan will be ‘very GP centric’ and health service leaders are 'committed to protecting partnerships', a senior NHS England official has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government to invest up to £10bn to bring NHS ‘into the digital age’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230779</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/government-to-invest-up-to-10bn-to-bring-nhs-into-the-digital-age/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T14:55:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chancellor Rachel Reeves has announced that the government will invest £10bn in NHS tech, as part of the latest spending review.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spending review promises 3% annual funding rise for NHS and 'thousands more GPs']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921456</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/spending-review-promises-3-annual-funding-rise-nhs-thousands-gps/article/1921456"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T13:24:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS funding will rise by £29bn in real terms between 2023/24 and 2028/29 - a 3% average annual increase - including funding to train 'thousands more GPs', chancellor Rachel Reeves has announced in the government's spending review.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Thousands more GPs’ to be trained with spending review NHS funding boost]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162590</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/thousands-more-gps-to-be-trained-with-spending-review-nhs-funding-boost/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T12:53:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The chancellor has specified GP training as a priority investment area while announcing a £29bn funding boost for the NHS in today’s long-term spending review. According to the Treasury announcement, ‘thousands more GPs’ will be ‘trained’ with the money which will see real terms day-to-day spending on NHS services increase by 3% on average. Reporting
The post ‘Thousands more GPs’ to be trained with spending review NHS funding boost appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4667 - MicroDicom Releases Security Update for DICOM Viewer]]></title>
        <id>c5db2af3-0ed2-4bfe-be1c-5227a414aed1</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4667"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T12:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 CVE-2025-5943 could allow a remote unauthenticated attacker to execute arbitrary code on affected installations of DICOM Viewer
 CVE-2025-5943 could allow a remote unauthenticated attacker to execute arbitrary code on affected installations of DICOM Viewer
 Updated: 11 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP News Update: Including 10-year health plan, GP jobs crisis, RCGP partnership warning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921451</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-news-update-including-10-year-health-plan-gp-jobs-crisis-rcgp-partnership-warning/article/1921451"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T12:46:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Catch up quickly with our weekly round-up of key news stories for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4666 - Microsoft Releases June 2025 Security Updates]]></title>
        <id>36ea869b-558f-4dbc-a66c-132937e31e98</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4666"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T12:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products, including security updates for 66 vulnerabilities, of which 1 has been reported as actively exploited.
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products, including security updates for 66 vulnerabilities, of which 1 has been reported as actively exploited.
 Updated: 11 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4665 - ConnectWise Releases Update to Rotate Code Signing Certificates for ScreenConnect, Automate and RMM]]></title>
        <id>49253ea7-c506-475a-a6a5-520d088fb078</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4665"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T10:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 ConnectWise has advised users of ScreenConnect or Automate "must update to the latest build and validate that all agents are updated before 13 June at 8:00pm ET [14 June at midnight UTC] to avoid disruptions or degraded experience."
 ConnectWise has advised users of ScreenConnect or Automate "must update to the latest build and validate that all agents are updated before 13 June at 8:00pm ET [14 June at midnight UTC] to avoid disruptions or degraded experience."
 Updated: 11 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10-year plan to overhaul GP incentives and 'completely reimagine' NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921423</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/10-year-plan-overhaul-gp-incentives-completely-reimagine-nhs/article/1921423"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T10:09:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The health service will be 'completely reimagined' under the forthcoming 10-year NHS plan, which will describe how contracts and incentives will be overhauled - potentially within the next 12 months - to drive collaboration between GPs and other providers, senior NHS leaders have said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better Meds and BD partner to advance medication management]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230703</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/better-meds-and-bd-partner-to-advance-medication-management/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T10:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BD Pyxis automated dispensing cabinets are being integrated with Better Meds’ electronic prescribing and medicines administration (ePMA).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE projects 500k robotic assisted operations a year by 2035]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230687</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhse-projects-500k-robotic-assisted-operations-a-year-by-2035/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T10:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Half a million operations will be supported by robotic surgery every year by 2035, up from 70,000 in 2023/24, according to NHSE projections.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP concern at private out-of-hours provider enforcing ‘morally wrong’ targets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162493</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/urgent-care/gp-concern-at-private-out-of-hours-provider-enforcing-morally-wrong-targets/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T09:55:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GPs working for a private out-of-hours (OOH) provider in the South West have raised serious concerns about new performance targets which they say are ‘morally completely wrong’.  HealthHero, a large digital health company which bought the OOH provider Medvivo in 2020, told its GP workforce in April that ‘allocation of shifts will go to
The post GP concern at private out-of-hours provider enforcing ‘morally wrong’ targets appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to start patients on heart failure drugs following updated NICE guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162586</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/gps-to-start-patients-on-heart-failure-drugs-following-updated-nice-guidance/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T09:38:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs can start treatment with certain heart failure drugs that previously had to be initiated by a specialist, NICE has said in updated guidance. Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) inhibitors and angiotensin receptor-neprilysin inhibitors (ARNIs) can for the first time be started by GPs, with advice from a heart failure specialist, potentially speeding up access, NICE said
The post GPs to start patients on heart failure drugs following updated NICE guidance appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency workers to be better protected from racial abuse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/emergency-workers-to-be-better-protected-from-racial-abuse</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/emergency-workers-to-be-better-protected-from-racial-abuse"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T09:23:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency workers will be better protected from violence and abuse when visiting homes as the government introduces new laws to support frontline staff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UPMC Ireland to implement MEDITECH Expanse EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230581</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/upmc-ireland-to-implement-meditech-expanse-epr/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T07:30:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global healthcare provider UPMC Ireland has confirmed it will implement the MEDITECH Expanse electronic patient record (EPR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in the dark as promised 4% pay rise yet to materialise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921263</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-dark-promised-4-pay-rise-yet-materialise/article/1921263"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have yet to receive confirmation from the government on how or when a promised 4% pay increase for general practice in 2025/26 will be delivered, amid fears the uplift will fall short.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Millions to benefit from NHS robot drive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267837</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/millions-to-benefit-from-nhs-robot-drive/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T23:01:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of patients will benefit from cutting-edge NHS robotic surgery over the next decade as part of radical plans to cut waiting times. Half a million operations will be supported by the trailblazing approach every year by 2035, up from 70,000 in 2023/24, according to NHS projections. 9 in 10 of all keyhole surgeries, such […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our plan to improve the lives of people with ME/CFS (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/our-plan-to-improve-the-lives-of-people-with-mecfs-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/our-plan-to-improve-the-lives-of-people-with-mecfs-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T16:02:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government has written a plan to support people who live with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed review of the statutory scheme for branded medicines pricing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/proposed-review-of-the-statutory-scheme-for-branded-medicines-pricing</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/proposed-review-of-the-statutory-scheme-for-branded-medicines-pricing"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T15:55:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This consultation seeks views on proposals to update the statutory scheme to control the cost of branded health service medicines.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fewer GPs taking advantage of partial retirement this year, NHS data shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162414</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/fewer-gps-taking-advantage-of-partial-retirement-this-year-nhs-data-shows/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T15:10:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fewer GPs are taking advantage of the option to partially retire this year, new NHS data has showed. According to data from a Freedom of Information (FOI) request to NHS Business Services Authority, 459 completed applications for partial retirement have been made by medical staff for the first five months of this year. This is
The post Fewer GPs taking advantage of partial retirement this year, NHS data shows appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS red tape blitz delivers game-changing new cancer treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nhs-red-tape-blitz-delivers-game-changing-new-cancer-treatment</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nhs-red-tape-blitz-delivers-game-changing-new-cancer-treatment"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T15:09:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients to benefit from new era in cancer treatment, as Government slashes red tape to unleash life-saving innovation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs providing continuity of care must be NHS priority, says CMO]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162576</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/scotland/gps-providing-continuity-of-care-must-be-nhs-priority-says-cmo/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T15:06:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Allowing GPs to provide continuity of care should be a priority for the NHS, Scotland’s Chief Medical Officer (CMO) has argued in his latest report. Professor Sir Gregor Smith, a GP and former medical director for primary care in NHS Lanarkshire, said that the NHS needs to recognise the ‘critical importance’ of continuity and relationship-based
The post GPs providing continuity of care must be NHS priority, says CMO appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS rolls out more personalised cervical screening for millions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267797</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-rolls-out-more-personalised-cervical-screening-for-millions/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T14:10:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More accurate human papillomavirus (HPV) testing will enable millions of women and people with a cervix in England to benefit from more personalised cervical screening from next month, the NHS has announced today. From July, younger women (aged 25 to 49) who test negative for HPV, meaning they are at very low risk of cervical […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland completes nationwide roll-out of Clinisys WinPath]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230565</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/northern-ireland-completes-nationwide-roll-out-of-clinisys-winpath/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T12:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A project to support the transformation of pathology services across all health and social care trusts in Northern Ireland has been completed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large numbers of GPs think physician associates should do vaccinations and health checks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162543</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/large-numbers-of-gps-think-physician-associates-should-do-vaccinations-and-health-checks/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T11:01:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Large numbers of GPs think physician associates (PAs) should be able to take on vaccinations and NHS health checks, a Pulse survey has revealed. GPs were asked what tasks they think PAs should be able to perform in general practice, including vaccinations, health checks, initiating investigations, managing chronic disease and doing physical examinations and
The post Large numbers of GPs think physician associates should do vaccinations and health checks appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK taxpayer cash 'training GPs for jobs in Australia', warns BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921233</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/uk-taxpayer-cash-training-gps-jobs-australia-warns-bma/article/1921233"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK taxpayers' money is training a generation of GPs to work overseas - because a shortage of jobs and low pay means there is no place for them in the NHS, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dapagliflozin shows promise in progressive liver disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162491</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/dapagliflozin-shows-promise-in-progressive-liver-disease/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T10:48:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diabetes drug dapagliflozin could also be beneficial for patients with progressive liver disease, a clinical trial has shown. A clinical trial of 154 adults with fatty liver disease or metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis (MASH) found a significant disease improvement in those taking the sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor compared with placebo. It follows several studies reporting that SGLT-2
The post Dapagliflozin shows promise in progressive liver disease appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229611</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-77/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T10:30:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's coffee briefing covers the launch of Calm Health in the UK and a campaign to inform the future of NHS radiology information systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation and Beamtree partner to launch AI data tool]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230421</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhs-confederation-and-beamtree-partner-to-launch-ai-data-tool/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS Confederation and Beamtree have partnered to roll out an AI and machine learning analytics platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP prescribing for chronic heart failure to expand under draft NICE guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921209</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-prescribing-chronic-heart-failure-expand-draft-nice-guidance/article/1921209"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T09:05:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could prescribe a wider range of treatments for chronic heart failure under draft NICE guidance on diagnosis and management of the disease.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Commercial procurement pipeline for DHSC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/commercial-procurement-pipeline-for-dhsc</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/commercial-procurement-pipeline-for-dhsc"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T08:14:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A forecast of potential commercial activity over the next 48 months where spend is over £2 million.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs urged to 'wait for evidence' as urologists back scrapping digital rectal exams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921159</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-urged-wait-evidence-urologists-back-scrapping-digital-rectal-exams/article/1921159"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T08:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have urged the profession to 'wait for the evidence' after surgeons said digital rectal exams are 'no longer a useful test for prostate cancer' and should be discontinued.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Irish startup to deploy clinical decision support tool in NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230445</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/irish-startup-to-deploy-clinical-decision-support-tool-in-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T07:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Irish health tech start-up xWave Technologies is partnering with three NHS trusts to deploy CDS, the company's clinical decision support tool.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands affected by contaminated blood scandal to get bespoke NHS psychological care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267738</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/thousands-affected-by-contaminated-blood-scandal-to-get-bespoke-nhs-psychological-care/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T23:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of people affected and infected by the contaminated blood scandal in England will be able to self-refer from today for psychological treatment from a bespoke new NHS service. The nationwide service, which began treating its first patients last September, will include access to talking therapies, peer support and psychosocial support, as well as other […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands affected by contaminated blood scandal to get bespoke NHS psychological]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267738</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/thousands-affected-by-contaminated-blood-scandal-to-get-bespoke-nhs-psychological/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T23:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of people affected and infected by the contaminated blood scandal in England will be able to self-refer from today for psychological treatment from a bespoke new NHS service. The nationwide service, which began treating its first patients last September, will include access to talking therapies, peer support and psychosocial support, as well as other […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Women and deprived communities undertreated for heart valve disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162483</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/women-and-deprived-communities-undertreated-for-heart-valve-disease/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T15:53:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Women and people from deprived communities with heart valve disease are less likely to be referred by their GP for specialist care, research has shown. Alongside those from ethnic minority groups, women are also less likely to have intervention for aortic stenosis, the study of more than 154,000 patient records concluded. Presenting the research at
The post Women and deprived communities undertreated for heart valve disease appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs no longer need to do rectal exam for prostate cancer, argue urologists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162534</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/renal-medicine-urology-mens-health/gps-no-longer-need-to-do-rectal-exam-for-prostate-cancer-argue-urologists/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T15:42:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should no longer have to do rectal exams when trying to diagnose prostate cancer as it is a ‘poor test’ for detection, leading urologists have argued.  The British Association of Urological Surgeons (BAUS) has called for the end of digital rectal examinations (DRE) in men with suspected prostate cancer, denouncing its efficacy and necessity. 
The post GPs no longer need to do rectal exam for prostate cancer, argue urologists appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Younger GPs don’t know how good we used to have it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162388</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/david-turner/younger-gps-dont-know-how-good-we-used-to-have-it/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T14:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr David Turner turns the clock back 25 years to see what younger GPs are missing out on Being a GP is a lonely job most of the time. Yes, we have patients coming in every ten minutes or so, but in between that, most of us spend the time alone in our consulting rooms.
The post Younger GPs don’t know how good we used to have it appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fourth meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) Emergency Committee regarding the upsurge of mpox 2024 – Temporary recommendations]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:469f3b4b-eeb6-4e01-886a-04cc9d874cd0</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/09-06-2025-fourth-meeting-of-the-international-health-regulations-(2005)-emergency-committee-regarding-the-upsurge-of-mpox-2024-temporary-recommendations"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T13:55:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Director-General of the World Health Organization (WHO), following the fourth meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR) Emergency Committee regarding the upsurge of mpox 2024, held on 5 June 2025, from 12:00 to 17:00 CEST, concurs with its advice that the event continues to meet the criteria of a public health emergency of international concern and, considering the advice of the Committee, he is hereby issuing a revised set of temporary recommendations.
The WHO Director-General expresses his most sincere gratitude to the Chair, Members, and Advisors of the Committee. The proceeding of the fourth meeting of the Committee will be shared with States Parties to the IHR and published in the coming days.
---------
Temporary recommendations
These temporary recommendations a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients to receive reminders and test results through NHS App first]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230519</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/patients-to-receive-reminders-and-test-results-through-nhs-app-first/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T12:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will receive appointment reminders, screening invitations and test results through the NHS App, as part of a £50 million upgrade.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health visitors to administer some childhood vaccinations to boost uptake, says NHSE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162529</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/health-visitors-to-administer-some-childhood-vaccinations-to-boost-uptake-says-nhse/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T10:56:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health visitors will be used to boost uptake of childhood vaccination from next year, NHS England has said. This forms part of plans to reduce pressure on A&E departments, unveiled in last week’s urgent and emergency care plan. Pilots of health visitors doing catch-up vaccinations were first announced last year, although the new plans appear
The post Health visitors to administer some childhood vaccinations to boost uptake, says NHSE appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP jobs advertised at lower salaries than a decade ago, BMA says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921057</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-jobs-advertised-lower-salaries-decade-ago-bma-says/article/1921057"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T10:49:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP roles are being advertised with salaries ‘drastically’ lower than they were a decade ago, leading GPs have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More patients to get test results and appointment reminders via NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162525</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/more-patients-to-get-test-results-and-appointment-reminders-via-nhs-app/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T10:14:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions more patients will receive appointment reminders, screening invitations and test results via the NHS App, avoiding the need for ‘at least 50 million letters’, the Government has said. In latest expansion of the app, push notifications will remind patients about upcoming appointments and relay important messages, in a bid to reduce the risk of
The post More patients to get test results and appointment reminders via NHS App appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northampton General Hospital to launch Nervecentre EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230313</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/northampton-general-hospital-to-launch-nervecentre-epr/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T10:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northampton General Hospital (NGH) NHS Trust has announced the go live date for its Nervecentre electronic patient record (EPR) system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mounjaro primary care plans not yet finalised despite looming deadline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162439</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/mounjaro-primary-care-plans-not-yet-finalised-despite-looming-deadline/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T09:57:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Many areas in England have not yet finalised plans for tirzepatide (Mounjaro) delivery in primary care, despite the NICE deadline being less than three weeks away. In response to a Pulse request to all 42 ICBs, only eight areas could confirm which model they will use to implement the NICE recommendation for tirzepatide prescribing
The post Mounjaro primary care plans not yet finalised despite looming deadline appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A digital-first approach to patient communications]]></title>
        <id>b27d3486-2040-48b6-8ddc-237e996b3e57</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/transformation-blog/2025/a-digital-first-approach-to-patient-communications"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T09:40:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe and Pete explain the greater emphasis being placed on digital patient messaging across the NHS and the potential to provide a more seamless experience for patients, reduce the number of missed appointments and save the NHS money. 


This week, the Secretary of State announced the start of our journey to becoming a "digital first NHS" – here is what it means for you.


In other aspects of our lives, it's second nature to receive messages digitally. Think online bank statements, email receipts for our online shopping or text messages confirming our home deliveries have arrived. But for various reasons, the NHS has found this challenging, and we still send out millions of letters to patients each year.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A digital-first approach to patient communications]]></title>
        <id>b27d3486-2040-48b6-8ddc-237e996b3e57</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/transformation-blog/2025/a-digital-first-approach-to-patient-communications"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T09:40:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe and Pete explain the greater emphasis being placed on digital patient messaging across the NHS and the potential to provide a more seamless experience for patients, reduce the number of missed appointments and save the NHS money. 


This week, the Secretary of State announced the start of our journey to becoming a "digital first NHS" – here is what it means for you.


In other aspects of our lives, it's second nature to receive messages digitally. Think online bank statements, email receipts for our online shopping or text messages confirming our home deliveries have arrived. But for various reasons, the NHS has found this challenging, and we still send out millions of letters to patients each year.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital trust hands back GP contracts as part of NHS neighbourhood shift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920916</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/hospital-trust-hands-back-gp-contracts-part-nhs-neighbourhood-shift/article/1920916"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T08:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three GP practices run by a hospital trust will be better placed to deliver 'joined-up care closer to home' now that the trust has agreed to step back from running them, an ICB has suggested.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flo Health adopts Databricks platform to power analytics and AI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230209</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/flo-health-adopts-databricks-platform-to-power-analytics-and-ai/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T07:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FemTech firm Flo Health  has adopted a data intelligence platform from Databricks to power its analytics and AI initiatives.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients to receive reminders and test results via the NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/patients-to-receive-reminders-and-test-results-via-the-nhs-app</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/patients-to-receive-reminders-and-test-results-via-the-nhs-app"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions more patients will receive appointments, screening invitations and other important information via the NHS App, as part of £50million upgrade.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance for panels on the updated job matching profiles for nursing and midwifery]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/guidance-for-panels-on-the-updated-job-matching-profiles-for-nursing-and-midwifery.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/guidance-for-panels-on-the-updated-job-matching-profiles-for-nursing-and-midwifery.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T10:19:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - This guidance has been written for local job evaluation leads and panellists to support their understanding and use of the updated profiles for nursing and midwifery. It provides an explanation of the updated format for profiles and provides further advice to ensure matching panels are able to use the profiles effectively and consistently. Guidance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Action needed on job evaluation outcomes for nursing and midwifery staff]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/action-needed-on-job-evaluation-outcomes-for-nursing-and-midwifery-staff.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/action-needed-on-job-evaluation-outcomes-for-nursing-and-midwifery-staff.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T10:17:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - This guidance, produced by the NHS Staff Council, is for local partnerships to support the publication of updated profiles for nursing and midwifery and improvement of local job evaluation practices. Guidance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Care Act 2014 and occupational therapy: a handy summary]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/the-care-act-2014-and-occupational-therapy-a-handy-summary.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/the-care-act-2014-and-occupational-therapy-a-handy-summary.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:56:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local Government Association (LGA) - This short resource has been developed to support the occupational therapy workforce as part of council preparations for CQC assessment. It summarises the key principles of the Care Act 2014 and the universal and specific duties placed on councils as they relate to occupational therapy, with particular focus on prevention, wellbeing, and promoting independence. Where...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for CQC assessment: a resource for principal occupational therapists]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/preparing-for-cqc-assessment-a-resource-for-principal-occupational-therapists.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/preparing-for-cqc-assessment-a-resource-for-principal-occupational-therapists.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:53:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local Government Association (LGA) - This resource was developed following consultation with principal occupational therapists (POTs) from the national and ADASS regional POT networks and incorporates learning and tips from POTs who have gone through Care Quality Commission (CQC) assessment. Guidance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Play well: resources for health play services for England]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/play-well-resources-for-health-play-services-for-england.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/play-well-resources-for-health-play-services-for-england.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:10:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England - This toolkit will help commissioners, service managers, health play practitioners and clinical leaders to design, plan and deliver high-quality health play services for babies, children and young people. The resources include guidelines, recommended standards and a quality checklist. Toolkit]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2025 Spending Review: what's the RCN asking for?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/2025-spending-review-whats-the-rcn-asking-for.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/2025-spending-review-whats-the-rcn-asking-for.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Nursing (RCN) - This submission to the government's 2025 Spending Review argues that there is an opportunity to start addressing some of the challenges within the nursing workforce and wider health and care system. The RCN ask that the 10-Year Health Plan and the forthcoming Workforce Plan for England, and the Spending Review are aligned in terms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cancer in the UK: overview 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/cancer-in-the-uk-overview-2025.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/cancer-in-the-uk-overview-2025.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T08:51:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cancer Research UK - This report finds that over the last 50 years, the proportion of the UK population dying from cancer has fallen by more than a fifth. However it also finds while people are now less likely to die from cancer, more people are likely to get it. And due to the UK’s growing and ageing population, the...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four big decisions for the 2025 Spending Review]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/four-big-decisions-for-the-2025-spending-review.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/four-big-decisions-for-the-2025-spending-review.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T16:31:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Fiscal Studies - The Spending Review 2025 will set detailed departmental budgets for most of this parliament. This analysis examines the key choices facing the government on spending in the NHS, health and care, pay and the public sector. Report]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spending Review 2025: priorities for health, the NHS and social care in England]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/spending-review-2025-priorities-for-health-the-nhs-and-social-care-in-england.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/spending-review-2025-priorities-for-health-the-nhs-and-social-care-in-england.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T16:18:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This analysis sets out the Health Foundation’s priorities for health and care investment at the Spending Review and options for how they could be achieved. It draws on evidence submitted to the Treasury in February 2025. It covers the investment needed in public health, the NHS and adult social care services; additionally, it sets out policy...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing innovative flexible working to combat escalating demand on services]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/implementing-innovative-flexible-working-to-combat-escalating-demand-on-services.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/implementing-innovative-flexible-working-to-combat-escalating-demand-on-services.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T10:28:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - This case study outlines how Imperial College Healthcare NHS Trust used an innovative flexible working model to combat escalating demand for imaging diagnostic services. Case study]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unlocking the potential of primary care provider collaboratives]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/unlocking-the-potential-of-primary-care-provider-collaboratives.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/unlocking-the-potential-of-primary-care-provider-collaboratives.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T10:18:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - Primary care provider collaboratives are fundamental to the successful delivery of a neighbourhood health service. Their role will be pivotal in shifting care from hospitals to community, reducing health inequalities and ensuring that everyone has access to high-quality care. In partnership with KPMG, the NHS Confederation's Primary Care Network has been exploring what is needed to unlock...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evaluation of the Better Care Fund Support Programme 2023 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/evaluation-of-the-better-care-fund-support-programme-2023-to-2025.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/evaluation-of-the-better-care-fund-support-programme-2023-to-2025.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T09:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) - The Department of Health and Social Care commissioned Ipsos UK, in partnership with the Institute of Public Care at Oxford Brookes University, to conduct an evaluation of the Better Care Fund (BCF) Support Programme. The evaluation explores local authorities' perceptions of the design and delivery of the BCF support programme; the enablers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The care expectation gap]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/the-care-expectation-gap.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/the-care-expectation-gap.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T10:53:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joseph Rowntree Foundation - This briefing suggests that people are unaware of the challenges of the social care system and thus are likely not preparing for a future in which they may have to meet significant care costs or care themselves. It found that only 19% of the general public correctly guessed that the cost of professional home care services...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital of the future: hospital as a service, not a building]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/hospital-of-the-future-hospital-as-a-service-not-a-building.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/hospital-of-the-future-hospital-as-a-service-not-a-building.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T15:37:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Re:State - This report outlines a model that fundamentally changes the configuration of the modern hospital. The paper proposes a model that combines a radical increase in virtual care with renewed approaches at system-wide integration. It argues that instead of inefficiently relocating hospital staff and infrastructure to communities, hospital-level care should be delivered as a service through entirely new care...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Putting young people at the heart of care]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/putting-young-people-at-the-heart-of-care-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/putting-young-people-at-the-heart-of-care-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T14:06:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This report features four case studies demonstrating how trusts are successfully improving services for children and young people across a variety of sectors: delivering mental health support to children and young people in the community; collaborating at neighbourhood level for the benefit of children and young people; improving access to care through digital interventions; and using co-production...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The short-and-medium-term impacts of Sure Start on children's outcomes]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/the-short-and-medium-term-impacts-of-sure-start-on-childrens-outcomes-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/the-short-and-medium-term-impacts-of-sure-start-on-childrens-outcomes-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T13:30:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[lnstitute for Fiscal Studies - This report finds that Sure Start – one of England’s biggest early years programmes – generated widespread and long-lasting benefits for children. It improved educational outcomes and health, and reduced school absences and less severe special educational needs and disabilities (SEND). Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global oncology trends 2025: adopting new therapies as modalities shift and expenditures rise]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/global-oncology-trends-2025-adopting-new-therapies-as-modalities-shift-and-expenditures-rise-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/global-oncology-trends-2025-adopting-new-therapies-as-modalities-shift-and-expenditures-rise-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T12:54:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IQVIA Institute for Human Data Science - This report profiles the current state of research and development in oncology, including key mechanisms, targets, and cancer types being investigated as well as pointing to some novel areas which are only just emerging. It also looks at metrics of clinical development productivity. Report More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HIV and long lives: new challenges in high-income countries]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/hiv-and-long-lives-new-challenges-in-high-income-countries-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/hiv-and-long-lives-new-challenges-in-high-income-countries-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T11:40:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[International Longevity Centre (ILC) - This report warns that health systems in high-income countries are dangerously underprepared for the growing number of people ageing with HIV. Thanks to advances in antiretroviral therapy, people with HIV are living longer than ever before, but social, economic and health systems have failed to keep up. Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>