<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html</id>
    <title>Industry Feed</title>
    <updated>2024-07-08T09:11:31.754Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who is new health and social care secretary Wes Streeting?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879772</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/new-health-social-care-secretary-wes-streeting/article/1879772"/>
        <updated>2024-07-08T07:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wes Streeting has been appointed health and social care secretary in Sir Keir Starmer’s new government. GPonline looks at what we know about the new secretary of state.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 6,000 operations and appointments delayed by London cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178729</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/over-6000-operations-and-appointments-delayed-by-london-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-08T07:30:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 6,000 operations and appointments have been postponed at London hospitals affected by the Synnovis cyber attack.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speech: Statement from the Secretary of State for Health and Social Care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/statement-from-the-secretary-of-state-for-health-and-social-care</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/statement-from-the-secretary-of-state-for-health-and-social-care"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T17:21:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Secretary of State for Health and Social Care delivers a statement setting out his mission for saving the NHS]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Streeting’s election encapsulates Labour MPs’ dilemma]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150550</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/streetings-election-encapsulates-labour-mps-dilemma/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T15:52:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse editor Jaimie Kaffash’s take on Labour’s victory and the consequences for general practice This was one of the most underwhelming election campaigns I can remember, but it has left us with a fascinating result that has several policy implications – no more so than in general practice. Of course, all the headlines are about
The post Streeting’s election encapsulates Labour MPs’ dilemma appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wes Streeting named first Labour health secretary for 14 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150547</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/wes-streeting-named-first-labour-health-secretary-for-14-years/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T15:17:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wes Streeting has been appointed health secretary under the new Labour Government, following the party’s landslide win in the general election yesterday. The MP for Ilford North only very narrowly held on to his parliamentary seat, with an independent candidate standing on a pro-Gaza platform just 500 votes behind. He was named shadow secretary of
The post Wes Streeting named first Labour health secretary for 14 years appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What will Labour mean for general practice?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150536</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/politics/what-will-labour-mean-for-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T14:37:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse looks at what a new government will mean for general practice Unless you’ve been living underground for the past six weeks/14 years, yesterday’s result in the general election will not have come as a shock. Keir Starmer’s Labour Party cruised to an historic win, utterly humiliating the Conservatives all across the UK. We have
The post What will Labour mean for general practice? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The final manifesto – a prescription for general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150488</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/margaret-ikpoh/the-final-manifesto-a-prescription-for-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T13:13:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Margaret Ikpoh lays out her general practice manifesto in the hopes the new government may take note Dear reader, For several weeks, the political landscape of our nation has been as frantic as a GP reception on a Monday morning. We have seen weeks of each party vying for our favour and by the
The post The final manifesto – a prescription for general practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General practice must be 'day one' priority for new Labour government, say GP leaders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879789</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-practice-day-one-priority-new-labour-government-say-gp-leaders/article/1879789"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T12:31:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new Labour government must make general practice a ‘day one’ priority and take steps to address the workload and workforce crisis, GP leaders have said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dublin-based healthcare clinic to go live with Aptvision RIS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178509</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/dublin-based-healthcare-clinic-to-go-live-with-aptvision-ris/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T12:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dublin-based clinic Sana Health Diagnostic is implementing Aptvision's radiology information system to advance the accessibility of its medical services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA warns Welsh government of potential GP contract dispute]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879762</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-warns-welsh-government-potential-gp-contract-dispute/article/1879762"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T10:06:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA Wales GP committee has warned the Welsh government that it is considering options for a formal contract dispute following delays to this year's negotiations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital healthcare market predicted to hit $836bn by 2031]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178661</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/digital-healthcare-market-predicted-to-hit-836bn-by-2031/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T10:00:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The digital healthcare market is poised for explosive growth, with a new report predicting it will reach $836.10 billion by 2031.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour to form Government as shadow health secretary narrowly holds on to seat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150505</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/labour-to-form-government-as-shadow-health-secretary-narrowly-holds-on-to-seat/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T09:15:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Labour Party will form the next Government following a landslide victory in yesterday’s general election. However, the party’s shadow health secretary only very narrowly held on to his parliamentary seat, with an independent candidate standing on a pro-Gaza platform just 500 votes behind. Wes Streeting was only 528 votes from losing his seat of
The post Labour to form Government as shadow health secretary narrowly holds on to seat appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS publishes data following junior doctors strike]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248666</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/07/nhs-publishes-data-following-junior-doctors-strike-4/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T09:05:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data on the recent industrial action by junior doctors can be found on the NHS England website. Since strikes began, the cumulative total of acute inpatient and outpatient appointments rescheduled is now nearly 1.5 million (1,491,303). Junior doctors took industrial action from 7am on Thursday 27 June to 7am on Tuesday 2 July. The action […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>fraja</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs think pharmacists are the most successful ARRS role]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150503</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gps-think-pharmacists-are-the-most-successful-arrs-role/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T08:47:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pharmacists rank top as the most successful Additional Roles Reimbursement Scheme (ARRS) role, a recent survey of GPs has found. The survey, carried out by Pulse publisher Cogora, asked 346 GPs which ARRS role they felt had been most successful in supporting patients and the practice. Pharmacists were considered among the most successful roles by
The post GPs think pharmacists are the most successful ARRS role appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Which GPs are heading to parliament after the general election?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879728</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-heading-parliament-general-election/article/1879728"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T07:58:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was a mixed night for GPs standing in the general election. GPonline looks at how they fared.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General election 2024: Health tech leaders react to Labour victory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178677</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/general-election-2024-health-tech-leaders-react-to-labour-victory/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-05T07:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We asked health tech leaders for their reactions to Labour’s victory in the general election and what the focus should be for health minister Wes Streeting.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update on cyber incident: clinical impact in South East London: Thursday 4 July]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248629</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/07/update-on-cyber-incident-clinical-impact-in-south-east-london-thursday-4-july/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T17:18:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England London has released its latest weekly data update on the clinical impact of the ransomware cyber attack against Synnovis on Monday 3 June. Over four weeks on from the cyber attack, NHS organisations across London continue to work in partnership to ensure people who require critical and urgent care receive it. NHS England […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overdiagnosis: Depression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150498</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/overdiagnosis-depression/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T15:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continuing our series on conditions that may be overdiagnosed, GP partner and trainer Dr David Coleman explores the evidence-based approach to diagnosing depression Low mood is one of the most common presenting complaints we encounter in general practice. The ensuing consultations frequently result in a diagnosis of depression and a referral to talking therapies, a
The post Overdiagnosis: Depression  appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welsh GPs threaten contract dispute in protest at negotiation delays]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150490</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/wales/welsh-gps-threaten-contract-dispute-in-protest-at-negotiation-delays/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T15:13:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welsh GPs are ‘actively evaluating all available options’ for dispute against the Government following delays to contract negotiations. BMA Wales’ GP committee chair Dr Gareth Oelmann said contract discussions with ministers for the 2024/25 contract have yet to start due to ‘continued delay’ from the Government. Yesterday, he wrote to Welsh First Minister Vaughan Gething,
The post Welsh GPs threaten contract dispute in protest at negotiation delays appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smoking rates in pregnancy fall to all-time low]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150491</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/smoking-rates-in-pregnancy-fall-to-all-time-low/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T14:44:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smoking rates among pregnant women have fallen to the lowest levels since records began, according to NHS Digital statistics. Rates of smoking at the point of delivery were 8.8% in 2022/23 among pregnant women but fell to 7.4% in 2023/24, which is a difference of around 6,000 women. However, this is still above the national ambition
The post Smoking rates in pregnancy fall to all-time low appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This campaign will leave an uncertain dawn for the NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/this-campaign-will-leave-an-uncertain-dawn-for-the-nhs.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/this-campaign-will-leave-an-uncertain-dawn-for-the-nhs.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T13:54:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - The authors of this long read review what has (and hasn’t) been said and promised by the main political parties in England on the key issues facing health and care leading up to the general election. The briefing emphasises how important it will be for the new government that people’s experiences of these services are improved. Nuffield...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practice has to call police after GP registrar verbally abused by patient]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879664</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/practice-call-police-gp-registrar-verbally-abused-patient/article/1879664"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T13:31:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP practice in Lancashire was forced to call the police after a patient was verbally aggressive and refused to leave a GP registrar’s consulting room.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Access Group confirmed as co-headline sponsor of Rewired 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178627</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/the-access-group-confirmed-as-co-headline-sponsor-of-rewired-2025/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T12:39:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Access Group, a leading provider of digital care software, has been confirmed as co-headline sponsor for Rewired 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA advises GPs not to share cloud-based telephony call data with NHSE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178599</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/bma-advises-gps-not-to-share-cloud-based-telephony-call-data-with-nhse/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T11:39:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA's GP Committee England has warned that NHS England could use cloud-based telephony data to ‘performance manage’ GP practices.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new way to find patients]]></title>
        <id>d585aac1-e2b6-41d9-8964-e0366454c1eb</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/data-points-blog/2023/a-new-way-to-find-patients"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T11:05:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Darren Hickling describes NHS Digital’s role in developing a platform to identify the highest risk COVID-19 patients so they could receive life-saving antiviral treatments.  


As COVID-19 emerged and treatment options were limited, pharmaceutical companies began researching and developing new antibody and antiviral treatments to reduce viral replication or alleviate symptoms in immunocompromised people.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coroner calls for online drug prescribers to communicate with patients’ GP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150466</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/long-term-conditions-prescribing/coroner-calls-for-online-drug-prescribers-to-communicate-with-patients-gp/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T10:32:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A coroner investigating an overdose death has raised ‘grave concerns’ about online drug sales, including the lack of communication with a patient’s GP. Last month, coroner Isabel Thistlewaite issued a ‘prevention of future deaths report’ to the health secretary following the death of a man in Leicestershire.  Nigel Dixon died in February 2023 from an
The post Coroner calls for online drug prescribers to communicate with patients’ GP appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA drops face-to-face consultations only from GP collective action options]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150464</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/bma-drops-face-to-face-consultations-only-from-collective-action-options/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T10:13:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has dropped two of its options for GP collective action, including seeing patients face to face as default. The union is currently planning for potential GP collective action to commence on 1 August, depending on the result of a ballot of GP partners which will close on Monday 29 July. In the ballot, partners
The post BMA drops face-to-face consultations only from GP collective action options appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178515</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-151/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T10:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Coffee Time Briefing includes an award for Addenbrooke’s Hospital’s virtual ward service and a new AI food diary app.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO updates laboratory biosecurity guidance]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:e676226a-9cf7-4a1d-a097-64c5d30d88a4</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/04-07-2024-who-updates-laboratory-biosecurity-guidance"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T09:28:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO recently issued updated guidance for national authorities and biomedical laboratories to manage biological risks.
Laboratories are essential components of health systems, critical for patient diagnosis and rapid clinical care, disease surveillance, pathogen characterization, and research and development for treatments and vaccines. Appropriately designed and equipped facilities, trained staff, evidence-based risk mitigating measures, transparent reporting and layered oversight mechanisms will safeguard the workforce and the community from pathogenic microorganisms and toxins. 
New updates in the guidance include the strengthening of cybersecurity measures and handling of confidential information such as patient records; reducing risks from new technologies, including those related to g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Collective energy’ needed to tackle discrimination in digital health]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178561</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/collective-energy-needed-to-tackle-discrimination-in-digital-health/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T07:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An event to discuss the creation of an ‘Equity Charter’ for digital health has called for “collective energy” to overcome discrimination in the sector.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Underfunding and practice closures, GP collective action, the GP standing to be a Green MP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879492</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-underfunding-practice-closures-gp-collective-action-gp-standing-green-mp/article/1879492"/>
        <updated>2024-07-04T07:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GPonline team discusses the BMA ballot on collective action and why GP funding is now a critical issue and speak to GP Dr Pallavi Devulapalli who is standing for the Green Party in the general election.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acute care doesn’t always go with the flowchart]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150452</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/acute-care-doesnt-always-go-with-the-flowchart/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T14:25:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Copperfield on ICSs trying to overhaul acute care  You only have to witness one day duty surgery to realise that we GPs are masters at creating order from chaos. So we can relate to ICSs’ attempts at trying to overhaul acute care. They’re trying to do on the macro what we do so successfully
The post Acute care doesn’t always go with the flowchart appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SAS doctor plans will bring ‘demise’ of GP profession, says GPC chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150443</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/sas-doctor-plans-will-bring-demise-of-gp-profession-says-gpc-chair/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T13:57:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England’s plans for SAS doctors to work as ‘primary care doctors’ in GP practices are ‘colluding in the demise of the profession’, the BMA’s GP committee chair has said. Dr Katie Bramall-Stainer said that the commissioner’s plans for Specialty and Associate Specialist (SAS) doctors to work in general practice are likely to cause a
The post SAS doctor plans will bring ‘demise’ of GP profession, says GPC chair appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress made on coronary heart disease offset by other cardiovascular conditions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150283</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/progress-made-on-coronary-heart-disease-offset-by-other-cardiovascular-conditions/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T13:43:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A substantial drop in rates of coronary heart disease over the past two decades has largely been offset by rising rates of other cardiovascular conditions, research shows. Analysis of data from 2000 to 2019 showed rates of coronary heart disease fell by about 30% with this improvement largely seen in the over 60s. The study
The post Progress made on coronary heart disease offset by other cardiovascular conditions appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The GP standing against Liz Truss in the general election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879494</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-standing-against-liz-truss-general-election/article/1879494"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T13:12:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPonline speaks to Norfolk GP and Green Party candidate and health spokesperson Dr Pallavi Devulapalli about standing for election in South West Norfolk, her role as a local councillor and her party's pledges on the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No strategy for AI being adopted in the NHS, says Health Foundation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178485</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/no-strategy-for-ai-being-adopted-in-the-nhs-says-health-foundation/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T12:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation has called for the government and NHS leaders to develop a dedicated strategy for AI in healthcare.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clearing the air: confronting the costs to cloud adopters of restrictive software licensing practices]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/clearing-the-air-confronting-the-costs-to-cloud-adopters-of-restrictive-software-licensing-practices.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/clearing-the-air-confronting-the-costs-to-cloud-adopters-of-restrictive-software-licensing-practices.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T10:02:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Social Market Foundation - This report calculates the wasted public sector money on software licensing due to restrictive rules to be worth at least £300 million over the next 5 years. Through interviews with public sector IT professionals, the authors learnt that current software licensing rules are making it harder to switch between providers, and thus keeping them locked into...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patient groups oppose NHSE plans for unified clinical registry platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178477</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/patient-groups-oppose-nhse-plans-for-unified-clinical-registry-platform/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T10:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patient groups for people with blood disorders have raised concerns about NHS England plans to combine clinical registries in a single platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost 14k doctors urge political leaders to address PA ‘scandal’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150436</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/almost-14k-doctors-urge-political-leaders-to-address-pa-scandal/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T09:31:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost 14,000 doctors have signed a BMA letter to the major political party leaders urging action on physician associates.  The letter, sent ahead of Thursday’s general election, expressed ‘grave concern’ about the deployment of associate professionals, and warned that PAs are working ‘in practical terms, as GPs’.  It called for the next government to take
The post Almost 14k doctors urge political leaders to address PA ‘scandal’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA’s PA regulation legal action ‘not even arguable’, claims GMC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150447</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/bmas-pa-regulation-legal-action-not-even-arguable-claims-gmc/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T09:15:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GMC has rejected the BMA’s plans for legal action on physician associate (PA) regulation, claiming the grounds for a judicial review are ‘not even arguable’. Last week, the BMA announced it was launching legal action against the GMC over the way in which it plans to regulate PAs, and in particular the use of
The post BMA’s PA regulation legal action ‘not even arguable’, claims GMC appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[13,000 doctors urge party leaders to address physician associate safety concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879425</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/13000-doctors-urge-party-leaders-address-physician-associate-safety-concerns/article/1879425"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T08:42:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A BMA letter signed by more than 13,000 doctors has been sent to the leaders of the major political parties warning that patients are at risk because of the way physician associates (PAs) are being used in the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[13,000 doctors urge party leaders to address physician associate safety concers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879425</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/13000-doctors-urge-party-leaders-address-physician-associate-safety-concers/article/1879425"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T08:42:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A BMA letter signed by more than 13,000 doctors has been sent to the leaders of the major political parties warning that patients are at risk because of the way physician associates (PAs) are being used in the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA takes next step in PA regulation legal action after GMC refutes concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879306</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-takes-next-step-pa-regulation-legal-action-gmc-refutes-concerns/article/1879306"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T07:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA is to take the next steps in its legal action against the GMC over physician associate regulation and apply for a judicial review after the regulator rejected concerns raised by the union.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA takes next step in legal action over PA regulation after GMC refutes concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879306</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-takes-next-step-legal-action-pa-regulation-gmc-refutes-concerns/article/1879306"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T07:53:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA is to take the next steps in its legal action against the GMC over physician associate regulation and apply for a judicial review after the regulator rejected concerns raised by the union.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Networks Awards 2024 finalists revealed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178461</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/digital-health-networks-awards-2024-finalists-revealed/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-03T07:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health has revealed the finalists of the 2024 Digital Health Networks Awards, which will take place at this year’s Summer Schools event in Durham.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE deny claims they tried to ‘frustrate’ GP collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150415</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/nhse-tried-deny-claims-they-tried-to-frustrate-gp-collective-action/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T15:20:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England’s director of primary care has rejected the BMA’s claims that it had tried to stop GPs from switching off an update to GP Connect – one of the collective actions put forward by the union. GPs across England took urgent action last weekend to switch off a GP Connect update permitting community pharmacies
The post NHSE deny claims they tried to ‘frustrate’ GP collective action appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Alan Stout appointed BMA Northern Ireland council chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150420</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/northern-ireland/dr-alan-stout-appointed-bma-northern-ireland-council-chair/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T14:50:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A former GP committee chair has been elected to lead the BMA’s Northern Ireland council. East Belfast GP Dr Alan Stout has been elected as chair of the council, and on 11 July will take over from Dr Tom Black, a GP in Derry who was in the role for the last six years. Dr
The post Dr Alan Stout appointed BMA Northern Ireland council chair appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being a ‘slow’ GP isn’t all bad]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149641</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/being-a-slow-gp-isnt-all-bad/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T14:33:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Seema Pattni looks to redefine the ‘slow’ GP label to one that values communication and attentiveness in a system that doesn’t always allow for it Many GPs identify as ‘slow,’ but the negative associations of being a ‘slow’ GP need to change. The daily reality of being a slow GP is hard: over-running clinics,
The post Being a ‘slow’ GP isn’t all bad appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4519 - Cisco Releases Advisory for Exploited Vulnerability in NX-OS software]]></title>
        <id>b3d2a495-9d03-4b42-bce9-94c2b5e70a03</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4519"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T13:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 CLI in NX-OS software contains a command injection vulnerability CVE-2024-20399 that is being exploited in the wild
 CLI in NX-OS software contains a command injection vulnerability CVE-2024-20399 that is being exploited in the wild
 Updated: 02 Jul 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP elected as new BMA Northern Ireland chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879305</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-elected-new-bma-northern-ireland-chair/article/1879305"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T12:55:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP Dr Alan Stout has been elected chair of the BMA Northern Ireland council.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE and NICE invite comments on pathway to fast-track MedTech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178427</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/nhse-and-nice-invite-comments-on-pathway-to-fast-track-medtech/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T12:29:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England and NICE have invited comments on proposals for MedTech developers to fast-track products for use in the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 facts about the NHS workforce]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/10-facts-about-the-nhs-workforce.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/10-facts-about-the-nhs-workforce.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T11:48:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - The NHS is the single largest employer in the UK. Although the size of its workforce is rising, the level of growth is not sufficient to meet the increasing demand for healthcare and complexity or level of patient need. Increases in staff numbers are not consistent across roles, and the service faces high numbers of vacancies overall....]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Priorities for an AI in health care strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/priorities-for-an-ai-in-health-care-strategy.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/priorities-for-an-ai-in-health-care-strategy.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T11:16:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This long read argues that a dedicated strategy for artifical intelligence (AI) in health care is needed to coordinate current fragmented efforts in the NHS in England. It sets out six priorities this strategy should address and some of the steps to do so. Long read]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPC warns NHS England may use call data to ‘performance manage’ practices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150401</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gpc-warns-nhs-england-may-use-call-data-to-performance-manage-practices/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T10:12:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA’s GP Committee England have raised concerns that NHS England could use cloud-based telephony data to ‘performance manage’ GP practices. GPC England chair Dr Katie Bramall-Stainer raised the concerns during an online roadshow last week, warning that the data collected could be used to check if practices close for lunch, or take half days,
The post GPC warns NHS England may use call data to ‘performance manage’ practices appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178173</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-150/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T10:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Digital Health's Coffee Time Briefing includes positive news on whole genome sequencing and a warning about CGM being used by non-diabetics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wandsworth Healthcare, DNV Imatis partner to improve patient journey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178363</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/wandsworth-healthcare-dnv-imatis-partner-to-improve-patient-journey/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T09:59:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wandsworth Healthcare and DNV Imatis have partnered to help NHS trusts tackle low digital maturity and improve operational efficiency.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workload crisis leaves GPs feeling they are 'short changing' patients, says former BMA chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878907</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/workload-crisis-leaves-gps-feeling-short-changing-patients-says-former-bma-chair/article/1878907"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T09:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spiralling workload in general practice has left GPs feeling like they are 'short changing' patients, leading to moral injury that has a detrimental impact on their wellbeing, a former BMA chair has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England statement on industrial action: Tuesday 2 July 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248488</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/07/nhs-england-statement-on-industrial-action-tuesday-2-july-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T09:22:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Professor Sir Stephen Powis, NHS National Medical Director said: “This round of industrial action has now ended, and staff will work quickly to rebook appointments that have been impacted. “I would like to thank NHS staff for their incredible efforts during the last 5 days and patients who have continued to use services as normal […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How has general practice changed since the last general election?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878917</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-practice-changed-last-general-election/article/1878917"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice has featured prominently in campaigning from political parties in the run-up to the 4 July general election. GPonline looks at what the data show about how general practice has changed since the last election.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK to switch to non-polio containing pertussis vaccine for pregnant women]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150302</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/uk-to-switch-to-non-polio-containing-pertussis-vaccine-for-pregnant-women/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T08:42:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK is switching to a different pertussis vaccine for pregnant women following advice from the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation. The maternal pertussis vaccination programme will move to using a vaccine that does not contain polio from July, after studies showed that component of the vaccine had a small impact on children’s antibodies
The post UK to switch to non-polio containing pertussis vaccine for pregnant women appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the month answers: Did you get what was the cause of this patient’s confusion?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150219</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/case-of-the-month-answers-did-you-get-what-was-the-cause-of-this-patients-confusion/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T08:18:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the third of our monthly series, Dr Roger Henderson asked readers to suggest what the cause of this patient’s confusion and change of mood was. Did you get the answer? Check below! (If you want to look at the case without spoilers, have a look at the original case here) The case A 38
The post Case of the month answers: Did you get what was the cause of this patient’s confusion? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heriot-Watt University partners with ABHI to advance health tech research]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178279</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/heriot-watt-university-partners-with-abhi-to-advance-health-tech-research/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-02T07:30:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Heriot-Watt University is focusing on accelerating health tech research and development, through a partnership with ABHI.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO releases first-ever clinical treatment guideline for tobacco cessation in adults]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:e8ccc53b-5d12-4328-9a34-5c68f5a22b17</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/02-07-2024-who-releases-first-ever-clinical-treatment-guideline-for-tobacco-cessation-in-adults"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T20:42:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) recommends a comprehensive set of tobacco cessation interventions, including behavioural support delivered by health-care providers, digital cessation interventions and pharmacological treatments in a first guideline on tobacco cessation.
The guideline focuses on helping the more than 750 million tobacco users who want to quit all forms of tobacco. The recommendations are relevant for all adults seeking to quit various tobacco products, including cigarettes, waterpipes, smokeless tobacco products, cigars, roll-your-own tobacco, and heated tobacco products (HTPs).

“This guideline marks a crucial milestone in our global battle against these dangerous products," said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General. "It empowers countries with the essen…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A&E by appointment only as ICB reveals radical plans for acute care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150381</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/integrated-care-systems/ae-by-appointment-only-as-icb-reveals-radical-plans-for-acute-care/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T16:13:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An ICB has drawn up plans to overhaul acute care in its area, including mandatory appointment booking for A&E departments and triage though ‘neighbourhood hubs’. Cambridgeshire and Peterborough ICB said it is planning to launch pilots of the strategy from December, aiming to shift from ‘traditional acute care to a community-based approach’. According to a
The post A&E by appointment only as ICB reveals radical plans for acute care appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General election briefing: health is our greatest asset]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/general-election-briefing-health-is-our-greatest-asset.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/general-election-briefing-health-is-our-greatest-asset.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T15:24:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Centre for Progressive Policy - This analysis reveals that failure to make realistic progress on health inequalities led to 64,000 more avoidable deaths between 2010-2019 – mostly due to failures in prevention. Yet the party manifestos almost exclusively look at health through the prism of the NHS – treatment of disease and waiting lists, while leaving aside those crucial policy...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ongoing decline in uptake of childhood vaccines, figures suggest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150300</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/vaccinations-prevention-screening/ongoing-decline-in-uptake-of-childhood-vaccines-figures-suggest/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T15:05:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccine uptake in babies in the UK is continuing to fall for most immunisations, the latest public health figures show. Figures for the first three months of this year show the steady decline seen over the past decade is still not showing signs of turnaround despite recent Government campaigns to encourage uptake. Between January and
The post Ongoing decline in uptake of childhood vaccines, figures suggest appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our vision for improving patient experience of diagnosis]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/our-vision-for-improving-patient-experience-of-diagnosis.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/our-vision-for-improving-patient-experience-of-diagnosis.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T14:52:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[National Voices - The process of getting a diagnosis is becoming increasingly challenging, with February 2024 statistics showing that the proportion of patients waiting six weeks or more for diagnostic tests is 20.8%. This report from National Voices (a coalition of 200 health and social care charities in England) sets out nine key recommendations they believe will significantly improve people’s...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What you don’t know about… doctor apprenticeships]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150330</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/what-you-dont-know-about/what-you-dont-know-about-doctor-apprenticeships/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T14:43:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the first of a new series looking at policies, funding pots and new initiatives that may have slipped your notice, Dr Ammad Butt looks at doctor apprenticeships and what they could mean for the future of general practice What is a doctor apprenticeship? The past year has seen reports of GPs being out of
The post What you don’t know about… doctor apprenticeships appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England statement on industrial action: Monday, 1 July]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248467</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/07/nhs-england-statement-on-industrial-action-monday-1-july/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T14:05:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Professor Sir Stephen Powis, NHS National Medical Director, said: “As we enter the final hours of industrial action, disruption is continuing across NHS services that were already under severe pressure – but staff have shown tremendous dedication in doing everything possible to prioritise urgent and emergency care. “Staff are working hard to rebook appointments that […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4518 - Juniper Networks Releases Out-of-Cycle Security Bulletin for Session Smart Router (SSR)]]></title>
        <id>466ea3f4-7cfd-48bb-be59-4a7a2324c428</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4518"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T12:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Authentication bypass vulnerability CVE-2024-2973 affects Session Smart Router, Conductor, and WAN Assurance Router
 Authentication bypass vulnerability CVE-2024-2973 affects Session Smart Router, Conductor, and WAN Assurance Router
 Updated: 01 Jul 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No clear NHS digital career pathway, more a ‘career rockface’ says Eccles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178287</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/no-clear-nhs-digital-career-pathway-more-a-career-rockface-says-eccles/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T12:47:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former NHS national CCIO Dr Simon Eccles said that people seeking digital roles in the NHS face a “career rockface” because there is no clear pathway.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protected: CPD: Key questions on the use of FIT in primary care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150340</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-areas/cancer/cpd-key-questions-on-the-use-of-fit-in-primary-care/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T11:08:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is no excerpt because this is a protected post.
The post Protected: CPD: Key questions on the use of FIT in primary care appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA advises practices to turn off GP Connect update functionality immediately]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879152</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-advises-practices-turn-off-gp-connect-update-functionality-immediately/article/1879152"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T11:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has advised practices to switch off the GP Connect functionality that allows third parties to add codes to patient records immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capital spending in public services: fixing how the government invests in the NHS, schools and prisons]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/capital-spending-in-public-services-fixing-how-the-government-invests-in-the-nhs-schools-and-prisons.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/capital-spending-in-public-services-fixing-how-the-government-invests-in-the-nhs-schools-and-prisons.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T10:59:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Government - This report, published with Grant Thornton UK LLP, reveals the impact of the UK’s historically low – and badly spent – capital budgets on the Department of Health and Social Care, Department for Education and Ministry of Justice. Report More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expecting the unexpected: homecare providers’ views of hospital discharge]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/expecting-the-unexpected-homecare-providers-views-of-hospital-discharge.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/expecting-the-unexpected-homecare-providers-views-of-hospital-discharge.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T10:57:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Homecare Association - This report looks at hospital discharge in the United Kingdom through the eyes of homecare providers and the people they support. The report reveals widespread problems with hospital discharge. Despite guidance, funding and a national taskforce, many integrated care systems are not getting the basics right. This puts the safety and wellbeing of people leaving hospital at...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elective hubs]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/elective-hubs.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/elective-hubs.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T10:38:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This report is the second instalment in NHS Providers' Provider collaboratives building capacity series, which highlights how provider collaboration is enabling delivery on major health system priorities. The report focuses on the role collaboration is playing in building capacity through the development of elective hubs. Report]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three quarters of GPs say that workload is a threat to patient safety, finds RCGP poll]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150347</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/three-quarters-of-gps-say-that-workload-is-a-threat-to-patient-safety-finds-rcgp-poll/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T10:28:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over three quarters of GPs have said that workload is compromising patients’ safety, a poll from the Royal College of GPs has revealed.  In the ‘GP Voice Survey’ of over 2000 GPs, 76% said that ‘patient safety was being compromised by their excessive workloads,’ and that six in ten GPs do not feel they have
The post Three quarters of GPs say that workload is a threat to patient safety, finds RCGP poll appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How can the next government improve hospital waits in England?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/how-can-the-next-government-improve-hospital-waits-in-england.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/how-can-the-next-government-improve-hospital-waits-in-england.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T10:12:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This long read looks at recent trends in waits for elective care (routine, non-urgent, hospital treatment) and urgent and emergency care (ambulance response times and waiting times in A&E departments). It also examines some of the main factors that affect how long people wait for these services and how these may be affected by lack of...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practices thwart NHS England attempts to prevent removal of GP Connect]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150341</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gp-practices-thwart-nhs-england-attempts-to-prevent-removal-of-gp-connect/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T10:10:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs across England took urgent action over the weekend to remove the GP Connect functionality from their systems, following instruction from the BMA. Removing GP Connect was one of BMA GP Committee England’s suggestions for potential industrial action to commence on 1 August, depending on the result of a ballot of GP partners which will close
The post Practices thwart NHS England attempts to prevent removal of GP Connect appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP workload is a threat to patient safety, warns RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879138</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-workload-threat-patient-safety-warns-rcgp/article/1879138"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T10:03:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients are bearing the ‘brunt’ of the general practice crisis with more than three-quarters of GPs saying that patient safety is being compromised by excessive GP workloads, the RCGP has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Wales prepares for drone-based blood transfer service]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178147</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/nhs-wales-prepares-for-drone-based-blood-transfer-service/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T10:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aerospace innovators will showcase technology as part of a project to prepare NHS Wales for drone-based services for the transfer of blood products.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The state of primary care: a PCN evaluation]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/the-state-of-primary-care-a-pcn-evaluation.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/07/the-state-of-primary-care-a-pcn-evaluation.html"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T09:44:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse - Primary care networks (PCNs) have been the biggest change in the primary care landscape in a decade. The development of these networks has been controversial and has affected all areas of primary care. As part of Pulse's State of Primary Care survey, answered by more that 1,700 health care professionals, GPs, nurses, pharmacists and managers were asked about...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New chair of BMA Northern Ireland GP committee elected]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1879116</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/new-chair-bma-northern-ireland-gp-committee-elected/article/1879116"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T08:41:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Frances O'Hagan has been elected as the new chair of the BMA Northern Ireland GP committee, becoming the first woman to take on the role.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Third of eligible under-50s fail to take up cervical screening]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150253</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/third-of-eligible-under-50s-fail-to-take-up-cervical-screening/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T08:27:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of people are being urged to come forward for cervical screening as latest figures show a third of eligible under-50s did not take up the offer. Latest figures show that as of December last year, 65.8% of the 11 million eligible 25-49-year-olds took up their cervical screening invitation and were screened within the recommended
The post Third of eligible under-50s fail to take up cervical screening appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disney-inspired new care model blueprint offers GPs local five-year contracts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878896</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/disney-inspired-new-care-model-blueprint-offers-gps-local-five-year-contracts/article/1878896"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An ICB is preparing a major shift in healthcare delivery that would remove the boundary between primary and acute care and offer practices locally-negotiated five-year contracts to adopt a new care model, according to a leaked draft blueprint seen by GPonline.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plymouth virtual ward occupancy rate over 80% with plans to expand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178257</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/07/plymouth-virtual-ward-occupancy-rate-over-80-with-plans-to-expand/"/>
        <updated>2024-07-01T07:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[University Hospitals Plymouth has confirmed that its virtual ward beds are now over 80% occupied, the best occupancy rate in Devon, with plans to expand.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicines eligible for Northern Ireland MHRA Authorised Route]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T15:54:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out medicines that can be moved to Northern Ireland to meet patient need.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP continuity of care could ‘effectively disappear’ unless action taken]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150310</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gp-continuity-of-care-could-effectively-disappear-unless-action-taken/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T15:27:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP continuity of care could ‘effectively disappear’ in England unless decisive action is taken now, warn researchers who have tracked its ongoing decline. A study led by the University of Leicester looking at data from 6,010 general practices found the national average of continuity of care, as measured through patient survey data, fell from 29.3%
The post GP continuity of care could ‘effectively disappear’ unless action taken appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big questions special: What are the parties planning?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150323</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/big-questions/big-questions-special-what-are-the-parties-planning/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T14:59:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With six days to go until the general election, Pulse scrutinises the manifestos and asks what each party will do for general practice.  Conservatives: How will you fix the crisis you created? The Conservatives’ manifesto promises nothing that we haven’t heard before. It commits to modernise 150 surgeries and build 100 more. That’s all very
The post Big questions special: What are the parties planning? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Norther Ireland GPC elects new chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150322</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/northern-ireland/norther-ireland-gpc-elects-new-chair/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T14:08:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new chair of the BMA’s Northern Ireland GP committee has said she wants to ‘bring more women onto the committee’ and into leadership roles within the union. Armagh GP partner Dr Frances O’Hagan was elected to succeed Dr Alan Stout, who chaired his last meeting of the committee earlier this month after six years
The post Norther Ireland GPC elects new chair appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Bolton Hospital provides noise-cancelling headphones for patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177707</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/royal-bolton-hospital-provides-noise-cancelling-headphones-for-patients/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T12:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Bolton Hospital has introduced noise-cancelling headphones for patients with learning disabilities to help support them in loud and busy environments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transfers of care toolkit]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/transfers-of-care-toolkit.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/transfers-of-care-toolkit.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T11:53:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Professional Record Standards Body - High volumes of patients are transferred every day between health and care settings. This toolkit concentrates on the PRSB eDischarge Summary Standard, which specifies the data to be shared between secondary and primary care to support the discharge of a patient from hospitals across the UK. It does not propose a one-size-fits-all approach and recognises...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England statement on industrial action: Friday, 28 June]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248414</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-england-statement-on-industrial-action-friday-28-june/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T11:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Professor Sir Stephen Powis, NHS National Medical Director, said: “With industrial action set to cause widespread disruption this weekend, and the NHS seeing record levels of patients in recent months, we urge the public to help us by using services as they normally would. “Everyone can also help by taking steps to keep themselves and others […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How GPs plan to vote in the 2024 general election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878603</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-plan-vote-2024-general-election/article/1878603"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T11:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GPonline poll ahead of next week's general election shows there has been a sharp drop in support from GPs for the Conservative Party since 2019.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One person confirmed to have died from E. coli outbreak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150298</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/one-person-confirmed-to-have-died-from-e-coli-outbreak/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T10:28:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One person has died from the E. coli outbreak, now linked to sandwich lettuce, the UK Health Security Agency has confirmed. In an update, the UKHSA said there had been a further 19 cases associated with the outbreak of STEC O145 in the past week bringing the total to 275. Around half of those infected have
The post One person confirmed to have died from E. coli outbreak appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPC negotiators will not accept another multi-year contract deal, says chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150317</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/gpc-negotiators-will-not-accept-another-multi-year-contract-deal-says-chair/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T10:22:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA’s GP Committee England will not accept another multi-year contract deal with the Government ‘anytime now’, its chair has said. Speaking at an online roadshow yesterday evening, Dr Katie Bramall-Stainer said that the five-year pay deal – which provided a 2% year-on-year funding rise from 2019-2024 – had contributed to pay erosion for partners
The post GPC negotiators will not accept another multi-year contract deal, says chair appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movers and Shakers news roundup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178157</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/movers-and-shakers-news-roundup-49/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T10:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Movers and Shakers roundup features new chief executives for trusts in west London, Warrington and Halton, and Greater Manchester.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Increased primary care funding needed to address NHS crisis, report says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878639</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/increased-primary-care-funding-needed-address-nhs-crisis-report-says/article/1878639"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T08:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Increasing funding for primary and community care should be a key priority for the next government if it wants to reduce hospital waits, meet performance targets and build a more sustainable NHS, according to a new report.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Streeting promises urgent post-election talks to improve GP working conditions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878816</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/streeting-promises-urgent-post-election-talks-improve-gp-working-conditions/article/1878816"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow health and social care secretary Wes Streeting has said a new Labour government would look to improve GP working conditions 'as quickly as possible' if it wins the general election next week.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors break strike to assist at sites hit by cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178193</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/junior-doctors-break-strike-to-assist-at-sites-hit-by-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T07:30:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guy’s and St Thomas’ and King’s College Hospital NHS Foundation Trusts continue to experience major disruption following the  cyber attack on Synnovis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Wes Streeting on Labour’s plans for general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878824</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-wes-streeting-labours-plans-general-practice/article/1878824"/>
        <updated>2024-06-28T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Labour’s shadow health and social care secretary Wes Streeting about the party’s plans for general practice if it wins next week’s general election.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England statement on industrial action: Thursday, 27 June]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248375</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-england-statement-on-industrial-action-thursday-27-june/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T15:58:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stella Vig, NHS National Clinical Director for Elective Care, said: “With the weekend approaching, ongoing strike action will continue to cause disruption – but we want to assure patients that staff are working extremely hard to prioritise urgent and emergency care. “Though the warm weather is subsiding, the NHS still faces significant pressure, with industrial […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once in a Lifetime: Addison’s disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150199</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/diabetes-endocrinology/once-in-a-lifetime-addisons-disease/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T14:56:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Professor of Endocrinology Simon H Pearce discusses the rarely-seen condition of Addison’s disease What is it? Addison’s disease or primary adrenal insufficiency is a high-value diagnosis. Without treatment it is inevitably fatal, but when recognised most people are rapidly restored to a good quality of life with oral steroid medication. It is most commonly caused
The post Once in a Lifetime: Addison’s disease appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour pledges to review ARRS and cut GP red tape]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150288</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/labour-pledges-to-review-arrs-and-cut-gp-red-tape/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T14:45:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour has pledged to review the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) and cut GP bureaucracy if the party wins next week’s general election. Doctor leaders have called for the addition of GPs to the scheme as it gives a ‘perverse incentive’ for PCNs to hire less-qualified healthcare professionals in the place of doctors, having inadvertently
The post Labour pledges to review ARRS and cut GP red tape appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could support almost half of patients to quit antidepressants, finds trial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150274</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gps-could-support-almost-half-of-patients-to-quit-antidepressants-finds-trial/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T14:09:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could support almost half of patients taking long-term antidepressants – who are well and willing to stop – to safely come off the drugs, researchers have claimed. The study, which was looking at the addition of a phone hotline or internet support to GP review in patients discontinuing antidepressants, found more than 40% safely
The post GPs could support almost half of patients to quit antidepressants, finds trial appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP recognises achievements of members in its annual Inspire Awards]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878846</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/rcgp-recognises-achievements-members-its-annual-inspire-awards/article/1878846"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T13:31:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP has recognised members who have undertaken work that benefits patients, local communities and general practice at its annual Inspire Awards.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Partners in minority for first time in history of general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878848</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/partners-minority-first-time-history-general-practice/article/1878848"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T13:20:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP partners are now in the minority for the first time in the history of general practice, a GPonline analysis of NHS data reveals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4517 - Critical Vulnerability in Fortra FileCatalyst Workflow]]></title>
        <id>b85665f7-b58e-472f-b685-6d5c251fcb37</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4517"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T12:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 The security update addresses a critical SQL injection vulnerability that could allow an attacker to modify data and create administrative users
 The security update addresses a critical SQL injection vulnerability that could allow an attacker to modify data and create administrative users
 Updated: 27 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NICE publishes draft guidance on digital management of COPD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178127</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nice-publishes-draft-guidance-on-digital-management-of-copd/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T12:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The National Institute for Health and Care Excellence has published draft guidance on digital supported self-management of COPD.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Responding to new final draft guidance from NICE for a new gene therapy for haemophilia B]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248338</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/responding-to-new-final-draft-guidance-from-nice-for-a-new-gene-therapy-for-haemophilia-b/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T11:17:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Professor Sir Stephen Powis, NHS National Medical Director, said: “This transformative gene therapy is the first of its kind for haemophilia B patients on the NHS and has the potential to significantly improve the lives of hundreds of people by helping to reduce symptoms such as painful bleeds. “It is a one-time therapy that could […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CQC chief executive steps down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150269</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/cqc-chief-executive-steps-down/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T11:15:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The chief executive of the CQC, Ian Trenholm, is stepping down at the end of June. Deputy chief executive Kate Terroni has been appointed as interim chief executive prior to a permanent appointment being made. Mr Trenholm has held the position since July 2018. Prior to that, he was CEO at NHS Blood and Transplant.
The post CQC chief executive steps down appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS launches final call for people to get their covid jab]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248222</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-launches-final-call-for-people-to-get-their-covid-jab/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T11:12:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With just days left of this year’s spring covid vaccine programme, the NHS is urging anyone eligible to get their jab by this Sunday [30 June 2024]. More than 4 million people have now received their spring booster jab since the campaign began in April. The NHS has made it easier than ever before for […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More GP appointments in May than before pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248324</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/more-gp-appointments-in-may-than-before-pandemic/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T11:07:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP teams delivered more than 30 million appointments for patients last month (May 2024), up by more than a fifth on the same period before the pandemic.   NHS data published today shows there were around 30.5 million appointments delivered by GPs and their teams in just one month, compared with an estimated 25.3 million in […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We need to talk about the GP partners who game the system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150265</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/we-need-to-talk-about-the-gp-partners-who-game-the-system/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T10:35:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Jaimie Kaffash argues that the 1% of partners who are cutting corners are making life harder for the 99% who aren’t  I can just imagine the conversations between GPC England and health ministers. ‘GP practices desperately need funding. We can’t afford to hire GPs.’ ‘No more funding. More than 2,000 partners earn more than
The post We need to talk about the GP partners who game the system appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some partners ‘substituting’ GPs with PAs to save money, leaders claim]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150184</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/some-partners-substituting-gps-with-pas-to-save-money-leaders-claim/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T10:31:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive There are concerns that some GP partners are making ‘wrong’ and potentially unfair use of the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS), Pulse has been told. A number of influential GPs told Pulse that some partners are ‘substituting’ GPs with less qualified staff, using the ARRS ‘to save money’. They said that some practices have
The post Some partners ‘substituting’ GPs with PAs to save money, leaders claim appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177867</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-149/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T10:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This morning's edition of Coffee Time Briefing includes a milestone for BSI, and an award for UK-based radiology solution provider Behold.ai.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE seeking provider to support cyber resilience in NHS supply chain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178093</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhse-seeking-provider-to-support-cyber-resilience-in-nhs-supply-chain/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T10:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England is letting a contract worth £4.3m to “enhance cyber risk visibility, assurance and resilience” throughout the NHS supply chain.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour will review ARRS to end 'absurd' GP unemployment crisis, says Streeting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878744</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/labour-will-review-arrs-end-absurd-gp-unemployment-crisis-says-streeting/article/1878744"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T07:56:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rules that prevent additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) cash being used to hire GPs have become a 'perverse set of handcuffs' and will be reviewed if Labour wins the general election, shadow health and social care secretary Wes Streeting has told GPonline.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health issues call for Rewired 2025 speakers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178037</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-issues-call-for-rewired-2025-speakers/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-27T07:30:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health is on the hunt for speakers to present at Rewired 2025, which takes place at the NEC in Birmingham on 18 and 19 March.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lib Dems demand 'emergency NHS budget' to hire more GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878697</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/lib-dems-demand-emergency-nhs-budget-hire-gps/article/1878697"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Liberal Democrats have called for an emergency NHS budget within four weeks of the general election to hire more GPs and invest in hospitals and social care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors begin 11th round of strikes in run-up to general election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878707</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/junior-doctors-begin-11th-round-strikes-run-up-general-election/article/1878707"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T16:16:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors have begun an 11th wave of strike action in England after the government failed to meet BMA demands for a commitment to restore pay.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Views of NHS website heat health advice double as temperatures soar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248213</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/views-of-nhs-website-heat-health-advice-double-as-temperatures-soar/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T16:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visits to heat exhaustion advice on the NHS website have more than doubled in the past 48 hours as temperatures surge in England. The warm weather comes at the same time as the NHS is facing major disruption with junior doctors launching industrial action from 7am tomorrow for five days. (7am Thursday 27 June until […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revealed: NHS England’s plans to replace traditional GP referrals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150010</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/referrals/revealed-nhs-englands-plans-to-replace-traditional-gp-referrals/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T15:52:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive An NHS England document has confirmed that that it wants to ‘optimise’ GP referrals to secondary care via an enhanced model of advice and guidance. GP leaders recently raised concerns that NHS England had encouraged ICBs to adopt the ‘advice and refer’ model, effectively replacing traditional GP referrals and adding barriers for patients in
The post Revealed: NHS England’s plans to replace traditional GP referrals appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a thin line between PAs and AI physio]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150200</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/its-a-thin-line-between-pas-and-ai-physio/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T15:06:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Copperfield on the connection between the rolling out of physician associates and the movement towards AI in healthcare, asking where GPs sit in all of this My, how we laughed when we discovered that the next big idea is AI physiotherapy. In my patch, this most hands-on of specialties has already been reduced to
The post It’s a thin line between PAs and AI physio appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Pharmacy First IT to ‘simplify’ referrals from GPs being rolled out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150226</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/referrals/new-pharmacy-first-it-to-simplify-referrals-from-gps-being-rolled-out/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T14:10:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new IT functionality to ‘simplify’ referrals from GP practices to community pharmacies is currently being rolled out, NHS England has said. IT system suppliers have started rolling out a new feature allowing Pharmacy First referrals from practices using EMIS Web Local Services or PharmRefer to go into the workflows in pharmacy clinical systems. GP
The post New Pharmacy First IT to ‘simplify’ referrals from GPs being rolled out appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4516 - Progress Software Releases Critical Security Updates for MOVEit Transfer]]></title>
        <id>b7626186-9d1c-49d3-900c-8c6412d703bf</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4516"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T13:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Improper authentication vulnerability can lead to authentication bypass
 Improper authentication vulnerability can lead to authentication bypass
 Updated: 26 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Health Lewisham helps develop AI training resources for COPD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177839</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/one-health-lewisham-helps-develop-ai-training-resources/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T12:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One Health Lewisham is working with TidalSense to develop training resources for an AI-powered device to diagnose respiratory illness.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA to explore GMC ‘fee withdrawal’ if PA regulation concerns not addressed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150194</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/bma-to-explore-gmc-fee-withdrawal-if-pa-regulation-concerns-not-addressed/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T10:31:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA will explore potential ‘fee withdrawal’ from the GMC if it fails to address concerns around the regulation of physician associates (PAs).  Yesterday, at the union’s Annual Representative Meeting (ARM) in Belfast, delegates passed a motion which called for a ‘plan for fee withdrawal’, as well as a ‘new regulator’ which would ‘take over’
The post BMA to explore GMC ‘fee withdrawal’ if PA regulation concerns not addressed appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs want new Government to focus on GP recruitment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149440</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gps-want-new-government-to-focus-on-gp-recruitment/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T10:06:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive More recruitment of GPs is the highest priority for the next Government – according to GPs. Out of around 400 GPs responding to Pulse publisher Cogora’s State of Primary Care survey, 61% ranked this as a top priority (on a 1-5 scale from ‘low priority’ to ‘high priority’). The issue of GP recruitment was
The post GPs want new Government to focus on GP recruitment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lancashire and South Cumbria NHS FT to launch AI-driven patient portal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177831</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/lancashire-and-south-cumbria-nhs-ft-to-launch-ai-driven-patient-portal/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T10:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mental health trust Lancashire and South Cumbria NHS FT has announced plans to roll out an AI-powered patient portal to deliver two-way conversations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former RCGP chair to become New Zealand chief medical officer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878561</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/former-rcgp-chair-become-new-zealand-chief-medical-officer/article/1878561"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T08:53:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former RCGP chair Professor Dame Helen Stokes-Lampard has been appointed as New Zealand's chief medical officer.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General practice has been 'broken' by underfunding, doctors warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878442</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-practice-broken-underfunding-doctors-warn/article/1878442"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T08:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice has been 'deliberately broken' by persistent underfunding that has left the profession without the resources it needs to deliver continuity of care, doctors have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health partners with AphA for AI and Data 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=178009</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-partners-with-apha-for-ai-and-data-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T07:30:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health has joined forces with AphA for AI and Data 2024, where the Data and Research Stage will transition into the AphA annual conference.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Party manifestos 'too focused on reform', say Rebuild GP campaigners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877722</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/party-manifestos-too-focused-reform-say-rebuild-gp-campaigners/article/1877722"/>
        <updated>2024-06-26T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manifesto commitments on general practice from the main political parties are too focused on reform and offer little on retaining the existing workforce or ending underfunding, GPs have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS faces fresh strike disruption amid heat health warnings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248102</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-faces-fresh-strike-disruption-amid-heat-health-warnings/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T23:01:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS will face major disruption this week as junior doctors launch five days of industrial action, with services already under increasing pressure, England’s top doctor has warned today. With Yellow Heat Health Alerts for many parts of the country, the NHS is urging the public to use services as they normally would if they […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour promises 'investment and reform' to bring back family doctor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878497</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/labour-promises-investment-reform-bring-back-family-doctor/article/1878497"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T21:31:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Labour Party has said it will provide the 'investment and reform needed' to help patients get a GP appointment with the doctor of their choice and 'bring back the family doctor' if it wins the general election.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour promises to deliver 'investment and reform' to bring back family doctor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878497</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/labour-promises-deliver-investment-reform-bring-back-family-doctor/article/1878497"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T21:31:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Labour Party has said it will provide the 'investment and reform needed' to help patients get a GP appointment with the doctor of their choice and 'bring back the family doctor' if it wins the general election.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 1.8 billion adults at risk of disease from not doing enough physical activity]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:d4ac19b0-87cc-4cc0-9750-d3de02a55878</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/26-06-2024-nearly-1.8-billion-adults-at-risk-of-disease-from-not-doing-enough-physical-activity"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T16:32:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New data show that nearly one third (31%) of adults worldwide, approximately 1.8 billion people, did not meet the recommended levels of physical activity in 2022. The findings point to a worrying trend of physical inactivity among adults, which has increased by about 5 percentage points between 2010 and 2022. 
If the trend continues, levels of inactivity are projected to further rise to 35% by 2030, and the world is currently off track from meeting the global target to reduce physical inactivity by 2030. The World Health Organization (WHO) recommends that adults have 150 minutes of moderate-intensity, or 75 minutes of vigorous-intensity physical activity, or equivalent, per week. Physical inactivity puts adults at greater risk of cardiovascular diseases such as heart attacks and strokes, t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behind the headlines: Admin staff outnumber GPs – but so what?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150108</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/behind-the-headlines/behind-the-headlines-admin-staff-outnumber-gps-but-so-what/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T15:22:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse scrutinises an article in the Daily Mail claiming that receptionists outnumber GPs at over 90% of surgeries. Maya Dhillon looks behind the numbers to uncover what is actually going on, and who or what is to blame. A recent Daily Mail article has released a ‘shock analysis’ claiming that receptionists vastly outnumber GPs in
The post Behind the headlines: Admin staff outnumber GPs – but so what? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former RCGP chair quits NHSE to become New Zealand CMO]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150175</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/former-rcgp-chair-quits-nhse-to-become-new-zealand-cmo/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T14:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former RCGP chair Professor Dame Helen Stokes-Lampard has been appointed as New Zealand’s national chief medical officer (CMO).  The appointment, effective from October, means she will step down from her role as the only GP on NHS England’s board at the end of September. Professor Stokes-Lampard, who was RCGP chair from 2016 to 2019, has
The post Former RCGP chair quits NHSE to become New Zealand CMO appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4515 - Avaya Releases Critical Security Update for IP Office]]></title>
        <id>9699ac3d-7ffc-44d6-b877-e1b5c6d92a04</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4515"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T12:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Two critical vulnerabilities could lead to remote code execution
 Two critical vulnerabilities could lead to remote code execution
 Updated: 25 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Royal Oldham Hospital goes live with digital image tech for biopsies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177785</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/the-royal-oldham-hospital-goes-live-with-digital-image-tech-for-biopsies/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T12:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Royal Oldham Hospital is the first pathology lab in Manchester to use digital images for biopsies, with the aim of speeding up test results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practices decide how many GPs they employ, says minister]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150165</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/practices-decide-how-many-gps-they-employ-says-minister/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T12:23:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has argued that it ‘does not decide how many GPs are in each practice’, in response to GP employment concerns.  Health minister Maria Caulfield said GP practices are given a contract and they ‘then decide who they directly employ’. Ms Caulfield was asked what the Government is doing to address GP unemployment during
The post Practices decide how many GPs they employ, says minister appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 3 million annual deaths due to alcohol and drug use, majority among men]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:8a048cb1-e291-4add-b2e7-d84157ec171c</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/25-06-2024-over-3-million-annual-deaths-due-to-alcohol-and-drug-use-majority-among-men"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T11:37:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new report from the World Health Organization (WHO) highlights that 2.6 million deaths per year were attributable to alcohol consumption, accounting for 4.7% of all deaths in that year, and 0.6 million deaths –to psychoactive drug use. Notably, 2 million of alcohol- and 0.4 million of drug-attributable deaths were among men.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177641</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-148/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T10:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's coffee briefing includes a report into the connected health revolution and tighter cybersecurity at Betsi Cadwaladr University Health Board.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Route 2 pathway: from healthcare support worker to registered nurse]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/route-2-pathway-from-healthcare-support-worker-to-registered-nurse-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/route-2-pathway-from-healthcare-support-worker-to-registered-nurse-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T10:16:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - University Hospital Dorset NHS Trust developed the Route 2 pathway for existing internationally educated nurses (IENs) in health care support worker (HCSW) roles, helping them to take part in a fast-tracked Objective Structured Clinical Examination (OSCE) course to support them with becoming a registered nurse here in the UK. Case study]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving our nation’s health: a whole-of-government approach to tackling the causes of long-term sickness and economic inactivity]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/improving-our-nations-health-a-whole-of-government-approach-to-tackling-the-causes-of-long-term-sick.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/improving-our-nations-health-a-whole-of-government-approach-to-tackling-the-causes-of-long-term-sick.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T10:09:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - The UK faces a series of complex health challenges, exemplified by the recent sharp rise in the number of people out of the workforce due to long-term sickness. This has significant impacts on individuals’ wellbeing, as well as large fiscal and economic costs. Tackling complex challenges such as this requires a fresh approach. This interim report, developed...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Intelligence analyses PACS and RIS market changes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177859</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-intelligence-analyses-pacs-and-ris-market-changes/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T10:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Intelligence's latest report shows that Sectra has become the leading PACS supplier for NHS trusts in England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Receiving the new medical certificate of cause of death (MCCD)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/guidance/receiving-the-new-medical-certificate-of-cause-of-death-mccd</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/receiving-the-new-medical-certificate-of-cause-of-death-mccd"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to get the new MCCD if your organisation uses the current MCCD.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: New MCCD: check that your organisation is on the distribution list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/new-mccd-check-that-your-organisation-is-on-the-distribution-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/new-mccd-check-that-your-organisation-is-on-the-distribution-list"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Current list of organisations that will receive the new medical certificate of cause of death (MCCD), which must be used from 9 September 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real patient data was leaked by cyber criminals, NHS England confirms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150148</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/technology/real-patient-data-was-leaked-by-cyber-criminals-nhs-england-confirms/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T09:17:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A laboratory company hit by a cyber attack earlier this month has confirmed that patient data were published by the cyber criminals, NHS England said. Last week, a cyber crime group – Qilin – published data which they claimed belonged to NHS patients, but NHS England and the company said an investigation was required to
The post Real patient data was leaked by cyber criminals, NHS England confirms appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CPD: Key questions on hyperlipidaemia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149847</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/cpd-key-questions-on-hyperlipidaemia-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T09:04:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP cardiology specialist Professor Ahmet Fuat outlines principles and best practice in diagnosing and managing hyperlipidaemia in primary care Learning objectives: 1. Should all patients with apparent hyperlipidaemia have further blood tests to rule out an underlying cause such as diabetes or hypothyroidism? Yes, it is generally recommended that patients with apparent hyperlipidaemia undergo further
The post CPD: Key questions on hyperlipidaemia appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA to investigate heckling of Jewish doctor at annual conference]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878376</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-investigate-heckling-jewish-doctor-annual-conference/article/1878376"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T08:57:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA is carrying out an investigation after a Jewish doctor was heckled during her speech at the association's annual representative meeting.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pilot PCNs to receive 10% funding uplift to expand GP clinical capacity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150128</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/pilot-pcns-to-receive-10-funding-uplift-to-expand-gp-clinical-capacity/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T08:57:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PCNs taking part in a new pilot scheme will receive a 10% funding uplift for more GP clinical staff to ‘accelerate’ delivery of the long-term workforce plan. The scheme is designed to ‘test’ whether implementing the plan, along with other digital tools such as process automation, can plug gaps in general practice capacity. Between 15
The post Pilot PCNs to receive 10% funding uplift to expand GP clinical capacity appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PCNs offered seven-figure sums to pilot controversial new GP models]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878274</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/pcns-offered-seven-figure-sums-pilot-controversial-new-gp-models/article/1878274"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Up to 20 'test sites' across England will be offered seven-figure sums to trial controversial new models of general practice, GPonline can reveal.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyber attacks on critical national infrastructure predicted to increase]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177683</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/cyber-attacks-on-critical-national-infrastructure-to-increase-warns-ciso-for-wales/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-25T07:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mark Edwards, CISO at Digital Health and Care Wales has warned that cyber attacks on critical national infrastructure are likely to increase.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP employment crisis ‘simply bonkers’, says BMA council chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150132</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gp-employment-crisis-simply-bonkers-says-bma-council-chair/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T16:02:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs ‘turning to other jobs to earn a living’ while practices cannot meet demand is ‘simply bonkers’, the BMA council chair has said. In his opening speech at the union’s Annual Representative Meeting (ARM) in Belfast this morning, Professor Phil Banfield said that ‘now is the time’ to bring ‘the full force’ of the BMA
The post GP employment crisis ‘simply bonkers’, says BMA council chair appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synnovis cyber attack – statement from NHS England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248059</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/synnovis-cyber-attack-statement-from-nhs-england-24-june/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T15:58:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England continues to work with Synnovis and the National Crime Agency to respond to the criminal ransomware attack on Synnovis systems. Synnovis has now confirmed through an initial analysis that the data published by a cyber crime group has been stolen from some of their systems. We understand people may be concerned by this, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patience and planning – the next Government must think long-term]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149629</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/zoe-rog/patience-and-planning-the-next-government-must-think-long-term/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T15:02:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Zoe Rog looks back on the health campaigns that inspired change, and laments politicians’ focus on quick solutions Early in my GP career, an incentive was funded to provide free baskets of fruit in our practice for patients to help themselves. This was accompanied by vouchers for subsidies on fruit and vegetables in local
The post Patience and planning – the next Government must think long-term appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices to vaccinate 2m over-75s against RSV from this year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878312</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-vaccinate-2m-over-75s-against-rsv-year/article/1878312"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T14:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices will be asked to deliver an RSV vaccination campaign to adults aged over 75 from September this year, the DHSC has confirmed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to deliver first RSV vaccination programme from 1 September]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150116</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/gps-to-deliver-first-rsv-vaccination-programme-from-1-september/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T14:04:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been asked to vaccinate older adults against respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) as part of essential contractual services this Autumn. From 1 September, the new RSV vaccination programme will be included as an essential service under the GP contract, the Department of Health and Social Care said, with contracting details due to follow from
The post GPs to deliver first RSV vaccination programme from 1 September appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4514 - Juniper Networks Releases Security Update for Juniper Secure Analytics]]></title>
        <id>d925b076-6869-45b3-83ef-021f7a24d378</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4514"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T12:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 The update addresses 225 vulnerabilities in Juniper Secure Analytics, including five rated critical
 The update addresses 225 vulnerabilities in Juniper Secure Analytics, including five rated critical
 Updated: 24 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaked NHSE review warns of ‘severe shortage’ of digital nurses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177673</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/leaked-nhse-review-warns-of-severe-shortage-of-digital-nurses/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T12:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A leaked copy of the unpublished Phillips Ives Report, seen by Nursing Times, warns of a 'severe shortage' of digital nurses to support NHSE ambitions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of appointments postponed since Synnovis cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177803</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/thousands-of-appointments-postponed-since-synnovis-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T10:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 1,134 elective procedures and 2,194 outpatient appointments have been postponed since the cyber attack on Synnovis on 3 June.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI physiotherapy clinic to roll out on NHS this year, makers say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150052</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/musculoskeletal-rheumatology-sports-medicine/ai-physiotherapy-clinic-to-roll-out-on-nhs-this-year-makers-say/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T09:51:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The makers of an AI-physiotherapy clinic said the app will be rolled out in the NHS this year to cut waiting lists. It was trialled in series of three-month pilot studies between May and December 2023 among more than 1,000 NHS staff with back pain self-referred to the ‘AI-powered clinic’ developed by Flok. NHS Lothian,
The post AI physiotherapy clinic to roll out on NHS this year, makers say appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK children shorter, more obese and less healthy than 20 years ago]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150054</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/uk-children-shorter-more-obese-and-less-healthy-than-20-years-ago/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T09:44:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A steady decline in children’s health over the past two decades in the UK means they are now shorter and more likely to have obesity and type 2 diabetes. A report from the Food Foundation found the height of five-year olds has been falling since 2013, with UK children now shorter than those in nearly
The post UK children shorter, more obese and less healthy than 20 years ago appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA to take legal action against GMC over PA regulation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150093</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/bma-to-take-legal-action-against-gmc-over-pa-regulation/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T09:21:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has announced it is taking legal action against the GMC over the way in which it plans to regulate physician associates (PAs). The union said that the plans will mean ‘dangerous blurring of lines’ for patients between ‘highly-skilled and experienced’ doctors and assistant roles. It also added that the GMC has been using
The post BMA to take legal action against GMC over PA regulation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA takes legal action against GMC over 'blurring lines' between doctors and PAs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878214</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-takes-legal-action-against-gmc-blurring-lines-doctors-pas/article/1878214"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T08:56:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has launched legal action against the GMC over its plans to regulate physician associates, warning it risks a 'dangerous blurring of lines' between doctors and non-doctors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP appointments cap will underpin collective action in general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878118</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-appointments-cap-will-underpin-collective-action-general-practice/article/1878118"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T08:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adopting safe working advice - including a cap on appointments GPs deliver each day - will be the mainstay of collective action practices will take from 1 August, the BMA has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Derby and Burton rolls out BadgerNet EPR for maternity services]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177671</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/derby-and-burton-rolls-out-badger-notes-system-for-maternity-services/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-24T07:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[University Hospitals of Derby and Burton NHS Foundation Trust has rolled out the BadgerNet electronic patient record in its maternity services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS urges more women to take up cervical screening invitations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247993</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-urges-more-women-to-take-up-cervical-screening-invitations/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T23:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of women are being urged to come forward for cervical screening as figures show a third of eligible under 50s didn’t take up the potentially lifesaving offer. The latest figures show that as of December last year, 65.8% of the 11 million eligible women aged 25-49 took up their cervical screening invitation and were screened within […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chair announced for PrimaryCareLearnings 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876967</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/chair-announced-primarycarelearnings-2024/article/1876967"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T16:09:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join Dr James Waldron, GP Educator  and Portfolio GP for this free, face-to-face, educational meeting in September]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Child death overview panels: contacts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T15:26:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Contact details of the people in child death overview panels (CDOPs) who are responsible for receiving child death notifications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic referral system switched off after ‘continuing’ IT issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150056</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/electronic-referral-system-switched-off-after-continuing-it-issues/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:59:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An electronic referral system has been turned off for SystmOne practices in Essex after it kept crashing practice computers putting clinical data at risk. The Local Medical Committee said they had campaigned for TPP’s iRefer system to be switched off completely after months of problems with no solution in sight. In a letter to practices,
The post Electronic referral system switched off after ‘continuing’ IT issues appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synnovis cyber attack – statement from NHS England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=248025</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/synnovis-cyber-attack-statement-from-nhs-england/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:54:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 3 June, Synnovis, a pathology laboratory which processes blood tests on behalf of a number of NHS organisations, primarily in South East London, was the victim of a cyber attack. NHS England has been made aware that a cyber criminal group published data last night which they are claiming belongs to Synnovis and was […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice forced to close after car crashed into its building]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150070</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/premises/gp-practice-forced-to-close-after-car-crashed-into-its-building/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:53:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP practice in Hereford had to close and cancel appointments after a car crashed into the front of its building. West Mercia Police told Pulse that the force was called to a report of a car that ‘had collided’ with the surgery building on Eastholme Avenue in Belmont around 10.30am yesterday (20 June). Belmont
The post GP practice forced to close after car crashed into its building appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why our high-performing practice in a deprived area had to close]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149952</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/the-very-last-resort-handing-back-our-contract/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:23:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, the East Barnwell Health Centre in Cambridge announced it was handing back its GMS contract after years of financial struggles. Here, the partners share their story with Pulse. Last week we – the partners at East Barnwell Health Centre – announced we were handing back our GMS contract. It was a devastating decision
The post Why our high-performing practice in a deprived area had to close appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What health and care need from the next government: #4 – improving access to treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/what-health-and-care-need-from-the-next-government-4-improving-access-to-treatment.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/what-health-and-care-need-from-the-next-government-4-improving-access-to-treatment.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T14:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - The fourth briefing in this series looks at waiting times for health care – the biggest cause for public dissatisfaction with the NHS and a central battleground of this election. It suggests seven tests that must be met which should be put to politicians as they battle to convince the public they have the answers. Briefing Nuffield...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Draft joint UK asthma guidance promises major changes to practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1878082</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/draft-joint-uk-asthma-guidance-promises-major-changes-practice/article/1878082"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T12:51:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Draft NICE/BTS/SIGN advice on asthma backs changes to prescribing and use of diagnostic tests that are likely to have a major impact on clinicians.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patient data published online following south east London cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177763</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/patient-data-published-online-following-south-east-london-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T12:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyber criminals have published patient data online which they claim was stolen as part of an attack on Synnovis, NHS England has confirmed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP concern as cyber criminals publish alleged NHS patient data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150045</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gp-concern-as-cyber-criminals-publish-alleged-nhs-patient-data/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T11:15:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The perpetrators of a recent cyber-attack on a pathology laboratory have published data which they claim belongs to NHS patients. NHS England is investigating this as a ‘matter of extreme urgency’ to determine the content of the files and establish whether NHS patients have been affected. GP practices in London continue to be impacted by
The post GP concern as cyber criminals publish alleged NHS patient data appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accelerating transformation: how to develop effective NHS-industry partnerships]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/accelerating-transformation-how-to-develop-effective-nhs-industry-partnerships.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/accelerating-transformation-how-to-develop-effective-nhs-industry-partnerships.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T11:13:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - This guidance aims to understand and unblock the barriers to making the potential of partnership a reality – exploring issues such as culture, trust and the challenge of stepping outside health system operational norms. It seeks to support the NHS and industry to develop, contract, implement, measure and deliver effective partnerships. It was jointly developed by the...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How likely is a general election to transform health and social care?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-likely-is-a-general-election-to-transform-health-and-social-care.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-likely-is-a-general-election-to-transform-health-and-social-care.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T10:50:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The King's Fund - Nicholas Timmins looks back at the last three big political transitions to ask - how fast might things change for health and social care? Long read The King's Fund - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[West Hertfordshire Teaching rolls out OptiRad radiology tech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177699</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/west-hertfordshire-teaching-rolls-out-optirad-radiology-tech/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T10:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[West Hertfordshire Teaching Hospital NHS Trust has rolled out Hexarad technology which aims to boost the performance of its radiology departments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitor social media for abusive patients, LMCs advises GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149838</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/special-investigations/gp-abuse/monitor-social-media-for-abusive-patients-lmcs-advises-gps/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T10:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[London GP leaders have urged practices to be ‘proactive’ in monitoring threats of patient abuse, including via social media and the design of their premises. They warned that a ‘failure to pro-actively engage’ with patients on social media ‘risks damage to the practice’s local reputation’ which could lead to more frustrated patients. In a new
The post Monitor social media for abusive patients, LMCs advises GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visits To NHS Website’s Hay Fever Page More Than Double]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247991</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/visits-to-nhs-websites-hay-fever-page-more-than-double/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T09:14:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The number of hay fever sufferers searching for NHS advice has more than doubled in the past week as temperatures rise across England. The NHS website has received an average of 11,736 visits a day since Monday compared to a daily average of 4,749 visits at the weekend – an increase of 147%. Visits to […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fifth of partners employing physician associates say they can't afford GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877934</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/fifth-partners-employing-physician-associates-say-cant-afford-gps/article/1877934"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T08:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One in five GP partners who have worked with physician associates (PAs) say they did so because they couldn't afford to recruit GPs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health’s monthly roundup of contracts and go lives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177667</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-healths-monthly-roundup-of-contracts-and-go-lives-41/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T07:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This roundup features new standard infusion pump software at Alder Hey Children’s Hospital and a new EPR for Kent Community Health’s sexual health service.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Rebuild General Practice on how politicians can end the GP crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877687</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-rebuild-general-practice-politicians-end-gp-crisis/article/1877687"/>
        <updated>2024-06-21T07:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Nottinghamshire GP Dr Carter Singh from the Rebuild General Practice campaign about how to solve the GP crisis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 80% of GP locums ‘cannot find work’, BMA survey finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150014</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/more-than-80-of-gp-locums-cannot-find-work-bma-survey-finds/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 80% of GP locums have reported that they ‘cannot find work’, a BMA survey has revealed. A survey of 1,852 locum GPs in England found that that four out of five (84%) are struggling to find work and that more than 50% are ‘expecting to make changes’ to their careers ‘in the next
The post More than 80% of GP locums ‘cannot find work’, BMA survey finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP careers derailed as four in five locums can't find work, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877937</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-careers-derailed-four-five-locums-cant-find-work-bma-warns/article/1877937"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than four in five locum GPs in England are unable to find work or struggling to find enough, according to BMA polling that sheds new light on the impact of underfunding in general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP careers derailed as most locums can't find work, BMA poll shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877937</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-careers-derailed-locums-cant-find-work-bma-poll-shows/article/1877937"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than four in five locum GPs in England are unable to find work or struggling to find enough, according to BMA polling that sheds new light on the impact of underfunding in general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP career plans derailed as most locums can't find work, BMA poll shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877937</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-career-plans-derailed-locums-cant-find-work-bma-poll-shows/article/1877937"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than four in five locum GPs in England are unable to find work or struggling to find enough, according to BMA polling that sheds new light on the impact of underfunding in general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-awaited joint asthma guidance overhauls diagnostics and treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=150012</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/long-awaited-joint-asthma-guidance-overhauls-diagnostics-and-treatment/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T16:02:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Long-awaited new draft UK joint guidelines on asthma care overhauls recommended diagnostics and treatment, but the review committee warned they will require ‘significant investment’. Draft NICE/BTS/SIGN guidelines on diagnosis, monitoring and management of asthma recommends significant changes to current treatment approaches, including replacing the use of short-acting beta agonist (SABA) alone with combined inhaled corticosteroid
The post Long-awaited joint asthma guidance overhauls diagnostics and treatment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS delivers 4 million spring covid vaccines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247986</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-delivers-4-million-spring-covid-vaccines/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T15:39:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 4 million people have now received their spring covid booster from the NHS just 10 weeks after bookings officially opened as part of the latest vaccination campaign. Around 7 million people are eligible for a spring covid jab this year, including those aged 75 and over, those with a weakened immune system and older […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Under the radar: Cauda equina syndrome case]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149829</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/musculoskeletal-rheumatology-sports-medicine/under-the-radar-cauda-equina-syndrome-case/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T15:33:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the first of a new series into diagnoses that could easily be missed, Dr Sharon Viner recalls when she spotted a care of cauda equina Clinical history A 30-year-old man was seen by the musculoskeletal team for acute on chronic low back pain radiating down his right leg to his foot. The back pain
The post Under the radar: Cauda equina syndrome case appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redirect ARRS and Pharmacy First funding to core GP, says DAUK manifesto]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149992</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/redirect-arrs-and-pharmacy-first-funding-to-core-gp-says-dauk-manifesto/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T14:41:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next Government should reallocate ARRS and Pharmacy First money to restore GP core funding, the Doctors’ Association UK has recommended in its election manifesto. The DAUK’s GP committee issued a 10-point manifesto to ‘relieve the pressure on general practice’, which was presented to prospective MPs during a webinar yesterday. It said that the next
The post Redirect ARRS and Pharmacy First funding to core GP, says DAUK manifesto appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse needs you: write for our new series]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149987</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/special/opinion/pulse-needs-you-write-for-our-new-series/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T14:15:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse is looking for your contributions! We have three new series to support and inform GPs, and we are looking for case studies and suggestions from readers.  The communication breakdown service A brand new column where readers can write in with real-life communication issues they have had at work. Anything from ‘I have an angry
The post Pulse needs you: write for our new series appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO issues warning on falsified medicines used for diabetes treatment and weight loss]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5a193851-d89b-4005-8476-84da5508f2c0</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/20-06-2024-who-issues-warning-on-falsified-medicines-used-for-diabetes-treatment-and-weight-loss"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T12:46:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) issued a medical product alert on falsified semaglutides, the type of medicines that are used for treatment of type 2 diabetes and obesity in some countries.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do the last five years measure up on levelling up?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-do-the-last-five-years-measure-up-on-levelling-up.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-do-the-last-five-years-measure-up-on-levelling-up.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T12:31:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Fiscal Studies - Five years ago, then Prime Minister Boris Johnson made ‘levelling up’ a central plank of the Conservative Party’s bid for re-election, with a manifesto pledge to ‘level up every part of the UK’. In 2022, the government published a thorough and ambitious White Paper setting out 12 levelling up ‘missions’ to achieve by 2030, as...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MHRA issues transparency guidance for machine learning medical devices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177609</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/mhra-issues-transparency-guidance-for-machine-learning-medical-devices/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T12:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) has published guidance on transparency for machine learning medical devices.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS App after the pandemic]]></title>
        <id>e1a8f60e-a136-47af-87f2-816581178f62</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/transformation-blog/2023/the-nhs-app-after-the-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T12:04:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Susie Day, Programme Director for the NHS App, looks at what’s changed since the app’s launch in January 2019 and how its services are evolving post-COVID.


NHS 75 is an incredibly proud moment for me and, I hope, for all the people who work so hard across the NHS and its wider ecosystem to provide care for patients up and down the country.


In the lead up to the NHS 75 celebrations, I have reflected on what has changed since NHS 70 and, particularly, about the evolution of the NHS App since its launch at the beginning of 2019.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How much funding does the NHS need over the next decade?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-much-funding-does-the-nhs-need-over-the-next-decade.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-much-funding-does-the-nhs-need-over-the-next-decade.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T11:08:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This long read projects a potential £38bn shortfall in the funding needed to improve the NHS by the end of the next parliament. With the pledges made by both the main political parties so far falling a long way short of this, the analysis raises questions about the trade-offs facing the next government in balancing the...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177359</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-147/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Digital Health's coffee time briefing includes a sustainability win for Swansea Bay University Health Board with a digital app.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177359</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-200624/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Digital Health's coffee time briefing includes a sustainability win for Swansea Bay University Health Board with a digital app.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP demands halt to recruitment of physician associates amid safety fears]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877810</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/rcgp-demands-halt-recruitment-physician-associates-amid-safety-fears/article/1877810"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:08:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP has called for an immediate halt to recruitment of physician associates (PAs) in general practice after a consultation found half of GPs were aware of 'specific examples' in which work by these staff had compromised patient safety.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCP president to step down over physician associate fallout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149964</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/rcp-president-to-step-down-over-physician-associate-fallout/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:08:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The president of the Royal College of Physicians (RCP) will step down following pressure from senior college officers and fellows over the college’s handling of the physician associate (PA) debate. Yesterday Dr Sarah Clarke informed the RCP Council of her intention to ‘step aside’ from the role of president ‘following a challenging time for the
The post RCP president to step down over physician associate fallout appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking: RCGP advises GP practices to halt PA recruitment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149965</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/breaking-rcgp-advises-gp-practices-to-halt-pa-recruitment/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP has urged GP practices across the UK to ‘halt’ recruitment of physician associates (PAs) until the profession is regulated later this year. This recommendation is based on ‘concerning findings’ from the RCGP’s recent consultation, which surveyed over 5,000 GPs and found that over 80% believe the use of PAs in general practices has
The post Breaking: RCGP advises GP practices to halt PA recruitment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ascom signs contract with Children’s Health Ireland to implement ANMS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177581</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/ascom-signs-contract-with-childrens-health-ireland-to-implement-anms/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T10:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ascom is to implement its Alerts and Notification Management System at the new Dublin children’s hospital as part of a deal with Children’s Health Ireland.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors offer government last chance to avert this month's strikes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877777</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/junior-doctors-offer-government-last-chance-avert-months-strikes/article/1877777"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T08:55:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Junior doctors have written to prime minister Rishi Sunak offering him a final chance to make an improved offer on pay to avert their next five-day strike that starts on 27 June.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atos denies that financial issues could have ‘severe’ effects on NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177561</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/atos-denies-that-financial-issues-could-have-severe-effects-on-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T07:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French IT giant Atos has denied reports that it is facing financial issues that could severely impact the NHS and other public services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better-paid APMS provider to pilot new care model after partners hand back contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877656</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/better-paid-apms-provider-pilot-new-care-model-partners-hand-back-contract/article/1877656"/>
        <updated>2024-06-20T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A popular practice forced out of business by underfunding will be replaced by a better-paid APMS provider piloting an untested new model of care, in a move GP leaders say raises 'grave concerns' for the future of general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS faces £38bn annual funding shortfall by end of next parliament]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877683</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-faces-38bn-annual-funding-shortfall-end-next-parliament/article/1877683"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS funding could fall £38bn short of the level needed to meet rising demand and deliver key improvements over the next parliament, policy experts have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PAs aren’t the enemy – this is a systemic issue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149959</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/pas-arent-the-enemy-this-is-a-systemic-issue/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T16:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Jaimie Kaffash argues that the toxicity of the debate around physician associates is detracting from the structural problems I’ve always believed that ‘punching down’ is reprehensible. And the whole debate around physician associates does make me feel uncomfortable. I say this having run a seven-part analysis and investigation into the role of physician associates
The post PAs aren’t the enemy – this is a systemic issue appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP fury as Creon shortages leave patient at risk of hospitalisation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149513</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gp-fury-as-creon-shortages-leave-patient-at-risk-of-hospitalisation/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T15:13:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP in Sheffield has told Pulse of her fury at ongoing drug shortages, after a vulnerable patient was left at risk of hospitalisation because no supplies of Creon (pancreatin) could be sourced. Dr Sarah Jones, a GP partner at the Norwood Medical Centre, said they a patient with learning disabilities who lives in a
The post GP fury as Creon shortages leave patient at risk of hospitalisation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP concerns around PAs need to be ‘seriously addressed’, says Streeting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149892</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gp-concerns-around-pas-need-to-be-seriously-addressed-says-streeting/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T14:12:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP concerns around the role of physician associates (PAs) need to be ‘seriously’ addressed, according to the shadow health secretary. However, PAs do ‘have a role to play’ in primary care, and should not be ‘thrown out with the bathwater, Wes Streeting added. Speaking at a Medical Journalists’ Association (MJA) event on Monday evening, he
The post GP concerns around PAs need to be ‘seriously addressed’, says Streeting appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chad eliminates human African trypanosomiasis as a public health problem]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:2565a01b-a1d7-4c47-abcb-57f79a517258</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/20-06-2024-chad-eliminates-human-african-trypanosomiasis-as-a-public-health-problem"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T13:02:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) congratulates Chad for having eliminated the gambiense form of human African trypanosomiasis, also known as sleeping sickness, as a public health problem. It marks the first neglected tropical disease to be eliminated in the country.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wales sets out to create a single national clinical data repository by 2030]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177517</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/wales-sets-out-to-create-a-single-national-clinical-data-repository-by-2030/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T12:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health and Care Wales (DHCW) has set out a mission to join up data by ensuring it flows to and from the National Data Resource (NDR) platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Providers deliver: achieving value for money]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/providers-deliver-achieving-value-for-money.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/providers-deliver-achieving-value-for-money.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T12:03:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This report shows how hospitals, mental health, community and ambulance services are finding new ways to provide better care and value for money. It says that the efforts of trusts must be matched by a commitment from government for capital investment to modernise buildings, equipment and technology in order to unlock greater productivity gains. It finds that...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Productivity in the NHS and health care sector]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/productivity-in-the-nhs-and-health-care-sector.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/productivity-in-the-nhs-and-health-care-sector.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T11:22:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The King's Fund - Productivity is one way people measure the performance of a sector – it compares the growth in the quantity of outputs to the growth in the quantity of inputs. This explainer looks at what productivity is and how different bodies measure health care productivity in England in different ways. The King's Fund - publications]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wes Streeting slams ‘glacial’ pace of FDP adoption]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177511</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/wes-streeting-slams-glacial-pace-of-fdp-adoption/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T10:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow health secretary Wes Streeting has criticised the “glacial” pace of adoption of the NHS Federated Data Platform (FDP).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICB to continue Fuller-lauded funding model despite GP criticism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148217</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/icb-to-continue-fuller-lauded-funding-model-despite-gp-criticism/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T09:38:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new GP funding model based on population need has been awarded money to run until next year, despite facing criticism from local GPs. The pilot run by Leicester, Leicestershire and Rutland ICB – whereby the cost-of-staff element in the Carr-Hill formula calculation has been replaced with a needs-and-deprivation element – had been lauded in
The post ICB to continue Fuller-lauded funding model despite GP criticism appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS dementia services ‘cannot meet need of newer treatments’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149764</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/nhs-dementia-services-cannot-meet-need-of-newer-treatments/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T09:29:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS dementia services will need to make big changes to identify which patients may be eligible for new disease-modifying therapies likely to be available later this year. Currently less than 1% of patients in NHS memory clinics had amyloid biomarker testing performed, and this will need ‘urgent’ service development if patients are to access newer
The post NHS dementia services ‘cannot meet need of newer treatments’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over half of job-seeking GPs are ‘struggling’ to find role, finds RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149924</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/over-half-of-job-seeking-gps-are-struggling-to-find-role-finds-rcgp/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T09:14:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six out of 10 GPs looking for jobs ‘are struggling to find vacancies’, a new poll of RCGP members has shown. The college said that 61% of the survey respondents who had looked for a GP role in the NHS over the past year found it ‘moderately difficult’ or ‘very difficult’ to find ‘an appropriate
The post Over half of job-seeking GPs are ‘struggling’ to find role, finds RCGP appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unemployment 'scandal' as most job-seeking GPs struggle to find work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877621</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/unemployment-scandal-job-seeking-gps-struggle-find-work/article/1877621"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T08:50:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six in 10 GPs looking for jobs have struggled to find a vacancy to apply for in the past year despite record workload in general practice, a shocking RCGP poll reveals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour promises brighter future for GPs and condemns 'failure to listen' on PAs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877603</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/labour-promises-brighter-future-gps-condemns-failure-listen-pas/article/1877603"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T08:41:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice 'will do well under a Labour government' if the party wins the general election, shadow health and social care secretary Wes Streeting has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EHR system restored at Ascension following cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177451</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/ehr-system-restored-at-ascension-following-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-19T07:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US non-profit health system Ascension says that its electronic health records system has been restored across following a ransomware incident in May 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General practice ‘will do well’ under Labour, Wes Streeting promises]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149881</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/general-practice-will-do-well-under-labour-wes-streeting-promises/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice ‘has a lot to look forward to’ should Labour win the upcoming general election, the shadow health secretary has said. Wes Streeting was speaking at an event organised by the Medical Journalists Association in London yesterday evening, when he said that general practice ‘will do well’ under a Labour government. He also said
The post General practice ‘will do well’ under Labour, Wes Streeting promises appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting to the heart of peer-to-peer recognition]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/getting-to-the-heart-of-peer-to-peer-recognition.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/getting-to-the-heart-of-peer-to-peer-recognition.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T16:10:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - Barts Health NHS Trust (BHT) recently launched a new programme of recognition based on feedback following engagement with its workforce. One of the big changes was the introduction of a recognition platform, with the main aim of enabling staff to benefit from visible and meaningful recognition from their peers. The new scheme allows peer-to-peer recognition for those...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sessional GPs should not be expected to supervise ARRS staff, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149822</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/sessional-gps-should-not-be-expected-to-supervise-arrs-staff-says-bma/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:51:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supervising non-doctors should not form part of a sessional GP’s job description ‘unless expressly and mutually agreed’, according to new advice from the BMA. The union said that with the ‘expansion’ of the additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) and the ‘diversification of the workforce’, GPs have seen a ‘dramatic increase’ in supervision responsibilities expected of
The post Sessional GPs should not be expected to supervise ARRS staff, says BMA appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pain killers don’t exist – so how can we help patients in pain?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149648</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/david-turner/pain-killers-dont-exist-so-how-can-we-help-patients-in-pain/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:47:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on a new campaign for patients with opioid dependency issues, Dr David Turner asks how GPs can best help those in need ‘Pain killers don’t exist.’ I thought this a rather curious statement for pharmacists to make, given that a significant proportion of their work is concerned with the dispensing of medication that does
The post Pain killers don’t exist – so how can we help patients in pain? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4513 - Broadcom Releases Critical Security Updates for VMware vCenter Server and Cloud Foundation]]></title>
        <id>360252d5-33e5-45b7-9a9c-b789f094f355</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4513"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisory addresses three vulnerabilities that could result in privilege escalation or remote code execution
 Advisory addresses three vulnerabilities that could result in privilege escalation or remote code execution
 Updated: 18 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA calls for investment to solve other pay disputes as SAS doctors accept uplift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877551</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-calls-investment-solve-pay-disputes-sas-doctors-accept-uplift/article/1877551"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:22:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Specialist and associate specialist (SAS) doctors have voted to accept a proposed pay uplift for 2023/24 - as the BMA said the 'right offer' could end disputes with other doctors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One in six adults go without prescription medicines due to supply issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877528</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/one-six-adults-go-without-prescription-medicines-due-supply-issues/article/1877528"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T14:20:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One in six UK adults report going without prescription medicines over the past two years due to ongoing supply issues, with more than a third blaming Brexit, new polling has revealed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSDG warns 150,000 patients to assume data has been published]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177423</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhsdg-warns-150000-patients-to-assume-data-has-been-published/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T12:29:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Dumfries and Galloway is warning around 150,000 patients to assume that their personal data is likely to have been stolen and published online.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[District nursing today: the view of district nurse team leaders in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/district-nursing-today-the-view-of-district-nurse-team-leaders-in-the-uk.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/district-nursing-today-the-view-of-district-nurse-team-leaders-in-the-uk.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T11:09:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Queen's Nursing Institute - Over 1500 district nurse team leaders from all countries of the UK contributed to the report, through an online survey undertaken in 2023. The survey makes extensive comparison with data gathered in 2019, illustrating trends in the workforce since the Covid-19 pandemic. The report focuses on the demographic profile of the workforce, working practices and...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How can the next government improve the health of the workforce and boost growth?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-can-the-next-government-improve-the-health-of-the-workforce-and-boost-growth.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-can-the-next-government-improve-the-health-of-the-workforce-and-boost-growth.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:54:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This general election briefing explores how the government can set the conditions for a healthy labour market for the long term. Briefing]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the month: What is the cause of this patient’s confusion?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149860</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/case-of-the-month-what-is-the-cause-of-this-patients-confusion/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:45:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the third of our monthly series, Dr Roger Henderson is asking readers to suggest what is the cause of this patient’s confusion and change of mood. Put your answers in the comments. Answers to be revealed on 20 June! The case A 38-year-old man had been experiencing anxiety, anger outbursts and some hallucinations over
The post Case of the month: What is the cause of this patient’s confusion? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE asks ICBs to ‘referee’ hospital/GP workload dump situations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149725</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/referrals/nhse-asks-icbs-to-referee-hospital-gp-workload-dump-situations/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:43:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has asked ICBs to act as ‘referees’ to resolve ‘tension’ between primary and secondary care around workload and referrals. NHSE deputy medical director Dr Kiren Collison said there is ‘a lot of tension at times between primary and secondary care’ and that NHSE is ‘trying to get away from that’. Speaking at the
The post NHSE asks ICBs to ‘referee’ hospital/GP workload dump situations appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177273</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-146/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:30:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Coffee Time includes Birdie being named one of the 500 fastest-growing tech companies and development of AI tech to predict heart events.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reform UK pledges private GP for patients left waiting for appointment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149852</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/reform-uk-pledges-private-gp-for-patients-left-waiting-for-appointment/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:19:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reform UK has pledged to give patients a ‘voucher for private treatment’ if they cannot see a GP within three days. Nigel Farage launched his party’s manifesto, which he called ‘Our Contract with You’, at an event in Wales on Monday.  He called for an ‘absolutely radical rethink’ of the way public services are run,
The post Reform UK pledges private GP for patients left waiting for appointment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most London GP practices 'feel unable to deliver safe care']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877499</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/london-gp-practices-feel-unable-deliver-safe-care/article/1877499"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:14:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most practices in London feel 'unable to deliver care that is either safe for patients or staff', GP leaders have warned as they launched resources to support safe working.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI-powered physio platform to be deployed in the NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177327</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/ai-powered-physio-platform-to-be-deployed-by-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T10:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI-powered physio clinic, Flok Health is planned to be rolled out in the NHS by Autumn 2024, with the aim of cutting physiotherapy waiting lists.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland’s blood transfusion service goes live with Clinisys WinPath]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177337</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/northern-irelands-blood-transfusion-service-goes-live-with-clinisys-winpath/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-18T07:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland's blood transfusion service has migrated to Clinisys WinPath, with the aim of creating a single technology platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delivering a general practice estate that is fit for purpose]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/delivering-a-general-practice-estate-that-is-fit-for-purpose.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/delivering-a-general-practice-estate-that-is-fit-for-purpose.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T15:58:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Government - GPs often work in buildings that are too cramped, too old and too inflexible for a modern health service – with a quarter of GPs’ buildings built before the NHS was founded. This report warns that the next government will need to urgently address the crumbling general practice estate. Report More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reform manifesto promises tax cuts for NHS staff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877384</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/reform-manifesto-promises-tax-cuts-nhs-staff/article/1877384"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T15:34:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Reform party has promised to scrap basic rate tax for health and social care staff for three years and write off student fees in return for NHS service as part of its general election manifesto.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS removes patient-facing material referring to PAs as ‘physicians’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149798</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/nhs-removes-patient-facing-material-referring-to-pas-as-physicians/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:57:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors have criticised ‘dangerous’ NHS posters which referred to physician associates (PAs) working in GP practices as ‘physicians’.  The posters formed part of a campaign developed by the Bradford branch of West Yorkshire ICB, aimed at helping patients to better understand new roles in general practice. The campaign material also referred to ‘cancer specialists’ working
The post NHS removes patient-facing material referring to PAs as ‘physicians’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The impact of hardship on primary schools and primary and community healthcare]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/the-impact-of-hardship-on-primary-schools-and-primary-and-community-healthcare.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/the-impact-of-hardship-on-primary-schools-and-primary-and-community-healthcare.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:42:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joseph Rowntree Foundation - Across Britain, millions of people are experiencing hardship, by which we mean they are going without basic essentials such as enough food, heating and appropriate clothing, because they cannot afford them. This report asks what impact hardship is having on the delivery of services in primary schools and primary and community healthcare setting such as GP...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA lists steps practices could take as part of collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877357</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-lists-steps-practices-part-collective-action/article/1877357"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:33:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has set out 12 steps practices could take as part of collective action later this year, as voting opened in a ballot of the profession.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA lists 12 steps practices could take as part of collective action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877357</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-lists-12-steps-practices-part-collective-action/article/1877357"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:33:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has set out 12 steps practices could take as part of collective action later this year, as voting opened in a ballot of the profession.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hematologic Cancer Opportunities for Patient Equality (HOPE)]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/hematologic-cancer-opportunities-for-patient-equality-hope.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/hematologic-cancer-opportunities-for-patient-equality-hope.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:25:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IQVIA Institute for Human Data Science - This report aims to quantify the trends around the availability and use of therapies for hematological malignancies across selected countries (including the United Kingdom) with reported oncology therapy access challenges and disparities. Trends in overall regulatory approvals, health technology assessments, reimbursement, and final therapy usage have been analyzed for drugs indicated in hematological...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICBs ‘increasing pressure’ on GPs to boost patient records access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149817</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/icbs-increasing-pressure-on-gps-to-boost-patient-records-access/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practices are under ‘increasing pressure’ from their ICBs to boost the number of patients with online access to medical records, according to GP leaders. Despite this pressure, the BMA’s GP Committee reminded practices that any ‘mitigations’ identified by their Data Protection Impact Assessment (DPIA) should be followed in order for records access to be ‘legal’.
The post ICBs ‘increasing pressure’ on GPs to boost patient records access appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General election 2024: the health and care manifesto pledges]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/general-election-2024-the-health-and-care-manifesto-pledges.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/general-election-2024-the-health-and-care-manifesto-pledges.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T14:03:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The King's Fund - This resource is intended as a summary of the commitments the three largest parties in England have made for the NHS, social care and public health in their manifestos, associated costing documents and media reports ahead of the general election on 4 July. Long read]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debate: Will AI replace clinicians?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=148011</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/debate/debate-will-ai-replace-clinicians/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T13:52:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of the ongoing conversation of artificial intelligence in healthcare, two GPs debate whether or not AI is a threat to the workforce YES: ‘AI will replace clinicians and reduce the workforce to 10% of what it currently is’ Like it or not, artificial intelligence is becoming an increasingly dominant force in healthcare, and
The post Debate: Will AI replace clinicians? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 800 operations postponed since London cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177335</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/more-than-800-operations-postponed-since-london-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T12:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 800 planned operations and 700 outpatient appointments were rearranged in the week following a cyber attack on Synnovis.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs urged to vote ‘yes’ to collective action as BMA ballot opens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149807</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/gps-urged-to-vote-yes-to-collective-action-as-bma-ballot-opens/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T11:06:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are being urged ‘take a stand’ and vote ‘yes’ to collective action, in a BMA ballot opening today.   The union is currently planning for potential GP collective action to commence on 1 August, depending on the result of the ballot which will close on Monday 29 July. In the ballot, GP partners are being
The post GPs urged to vote ‘yes’ to collective action as BMA ballot opens appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs urged to back collective action as BMA ballot opens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877288</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-urged-back-collective-action-bma-ballot-opens/article/1877288"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:47:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have urged the profession to vote in favour of collective action over 'derisory' funding uplifts for general practice, as a BMA ballot opened on 17 June.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How PAs can be a successful part of an MDT]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149808</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/special-investigations/how-pas-can-be-a-successful-part-of-an-mdt/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:47:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse’s review into the role of the physician associate has highlighted issues around GP recruitment and clinical risk. Now, Stephen Nash, Chief Executive of UMAPs, puts forward the positives of having PAs in a multi-disciplinary team It has been glaringly obvious for some time that one narrative regarding physician associates (PAs), and medical associate professions
The post How PAs can be a successful part of an MDT appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Semaglutide can sustain weight loss for four years and cut CVD risk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=147623</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/semaglutide-can-sustain-weight-loss-for-four-years-and-cut-cvd-risk/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:46:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weight loss in patients with semaglutide can be sustained for up to four years, according to results from the SELECT study presented at the European Congress on Obesity and published in Nature Medicine. A second as yet unpublished analysis from the same trial also presented at the conference found it delivered cardiovascular benefits irrespective of
The post Semaglutide can sustain weight loss for four years and cut CVD risk appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ming Tang announced as keynote at AI and Data 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177319</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/ming-tang-announced-as-keynote-at-ai-and-data-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T10:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ming Tang, the national leader at the forefront of the NHS’ data revolution in England, returns as national keynote at Digital Health AI and Data 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How much spending on the NHS have the major parties committed to in their election manifestos?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-much-spending-on-the-nhs-have-the-major-parties-committed-to-in-their-election-manifestos.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/how-much-spending-on-the-nhs-have-the-major-parties-committed-to-in-their-election-manifestos.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T09:54:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - To help inform the debate around the imminent general election, this explainer looks at the manifesto commitments that have been made on NHS spending by each of the main parties. How do they stack up, and what would it mean in practice for the NHS budget in coming years if their commitments were enacted? Explainer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 general election: manifesto briefing]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/2024-general-election-manifesto-briefing-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/2024-general-election-manifesto-briefing-.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T09:51:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This briefing provides a summary of the main health and social care commitments, and other relevant policy commitments, made by the Liberal Democrat, Conservative, and Labour parties. Briefing More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP services 'staggering under the weight of hardship' among patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877257</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-services-staggering-weight-hardship-among-patients/article/1877257"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T09:35:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP services are 'staggering under the weight of hardship' among their patient populations, often directly providing food banks, facing increased workload and struggling to cope with patients unable to follow medical advice because of poverty, a report shows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs recognised in King's birthday honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877241</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-recognised-kings-birthday-honours/article/1877241"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T09:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs, including King Charles's GP and the GP who is head of the Royal Medical Household, have been recognised in the King's birthday honours list.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lewisham and Greenwich NHS Trust goes live with CardMedic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177309</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/lewisham-and-greenwich-nhs-trust-goes-live-with-cardmedic/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T07:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthcare translation app CardMedic has been downloaded by nearly 400 members of staff at Lewisham and Greenwich NHS Trust since its roll out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA roadshow diary: GPs 'angry and exhausted', says Dr David Wrigley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877170</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-roadshow-diary-gps-angry-exhausted-says-dr-david-wrigley/article/1877170"/>
        <updated>2024-06-17T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With a ballot on collective action in general practice opening this month, BMA England GP committee leaders are touring the country to talk to the profession. Deputy chair Dr David Wrigley writes about pressures on general practice after roadshows in Stafford and Warrington.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff among those recognised in 2024 King’s Birthday Honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247740</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-staff-among-those-recognised-in-2024-kings-birthday-honours/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T21:39:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff including paramedics, nurses and doctors are among dozens of frontline workers recognised in the 2024 King’s Birthday Honours list, released today (Friday 14 June). The head of the NHS, Amanda Pritchard, has said the awards recognise the dedication and skill of NHS staff. Among the staff recognised for their hard work and dedication […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: Birthday Honours 2024: Ambulance Service list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/birthday-honours-2024-ambulance-service-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/birthday-honours-2024-ambulance-service-list"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T21:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recipients of the King's Ambulance Service Medal 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO concerned about escalating health crisis in West Bank]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5ce74b93-7081-41fc-bbf9-c59567f952db</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/14-06-2024-who-concerned-about-escalating-health-crisis-in-west-bank"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T19:24:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO remains concerned about the escalating health crisis in the occupied Palestinian territory, including the West Bank, where attacks on health infrastructure and increased restrictions on movement are obstructing access to health care.  

A spike in violence in the West Bank, including East Jerusalem, since the war in Gaza started has resulted in the deaths of 521 Palestinians, including 126 children between 7 October 2023 and 10 June 2024. In addition, over 5200 people, 800 of them children, have been injured, adding to the growing burden of trauma and emergency care at already strained health facilities.

As of 28 May, WHO has documented 480 attacks on health care in the West Bank since 7 October 2023, resulting in 16 deaths and 95 injuries. The attacks affected 54 health facilities, 2…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SystmOne investigates IT crash issue with diagnostic test ordering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149778</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/systmone-investigates-it-crash-issue-with-diagnostic-test-ordering/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T15:48:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Practices are being asked to provide more information about a SystmOne issue that has been causing computers to crash when clinicians try to order diagnostic tests. In a letter to practices, Mid and South Essex ICB said all practices had been reporting IT systems crashing when printing out pathology forms but this had now extended
The post SystmOne investigates IT crash issue with diagnostic test ordering appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PAs ‘small but important’ part of workforce plan, says NHS chief]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149792</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/pas-small-but-important-part-of-workforce-plan-says-nhs-chief/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T15:33:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Physician associates (PAs) are a ‘small but important’ part of the NHS workforce plan and ‘crucially’ need to be ‘well-supported as colleagues’, NHS England’s chief executive has said. Speaking at the NHS Confederation Expo in Manchester earlier this week, Amanda Pritchard said that NHS England ‘must work’ with royal colleges and the GMC to ‘ensure’
The post PAs ‘small but important’ part of workforce plan, says NHS chief appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS is circling the drain – the care merry-go-round is exasperating]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149718</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/the-nhs-is-circling-the-drain-the-care-merry-go-round-is-exasperating/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T14:20:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Copperfield is fed up with the dizzying circus that is accessing care in the NHS, and the position in which it leaves GPs So proud of the NHS this week. And I’m sure you were, too, when you heard the widely reported story of how superbly the service dealt with a patient in Telford
The post The NHS is circling the drain – the care merry-go-round is exasperating appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integrated Care Systems report 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/integrated-care-systems-report-2024.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/integrated-care-systems-report-2024.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T13:53:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Association of Directors of Public Health - Integrated Care Systems (ICSs) were formalised across England as legal entities with statutory powers and responsibilities in July 2022. Directors of Public Health (DsPH) and their teams have adapted and sought to collaborate with ICSs effectively for the benefit of the health and wellbeing of local populations. This report summarises the results of...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What health and care need from the next government: general practice and dentistry]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/what-health-and-care-need-from-the-next-government-general-practice-and-dentistry.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/what-health-and-care-need-from-the-next-government-general-practice-and-dentistry.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T13:29:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nuffield Trust - This briefing looks at general practice and dentistry, two of the most visible points of contact with the NHS, both of which are struggling to meet the needs of their patients. It suggests six tests for general practice and three for dentistry that the next government must meet to tackle the problems surrounding these services. Briefing Nuffield...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General election: The parties' pledges on general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1877112</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-election-parties-pledges-general-practice/article/1877112"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T13:25:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPonline rounds up the key points on general practice from the Conservatives, Labour, Liberal Democrats, Green Party and Plaid Cymru manifestos.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kent Community Health sexual health service goes live with EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177225</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/kent-community-health-sexual-health-service-goes-live-with-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T12:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kent Community Health NHS Foundation Trust's sexual health service has implemented a new electronic patient record provided by Inform Health.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public harms: racism and misogyny in policing, education, and mental health services]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/public-harms-racism-and-misogyny-in-policing-education-and-mental-health-services.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/public-harms-racism-and-misogyny-in-policing-education-and-mental-health-services.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T11:41:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Black Equity Organisation - This project draws together women’s experiences across three themes: mental health, policing and education. It aims to amplify the experiences of Black women who face the greatest harm within these institutions while also connecting with the broader experiences of women from other backgrounds, to reimagine a feminist, anti-racist and anti-discriminatory model for public services. Report Black...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OOH provider tells GPs to review all patients seen by PA before discharge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149442</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/urgent-care/ooh-provider-tells-gps-to-review-all-patients-seen-by-pa-before-discharge/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:49:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Out-of-hours GPs in Doncaster will now have to review ‘all assessments’ made by a physician associate (PA) before a patient is discharged, in a bid to address safety concerns.  Clinical leaders at FCMS, a provider of GP OOH services in Doncaster and across Lancashire, have ‘formally agreed’ the new policy following ‘concerns regarding legislation around
The post OOH provider tells GPs to review all patients seen by PA before discharge appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How much does your area rely on physician associates?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149745</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/special-investigations/the-rise-of-the-physician-associates/how-much-does-your-area-rely-on-physician-associates/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:43:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse’s analysis has shown the areas where physician associates are most likely to be employed. See how much your region relies on them Our investigation into the rise of the physician associates has revealed that, while numbers remain relatively low, they are increasing. The data analysis into what kind of practices and primary care networks
The post How much does your area rely on physician associates? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Warnings of rising cases of dengue fever in European countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149761</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/warnings-of-rising-cases-of-dengue-fever-in-european-countries/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:09:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public health officials have warned that cases of dengue fever in Europe are continuing to rise as climate change creates favourable conditions for invasive mosquitoes. Figures show that last year there were 130 cases of dengue acquired in a European country compared with 71 in 2022. Between 2020 and 2021 there were only 73 locally
The post Warnings of rising cases of dengue fever in European countries appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital platform offers online consultations with community pharmacists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177245</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-platform-offers-online-consultations-with-community-pharmacists/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T10:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new digital platform has been launched, allowing patients to book free online Pharmacy First consultations with community pharmacists.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Devastated' partners at highly-rated GP practice hand back contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876776</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/devastated-partners-highly-rated-gp-practice-hand-back-contract/article/1876776"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP partners at a highly-rated 8,000-patient practice in Cambridge have handed back their contract - warning that soaring premises fees and inadequate local and national funding left them no choice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calderdale and Huddersfield awarded HIMSS stage 6 for analytics capabilities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176865</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/calderdale-and-huddersfield-awarded-himss-stage-6-for-analytics-capabilities/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T07:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Calderdale and Huddersfield NHS Foundation Trust has achieved a stage 6 validation from HIMSS for its use of data and approach to data science.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: GP unemployment crisis, general election manifestos, physician associate regulation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876975</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-gp-unemployment-crisis-general-election-manifestos-physician-associate-regulation/article/1876975"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T07:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GPonline team discusses the latest news affecting primary care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO releases report on state of development of antibacterials]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:90da8491-404e-4d83-a3d5-bbe6d6f0cf8e</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/14-06-2024-who-releases-report-on-state-of-development-of-antibacterials"/>
        <updated>2024-06-14T07:09:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today released its latest report on antibacterial agents, including antibiotics, in clinical and preclinical development worldwide. Although the number of antibacterial agents in the clinical pipeline increased from 80 in 2021 to 97 in 2023, there is a pressing need for new, innovative agents for serious infections and to replace those becoming ineffective due to widespread use. 
First released in 2017, this annual report evaluates whether the current research and development (R&D) pipeline properly addresses infections caused by the drug-resistant bacteria most threatening to human health, as detailed in the  2024 WHO bacterial priority pathogen list (BPPL). Both documents aim to steer antibacterial R&D to better counter the ever-growing threat of antim…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detention of United Nations and non-governmental organization personnel in Yemen]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:abd0e8c0-5908-4cb5-b332-44e90cbafb08</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/13-06-2024-detention-of-united-nations-and-non-governmental-organization-personnel-in-yemen"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T17:08:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We, the Principals of the affected United Nations (UN) entities and international non-governmental organizations (NGOs), call for the immediate and unconditional release of all personnel held in Yemen by the Houthi de facto authorities. 
We are extremely concerned about the Houthi de facto authorities’ recent detention of 17 members of our organizations [UN entities and INGOs] and many others associated with civil society organizations, national and international NGOs, and other organizations supporting humanitarian activities. 
These detentions are unprecedented – not only in Yemen but globally – and directly impede our ability to reach the most vulnerable people in Yemen, including the 18.2 million people who need humanitarian aid and protection.
We ask the de facto authorities to confirm the exact whereabouts of those detained and the conditions in which they are being held, as well as for immediate access to them. 
International law prohibits the arbitrary deprivation of liberty. International Humanitarian Law requires all parties to armed conflict to respect and protect humanitarian personnel, including against harassment, mistreatment, and unlawful arrest or detention. 
The targeting of humanitarian, human rights, and development workers in Yemen must stop. All those detained must be immediately released. 
 
Signed by:
Achim Steiner, Administrator, UNDP 
Amitabh Behar, Executive Director (interim), Oxfam International
Audrey Azoulay, Director-General, UNESCO 
Catherine Russell, Executive Director, UNICEF
Cindy McCain, Executive Director, WFP 
Inger Ashing, Chief Executive Officer, Save the Children International
Michelle Nunn, President and CEO, CARE
Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, Director-General, WHO
Volker Türk, United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights, OHCHR]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open consultation: Community water fluoridation expansion in the north east of England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/community-water-fluoridation-expansion-in-the-north-east-of-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/community-water-fluoridation-expansion-in-the-north-east-of-england"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T15:59:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government is seeking views on expanding community water fluoridation schemes in the north east with new arrangements or by varying existing arrangements.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General practice needs more GPs but must embrace reform, says NHS chief]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876958</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-practice-needs-gps-embrace-reform-says-nhs-chief/article/1876958"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T15:44:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[General practice needs more GPs - particularly in some parts of the country - but must embrace reform to cope with rising demand, NHS England's chief executive has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How low-funded practices are more likely to rely on physician associates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149587</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/special-investigations/the-rise-of-the-physician-associates/how-low-funded-practices-are-more-likely-to-rely-on-physician-associates/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T14:56:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the fourth part of our series on the rise of physician associates, Madeline Sherratt and Jaimie Kaffash dig deep into the data to look at the characteristics of GP practices and PCNs that are more likely to employ PAs. And the results are illuminating… We have already reviewed the effect of physician associates on
The post How low-funded practices are more likely to rely on physician associates appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs asked to order alternatives as Sanofi’s QIVr flu vaccine unavailable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149751</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/vaccinations-prevention-screening/gps-asked-to-order-alternatives-as-sanofis-qivr-flu-vaccine-unavailable/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T14:50:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have been advised they should order alternative vaccines from an approved list, after Sanofi told health officials their recombinant quadrivalent influenza vaccine would not be available for this year’s flu programme. The UK Health Security Agency confirmed to Pulse that an alternative has been secured to meet demand for flu vaccines this coming winter
The post GPs asked to order alternatives as Sanofi’s QIVr flu vaccine unavailable appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners protest against Palantir at NHS Confed Expo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177167</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/campaigners-protest-against-palantir-at-nhs-confed-expo/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T12:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demonstrators gathered outside the NHS Confed Expo conference to protest against its sponsorship by US data analytics giant Palantir.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4512 - MicroDicom Releases DICOM Viewer Software Update]]></title>
        <id>90e84f8a-cc60-4913-aab8-04a06d9e632c</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4512"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T11:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Low
 One vulnerability could allow an attacker retrieve and plant medical image files and another could lead to arbitrary code execution
 One vulnerability could allow an attacker retrieve and plant medical image files and another could lead to arbitrary code execution
 Updated: 13 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour manifesto promises reform to 'bring back the family doctor']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876885</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/labour-manifesto-promises-reform-bring-back-family-doctor/article/1876885"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T11:14:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Labour party has promised 'thousands more GPs' and to 'bring back the family doctor', with trials of new neighbourhood health centres to move care out of hospital in its general election manifesto.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour to ‘reform’ general practice with new ‘neighbourhood health centres’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149728</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/labour-to-reform-general-practice-with-new-neighbourhood-health-centres/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:54:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour’s manifesto has pledged to ‘reform’ primary care, trialling ‘neighbourhood health centres’ which would have GPs and other community health staff ‘under one roof’. According to the document, published this morning, ‘GPs are the front door to the health service for most people’, with ‘excellent primary care’ the ‘key to earlier diagnosis’. However it claimed
The post Labour to ‘reform’ general practice with new ‘neighbourhood health centres’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England must respond to GP unemployment crisis, senior official says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876880</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-england-respond-gp-unemployment-crisis-senior-official-says/article/1876880"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:45:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A senior NHS England official has said the health service must respond to the GP job shortage that has left thousands of GPs struggling to find work, and doctors about to qualify fearing for their futures.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workforce census reports]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/workforce-census-reports.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/workforce-census-reports.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:41:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Radiologists - These two reports - one on the clinical radiology workforce and the other on clinical oncology workforce - are based on surveys of cancer centre heads and clinical directors of radiology departments. They reveal concerns on the current state of cancer care in the UK due to workforce shortages. They conclude that delays in diagnosis...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176911</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing130624/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing includes the relaunch of System C's CareFlow EPR and an online genetic support programme for MSD from Sano Genetics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176911</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing includes the relaunch of System C's CareFlow EPR and an online genetic support programme for MSD from Sano Genetics.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practices are paid 'less than the cost of an apple a day' per patient, BMA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876873</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/practices-paid-less-cost-apple-day-per-patient-bma-warns/article/1876873"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:08:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices receive just 30p a day for every patient registered with them - less than the cost of the proverbial 'apple a day to keep the doctor away', a BMA campaign warns.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cancer treatment delays ‘have become routine and put patients at risk’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149722</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cancer/cancer-treatment-delays-have-become-routine-and-put-patients-at-risk/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:08:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delays in starting vital cancer treatment have now become ‘routine’ with hundreds of thousands of patients waiting longer than they should over the past decade. A report from Cancer Research UK found that 382,000 cancer patients in England were not treated on time since 2015. Only 66.6% of people in England received their diagnosis and
The post Cancer treatment delays ‘have become routine and put patients at risk’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS tech is at ‘tipping point’, says Amanda Pritchard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177161</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhs-tech-is-at-tipping-point-says-amanda-pritchard/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T10:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England chief executive, Amanda Pritchard said the NHS is at “a tipping point” when it comes to the use of technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lowest-funded GP practices have twice as many patients per staff as highest funded]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149663</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/lowest-funded-gp-practices-have-twice-as-many-patients-per-staff-as-highest-funded/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T09:41:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GP practices in the bottom 10% of funding per patient have around 1,200 patients per clinical staff member, compared with around 600 in the top-funded practices. Exclusive Pulse research, based on NHS Digital data, also found that in those practices in the lowest decile in terms of payments per patient, around 3.5% of medical
The post Lowest-funded GP practices have twice as many patients per staff as highest funded appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS continues to face record demand for services, new data shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247511</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-continues-to-face-record-demand-for-services-new-data-shows/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T09:37:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff continue to face significant demand for urgent care, with new figures showing that A&Es in England managed their busiest ever month for attendances in May. New monthly performance data also shows that it was a record April for the number of elective appointments delivered for hundreds of thousands of patients. The latest statistics, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital heart check service to integrate with NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177115</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-heart-check-service-to-integrate-with-nhs-app/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-13T07:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PocDoc's home testing kit for cardiovascular disease is to be integrated with the NHS App, allowing patients to see test results on their NHS patient record.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Myths and facts: HIV]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149679</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/sexual-health/myths-and-facts-hiv/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T16:25:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the third of a new series exploring some common misconceptions about conditions seen in general practice, GP Dr Toni Hazell debunks some myths about HIV – and explains some less well known facts Myths 1. Pre-test counselling is needed before an HIV test is requested We don’t all remember the stigma present in the early
The post Myths and facts: HIV appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greens pledge increased GP funding and ‘rapid access’ guarantee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149706</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/greens-pledge-increased-gp-funding-and-rapid-access-guarantee/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T15:15:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Green Party MPs elected on 4 July will ‘push for’ increased funding to primary care, with an aim for additional annual spending to reach £1.5bn by 2030. The Greens, which currently have just one member of Parliament, also said they want a ‘guarantee’ for ‘rapid access to a GP and same-day access in case of
The post Greens pledge increased GP funding and ‘rapid access’ guarantee appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4510 - Microsoft Releases June 2024 Security Updates]]></title>
        <id>1852598a-74ab-4f99-92a8-db9df9223437</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4510"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T14:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products, including security updates for 50 vulnerabilities
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products, including security updates for 50 vulnerabilities
 Updated: 12 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP at-scale pilots to be ‘integral’ to NHS future, says chief executive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149698</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-at-scale-pilots-to-be-integral-to-nhs-future-says-chief-executive/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T14:35:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pilots of new ways of working for GP practices – modelled on the Fuller Stocktake – will be ‘integral to the future of the NHS’, NHS England’s chief executive said today. Amanda Pritchard was speaking at the NHS Confederation Expo in Manchester today when she said that the NHS needs ‘a modern vision for primary
The post GP at-scale pilots to be ‘integral’ to NHS future, says chief executive appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS identifies over half a million more people at risk of type 2 diabetes in a Year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=247480</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2024/06/nhs-identifies-over-half-a-million-more-people-at-risk-of-type-2-diabetes-in-a-year/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T13:22:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over half a million (549,000) more people in England have been identified by the NHS as being at risk of developing type 2 diabetes in a year, NHS figures show. The latest National Diabetes Audit shows that 3,615,330 people registered with a GP were found to have non-diabetic hyperglycaemia – also known as pre-diabetes -in […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>kbradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kettering General Hospital cuts neurology waiting list through telemedicine tech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177053</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/kettering-general-hospital-cuts-neurology-waiting-list-through-telemedicine-tech/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T12:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kettering General Hospital has reduced its neurology waiting lists by 50% by using telemedicine technology to triage patients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More money, more choice, more of the private sector: can the next government repeat the feat of the 2000s and cut waiting times?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/more-money-more-choice-more-of-the-private-sector-can-the-next-government-repeat-the-feat-of-the-200.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2024/06/more-money-more-choice-more-of-the-private-sector-can-the-next-government-repeat-the-feat-of-the-200.html"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T11:46:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - NHS waiting times are a central issue of the 2024 election campaign. Proposed solutions – more money, more staff, more use of the independent sector and strengthening patient choice – are mostly shared between the two main parties. More money, more choice and more private sector provision helped reduce median waiting times (under old measures) from...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4511 - Arm Releases Security Advisory for Exploited Mali GPU Driver Vulnerability]]></title>
        <id>5eaa15f8-dd94-40e6-ae38-368ea32c352b</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4511"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T11:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Exploitation could allow a local attacker to gain access to freed memory
 Exploitation could allow a local attacker to gain access to freed memory
 Updated: 12 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Green Party manifesto pledges primary care funding boost and junior doctor pay restoration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876705</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/green-party-manifesto-pledges-primary-care-funding-boost-junior-doctor-pay-restoration/article/1876705"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T11:04:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Green Party MPs in the next parliament will push for increasing the share of NHS funding that goes to primary care and an immediate boost to NHS staff pay, including pay restoration for junior doctors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England director admits GP trainee jobs ‘are not there for them’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149690</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/nhs-england-director-admits-gp-trainee-jobs-are-not-there-for-them/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T11:01:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The jobs that newly qualified GPs would want ‘are not there for them’, NHS England’s national director of primary care has admitted. Dr Amanda Doyle made the comments in a talk on best practices in primary care at the NHS Confederation Expo in Manchester this morning. She said that NHS England has heard from young
The post NHS England director admits GP trainee jobs ‘are not there for them’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPC campaign urges voters to make GP crisis the doorstep election issue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149678</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gpc-campaign-urges-voters-to-make-gp-crisis-the-doorstep-election-issue/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:43:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA’s GP Committee has launched a new patient-facing campaign ahead of the general election, titled ‘GPs Are On Your Side’. The GPC has produced leaflets that voters can put in their window during the run-up to the election and it is urging patients to make general practice the doorstep election topic. Highlighting that GP
The post GPC campaign urges voters to make GP crisis the doorstep election issue appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish Government invests £3.6m in Hospital at Home for older people]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176971</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/scottish-government-invests-3-6m-in-hospital-at-home-for-older-people/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Scottish Government has announced an additional investment of £3.6 million to fund its Hospital at Home initiative for older people in 2024- 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: National flu immunisation programme plan 2024 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/national-flu-immunisation-programme-plan-2024-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/national-flu-immunisation-programme-plan-2024-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The annual flu letter describes the national flu immunisation programme and outlines which groups are eligible for flu vaccination.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Cornwall and Isles of Scilly ICS restoring systems following IT outage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=177105</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhs-cornwall-and-isles-of-scilly-ics-restoring-services-following-it-outage/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-12T07:30:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Cornwall and Isles of Scilly Integrated Care System (ICS) has confirmed that its IT systems are "coming back online" following a network outage.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medicines shortages triggering ‘moral distress’ in GPs, survey shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876581</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/medicines-shortages-triggering-moral-distress-gps-survey-shows/article/1876581"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T15:39:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost nine in 10 GPs say prescription drug shortages are severely impacting their ability to practise safely, with three quarters experiencing ‘moral distress’ as a result, a survey shows.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How effective are PAs and do they reduce GP workload?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149542</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/special-investigations/the-rise-of-the-physician-associates/how-effective-are-pas-and-do-they-reduce-gp-workload/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T15:39:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the third part of our series on physician associates in general practice, Eliza Parr asks whether the increase in numbers is worth the money, and whether they are easing pressures on GPs For those cynics among you, it may seem unlikely that the Government will listen to doctors’ concerns about the clinical safety of
The post How effective are PAs and do they reduce GP workload? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 80 fellows declare no confidence in RCP in physician associates fallout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149659</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/more-than-80-fellows-resign-from-rcp-in-physician-associates-fallout/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T15:36:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 80 fellows of the Royal College of Physicians have declared a lack of confidence in the college’s leadership over its handling of the debate around physician associates (PAs). There have also been calls for the RCP president to resign, with five senior officers writing to the college to demand Dr Sarah Clarke’s resignation.
The post More than 80 fellows declare no confidence in RCP in physician associates fallout appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gavi to boost access to life-saving human rabies vaccines in over 50 countries: Gavi, WHO and UAR]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:d038eb3a-e7db-46b3-a5b6-b5e18629b27a</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/13-06-2024-gavi-to-boost-access-to-life-saving-rabies-vaccines-human-in-over-50-countries-gavi-who-and-uar"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T14:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, in collaboration with partners, is announcing support for human rabies vaccines for post exposure prophylaxis (PEP) as part of routine immunisation. Eligible countries are receiving guidance on how to access these vaccines under Gavi’s cofinancing policy. The first round of applications will be reviewed in July 2024. Ninety-five percent of human rabies deaths occur in Africa and Asia, most often in marginalised communities that lack access to care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4509 - Critical Security Update Released for IntelliJ-based IDEs and JetBrains GitHub Plugin]]></title>
        <id>31f7c1b1-d478-4c06-8557-eee708b68765</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4509"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T14:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Exploitation of the vulnerability could lead to the disclosure of access tokens to third-party sites
 Exploitation of the vulnerability could lead to the disclosure of access tokens to third-party sites
 Updated: 11 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conservative manifesto promises to 'modernise primary care services']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876556</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/conservative-manifesto-promises-modernise-primary-care-services/article/1876556"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T13:48:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Conservative manifesto promises to 'modernise primary care services' - but experts said the party's plans on general practice were 'a drop in the ocean' compared with what is needed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ensure best outcomes from inhaler use with a MIMS Learning webinar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876537</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/ensure-best-outcomes-inhaler-use-mims-learning-webinar/article/1876537"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T13:32:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join a free evening webinar on Thursday 18 June to understand more about how to prescribe inhalers effectively and achieve the best outcomes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Rewired 2025 opens for registration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176929</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-rewired-2025-opens-for-registration/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T12:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Registration has opened for Rewired 2025, the largest UK digital health expo  the use of digital and data to deliver improvements in health and care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medicine shortages cause ‘moral distress’ for three-in-four GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149631</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/medicine-shortages-cause-moral-distress-for-three-in-four-gps/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T12:02:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three quarters (74%) of GPs experience moral distress because they are unable to prescribe medicines patients need due to ongoing shortages. This is the finding of a survey carried out by indemnity provider MDDUS, which also found almost a third of this group (30%) suffer moral distress every day at work; and 37% several times
The post Medicine shortages cause ‘moral distress’ for three-in-four GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4508 - Critical Vulnerability in PHP]]></title>
        <id>5c861db6-ec67-4868-ad15-4d63ecdfe5a0</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2024/cc-4508"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T11:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 New versions of PHP address a critical vulnerability that could lead to arbitrary PHP code execution
 New versions of PHP address a critical vulnerability that could lead to arbitrary PHP code execution
 Updated: 11 Jun 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Masterclass: A complete GP’s guide to chronic kidney disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149601</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/renal-medicine-urology-mens-health/masterclass-a-complete-gps-guide-to-chronic-kidney-disease/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T11:10:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the next in our Masterclass series, consultant nephrologist Dr Colin Jones explains the latest knowledge and best practice in the management of CKD in primary care.  This series showcases content from our Pulse Reference site, which supports GPs in making diagnoses. We are expanding this service to include advice on managing and treating conditions
The post Masterclass: A complete GP’s guide to chronic kidney disease appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPC manifesto to demand 15% share of NHS budget for GP and community care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149621</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gpc-manifesto-to-demand-15-share-of-nhs-budget-for-gp-and-community-care/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:59:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive The BMA’s GP committee will ask the next Government to ensure that funding for out-of-hospital care gets ‘at least a 15% share’ of the NHS budget, its chair has revealed. Dr Katie Bramall-Stainer told Pulse that this would form part of GPC England’s manifesto, which is also expected to include ‘an ambition towards’ a
The post GPC manifesto to demand 15% share of NHS budget for GP and community care appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176813</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing110624/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This Coffee Time Briefing includes a call for countries to align health checks across borders through WHO’s Global Digital Health Certification Network.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[University Hospitals Coventry and Warwickshire to launch new EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176919</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/university-hospitals-coventry-and-warwickshire-to-launch-new-epr/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T10:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new EPR is to be deployed at University Hospitals Coventry and Warwickshire NHS Trust with the aim of improving patients' experience.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP 'black alert' trial will allow struggling practices to divert patients elsewhere]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1875870</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-black-alert-trial-will-allow-struggling-practices-divert-patients-elsewhere/article/1875870"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T09:49:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices under extreme pressure will be allowed to divert patients elsewhere and offered additional support under a hospital-style 'black alert' scheme being trialled in part of England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lib Dems pledges ‘small surgeries fund’ to protect rural GP access]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149609</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/lib-dems-pledges-small-surgeries-fund-to-protect-rural-gp-access/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T09:06:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Liberal Democrats would set up a ‘Strategic Small Surgeries Fund to ‘sustain services in rural and remote areas’, according to its election manifesto. The document, published yesterday, also pledged to ‘remove’ existing ‘top-down bureaucracy’ to ‘let practices hire the staff they need’. Health policy experts said the plans were ‘ambitious’ but ‘light on detail’.
The post Lib Dems pledges ‘small surgeries fund’ to protect rural GP access appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Digital babies’ created to advance infant precision medicine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176897</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/digital-babies-to-advance-infant-precision-medicine/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-11T07:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A joint Irish-German study is exploring the use of 'digital babies' to help advance precision medicine for infants with inherited metabolic diseases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lib Dems promise £1bn plan for 8,000 GPs and hint at relaxed ARRS rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876396</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/lib-dems-promise-1bn-plan-8000-gps-hint-relaxed-arrs-rules/article/1876396"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Liberal Democrats have promised a £1bn package to improve general practice, with a manifesto promising 8,000 more full-time equivalent (FTE) GPs in England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Chaand Nagpaul to give keynote address at Pulse Live Birmingham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149612</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/pulse-live/dr-chaand-nagpaul-to-give-keynote-address-at-pulse-live-birmingham/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T16:23:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Live will come back to Birmingham tomorrow (11 June), with a keynote speech from former BMA chair Dr Chaand Nagpaul, among a host of clinical education sessions. Dr Nagpaul will be discussing what GPs can do to stay afloat in the final session of the day, at the National Conference Centre in Solihull. Alongside
The post Dr Chaand Nagpaul to give keynote address at Pulse Live Birmingham appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The debate around the clinical responsibilities of physician associates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149521</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/clinical-areas/long-term-conditions-prescribing/the-debate-around-the-clinical-responsibilities-of-physician-associates/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T14:38:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the second part of our analysis of the role of physician associates within general practice, Eliza Parr looks at what clinical responsibilities they are being given, and the potential risks in their practice A handful of high-profile, tragic cases involving physician associates have caught public attention over the last year. Emily Chesterton, a 30-year-old
The post The debate around the clinical responsibilities of physician associates appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour scraps plans to reintroduce pensions lifetime allowance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149584</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/labour-scraps-plans-to-reintroduce-pensions-lifetime-allowance/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T14:16:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour has abandoned its plans to reintroduce the pensions lifetime allowance, with the BMA saying this will help ‘help retain doctors in the NHS’. It was abolished last year, as part of chancellor Jeremy Hunt’s plan to ‘help people extend their working lives’. The Labour Party shortly after said it would reverse the move if
The post Labour scraps plans to reintroduce pensions lifetime allowance appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Standard infusion pump software to go live at Alder Hey Children’s Hospital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176613</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/standard-infusion-pumps-with-new-software-to-go-live-fully-at-alder-hey/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T12:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peter White, CNIO at Alder Hey Children’s Hospital, tells Digital Health about a project to create standardised pediatric datasets for infusion pumps.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and pharmacists call for action on volatile drug costs as prescribing bill spirals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876325</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-pharmacists-call-action-volatile-drug-costs-prescribing-bill-spirals/article/1876325"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T11:02:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs and pharmacists have called for action to tackle volatile drug costs after a £500m surge in prescribing spending in 2023/24, with spending on some medications more than doubling.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP confronts Prime Minister over ‘constructive dismissal’ of general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149571</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/gp-confronts-prime-minister-over-constructive-dismissal-of-general-practice/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:26:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The public is ‘not stupid’ and will not allow the Conservatives to ‘replace’ doctors with ‘half-qualified’ staff, a heckling GP told Rishi Sunak last week. Locum GP Dr Jane Lees-Millais confronted the Prime Minister on the ‘constructive dismissal’ of general practice during an election rally on Friday. She interrupted Mr Sunak during his visit to
The post GP confronts Prime Minister over ‘constructive dismissal’ of general practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA calls GP unemployment a ‘national disgrace’ after GP confronts Sunak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1876299</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-calls-gp-unemployment-national-disgrace-gp-confronts-sunak/article/1876299"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:10:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has declared the current GP unemployment crisis a ‘national disgrace’ after a GP confronted prime minister Rishi Sunak over the 'constructive dismissal' of general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only one in six patients experience antidepressant withdrawal, finds study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=149435</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/only-one-in-six-patients-experience-antidepressant-withdrawal-finds-study/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Only one in six people who stop taking antidepressants will experience withdrawal symptoms as a direct result, according to a new study.  This is a much lower proportion than other studies have suggested, with previous estimates that over half of patients experience symptoms. The research, published in the Lancet Psychiatry (5 June), found that overall
The post Only one in six patients experience antidepressant withdrawal, finds study appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS issues urgent call for O-type blood donors following London cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176879</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/nhs-issues-urgent-call-for-o-type-blood-donors-following-london-cyber-attack/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T10:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Blood and Transplant has urgently called for donations of O type blood following a ransomware attack which has disrupted pathology services in London.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belfast Health and Social Care Trust goes live with digital record system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=176853</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2024/06/belfast-health-and-social-care-trust-goes-live-with-digital-record-system/"/>
        <updated>2024-06-10T07:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Belfast Health and Social Care Trust has announced that it has gone live with the encompass digital record system, replacing paper processes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>