<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html</id>
    <title>Industry Feed</title>
    <updated>2025-06-24T07:13:52.103Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://mbloomer04.github.io/feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA leaders back GPs declining to prescribe specialist medication]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=163010</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/bma-leaders-back-gps-declining-to-prescribe-specialist-medication/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T15:28:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctor leaders have voted in support of GPs declining to prescribe specialist medication in certain circumstances, including if initiated by non-prescribers, and demanded electronic prescribing is rolled out across the UK. At their annual representative meeting (ARM) in Liverpool today, BMA leaders passed a motion arguing that requests from secondary care clinicians asking GPs to
The post BMA leaders back GPs declining to prescribe specialist medication appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tobacco control efforts protect 6.1 billion people – WHO’s new report]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:ed95873b-68f2-4cb9-b4c1-ebce9f8edfab</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/23-06-2025-tobacco-control-efforts-protect-6.1-billion-people-who-s-new-report"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T14:19:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today released its report on the Global Tobacco Epidemic 2025 at the World Conference on Tobacco Control in Dublin, warning that action is needed to maintain and accelerate progress in tobacco control as rising industry interference challenges tobacco policies and control efforts.
The report focuses on the six proven WHO MPOWER tobacco control measures to reduce tobacco use, which claims over 7 million lives a year:

Monitoring tobacco use and prevention policies;
Protecting people from tobacco smoke with smoke-free air legislation;
Offering help to quit tobacco use;
Warning about the dangers of tobacco with pack labels and mass media;
Enforcing bans on tobacco advertising, promotion and sponsorship; and
Raising taxes on tobacco.

Since 2007, 155 countri…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients Know Best launches nationwide GP data integration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231731</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/patients-know-best-launches-nation-wide-gp-data-integration/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T12:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients Know Best (PKB) has launched GP data integration across England within its single patient record platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK warning over high levels of typhoid and malaria linked to travel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162637</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/uk-warning-over-high-levels-of-typhoid-and-malaria-linked-to-travel/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T11:55:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK public health officials have warned of a record high in reports of typhoid and paratyphoid fever associated with travel. Cases in 2024 jumped up 8% to 702 – the highest annual figure recorded to date, the UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) said. It comes amidst a raft of health warnings as people prepare to
The post UK warning over high levels of typhoid and malaria linked to travel appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Heather Ryan: How my own GLP-1 journey has reshaped patient consultations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=158639</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/dr-heather-ryan-how-my-own-glp-1-journey-has-reshaped-patient-consultations/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T11:43:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Heather Ryan shares her weight-loss journey as a GP using GLP-1 medication as primary care prescribing of tirzepatide for obesity begins this week Conflicts of interest declared: Dr Ryan co-owns a private GP clinic where her husband, but not herself, provides weight-loss services. She is also a member of the Nestle Nutrition Paediatric Advisory
The post Dr Heather Ryan: How my own GLP-1 journey has reshaped patient consultations appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National insurance costs threaten viability of GP practices, doctors warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922935</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/national-insurance-costs-threaten-viability-gp-practices-doctors-warn/article/1922935"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T11:29:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Increased employer national insurance costs that took effect from April threaten the viability of GP practices across the UK, doctors' leaders have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health and Social Care Secretary speech at RCOG World Congress]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/health-and-social-care-secretary-speech-at-rcog-world-congress</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/health-and-social-care-secretary-speech-at-rcog-world-congress"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T11:18:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health and Social Care Secretary Wes Streeting spoke at RCOG World Congress, announcing a national investigation into maternity and neonatal services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ADHD services should move to primary care, NHS taskforce recommends]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162965</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/adhd-services-should-move-to-primary-care-nhs-taskforce-recommends/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T10:44:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS’s official taskforce into ADHD has recommended that general practice takes a greater role in management of the condition, similar to diabetes care. The first report from the taskforce, commissioned by NHS England last year, recommends a shift to ‘accessible, regulated and generalist models of care in the community, including primary care and other
The post ADHD services should move to primary care, NHS taskforce recommends appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA calls for GMC to be replaced with new regulator ‘for doctors only’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162967</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/bma-calls-for-gmc-to-be-replaced-with-new-regulator-for-doctors-only/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T10:26:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has called for a new professional regulator for doctors, arguing that the GMC is failing to support doctors and patient safety. In a speech at the BMA annual representative meeting (ARM) in Liverpool this morning, council chair Professor Philip Banfield warned that the GMC’s approach to regulating physician associates (PAs) has led to
The post BMA calls for GMC to be replaced with new regulator ‘for doctors only’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers call for stronger regulation of period tracking apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231483</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/researchers-call-for-stronger-regulation-of-period-tracking-apps/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have warned that period tracking apps may compromise users’ privacy and reproductive autonomy.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National maternity investigation launched to drive improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/national-maternity-investigation-launched-to-drive-improvements</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/national-maternity-investigation-launched-to-drive-improvements"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T09:16:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The rapid national investigation into NHS maternity and neonatal services will provide truth to families suffering harm and urgently improve care and safety.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA demands new medical regulator to replace 'failing' GMC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922908</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-demands-new-medical-regulator-replace-failing-gmc/article/1922908"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T09:08:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has called for the creation of a new medical regulator, warning that the GMC is failing to protect patients and support doctors.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Introducing new medicines in the NHS in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/introducing-new-medicines-in-the-nhs-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/introducing-new-medicines-in-the-nhs-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T08:45:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A pathway summarising the processes pharmaceutical companies should follow when preparing to launch new products in the UK.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research: WorkWell Pilots Evaluation Feasibility Study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/workwell-pilots-evaluation-feasibility-study</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/workwell-pilots-evaluation-feasibility-study"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T08:30:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An assessment of feasibility of evaluation options for the WorkWell pilot programme programme]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherwood Forest selects Nervecentre as preferred EPR supplier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231475</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/sherwood-forest-selects-nervecentre-as-preferred-epr-supplier/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-23T07:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sherwood Forest Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust has selected Nervecentre as its preferred electronic patient record (EPR) supplier.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS web visits to heat exhaustion advice surge by nearly 200 per cent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268424</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-web-visits-to-heat-exhaustion-advice-surge-by-nearly-200/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T20:14:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visits to the heat exhaustion advice on the NHS website have increased by 198 pre cent as temperatures rise across England.  There have been 31,524 visits to the heat exhaustion and heatstroke web page in the 48 hours since a heat-health alert was introduced across most of England at midday on Wednesday, compared to 10,578 visits […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors warn assisted dying must not become 'core GP work' after Commons vote]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922798</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/doctors-warn-assisted-dying-not-become-core-gp-work-commons-vote/article/1922798"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T15:32:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have warned that assisted dying should never 'be deemed core GP work' after MPs backed the Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill at its third reading in the House of Commons.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: DHSC public appointments: 2025 to 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-public-appointments-2025-to-2026</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-public-appointments-2025-to-2026"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T15:04:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Non-executive appointments to the Department of Health and Social Care's public bodies and committees from April 2025 to March 2026.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Checker: Out-of-work GPs to be hired as physician associates’ assistants (PAAs)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162702</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/pulse-checker/pulse-checker-out-of-work-gps-to-be-hired-as-physician-associates-assistants-paas/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T14:53:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse Checker returns with its not-entirely-serious take on the month’s events. None of these stories are true (to the best of our knowledge) Ministers announce ‘Physician Associate’s Associate’ role to combat GP unemployment Out-of-work GPs will be able to apply for new jobs supporting the growing number of physician associates in general practice, under new
The post Pulse Checker: Out-of-work GPs to be hired as physician associates’ assistants (PAAs) appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most people think GPs ‘do not work hard enough’, ‘disheartening’ survey finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162907</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workload/most-people-think-gps-do-not-work-hard-enough-disheartening-survey-finds/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T14:48:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most people think GPs do not work hard enough, a nationally representative poll of attitudes towards general practice has revealed. In the survey commissioned by a specialist accountancy firm, which involved 2,000 people, only 23% said they believed GPs work hard enough. It also found just 31% of respondents think GPs should receive more support
The post Most people think GPs ‘do not work hard enough’, ‘disheartening’ survey finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New training code published for GPs on learning disability and autism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162890</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/new-training-code-published-for-gps-on-learning-disability-and-autism/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T14:29:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government has published a new code of practice to ensure consistency of training for health and social care providers looking after people with a learning disability or autism. It sets out the standards that any CQC-registered provider, including GP practices, will have to meet to be compliant with the law. The new code also
The post New training code published for GPs on learning disability and autism appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MPs back assisted dying bill in final Commons reading]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162939</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/mps-back-assisted-dying-bill-in-final-commons-reading/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T13:43:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs have voted to support the assisted dying bill in its final reading in the House of Commons today, following hours of debate. The draft legislation, which would allow terminally ill adults to end their lives, was initially backed by MPs in a vote in November and has gone through committee and report stages, with MPs debating amendments
The post MPs back assisted dying bill in final Commons reading appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VR improves patient experience at Leeds Children’s Hospital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231301</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/vr-improves-patient-experience-at-leeds-childrens-hospital/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T12:30:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Virtual reality technology at Leeds Children's Hospital is enabling young patients to undergo medical procedures without general anaesthetic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medway launches digital platform to help scale virtual hospital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231275</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/medway-launches-digital-platform-to-help-scale-virtual-hospital/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T12:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Medway NHS Foundation Trust has implemented a new digital platform as part of its strategy to scale its virtual hospital initiative.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England responds to ADHD Taskforce interim report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268418</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-england-responds-to-adhd-taskforce-interim-report/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T11:20:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An independent taskforce set up to tackle challenges in attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) care has published its interim report and recommendations today (Friday 20 June 2025). The report describes that the rates of recognised ADHD in England are lower than the expected prevalence and stresses the need for timely access to needs-based support. To […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only half of overseas doctors who moved to the UK say their expectations have been met]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162917</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/only-half-of-overseas-doctors-who-moved-to-the-uk-say-their-expectations-have-been-met/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T10:45:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Only half of doctors who qualified overseas and moved to the UK said that their expectations had been met, according to new research published by the GMC. Those unsatisfied with the move blamed heavy workload, stress and a poor work-life balance. The research, commissioned by the GMC, surveyed over 3,000 doctors between June and August
The post Only half of overseas doctors who moved to the UK say their expectations have been met appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speediatrics: What’s causing this infant’s widespread and intensely itchy rash?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162871</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/paediatrics/speediatrics-whats-causing-this-infants-widespread-and-intensely-itchy-rash/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T10:32:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next in our series of quick quizzes in paediatric care asks – what is the likely diagnosis in this case of a persistent, widespread and intensely itchy rash? AI was used to assist in creation of this article, with thorough review by our medical advisors before publication
The post Speediatrics: What’s causing this infant’s widespread and intensely itchy rash? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices told to appoint trained officer before using AI transcription tools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162878</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/gp-practices-told-to-appoint-trained-officer-before-using-ai-transcription-tools/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T10:21:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GP practices have been advised to appoint a ‘clinical safety officer’ (CSO) who has two days’ training before using any medical transcription tools – amid confusion around new NHS England guidance. A letter issued earlier this month by NHS England further developed its guidance on the use of ambient voice technology (AVT) – the
The post GP practices told to appoint trained officer before using AI transcription tools appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA warns GPs on the ‘substantial’ risks of AI scribing tools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231437</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/bma-warns-gps-on-the-substantial-risks-of-ai-scribing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The British Medical Association has advised that GPs should pause the use of AI scribing tools unless they have carried out safety checks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bradford Teaching Hospitals launches virtual access guides]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230973</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/bradford-teaching-hospitals-launches-virtual-access-guides/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T07:30:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bradford Teaching Hospitals, in partnership with AccessAble, has launched virtual access guides for visitors to Bradford Royal Infirmary.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government explores private funding for GP infrastructure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922628</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/government-explores-private-funding-gp-infrastructure/article/1922628"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government proposals to pay for new primary care infrastructure through public-private partnerships have sparked 'serious concerns' among GP leaders.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: What do we know about the 10-year NHS plan?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922605</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-know-10-year-nhs-plan/article/1922605"/>
        <updated>2025-06-20T06:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GPonline team discusses the spending review and looks at what the government's 10-year health plan might say about general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA sets out GP advice on Mounjaro prescribing due to launch next week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162898</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/bma-sets-out-gp-advice-on-mounjaro-prescribing-due-to-launch-next-week/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T15:18:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA has set out advice for the time and costs for GPs in setting up locally commissioned services to provide tirzepatide (Mounjaro) weight loss injections on the NHS. NICE interim commissioning guidance states that tirzepatide for weight loss must be implemented in primary care by 23 June 2025. ICBs have been tasked with getting
The post BMA sets out GP advice on Mounjaro prescribing due to launch next week appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ice slush drinks not suitable for children under seven, FSA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162888</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/ice-slush-drinks-not-suitable-for-children-under-seven-fsa-warns/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T14:51:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Food Standards Agency (FSA) has updated its advice that slush ice drinks containing glycerol are not suitable for children under seven. It follows research in the Archives of Diseases in Childhood earlier this year reporting 21 cases of children aged between two and seven years in the UK and Ireland who needed hospital treatment
The post Ice slush drinks not suitable for children under seven, FSA warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4673 - BeyondTrust Releases Security Advisory for Remote Support & Privileged Remote Access]]></title>
        <id>f723a117-4242-40fb-b12a-7e8f916edf65</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4673"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 A critical vulnerability in BeyondTrust remote access tools could lead to code injection
 A critical vulnerability in BeyondTrust remote access tools could lead to code injection
 Updated: 19 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Care for those with learning disabilities or autistic people]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/care-for-those-with-learning-disabilities-or-autistic-people</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/care-for-those-with-learning-disabilities-or-autistic-people"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:40:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New guidance published today will provide a boost in the quality of care for people with a learning disability or autistic people]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men's Health Strategy for England: call for evidence in British Sign Language]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence-in-british-sign-language</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence-in-british-sign-language"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We want to hear your views and ideas about men's health issues. Your ideas will help the government to make a Men's Health Strategy for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men's Health Strategy for England: call for evidence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:04:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This call for evidence is seeking the views of the public, as well as health and social care professionals, academics, employers and stakeholder organisations to inform a Men’s Health Strategy for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men's Health Strategy for England: call for evidence (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/mens-health-strategy-for-england-call-for-evidence-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T13:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We want to hear your views and ideas about men's health issues. Your ideas will help the government to make a Men's Health Strategy for England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New data laws will make life easier for British people, cutting life admin, easing traffic and speeding up roadworks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-data-laws-will-make-life-easier-for-british-people-cutting-life-admin-easing-traffic-and-speeding-up-roadworks</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-data-laws-will-make-life-easier-for-british-people-cutting-life-admin-easing-traffic-and-speeding-up-roadworks"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T12:34:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British people will benefit from new laws which will make their day-to-day lives easier – from slashing grocery bills and cutting traffic jams to speeding up NHS diagnoses – as the government delivers on manifesto commitments.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two national keynotes complete Summer Schools 2025 line-up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231563</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/two-national-keynotes-complete-summer-schools-2025-line-up/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T12:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two national keynotes have been added to the Digital Health Summer Schools 2025 conference programme, which has been published in full today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England publishes contractual GP ‘patient charter’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162861</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/nhs-england-publishes-contractual-gp-patient-charter/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T11:23:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has published the ‘patient charter’ which GP practices will need to display on their website, setting out the standard of care they are contracted to provide. As part of the GP contract changes for 2025/26, practices will be required to publish a ‘publicly accessible document’, which sets out ‘in black and white’ what
The post NHS England publishes contractual GP ‘patient charter’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical conundrum: Patient with treatment-resistant depression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162852</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/clinical-conundrum-patient-with-treatment-resistant-depression/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:53:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP and mental health specialist Dr Emma Nash explores the management options for a young adult male patient with recurrent depression that has not responded to three different medications and who is concerned about his drinking A 28-year-old man with a history of depression attends for follow up. He has suffered recurrent depression since his
The post Clinical conundrum: Patient with treatment-resistant depression appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230337</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-79/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Coffee Time includes PKB's contract to provide a single patient ecord (SPR) system to the state government of Lagos.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oliver McGowan draft code of practice (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oliver-mcgowan-draft-code-of-practice-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oliver-mcgowan-draft-code-of-practice-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We want to know if you think the guidance for training on learning disability and autism is good enough. This guidance is called a code of practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Policy paper: Explanatory memorandum on the Oliver McGowan code of practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/explanatory-memorandum-on-the-oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/explanatory-memorandum-on-the-oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explanatory memorandum to Parliament about the Oliver McGowan code of practice on statutory learning disability and autism training.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Oliver McGowan code of practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out standards for training on learning disability and autism for Care Quality Commission (CQC)-registered health and social care providers and their staff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Oliver McGowan code of practice (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/oliver-mcgowan-code-of-practice-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance about the training on learning disability and autism that health and care staff must do if they work in services registered with CQC in England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oliver McGowan draft code of practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oliver-mcgowan-draft-code-of-practice</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/oliver-mcgowan-draft-code-of-practice"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This consultation considers the draft code and if it gives CQC registered providers the guidance needed to meet the legislative requirement to ensure all staff receive learning disability and autism training appropriate to their role.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA ‘increasingly’ seeing non-GPs appointed as training programme supervisors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162841</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/education-and-training/bma-increasingly-seeing-non-gps-appointed-as-training-programme-supervisors/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:26:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive The BMA has raised concerns about the growing shortage of GP trainers and warned it is ‘increasingly’ seeing non-GPs appointed as training programme directors and supervisors. The union’s GP registrars committee said there are concerns that non-GPs are increasingly becoming involved in overseeing some aspects of GP training, including allied health professionals ‘who have
The post BMA ‘increasingly’ seeing non-GPs appointed as training programme supervisors appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs left to pick up pieces from ‘harmful’ filler and botox procedures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162822</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/dermatology-and-wound-care/gps-left-to-pick-up-pieces-from-harmful-filler-and-botox-procedures/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:18:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The national consumer watchdog has called on the Government to urgently regulate harmful aesthetic procedures such as botox and fillers, which leave GPs picking up the pieces. The Chartered Trading Standards Institute (CTSI), which promotes fair trading practices and protects consumers, issued a warning saying unregulated aesthetic procedures – such as fat injections, Brazilian Butt
The post GPs left to pick up pieces from ‘harmful’ filler and botox procedures appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NICE says another no to Alzheimer’s drugs in final draft guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162845</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/nice-says-another-no-to-alzheimers-drugs-in-final-draft-guidance/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:13:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NICE has once again rejected new drugs for early Alzheimer’s disease because the costs are too great to justify the small benefits. An independent committee had reviewed new evidence submitted as part of an ongoing consultation process but said it did not change their position on whether donanemab and lecanemab should be made available on
The post NICE says another no to Alzheimer’s drugs in final draft guidance appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 9,000 robotic surgeries completed at North Bristol NHS Trust]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231385</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/over-9000-robotic-surgeries-completed-at-north-bristol-nhs-trust/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 9,000 robotic surgeries have been completed to date at North Bristol NHS Trust, as the use of the technology across the NHS increases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crackdown urged as half of GPs see patients injured by aesthetic procedures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922533</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/crackdown-urged-half-gps-patients-injured-aesthetic-procedures/article/1922533"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T09:38:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have backed a crackdown on unregulated aesthetic procedures after polling by a medico-legal organisation found nearly half have treated patients injured by procedures such as botox, liposuction or dermal fillers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England unveils GP contract patient charter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922507</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-england-unveils-gp-contract-patient-charter/article/1922507"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T08:47:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has published a 'patient charter' outlining standards patients can expect from their GP practice, which practices will be required to publish on their website as part of this year's GP contract.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England unveils GP patient charter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922507</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-england-unveils-gp-patient-charter/article/1922507"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T08:47:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has published a 'patient charter' outlining standards patients can expect from their GP practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Care Alliance to roll out eDMS in partnership with Hyland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230945</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/northern-care-alliance-to-roll-out-edms-in-partnership-with-hyland/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T07:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Northern Care Alliance NHS Foundation Trust is rolling out an electronic document management system (eDMS) in partnership with Hyland.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO issues first global guideline to improve pregnancy care for women with sickle cell disease]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5966cd79-a116-4ae1-b70e-d274656f90ff</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/19-06-2025-who-issues-first-global-guideline-to-improve-pregnancy-care-for-women-with-sickle-cell-disease"/>
        <updated>2025-06-19T05:01:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today released its first-ever global guideline on the management of sickle cell disease (SCD) during pregnancy, addressing a critical and growing health challenge that can have life-threatening consequences for both women and babies.
SCD is a group of inherited blood disorders characterized by abnormally shaped red blood cells that resemble crescents or sickles. These cells can block blood flow, causing severe anaemia, episodes of severe pain, recurrent infections, as well as medical emergencies like strokes, sepsis or organ failures.
Health risks associated with SCD intensify during pregnancy, due to heightened demands on the body’s oxygen and nutrient supply. Women with SCD face a 4- to 11-fold higher likelihood of maternal death than those without. Th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders welcome ‘long overdue’ change in abortion law]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162825</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/gp-leaders-welcome-long-overdue-change-in-abortion-law/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T16:13:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP and BMA have welcomed the ‘long overdue’ changes of abortion laws in England and Wales following a vote in Parliament yesterday. MPs voted to ‘decriminalise’ abortion in an amendment to the Government’s Crime and Policing Bill, ensuring that women who have an abortion outside of the legal framework no longer face the threat
The post GP leaders welcome ‘long overdue’ change in abortion law appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Form: Child death reviews: forms for reporting child deaths]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-reviews-forms-for-reporting-child-deaths</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-reviews-forms-for-reporting-child-deaths"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T15:37:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forms to help child death overview panels (CDOPs) assess the causes of a child’s death as part of the child death review process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4762 - Proof-of-Concept Exploit Released for Pre-Auth RCE Chain in Sitecore Experience Platform]]></title>
        <id>751f97b8-6d15-46c7-9e31-dfb808de4e56</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4672"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T15:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security researchers have released a technical writeup which, with minimal modification, serves as a proof-of-concept exploit that could allow unauthenticated remote attackers to execute arbitrary code 
 Security researchers have released a technical writeup which, with minimal modification, serves as a proof-of-concept exploit that could allow unauthenticated remote attackers to execute arbitrary code 
 Updated: 18 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs need more than three strikes before we’re out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162812</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/gps-need-more-than-three-strikes-before-were-out/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T15:24:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield reflects on the impact of eponymous laws from grieving families on GPs, after NHS England’s primary care director spoke in favour of ‘Jess’s Law’ Another day, another eponymous law. This time, it’s Jess’s Law, the primary care version of Martha’s Rule. And that, in case you’ve forgotten, is NHSE’s guarantee that patients under hospital
The post GPs need more than three strikes before we’re out appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activist GP Dr Sarah Benn suspended for a further 12 months]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162817</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/activist-gp-dr-sarah-benn-suspended-for-a-further-12-months/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T14:31:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A retired GP who was suspended from the medical register after taking part in climate change protests should be suspended for a further 12 months, a tribunal has decided. Dr Sarah Benn, who took part in climate change protests at a Warwickshire oil terminal in 2022, was referred to the Medical Practitioners Tribunal Service (MPTS) for
The post Activist GP Dr Sarah Benn suspended for a further 12 months appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Pressure ulcers: how to safeguard adults]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/pressure-ulcers-how-to-safeguard-adults</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/pressure-ulcers-how-to-safeguard-adults"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T13:31:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to respond to individuals at risk of developing pressure ulcers, prevent harm where they occur and raise a safeguarding concern.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physiotherapy platform Phio goes live at 11 NHS organisations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231225</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/physiotherapy-platform-phio-goes-live-at-11-nhs-organisations/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T12:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eleven NHS organisations, including three primary care networks, have deployed Phio, a musculoskeletal triage and rehabilitation technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to chair ‘localities’ as part of ICB move to neighbourhood model]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162654</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/nhs-structures/gps-to-chair-localities-as-part-of-icb-move-to-neighbourhood-model/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T11:32:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GPs in Birmingham will be in charge of chairing health partnerships looking after 250,000 to 300,000 people, known as ‘localities’, as part of a move to a neighbourhood health service model. Birmingham and Solihull ICB has published its plans to roll out a neighbourhood health service model, which include splitting the area into six
The post GPs to chair ‘localities’ as part of ICB move to neighbourhood model appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP News Update: GPs ‘could run hospitals’, AI scribes, practices on the brink]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922387</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-news-update-gps-could-run-hospitals-ai-scribes-practices-brink/article/1922387"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T11:23:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Catch up quickly with our weekly round-up of key news stories for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4671 - Veeam Releases Security Updates for Backup & Replication and Windows Agent]]></title>
        <id>6d3619b8-976d-418e-88fc-7acd49c862fc</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4671"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T10:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security bulletin addresses critical severity vulnerabilities that could allow for remote code execution and privilege escalation
 Security bulletin addresses critical severity vulnerabilities that could allow for remote code execution and privilege escalation
 Updated: 18 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pitchfest 2022 winner CardMedic secures £411k Innovate UK grant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231135</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/pitchfest-2022-winner-cardmedic-secures-411k-innovate-uk-grant/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T10:00:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Pitchfest winner CardMedic has secured £411,000 from Innovate UK’s SMART grant programme for its healthcare language app.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICB boosts GP funding as NHS reforms take shape]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922365</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/icb-boosts-gp-funding-nhs-reforms-shape/article/1922365"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T09:14:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS leaders in Nottinghamshire have increased local enhanced services (LES) funding for GP practices and set out plans for a large-scale 'GP provider collaborative' to take on services moved out of hospital, as health service reforms begin to take shape.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public favours tiered system of access for single patient record]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230987</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/public-favours-tiered-system-of-access-for-single-patient-record/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-18T07:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The public believe that not all health professionals should have full access to a single patient record, according to research by NHSE.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS launches drive to catch one of the most lethal cancers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268215</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-launches-drive-to-catch-one-of-the-most-lethal-cancers/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of GP practices will comb patient records to offer urgent tests to people most at risk of pancreatic cancer, one of the deadliest forms of the disease. GP teams will scour online patients records to identify people over 60 who have the key early warning signs of pancreatic cancer including being recently diagnosed with […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom W</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs asked to case find pancreatic cancer via patient records]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162803</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cancer/gps-asked-to-case-find-pancreatic-cancer-via-patient-records/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS has launched a pilot scheme which will see GP practices asked to help identify patients most at risk of pancreatic cancer.  GPs will be asked to go through patient records to flag people over the age of 60 who have the early warning signs of pancreatic cancer. This includes being recently diagnosed with
The post GPs asked to case find pancreatic cancer via patient records appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of GP practices join pancreatic cancer early detection plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922173</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/hundreds-gp-practices-join-pancreatic-cancer-early-detection-plan/article/1922173"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 300 GP practices have joined a scheme to boost early detection of pancreatic cancer by checking patient records for warning signs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Professor Gillian Leng: ‘There’s nothing that says PAs are 100% safe in primary care’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162780</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/big-interviews/professor-gillian-leng-theres-nothing-that-says-pas-are-100-safe-in-primary-care/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T15:58:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a relaunch of Pulse’s ‘Big Interview’ series, editor Sofia Lind speaks to Professor Gillian Leng, leader of the Government’s review into physician associates (PAs). Commissioned by the health secretary in November, Professor Leng’s review has seen her engage with over 1,000 people to look into the safety and effectiveness of PAs in the workforce.
The post Professor Gillian Leng: ‘There’s nothing that says PAs are 100% safe in primary care’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 160 sessional GPs currently ‘seeking work’ in Scotland alone]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162789</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/nearly-160-sessional-gps-currently-seeking-work-in-scotland-alone/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T15:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 160 full-time equivalent salaried and locum GPs in Scotland are currently ‘seeking work’, a new BMA survey has revealed. The poll found that nearly half of GPs (44.58%) in Scotland say the future of their practice is ‘precarious’ or ‘not sustainable’, up 10% since 2023, and that many GPs are struggling to cope with
The post Nearly 160 sessional GPs currently ‘seeking work’ in Scotland alone appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4670 - Citrix Releases Security Updates for NetScaler ADC and NetScaler Gateway]]></title>
        <id>9d8eab47-cf8e-4dfc-8227-92dc9356cf96</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4670"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T15:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisory addresses two vulnerabilities that could lead to unauthorised access and memory overload
 Advisory addresses two vulnerabilities that could lead to unauthorised access and memory overload
 Updated: 17 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First keynote speakers announced for Digital Health Rewired 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231247</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/brotherton-and-power-first-keynotes-confirmed-for-rewired-2026/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T12:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Brotherton and Rachel Power have been confirmed as the first keynotes for Digital Health Rewired 2026.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO calls for global expansion of midwifery models of care]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5623bd5d-9728-4121-bb2f-8cddb1c9d292</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/18-06-2025-who-calls-for-global-expansion-of-midwifery-models-of-care"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T11:29:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO) today released new guidance to help countries adopt and expand midwifery models of care - where midwives serve as the main care provider for women and babies throughout pregnancy, childbirth, and the postnatal period.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CQC primary care inspector awarded high honour by King]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162781</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/cqc-primary-care-inspector-awarded-high-honour-by-king/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T10:43:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who was recently appointed as the new CQC chief inspector of primary care has been recognised in the 2025 King’s Birthday Honours list. Professor Bola Owolabi, a GP and director of inequalities at NHS England, was awarded a CBE ‘for her services to reducing health inequalities’.  She is currently director of the National
The post CQC primary care inspector awarded high honour by King appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230299</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-78/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T10:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This edition of Coffee Time includes the launch of a digital reminder service for medication intake and the UK's AI regulation under scrutiny.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Partners must ensure career progression for younger GP colleagues, says primary care lead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162768</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/partners-must-ensure-career-progression-for-younger-gp-colleagues-says-primary-care-lead/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T10:21:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is incumbent on GP partners to provide their younger, salaried GPs with a career structure outside partnerships, NHS England’s primary care director has said. Speaking at the NHS Confederation conference in Manchester last week, Dr Amanda Doyle told delegates that the ‘new generation of GPs don’t want to become a partner at 29’. She
The post Partners must ensure career progression for younger GP colleagues, says primary care lead appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Central London Community Healthcare goes live in NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231041</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/central-london-community-healthcare-goes-live-in-nhs-app/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T10:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Central London Community Healthcare NHS Trust has launched a pilot which enables patients to view their appointments in the NHS App.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs advised to stop using AI scribes without key assurances]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922151</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-advised-stop-using-ai-scribes-without-key-assurances/article/1922151"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T08:55:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should pause use of AI scribing tools unless they have carried out data protection and safety checks and sought assurances that products meet NHS standards, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ground robots to join London’s NHS drone delivery network]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231289</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/ground-robots-to-join-londons-nhs-drone-delivery-network/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-17T07:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Autonomous ground delivery robots are planned to join the drone delivery network in London to deliver NHS supplies.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The WHO Hub in Berlin: driving innovation to make the world safer from health threats]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:0e359b28-f5f3-4192-bdf6-02da28df08ff</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/17-06-2025-the-who-hub-in-berlin-driving-innovation-to-make-the-world-safer-from-health-threats"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T15:41:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building on lessons learned from the COVID-19 pandemic, the WHO Hub for Pandemic and Epidemic Intelligence in Berlin leverages innovative tools and collaborations for more effective disease surveillance worldwide. Just over three years after its inauguration, the Hub now supports over 150 countries in detecting health threats more effectively and rapidly. The Hub’s latest annual report highlights the growing impact of this work and provides key insights into progress made in 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physician associates introduced to NHS ‘without a clear vision’, says review lead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162742</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/physician-associates-introduced-to-nhs-without-a-clear-vision-says-review-lead/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T15:33:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Physician associates (PAs) were introduced into the NHS ‘without clear vision’ and workforce planning, the leader of the independent review has said. During an interview at Pulse LIVE Birmingham last week, Professor Gillian Leng suggested the rollout of PAs could have been handled better. Professor Leng, who is the former CEO of NICE, is
The post Physician associates introduced to NHS ‘without a clear vision’, says review lead appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-term desogestrel associated with small increased risk of meningioma]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162643</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/long-term-desogestrel-associated-with-small-increased-risk-of-meningioma/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T15:24:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Long-term use of the progestogen-only desogestrel contraceptive pill is linked to small increased brain tumour risk, researchers have concluded. However, the study of more than 92,000 patients found the risk was much lower than some other progestogens and disappeared one year after stopping treatment. The French researchers noted that prolonged use of several progestogens had
The post Long-term desogestrel associated with small increased risk of meningioma appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: Physician associate review lead Professor Gillian Leng; and how GPs should manage antidepressant withdrawal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162667</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/pulse-in-focus/podcast-physician-associates-review-lead-professor-gillian-leng-and-how-gps-should-manage-antidepressant-withdrawal/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T14:50:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next episode of Pulse in Focus: The Podcast for GPs is live and available wherever you get your podcasts from. Editor Sofia Lind and features assistant Maya Dhillon reflect on Sofia’s interview with Professor Gillian Leng – leader of the Government-commissioned review into PAs – at Pulse LIVE Birmingham last week. Ahead of the
The post Podcast: Physician associate review lead Professor Gillian Leng; and how GPs should manage antidepressant withdrawal appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Half of GPs in Scotland say their practice is 'on the brink']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1922057</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/half-gps-scotland-say-practice-on-brink/article/1922057"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T13:16:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly half of GPs in Scotland say their practice is at risk and that they are struggling to cope - but practices can't afford to hire scores of qualified GPs desperate for more work, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perci Health raises £3m to scale AI-powered virtual cancer clinic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230915</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/perci-health-raises-3m-to-scale-ai-powered-virtual-cancer-clinic/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T12:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Perci Health has raised £3m in its latest funding round supporting it to scale its AI-powered, multidisciplinary cancer care care clinic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over a third of GPs see patient health adversely affected by low literacy every week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162681</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/over-a-third-of-gps-see-patient-health-adversely-affected-by-low-literacy-every-week/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T10:44:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Over a third of GPs (37%) see patients whose health is adversely affected by low literacy every week, a Pulse survey has revealed. A poll of 731 GPs – conducted in conjunction with Channel 5 – found that every day 9% encounter patients having adverse health effects as a direct result of low literacy
The post Over a third of GPs see patient health adversely affected by low literacy every week appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS App feature will enable patients to sign up for clinical trials]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231181</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhs-app-feature-will-enable-patients-to-sign-up-for-clinical-trials/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T10:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will be able to browse and sign up to clinical trials via the NHS App, the Department of Health and Care (DHSC) has announced.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS App to match patients with clinical trials under 10-year health plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162701</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/nhs-app-to-match-patients-with-clinical-trials-under-10-year-health-plan/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T09:49:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will be able to register for clinical trials via the NHS App under new Government plans to revive the UK’s struggling research sector and speed up access to new treatments. The initiative, part of the forthcoming 10-year health plan, aims to significantly reduce trial set-up times, increase public participation in research, and boost the
The post NHS App to match patients with clinical trials under 10-year health plan appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS 10-year plan 'make or break' for general practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921951</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-10-year-plan-make-break-general-practice/article/1921951"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T09:43:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have urged the government to commit explicitly to a new contract for general practice in the upcoming 10-year NHS plan - warning that the government's health service blueprint will be 'make or break' for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS image bank of how conditions appear on different skin tones launched]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162696</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/paediatrics/nhs-image-bank-of-how-conditions-appear-on-different-skin-tones-launched/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T09:26:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A free NHS-funded image library showing how diseases appear on a range of skin tones has now been made live. GPs and other healthcare professionals can search through the bank of more than 3,000 high-resolution images to help them recognise signs of disease and illness. The Reframe initiative was funded by NHS England and led
The post NHS image bank of how conditions appear on different skin tones launched appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs recognised in King's birthday honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921931</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-recognised-kings-birthday-honours/article/1921931"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T08:11:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are among those who have been recognised in the King's birthday honours.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Reciprocal healthcare privacy notice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/reciprocal-healthcare-privacy-notice</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/reciprocal-healthcare-privacy-notice"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T07:57:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out how DHSC and NHSBSA collect and use personal information as part of the process of providing reciprocal healthcare.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overhaul of medical device regulations in UK takes effect]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231101</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/overhaul-of-medical-device-regulations-in-uk-takes-effect/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-16T07:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency’s (MHRA) has announced a major overhaul of how medical devices are regulated.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unprecedented boost for clinical trials under 10 Year Health Plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/unprecedented-boost-for-clinical-trials-under-10-year-health-plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/unprecedented-boost-for-clinical-trials-under-10-year-health-plan"/>
        <updated>2025-06-15T23:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions will take part in clinical trials under the 10 Year Health Plan which will speed up clinical research.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Responders to Southport attack among NHS staff receiving King’s Birthday Honours]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=268077</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/responders-to-southport-attack-among-nhs-staff-receiving-kings-birthday-honours/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T21:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS staff involved in the response to the Southport knife attack are among those being recognised in the 2025 King’s Birthday Honours list, released today (Friday 13 June). Sir Jim Mackey, Chief Executive at NHS England, said the awards highlight the “incredible dedication and commitment” of those who responded to the attack in July 2024. Paul […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: Birthday Honours 2025: Ambulance Service list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/birthday-honours-2025-ambulance-service-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/birthday-honours-2025-ambulance-service-list"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T21:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recipients of the King's Ambulance Service Medal 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blue-sky thinking is great, but not if it fails to reach the grassroots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162683</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/blue-sky-thinking-is-great-but-not-if-it-fails-to-reach-the-grassroots/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T15:56:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse editor-in-chief Jaimie Kaffash tells the tale of his trip to the land of NHS managers, also known as NHS Confed Expo, where he encounters a lot of blue-sky thinking I can’t speak NHS Manager. Despite living in the locality/neighbourhood/place since starting at Pulse in 2012, I never picked up the lingo. Sure, I know
The post Blue-sky thinking is great, but not if it fails to reach the grassroots appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spain strengthens global health leadership with increased support to WHO]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:573441db-70f2-40e5-9f18-0e8091831dec</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/13-06-2025-spain-strengthens-global-health-leadership-with-increased-support-to-who"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T15:52:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Spanish Agency for International Development Cooperation (AECID) and the World Health Organization (WHO) today signed a new agreement and contribution of €5.25 million to support key WHO initiative.
“Spain has long been a close and steadfast partner to WHO and global health," said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General. "We thank Spain for its increased flexible funding of our work, in doing so helping WHO be stronger and more independent and allowing us to deliver the services that countries and communities need from us.”
This year, Spain’s commitment to global health entered a new chapter as it returned to the WHO Executive Board for the 2025–2028 term, nearly two decades since its last membership. This renewed engagement is supported by the country’s new Global Health Strategy, launched on 27 May 2025.
This is underscored by today’s signing of a new agreement between Spain and WHO and a growing collaboration between both partners. At the heart of this effort is the Spanish Agency for International Development Cooperation (AECID), under the leadership of Mr Antón Leis; AECID has significantly stepped up flexible and strategic funding for WHO activities.
AECID's €5.25 million contribution to WHO is part of a broader €60 million pledge announced by Prime Minister Pedro Sánchez in November 2024. Spain’s multi-year commitment also includes support for critical health programmes in countries such as Jordan, Mali, and Sudan, as well as other global initiatives. 
Looking forward, Spain will host the 4th International Conference on Financing for Development (FFD4) in Seville, 30 June–3 July 2025, where it aims to elevate health financing as a core development priority. A high-level special event – co-sponsored by WHO and featuring leaders from global health, finance, and academia – will call for bold action through the “Health financing for a safe and sustainable economy: towards Seville health financing agenda for action.”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate protest GP’s fitness to practise ‘remains impaired’, tribunal rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162677</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/climate-protest-gps-fitness-to-practise-remains-impaired-tribunal-rules/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T15:07:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A tribunal has ruled that the fitness to practise of Dr Sarah Benn – a retired GP who was suspended after taking part in climate change protests – remains impaired. Dr Sarah Benn, who took part in climate change protests at a Warwickshire oil terminal in 2022, was referred to the Medical Practitioners Tribunal Service
The post Climate protest GP’s fitness to practise ‘remains impaired’, tribunal rules appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alzheimer’s Society Accelerator selects two dementia innovations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230471</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/alzheimers-society-accelerator-selects-two-dementia-innovations/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T12:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An app that monitors changes in dementia symptoms and a device that tracks dehydration are partners in the Alzheimer’s Society’s Accelerator.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS primary care lead supportive of GP ‘three strikes and refer’ rule]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162662</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/nhs-primary-care-lead-supportive-of-gp-three-strikes-and-refer-rule/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T11:26:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England’s clinical director of primary care has spoken out in support of a proposed ‘three strikes and escalate’ law, which would generate an automatic patient review after the third contact with their GP surgery about a specific symptom or condition. Speaking at the NHS Confederation conference in Manchester this week, Dr Claire Fuller said
The post NHS primary care lead supportive of GP ‘three strikes and refer’ rule appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaimie Kaffash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4669 - Active Exploitation of Critical RCE Vulnerability in Wazuh]]></title>
        <id>5cd2fb60-7bf6-45d6-8598-18b3ac9b7af6</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4669"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T11:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 CVE-2025-24016 could allow a remote, authenticated attacker to execute arbitrary Python code on the Wazuh server
 CVE-2025-24016 could allow a remote, authenticated attacker to execute arbitrary Python code on the Wazuh server
 Updated: 13 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New endometriosis training programme ‘boosted GP knowledge’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162647</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/new-endometriosis-training-programme-boosted-gp-knowledge/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T10:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new training programme in Wales is helping GPs to recognise the symptoms of endometriosis earlier, the Welsh Government says. The Endometriosis in Primary Care programme has led to a 43% improvement in knowledge of the condition among the GPs who have taken part so far. It is one of a range of training programmes
The post New endometriosis training programme ‘boosted GP knowledge’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs can now refer contaminated blood-affected patients for psychological treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162639</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/gps-can-now-refer-contaminated-blood-affected-patients-for-psychological-treatment/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T10:12:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients across England who were affected and infected by the contaminated blood scandal will now have access to bespoke psychological treatment. The Infected Blood Psychological Service first opened last September after a recommendation from the interim inquiry but was rolled out in phases. Those eligible for the service also include bereaved partners, parents, children, and
The post GPs can now refer contaminated blood-affected patients for psychological treatment appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital and community to take over from hospitals, says Streeting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=231011</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-and-community-to-take-over-from-hospitals-says-streeting/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T08:45:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS 10 year health plan will see digital, remote and neighbourhood care, taking over much of the role of hospitals, said Wes Streeting.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doccla teams with Gophr for same-day delivery of medical devices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230237</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/doccla-teams-with-gophr-for-same-day-delivery-of-medical-devices/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T07:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A partnership between Doccla and Gophr is supporting the rapid deployment of medical devices to patients and hospital sites to ensure vulnerable patients receive vital medical equipment promptly.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General practice must be 'cornerstone of neighbourhood NHS']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921657</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/general-practice-cornerstone-neighbourhood-nhs/article/1921657"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T06:31:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A neighbourhood NHS should involve all services in a local area that could help people manage their health and wellbeing better, founded on the 'cornerstone' of general practice, a leading GP has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: How does general practice fit into a neighbourhood NHS?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921582</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-does-general-practice-fit-neighbourhood-nhs/article/1921582"/>
        <updated>2025-06-13T06:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talking General Practice speaks to Dr Caroline Taylor, chair of the National Association of Primary Care and a GP in Calderdale, West Yorkshire, about how neighbourhood working benefits patients, GPs and practices - and how it could help the NHS shift its focus towards prevention.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS first in world to roll out new ‘trojan horse’ therapy for blood cancer patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267982</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-first-in-world-to-roll-out-new-trojan-horse-therapy-for-blood-cancer-patients/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T23:01:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS in England will be the first health system in the world to roll-out a ‘trojan horse’ targeted therapy for blood cancer patients which could halt the disease’s progression by nearly three times as long as existing treatments.  Around 1,500 patients a year with multiple myeloma – an incurable cancer of the bone marrow […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sickle cell patients to get better treatment after £9m boost]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/sickle-cell-patients-to-get-better-treatment-after-9m-boost</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/sickle-cell-patients-to-get-better-treatment-after-9m-boost"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients living with rare blood disorders to benefit from increased access to treatment and availability of services, thanks to £9 million investment.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing menstrual disorders in young women – key points for GPs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162528</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/managing-menstrual-disorders-in-young-women-key-points-for-gps/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T16:13:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the next in our series showcasing Pulse 365 Live and Virtual presentations, Dr Shona Biggart explains the key take-home messages for GPs in management of menstrual disorders in adolescent and young adult women Dysmenorrhoea and menorrhagia – early recognition and intervention Dysmenorrhoea affects approximately one in three women and is frequently undertreated. Primary dysmenorrhoea
The post Managing menstrual disorders in young women – key points for GPs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we have learned about retiring APIs]]></title>
        <id>13f419d4-1d3b-4957-b1c9-14ddae00dacc</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/tech-talk/2023/what-we-have-learned-about-retiring-apis"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T15:55:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Business analyst Matthew Firth gives an update on what NHS Digital has been doing to progress the API ‘sunsetting’ strategy to retire some of our APIs over the last year. 


Last year we published our blog ‘What happens when we ‘sunset’ our APIs?’ in which Munish Jokhani explained how we actively deprecate (where we advise of our intention to retire the API while retaining all existing service levels) and retire our APIs, and the effect this had on developers. By working with our suppliers and engaging them early in the process, we found that we were able to agree and align the retirement dates so that we met our suppliers’ requirements.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does good look like for APIs?]]></title>
        <id>7c853843-4b2d-4150-b4b4-dcbbcc648efb</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/tech-talk/2023/what-does-good-look-like-for-apis"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T15:54:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matthew Firth describes our best practice policies around APIs – and how the most important one is not about the technical aspects of the work.


For the past 3 years, we have been on a mission to make integration easier within the NHS for people building healthcare technology.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our vision for a new model of NHS care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/our-vision-for-a-new-model-of-nhs-care</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/our-vision-for-a-new-model-of-nhs-care"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T15:28:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health and Social Care Secretary spoke at NHS ConfedExpo 2025 in Manchester.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England GPs to call women for cervical screening every five years instead of three]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162633</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/england-gps-to-call-women-for-cervical-screening-every-five-years-instead-of-three/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T14:31:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS in England is changing cervical cancer screening intervals from three to five years for women aged 25 to 49 years who have a negative HPV test. From July, the changes will also mean that individuals whose sample indicates the presence of HPV or who have a recent history of HPV will continue to
The post England GPs to call women for cervical screening every five years instead of three appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse hosting free women’s health online event for GPs on Tuesday]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162582</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/pulse-hosting-free-womens-health-online-event-for-gps-on-tuesday/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T14:21:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs are invited to a free virtual conference held by Pulse 365 on women’s health on Tuesday 17 June. The event, worth five CPD hours, is one of Pulse 365’s ‘spotlight conferences’ which give GPs the opportunity to hear from experts in particular clinical areas. The conference agenda will feature discussions on hormonal shifts and
The post Pulse hosting free women’s health online event for GPs on Tuesday appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could run 'run local hospitals,' says Wes Streeting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921646</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-run-run-local-hospitals-says-wes-streeting/article/1921646"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T14:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should be able to run hospitals - but acute trusts could also take on primary care services as integration blurs traditional boundaries between parts of the NHS, the health and social care secretary has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs ‘should run local hospitals’ as part of NHS reform, says health secretary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162620</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/gps-should-run-local-hospitals-as-part-of-nhs-reform-says-health-secretary/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T13:05:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs ‘should be able to run local hospitals’ as part of a radical reform of the NHS, the health secretary has said.   During a speech at NHS Confederation Expo conference this afternoon, Wes Streeting said the NHS ‘should not be bound by traditional expectations of how services should be arranged’. He argued that acute
The post GPs ‘should run local hospitals’ as part of NHS reform, says health secretary appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Herefordshire and Worcestershire Health and Care rolls out Rio EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230753</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/herefordshire-and-worcestershire-health-and-care-rolls-out-rio-epr/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T12:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Herefordshire and Worcestershire Health and Care NHS Trust has rolled out the Access Rio electronic patient record (EPR) system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spending review allocations ‘will make or break general practice’, says GPC chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162618</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/spending-review-allocations-will-make-or-break-general-practice-says-gpc-chair/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T11:23:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS budget allocations following the Government’s spending review ‘will make or break general practice’, the BMA’s GP committee chair has said. Yesterday the chancellor specified GP training as a priority investment area while announcing a £29bn funding boost for the NHS until the end of this Parliament. According to the Treasury announcement, ‘thousands more GPs’
The post Spending review allocations ‘will make or break general practice’, says GPC chair appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4668 - Mitel Releases Security Advisory for MiCollab]]></title>
        <id>1dac23da-abc7-4af7-a408-82275eccd554</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4668"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T10:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Critical path traversal vulnerability could allow a remote unauthenticated attacker to perform unauthorised administrative actions
 Critical path traversal vulnerability could allow a remote unauthenticated attacker to perform unauthorised administrative actions
 Updated: 12 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs criticised by coroner for ‘not understanding’ medical examiner process]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162182</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-criticised-by-coroner-for-not-understanding-medical-examiner-process/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T10:46:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A London coroner has criticised GPs for ‘not understanding’ the medical examiner process and for making unnecessary death referrals. At a pre-inquest hearing for the death of a 94-year-old woman, senior coroner for east London Graeme Irvine said that the frequency with which doctors offer a cause of death ‘has declined considerably’ and that communications
The post GPs criticised by coroner for ‘not understanding’ medical examiner process appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229509</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-76/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T10:30:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's news roundup covers new interpreting systems in Walsall and pioneering virtual mental healthcare in Cambridgeshire and Peterborough.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE creating national population health management tool for FDP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230867</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhse-creating-national-population-health-management-tool-for-fdp/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T10:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE is working with NHS Frimley ICB to create a population health management tool which will run on the federated data platform (FDP).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS waiting list hits two-year low as staff work to ‘turn the tide’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267951</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-waiting-list-hits-two-year-low-as-staff-work-to-turn-the-tide/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T09:23:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS waiting list has fallen to its lowest level in two years, the first April drop since 2008*, as health chiefs hailed staff for continuing to tackle demand and drive progress for patients. New data published today shows that the NHS waiting list has fallen to 7.39 million, down from 7.42 million – the first time […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>nowen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EMIS and SystmOne dominance of GP IT a 'barrier to change', says government advisor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921528</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/emis-systmone-dominance-gp-barrier-change-says-government-advisor/article/1921528"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T08:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A senior government health advisor has blasted the EMIS and SystmOne 'duopoly' in GP IT system provision as a 'barrier to change' and warned that he is actively pushing for more competition.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital health sector reacts to ‘record’ investment in NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230815</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-sector-reacts-to-record-investment-in-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-12T07:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The digital health sector has reacted to the government's Spending Review, which included up to £10bn of investment in tech for the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘GP-centric’ 10-year plan ‘won’t come with big bag of money’, says NHS England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162609</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-centric-10-year-plan-wont-come-with-big-bag-of-money-says-nhs-england/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T15:53:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government’s upcoming 10-year plan for health will be ‘GP-centric’, but will not include huge shifts of funding from secondary to primary care immediately, NHS England’s director for primary care and community services has said. Speaking at the NHS Confederation conference in Manchester today, Dr Amanda Doyle said that she believes that the future for
The post ‘GP-centric’ 10-year plan ‘won’t come with big bag of money’, says NHS England appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['GP-centric' 10-year NHS plan will protect partnerships]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921502</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-centric-10-year-nhs-plan-will-protect-partnerships/article/1921502"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T14:57:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The upcoming 10-year NHS plan will be ‘very GP centric’ and health service leaders are 'committed to protecting partnerships', a senior NHS England official has said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government to invest up to £10bn to bring NHS ‘into the digital age’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230779</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/government-to-invest-up-to-10bn-to-bring-nhs-into-the-digital-age/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T14:55:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chancellor Rachel Reeves has announced that the government will invest £10bn in NHS tech, as part of the latest spending review.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spending review promises 3% annual funding rise for NHS and 'thousands more GPs']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921456</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/spending-review-promises-3-annual-funding-rise-nhs-thousands-gps/article/1921456"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T13:24:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS funding will rise by £29bn in real terms between 2023/24 and 2028/29 - a 3% average annual increase - including funding to train 'thousands more GPs', chancellor Rachel Reeves has announced in the government's spending review.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Thousands more GPs’ to be trained with spending review NHS funding boost]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162590</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/thousands-more-gps-to-be-trained-with-spending-review-nhs-funding-boost/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T12:53:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The chancellor has specified GP training as a priority investment area while announcing a £29bn funding boost for the NHS in today’s long-term spending review. According to the Treasury announcement, ‘thousands more GPs’ will be ‘trained’ with the money which will see real terms day-to-day spending on NHS services increase by 3% on average. Reporting
The post ‘Thousands more GPs’ to be trained with spending review NHS funding boost appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4667 - MicroDicom Releases Security Update for DICOM Viewer]]></title>
        <id>c5db2af3-0ed2-4bfe-be1c-5227a414aed1</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4667"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T12:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 CVE-2025-5943 could allow a remote unauthenticated attacker to execute arbitrary code on affected installations of DICOM Viewer
 CVE-2025-5943 could allow a remote unauthenticated attacker to execute arbitrary code on affected installations of DICOM Viewer
 Updated: 11 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP News Update: Including 10-year health plan, GP jobs crisis, RCGP partnership warning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921451</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-news-update-including-10-year-health-plan-gp-jobs-crisis-rcgp-partnership-warning/article/1921451"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T12:46:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Catch up quickly with our weekly round-up of key news stories for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4666 - Microsoft Releases June 2025 Security Updates]]></title>
        <id>36ea869b-558f-4dbc-a66c-132937e31e98</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4666"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T12:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products, including security updates for 66 vulnerabilities, of which 1 has been reported as actively exploited.
 Scheduled updates for Microsoft products, including security updates for 66 vulnerabilities, of which 1 has been reported as actively exploited.
 Updated: 11 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4665 - ConnectWise Releases Update to Rotate Code Signing Certificates for ScreenConnect, Automate and RMM]]></title>
        <id>49253ea7-c506-475a-a6a5-520d088fb078</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4665"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T10:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 ConnectWise has advised users of ScreenConnect or Automate "must update to the latest build and validate that all agents are updated before 13 June at 8:00pm ET [14 June at midnight UTC] to avoid disruptions or degraded experience."
 ConnectWise has advised users of ScreenConnect or Automate "must update to the latest build and validate that all agents are updated before 13 June at 8:00pm ET [14 June at midnight UTC] to avoid disruptions or degraded experience."
 Updated: 11 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10-year plan to overhaul GP incentives and 'completely reimagine' NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921423</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/10-year-plan-overhaul-gp-incentives-completely-reimagine-nhs/article/1921423"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T10:09:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The health service will be 'completely reimagined' under the forthcoming 10-year NHS plan, which will describe how contracts and incentives will be overhauled - potentially within the next 12 months - to drive collaboration between GPs and other providers, senior NHS leaders have said.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better Meds and BD partner to advance medication management]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230703</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/better-meds-and-bd-partner-to-advance-medication-management/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T10:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BD Pyxis automated dispensing cabinets are being integrated with Better Meds’ electronic prescribing and medicines administration (ePMA).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE projects 500k robotic assisted operations a year by 2035]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230687</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhse-projects-500k-robotic-assisted-operations-a-year-by-2035/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T10:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Half a million operations will be supported by robotic surgery every year by 2035, up from 70,000 in 2023/24, according to NHSE projections.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP concern at private out-of-hours provider enforcing ‘morally wrong’ targets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162493</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/urgent-care/gp-concern-at-private-out-of-hours-provider-enforcing-morally-wrong-targets/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T09:55:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive GPs working for a private out-of-hours (OOH) provider in the South West have raised serious concerns about new performance targets which they say are ‘morally completely wrong’.  HealthHero, a large digital health company which bought the OOH provider Medvivo in 2020, told its GP workforce in April that ‘allocation of shifts will go to
The post GP concern at private out-of-hours provider enforcing ‘morally wrong’ targets appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to start patients on heart failure drugs following updated NICE guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162586</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/gps-to-start-patients-on-heart-failure-drugs-following-updated-nice-guidance/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T09:38:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs can start treatment with certain heart failure drugs that previously had to be initiated by a specialist, NICE has said in updated guidance. Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) inhibitors and angiotensin receptor-neprilysin inhibitors (ARNIs) can for the first time be started by GPs, with advice from a heart failure specialist, potentially speeding up access, NICE said
The post GPs to start patients on heart failure drugs following updated NICE guidance appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency workers to be better protected from racial abuse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/emergency-workers-to-be-better-protected-from-racial-abuse</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/emergency-workers-to-be-better-protected-from-racial-abuse"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T09:23:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency workers will be better protected from violence and abuse when visiting homes as the government introduces new laws to support frontline staff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UPMC Ireland to implement MEDITECH Expanse EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230581</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/upmc-ireland-to-implement-meditech-expanse-epr/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T07:30:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global healthcare provider UPMC Ireland has confirmed it will implement the MEDITECH Expanse electronic patient record (EPR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in the dark as promised 4% pay rise yet to materialise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921263</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-dark-promised-4-pay-rise-yet-materialise/article/1921263"/>
        <updated>2025-06-11T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have yet to receive confirmation from the government on how or when a promised 4% pay increase for general practice in 2025/26 will be delivered, amid fears the uplift will fall short.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Millions to benefit from NHS robot drive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267837</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/millions-to-benefit-from-nhs-robot-drive/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T23:01:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of patients will benefit from cutting-edge NHS robotic surgery over the next decade as part of radical plans to cut waiting times. Half a million operations will be supported by the trailblazing approach every year by 2035, up from 70,000 in 2023/24, according to NHS projections. 9 in 10 of all keyhole surgeries, such […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our plan to improve the lives of people with ME/CFS (easy read)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/our-plan-to-improve-the-lives-of-people-with-mecfs-easy-read</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/our-plan-to-improve-the-lives-of-people-with-mecfs-easy-read"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T16:02:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government has written a plan to support people who live with myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed review of the statutory scheme for branded medicines pricing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/proposed-review-of-the-statutory-scheme-for-branded-medicines-pricing</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/proposed-review-of-the-statutory-scheme-for-branded-medicines-pricing"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T15:55:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This consultation seeks views on proposals to update the statutory scheme to control the cost of branded health service medicines.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fewer GPs taking advantage of partial retirement this year, NHS data shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162414</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/fewer-gps-taking-advantage-of-partial-retirement-this-year-nhs-data-shows/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T15:10:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fewer GPs are taking advantage of the option to partially retire this year, new NHS data has showed. According to data from a Freedom of Information (FOI) request to NHS Business Services Authority, 459 completed applications for partial retirement have been made by medical staff for the first five months of this year. This is
The post Fewer GPs taking advantage of partial retirement this year, NHS data shows appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS red tape blitz delivers game-changing new cancer treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nhs-red-tape-blitz-delivers-game-changing-new-cancer-treatment</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nhs-red-tape-blitz-delivers-game-changing-new-cancer-treatment"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T15:09:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients to benefit from new era in cancer treatment, as Government slashes red tape to unleash life-saving innovation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs providing continuity of care must be NHS priority, says CMO]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162576</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/scotland/gps-providing-continuity-of-care-must-be-nhs-priority-says-cmo/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T15:06:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Allowing GPs to provide continuity of care should be a priority for the NHS, Scotland’s Chief Medical Officer (CMO) has argued in his latest report. Professor Sir Gregor Smith, a GP and former medical director for primary care in NHS Lanarkshire, said that the NHS needs to recognise the ‘critical importance’ of continuity and relationship-based
The post GPs providing continuity of care must be NHS priority, says CMO appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS rolls out more personalised cervical screening for millions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267797</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/nhs-rolls-out-more-personalised-cervical-screening-for-millions/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T14:10:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More accurate human papillomavirus (HPV) testing will enable millions of women and people with a cervix in England to benefit from more personalised cervical screening from next month, the NHS has announced today. From July, younger women (aged 25 to 49) who test negative for HPV, meaning they are at very low risk of cervical […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>rwootton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland completes nationwide roll-out of Clinisys WinPath]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230565</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/northern-ireland-completes-nationwide-roll-out-of-clinisys-winpath/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T12:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A project to support the transformation of pathology services across all health and social care trusts in Northern Ireland has been completed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large numbers of GPs think physician associates should do vaccinations and health checks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162543</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/large-numbers-of-gps-think-physician-associates-should-do-vaccinations-and-health-checks/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T11:01:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Large numbers of GPs think physician associates (PAs) should be able to take on vaccinations and NHS health checks, a Pulse survey has revealed. GPs were asked what tasks they think PAs should be able to perform in general practice, including vaccinations, health checks, initiating investigations, managing chronic disease and doing physical examinations and
The post Large numbers of GPs think physician associates should do vaccinations and health checks appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK taxpayer cash 'training GPs for jobs in Australia', warns BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921233</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/uk-taxpayer-cash-training-gps-jobs-australia-warns-bma/article/1921233"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK taxpayers' money is training a generation of GPs to work overseas - because a shortage of jobs and low pay means there is no place for them in the NHS, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dapagliflozin shows promise in progressive liver disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162491</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/dapagliflozin-shows-promise-in-progressive-liver-disease/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T10:48:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diabetes drug dapagliflozin could also be beneficial for patients with progressive liver disease, a clinical trial has shown. A clinical trial of 154 adults with fatty liver disease or metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis (MASH) found a significant disease improvement in those taking the sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor compared with placebo. It follows several studies reporting that SGLT-2
The post Dapagliflozin shows promise in progressive liver disease appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229611</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-77/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T10:30:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's coffee briefing covers the launch of Calm Health in the UK and a campaign to inform the future of NHS radiology information systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation and Beamtree partner to launch AI data tool]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230421</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhs-confederation-and-beamtree-partner-to-launch-ai-data-tool/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS Confederation and Beamtree have partnered to roll out an AI and machine learning analytics platform.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP prescribing for chronic heart failure to expand under draft NICE guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921209</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-prescribing-chronic-heart-failure-expand-draft-nice-guidance/article/1921209"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T09:05:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs could prescribe a wider range of treatments for chronic heart failure under draft NICE guidance on diagnosis and management of the disease.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Commercial procurement pipeline for DHSC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/commercial-procurement-pipeline-for-dhsc</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/commercial-procurement-pipeline-for-dhsc"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T08:14:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A forecast of potential commercial activity over the next 48 months where spend is over £2 million.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs urged to 'wait for evidence' as urologists back scrapping digital rectal exams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921159</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-urged-wait-evidence-urologists-back-scrapping-digital-rectal-exams/article/1921159"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T08:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders have urged the profession to 'wait for the evidence' after surgeons said digital rectal exams are 'no longer a useful test for prostate cancer' and should be discontinued.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Irish startup to deploy clinical decision support tool in NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230445</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/irish-startup-to-deploy-clinical-decision-support-tool-in-nhs/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-10T07:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Irish health tech start-up xWave Technologies is partnering with three NHS trusts to deploy CDS, the company's clinical decision support tool.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands affected by contaminated blood scandal to get bespoke NHS psychological care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267738</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/thousands-affected-by-contaminated-blood-scandal-to-get-bespoke-nhs-psychological-care/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T23:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of people affected and infected by the contaminated blood scandal in England will be able to self-refer from today for psychological treatment from a bespoke new NHS service. The nationwide service, which began treating its first patients last September, will include access to talking therapies, peer support and psychosocial support, as well as other […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands affected by contaminated blood scandal to get bespoke NHS psychological]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267738</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/thousands-affected-by-contaminated-blood-scandal-to-get-bespoke-nhs-psychological/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T23:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of people affected and infected by the contaminated blood scandal in England will be able to self-refer from today for psychological treatment from a bespoke new NHS service. The nationwide service, which began treating its first patients last September, will include access to talking therapies, peer support and psychosocial support, as well as other […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Women and deprived communities undertreated for heart valve disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162483</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/women-and-deprived-communities-undertreated-for-heart-valve-disease/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T15:53:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Women and people from deprived communities with heart valve disease are less likely to be referred by their GP for specialist care, research has shown. Alongside those from ethnic minority groups, women are also less likely to have intervention for aortic stenosis, the study of more than 154,000 patient records concluded. Presenting the research at
The post Women and deprived communities undertreated for heart valve disease appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs no longer need to do rectal exam for prostate cancer, argue urologists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162534</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/renal-medicine-urology-mens-health/gps-no-longer-need-to-do-rectal-exam-for-prostate-cancer-argue-urologists/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T15:42:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs should no longer have to do rectal exams when trying to diagnose prostate cancer as it is a ‘poor test’ for detection, leading urologists have argued.  The British Association of Urological Surgeons (BAUS) has called for the end of digital rectal examinations (DRE) in men with suspected prostate cancer, denouncing its efficacy and necessity. 
The post GPs no longer need to do rectal exam for prostate cancer, argue urologists appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Younger GPs don’t know how good we used to have it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162388</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/david-turner/younger-gps-dont-know-how-good-we-used-to-have-it/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T14:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr David Turner turns the clock back 25 years to see what younger GPs are missing out on Being a GP is a lonely job most of the time. Yes, we have patients coming in every ten minutes or so, but in between that, most of us spend the time alone in our consulting rooms.
The post Younger GPs don’t know how good we used to have it appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fourth meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) Emergency Committee regarding the upsurge of mpox 2024 – Temporary recommendations]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:469f3b4b-eeb6-4e01-886a-04cc9d874cd0</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/09-06-2025-fourth-meeting-of-the-international-health-regulations-(2005)-emergency-committee-regarding-the-upsurge-of-mpox-2024-temporary-recommendations"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T13:55:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Director-General of the World Health Organization (WHO), following the fourth meeting of the International Health Regulations (2005) (IHR) Emergency Committee regarding the upsurge of mpox 2024, held on 5 June 2025, from 12:00 to 17:00 CEST, concurs with its advice that the event continues to meet the criteria of a public health emergency of international concern and, considering the advice of the Committee, he is hereby issuing a revised set of temporary recommendations.
The WHO Director-General expresses his most sincere gratitude to the Chair, Members, and Advisors of the Committee. The proceeding of the fourth meeting of the Committee will be shared with States Parties to the IHR and published in the coming days.
---------
Temporary recommendations
These temporary recommendations a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients to receive reminders and test results through NHS App first]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230519</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/patients-to-receive-reminders-and-test-results-through-nhs-app-first/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T12:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will receive appointment reminders, screening invitations and test results through the NHS App, as part of a £50 million upgrade.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health visitors to administer some childhood vaccinations to boost uptake, says NHSE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162529</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/health-visitors-to-administer-some-childhood-vaccinations-to-boost-uptake-says-nhse/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T10:56:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health visitors will be used to boost uptake of childhood vaccination from next year, NHS England has said. This forms part of plans to reduce pressure on A&E departments, unveiled in last week’s urgent and emergency care plan. Pilots of health visitors doing catch-up vaccinations were first announced last year, although the new plans appear
The post Health visitors to administer some childhood vaccinations to boost uptake, says NHSE appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP jobs advertised at lower salaries than a decade ago, BMA says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1921057</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-jobs-advertised-lower-salaries-decade-ago-bma-says/article/1921057"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T10:49:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP roles are being advertised with salaries ‘drastically’ lower than they were a decade ago, leading GPs have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More patients to get test results and appointment reminders via NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162525</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/more-patients-to-get-test-results-and-appointment-reminders-via-nhs-app/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T10:14:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions more patients will receive appointment reminders, screening invitations and test results via the NHS App, avoiding the need for ‘at least 50 million letters’, the Government has said. In latest expansion of the app, push notifications will remind patients about upcoming appointments and relay important messages, in a bid to reduce the risk of
The post More patients to get test results and appointment reminders via NHS App appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northampton General Hospital to launch Nervecentre EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230313</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/northampton-general-hospital-to-launch-nervecentre-epr/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T10:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northampton General Hospital (NGH) NHS Trust has announced the go live date for its Nervecentre electronic patient record (EPR) system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mounjaro primary care plans not yet finalised despite looming deadline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162439</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/mounjaro-primary-care-plans-not-yet-finalised-despite-looming-deadline/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T09:57:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive Many areas in England have not yet finalised plans for tirzepatide (Mounjaro) delivery in primary care, despite the NICE deadline being less than three weeks away. In response to a Pulse request to all 42 ICBs, only eight areas could confirm which model they will use to implement the NICE recommendation for tirzepatide prescribing
The post Mounjaro primary care plans not yet finalised despite looming deadline appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital trust hands back GP contracts as part of NHS neighbourhood shift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920916</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/hospital-trust-hands-back-gp-contracts-part-nhs-neighbourhood-shift/article/1920916"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T08:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three GP practices run by a hospital trust will be better placed to deliver 'joined-up care closer to home' now that the trust has agreed to step back from running them, an ICB has suggested.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flo Health adopts Databricks platform to power analytics and AI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230209</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/flo-health-adopts-databricks-platform-to-power-analytics-and-ai/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-09T07:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FemTech firm Flo Health  has adopted a data intelligence platform from Databricks to power its analytics and AI initiatives.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients to receive reminders and test results via the NHS App]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/patients-to-receive-reminders-and-test-results-via-the-nhs-app</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/patients-to-receive-reminders-and-test-results-via-the-nhs-app"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions more patients will receive appointments, screening invitations and other important information via the NHS App, as part of £50million upgrade.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A digital-first approach to patient communications]]></title>
        <id>b27d3486-2040-48b6-8ddc-237e996b3e57</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/transformation-blog/2025/a-digital-first-approach-to-patient-communications"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T15:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe and Pete explain the greater emphasis being placed on digital patient messaging across the NHS and the potential to provide a more seamless experience for patients, reduce the number of missed appointments and save the NHS money. 


This week, the Secretary of State announced the start of our journey to becoming a "digital first NHS" – here is what it means for you.


In other aspects of our lives, it's second nature to receive messages digitally. Think online bank statements, email receipts for our online shopping or text messages confirming our home deliveries have arrived. But for various reasons, the NHS has found this challenging, and we still send out millions of letters to patients each year.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A digital-first approach to patient communications]]></title>
        <id>b27d3486-2040-48b6-8ddc-237e996b3e57</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/transformation-blog/2025/a-digital-first-approach-to-patient-communications"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T15:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe and Pete explain the greater emphasis being placed on digital patient messaging across the NHS and the potential to provide a more seamless experience for patients, reduce the number of missed appointments and save the NHS money. 


This week, the Secretary of State announced the start of our journey to becoming a "digital first NHS" – here is what it means for you.


In other aspects of our lives, it's second nature to receive messages digitally. Think online bank statements, email receipts for our online shopping or text messages confirming our home deliveries have arrived. But for various reasons, the NHS has found this challenging, and we still send out millions of letters to patients each year.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP calls on Government to ‘break down barriers’ to GP partnership]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162513</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/rcgp-calls-on-government-to-break-down-barriers-to-gp-partnership/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T14:25:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RCGP has called on the Government to take action to ‘break down barriers’ to GP partnership, amid concern that a recent decline in partner numbers could destabilise the model entirely. In a new report published today, the college said it has been considering the future of the partnership model, as GP partner numbers have
The post RCGP calls on Government to ‘break down barriers’ to GP partnership appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP partnership model needs help to remain a realistic option, warns RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920976</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-partnership-model-needs-help-remain-realistic-option-warns-rcgp/article/1920976"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T13:31:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GP partnership model needs support to remain a realistic option for general practice, according to an RCGP report that highlights its strengths but flags concern over falling numbers of partners.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If we say goodbye to physician associates in general practice, what next?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162502</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/editors-blog/if-we-say-goodbye-to-physician-associates-in-general-practice-what-next/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T13:14:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor Sofia Lind on what comes after the ‘physician associates in general practice’ debate, ahead of Professor Leng’s interview at Pulse LIVE next week The debate over physician associates (PAs) in general practice may finally be drawing to a close. The safety review led by Professor Gillian Leng was expected to report at the start
The post If we say goodbye to physician associates in general practice, what next? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Scotland publishes £206m tender for cloud integration solution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230071</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhs-scotland-publishes-206m-tender-for-cloud-integration-solution/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T12:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Scotland has published a tender worth £206m seeking a cloud solution and systems implementer as part of a software-as-a-service overhaul.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cold sore virus linked to Alzheimer’s disease in large study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162077</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/cold-sore-virus-linked-to-alzheimers-disease-in-large-study/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T10:52:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Symptomatic infection with cold sore virus herpes simplex 1 may be implicated in the development of Alzheimer’s disease, researchers have reported. A study published in BMJ Open also found that treatment with antiviral therapy appears to be associated with a lower risk of the condition. The research done on 700,000 patients from US database of
The post Cold sore virus linked to Alzheimer’s disease in large study appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integrated neighbourhood team pilot frees up thousands of GP appointments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920681</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/integrated-neighbourhood-team-pilot-frees-thousands-gp-appointments/article/1920681"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T10:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An ICB has slashed GP appointments by a third among high-intensity patients by monitoring them and offering targeted support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newcastle Hospitals to create data platform for medical research]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230261</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/promptly-and-newcastle-hospitals-to-unlock-existing-nhs-data/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T10:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Promptly Health and Flatiron have been selected by Newcastle Hospitals NHS FT to help support the transformation of its dataset.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cora Lydon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-awaited urgent care plan completely overlooks general practice, GPs warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162474</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/urgent-care/long-awaited-urgent-care-plan-completely-overlooks-general-practice-gps-warn/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T09:34:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government’s plan to reform urgent and emergency care is a ‘huge missed opportunity’ as it fails to offer proposals or funding to increase capacity in general practice, GP leaders have warned. Announcing the plan today, the Department of Health and Social Care said it wants to ‘shift more patient care’ into ‘more appropriate care
The post Long-awaited urgent care plan completely overlooks general practice, GPs warn appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the month: What’s the diagnosis in this withdrawn child who ‘can’t shake off a bug’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162463</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/paediatrics/case-of-the-month-whats-the-diagnosis-in-this-withdrawn-child-who-cant-shake-off-a-bug/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T09:21:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the next in our series, Dr David Capehorn asks what might be the underlying cause in a child who is withdrawn and lethargic several weeks after apparent gastroenteritis. Put your suggestions in the comments below – answer to be revealed soon! Note details of the case have been changed to protect individuals’ identities A
The post Case of the month: What’s the diagnosis in this withdrawn child who ‘can’t shake off a bug’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movers and Shakers news roundup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230217</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/movers-and-shakers-news-roundup-60/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T07:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our latest Movers and Shakers roundup features Joe Harrison joining NHS Supply Chain and Tom Kibasi joining NHS England.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: GP pay rise, job prospects for the next generation, NI contract imposed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920755</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-gp-pay-rise-job-prospects-next-generation-ni-contract-imposed/article/1920755"/>
        <updated>2025-06-06T07:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GPonline team discusses the key news stories affecting general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New ambulances and faster emergency care for patients next winter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267657</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/new-ambulances-and-faster-emergency-care-for-patients-next-winter/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T23:01:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will receive better, faster and more appropriate emergency care as the government sets out reforms to shorten waiting times and tackle persistently failing trusts. The new package of investment and reforms will improve patients’ experiences this year, including by caring for more patients in the community, rather than in hospital which is often worse […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New ambulances and faster emergency care for patients next winter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-ambulances-and-faster-emergency-care-for-patients-next-winter</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-ambulances-and-faster-emergency-care-for-patients-next-winter"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patients will receive better, faster and more appropriate emergency care as the government sets out reforms to shorten waiting times in A&E.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[£450m urgent care plan 'wrong solution' amid GP jobs crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920796</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/450m-urgent-care-plan-wrong-solution-amid-gp-jobs-crisis/article/1920796"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have questioned a £450m government plan to expand urgent and emergency care - warning the proposals are a missed opportunity to boost capacity in general practice by creating jobs for thousands of out-of-work GPs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO calls for urgent protection of Nasser Medical Complex and Al-Amal Hospital in the Gaza Strip]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5a669a79-5599-4a32-814b-3a4dc74f0161</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/05-06-2025-who-calls-for-urgent-protection-of-nasser-medical-complex-and-al-amal-hospital-in-the-gaza-strip"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T20:35:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO warns that the Gaza Strip’s health system is collapsing, with Nasser Medical Complex, the most important referral hospital left in Gaza, and Al-Amal Hospital at risk of becoming non-functional. There are already no hospitals functioning in the north of Gaza. 
Nasser and Amal are the last two functioning public hospitals in Khan Younis, where currently most of the population is living. Without them, people will lose access to critical health services. 
While these hospitals have not received orders to evacuate patients or staff, they lie within or just outside the evacuation zone announced on 2 June. Israeli authorities have informed the Ministry of Health that access routes leading to both hospitals will be obstructed. As a result, safe access for new patients and staff will be difficu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: NHS injury costs recovery scheme: April 2025 to March 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-injury-costs-recovery-scheme-april-2025-to-march-2026</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nhs-injury-costs-recovery-scheme-april-2025-to-march-2026"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T16:25:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data on the funds collected by the Compensation Recovery Unit and funds paid to the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complicated contraception: Family history as a risk factor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162433</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/complicated-contraception-family-history-as-a-risk-factor/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T16:10:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the third and final part of our mini-series on difficult contraception prescribing scenarios, Dr Toni Hazell discusses the issues to consider in a woman with a family history which may be relevant to her contraception choice What family history should we routinely take when prescribing contraception? The reason for taking a history before prescribing
The post Complicated contraception: Family history as a risk factor appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mollie Fraser-Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practice appeals ICB decision to award its APMS contract to private provider]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162443</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/gp-practice-appeals-icb-decision-to-award-its-apms-contract-to-private-provider/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T15:37:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors running a GP practice in Brighton are appealing the decision by the local ICB to transfer their APMS contract to a private provider. Wellsbourne Healthcare, a community interest company set up in 2018 by doctors and nurses working in the area, has been running the practice in Whitehawk for the past seven years. As
The post GP practice appeals ICB decision to award its APMS contract to private provider appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ongoing measles outbreaks could surge in summer, UKHSA warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162449</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/respiratory/ongoing-measles-outbreaks-could-surge-in-summer-ukhsa-warns/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T14:57:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health officials have warned of a potential surge of measles cases in the summer holidays as outbreaks continue around the country. The UK Health Security Agency (UKHSA) said there were 109 cases of measles confirmed in April and 86 so far in May across England. Most cases have been in unvaccinated children aged 10 years
The post Ongoing measles outbreaks could surge in summer, UKHSA warns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4664 - Cisco Releases Security Advisory Affecting Cisco Identity Service Engine]]></title>
        <id>a31fe87b-965a-410d-abae-535543ce5bae</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4664"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Advisory addresses a critical severity vulnerability in Cisco Identity Service Engine which could be exploited to allow a remote attacker to achieve high-level access
 Advisory addresses a critical severity vulnerability in Cisco Identity Service Engine
 Updated: 05 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tackling modern slavery in NHS procurement: proposed regulations and guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/tackling-modern-slavery-in-nhs-procurement-proposed-regulations-and-guidance</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/consultations/tackling-modern-slavery-in-nhs-procurement-proposed-regulations-and-guidance"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T12:48:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government is inviting views on the draft National Health Service (Procurement, Slavery and Human Trafficking) Regulations 2024 and accompanying guidance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mental health trust awards DrDoctor £572k patient portal contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230189</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/mental-health-trust-awards-drdoctor-572k-patient-portal-contract/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T12:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greater Manchester Mental Health NHS Foundation Trust (GMMH) has awarded a patient engagement portal contract worth £572,000 to DrDoctor.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229483</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-75/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T10:30:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Coffee Time Briefing covers DocHQ's partnership with First Point Physio and a new milestone for MyFrimleyHealth Record.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physician associates take up GP training opportunities, BMA warns NHS England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162425</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/education-and-training/physician-associates-take-up-gp-training-opportunities-bma-warns-nhs-england/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T10:18:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Physician associates are taking up training opportunities that could be offered to GPs instead, the BMA has warned. In its submission to NHS England’s review of all postgraduate medical training, including GP programmes, the union warned that PAs and anaesthesia associates are ‘taking training opportunities that could be offered to medical students or doctors’. It
The post Physician associates take up GP training opportunities, BMA warns NHS England appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Medicines eligible for Northern Ireland MHRA Authorised Route]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/medicines-eligible-for-northern-ireland-mhra-authorised-route"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T10:18:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out medicines that can be moved to Northern Ireland to meet patient need.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MHRA launches digital hub in Leeds to drive innovation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230153</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/mhra-launches-digital-hub-in-leeds-to-drive-innovation/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T10:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) has launched a digital hub in Leeds to advance innovation and growth.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs working unpaid sessions to avoid losing their licence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920682</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-working-unpaid-sessions-avoid-losing-licence/article/1920682"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T09:45:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unemployed GPs are working sessions for free to avoid losing their licence to practise and to try to prevent long gaps on their CVs, doctors' leaders have warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MHRA issues warning on contraception use alongside weight-loss injections]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162420</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/womens-health-gynaecology-obstetrics/mhra-issues-warning-on-contraception-use-alongside-weight-loss-injections/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T09:38:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The medicines regulator has issued new guidance warning women taking weight-loss injections to ensure they are also using effective contraception. While the information is already contained in patient information leaflets, the alert raises concerns that with many women purchasing the drugs online, they may not be aware of the risks. In particular, women taking tirzepatide
The post MHRA issues warning on contraception use alongside weight-loss injections appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expand your knowledge in managing comorbidity: join the PrimaryCareLearnings 2025 pre-event webinar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1917069</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/expand-knowledge-managing-comorbidity-join-primarycarelearnings-2025-pre-event-webinar/article/1917069"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join our expert speaker, Dr Anish Kotecha, GP, for the PrimaryCareLearnings 2025 pre-event webinar – Proactive practice: integrating preventive health and comorbidity management in primary care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Adult social care in England statistics: background quality and methodology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/adult-social-care-in-england-statistics-background-quality-and-methodology"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T08:30:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) puts together the data in its monthly reports.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Official Statistics: Adult social care in England, monthly statistics: June 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-june-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/adult-social-care-in-england-monthly-statistics-june-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T08:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Official statistics on a range of topics including occupancy and infection control measures in adult social care settings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE cancels £69m eBCMS programme to fund more EPRs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230117</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhse-cancels-69m-ebcms-programme-to-fund-more-eprs/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T07:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has cancelled a £69m electronic bed capacity management systems (eBCMS) programme to fund more electronic patient records (EPRs).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notice: Life Sciences Healthcare Goals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/life-sciences-healthcare-goals</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/life-sciences-healthcare-goals"/>
        <updated>2025-06-05T07:28:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bringing together industry, academia, the third sector and the NHS to tackle healthcare challenges such as dementia, cancer, mental health, obesity and addiction.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One in 20 Northern Ireland GP practices hand back contract over two years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162373</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/northern-ireland/one-in-20-northern-ireland-gp-practices-hand-back-contract-over-two-years/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T14:59:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than one in 20 GP practices in Northern Ireland have handed back their contracts over the last two years, according to the Government.  Speaking in the Assembly, health minister Mike Nesbitt said there have been 16 hand-backs over the financial years 2023/24 and 2024/25. BMA NI GP Committee chair Dr Frances O’Hagan confirmed to
The post One in 20 Northern Ireland GP practices hand back contract over two years appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Public health commissioning in the NHS: 2025 to 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/public-health-commissioning-in-the-nhs-2025-to-2026</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/public-health-commissioning-in-the-nhs-2025-to-2026"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T14:52:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information about NHS England's objectives and funding arrangements as it commissions public health services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bullshit bureaucracy is back to block the system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162403</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/bullshit-bureaucracy-is-back-to-block-the-system/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T14:49:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield harangues the red tape and bureaucracy getting in the way of him doing his job Maybe I just dreamed it. But you know that viral phase we all went through a few years back? Wasn’t that supposed to herald a new and ongoing era of all overbearing and soul-destroying GP regulation/bureaucracy etc. being trashed?
The post Bullshit bureaucracy is back to block the system appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Restricting advertising of less healthy food or drink on TV and online: products in scope]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/restricting-advertising-of-less-healthy-food-or-drink-on-tv-and-online-products-in-scope</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/restricting-advertising-of-less-healthy-food-or-drink-on-tv-and-online-products-in-scope"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T14:28:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Outlines the provisions of the Advertising (Less Healthy Food Definitions and Exemptions) Regulations 2024 which will come into force on 5 January 2026.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4663 - Roundcube Releases Security Updates for Webmail]]></title>
        <id>102d9437-a48d-4672-a1f8-75c365186285</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4663"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T13:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Updates address a vulnerability that could lead to authenticated remote code execution
 Security update addresses a critical severity security vulnerability in Roundcube Webmail
 Updated: 04 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Older people have increased risk of postural hypotension in first month of antidepressants]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162062</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/older-people-have-increased-risk-of-postural-hypotension-in-first-month-of-antidepressants/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T13:13:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Older people have a substantially increased risk of postural hypotension in the first month after starting antidepressants, researchers have found. GPs may want to monitor patients over 65 years more closely when they initiate antidepressant prescriptions, particularly those who are on many other medicines, the researchers said. The study looked at patient records from 41,000
The post Older people have increased risk of postural hypotension in first month of antidepressants appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer Schools 2025 draft programme published]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230091</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/summer-schools-2025-draft-programme-published/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T12:30:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The highly anticipated programme for Digital Health Summer Schools 2025 has been published in draft, featuring leading CIOs, CCIOs and CNIOs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP News Update: Including NHS pauses AI project, GPs miss out on compensation, practice funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920539</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-news-update-including-nhs-pauses-ai-project-gps-miss-compensation-practice-funding/article/1920539"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T11:58:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Catch up quickly with our weekly round-up of key news stories for general practice]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Funding for advice and guidance DES insufficient, GPs warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920521</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/funding-advice-guidance-des-insufficient-gps-warn/article/1920521"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T11:04:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fewer than one in four GPs and practice managers believe funding for the advice and guidance DES is enough to cover the work involved, a GPonline poll has found.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transparency data: DHSC: workforce management information March 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-march-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/dhsc-workforce-management-information-march-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T10:40:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reports on departmental staff numbers and costs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physician associates ‘likely to be renamed’ after safety review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162393</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/physician-associates-likely-to-be-renamed-after-safety-review/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T10:24:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government-commissioned safety review of physician associates will reportedly conclude that their title should be changed to avoid patient confusion. This morning, the Guardian reported that the Government is likely to accept Professor Gillian Leng’s review findings on a title change, which could lead to PAs being renamed ‘physician assistants’ – their original title in
The post Physician associates ‘likely to be renamed’ after safety review appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse journalist wins award for delving behind  misleading GP headlines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162391</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/pulse-journalist-wins-award-for-delving-behind-misleading-gp-headlines/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T10:21:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pulse’s features assistant Maya Dhillon has won a prestigious award for her ‘important’ journalism, shining a light on the negative impact of misleading GP headlines. At the British Society of Magazine Editors Talent Awards yesterday evening, Maya took home the Unsung Hero award, celebrating the ‘secret powerhouses’ of magazine and digital media brands. The judges
The post Pulse journalist wins award for delving behind  misleading GP headlines appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI project to predict health outcomes paused over GP data concern]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230051</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/ai-project-to-predict-health-outcomes-paused-over-gp-data-concern/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T10:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE has paused development of an AI model capable of predicting future health outcomes after concerns about the use of GP patient data.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One year in detention: heads of United Nations agencies and INGOs renew demand for release of staff detained in northern Yemen]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:5757e0c3-1684-4801-9ed0-d7fc163f2566</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/03-06-2025-one-year-in-detention--heads-of-united-nations-agencies-and-ingos-renew-demand-for-release-of-staff-detained-in-northern-yemen"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T09:35:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week marks one year since dozens of personnel from the United Nations, nongovernmental and civil society organizations, and diplomatic missions were arbitrarily detained by the Houthi de facto authorities in northern Yemen. Others have been detained since as far back as 2021. Today, we reiterate our urgent demand for their immediate and unconditional release.
As of today, 23 UN and five international nongovernmental organizations (INGOs) personnel remain arbitrarily detained. Tragically, one UN staff member and another from Save the Children have died in detention. Others have lost loved ones while being held, denied the chance to attend their funerals or say goodbye.   Our arbitrarily detained colleagues have spent at least 365 days – and for some, over 1000 days – isolated from thei…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA warning over advice and guidance DES limit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920444</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/bma-warning-advice-guidance-des-limit/article/1920444"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T08:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices that come under pressure locally to use advice and guidance 'over and above' agreed levels should flag the problem with their LMC or GP committee leaders, the BMA has warned.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to stay one step ahead of a cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>6ab0f5de-f313-4c2d-9d3a-d50a679a3cec</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/transformation-blog/2024/how-to-stay-one-step-ahead-of-a-cyber-attack"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T07:36:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ryan Lee explains how our Threat Operations team use a unique network of intelligence and techniques to detect advanced cyber threats before they can cause harm – and what everyone working in the NHS should do to help.


If you worked for the NHS 10 years ago, you would have heard cyber security spoken about quite differently. It was often seen as an IT issue, lumped into conversations about software updates and internet usage. Now, cyber is rightly understood to be a patient safety issue.


As the cyber threat has become more sophisticated, so has our cyber security approach for the NHS. We have evolved significantly in recent years in response to the growing threat. My team’s specialist work in threat operations is one example of this, and just one part of our central cyber security defence approach.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to stay one step ahead of a cyber attack]]></title>
        <id>6ab0f5de-f313-4c2d-9d3a-d50a679a3cec</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/transformation-blog/2024/how-to-stay-one-step-ahead-of-a-cyber-attack"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T07:36:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ryan Lee explains how our Threat Operations team use a unique network of intelligence and techniques to detect advanced cyber threats before they can cause harm – and what everyone working in the NHS should do to help.


If you worked for the NHS 10 years ago, you would have heard cyber security spoken about quite differently. It was often seen as an IT issue, lumped into conversations about software updates and internet usage. Now, cyber is rightly understood to be a patient safety issue.


As the cyber threat has become more sophisticated, so has our cyber security approach for the NHS. We have evolved significantly in recent years in response to the growing threat. My team’s specialist work in threat operations is one example of this, and just one part of our central cyber security defence approach.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coventry and Warwickshire Partnership selects TPP for EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=230021</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/coventry-and-warwickshire-partnership-selects-tpp-for-epr/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-04T07:30:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coventry and Warwickshire Partnership NHS Trust (CWPT) has confirmed TPP as the supplier of its electronic patient record (EPR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New JCVI Chair appointed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-jcvi-chair-appointed</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/new-jcvi-chair-appointed"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T16:57:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Professor Wei Shen Lim KBE will become the new Chair of the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation from October.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big questions: GP tirzepatide prescribing and international medical graduates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162369</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/big-questions/big-questions-gp-tirzepatide-prescribing-and-international-medical-graduates/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T15:17:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maya Dhillon takes on May’s talking points – how involved will GPs be in tirzepatide prescribing, and how do we approach conversations about ‘prioritising’ domestic medical graduates over international ones? What role will GPs really play in weight-loss drugs? The rollout of tirzepatide (Mounjaro) in primary care begins this month, a year since the initial NICE
The post Big questions: GP tirzepatide prescribing and international medical graduates appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS pauses AI project after concerns over use of GP data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920439</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/nhs-pauses-ai-project-concerns-use-gp-data/article/1920439"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T15:13:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has paused development of an artificial intelligence (AI) model after doctors' leaders raised concerns over the use of GP patient data to train it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients with mental health and substance use disorders falling through NHS cracks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=161938</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/patients-with-mental-health-and-substance-use-disorders-falling-through-nhs-cracks/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T15:13:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People with co-occurring substance use disorder and mental health conditions are being failed by NHS services that are not designed to meet their needs, the Royal College of Psychiatrists has warned. Patients who have both alcohol and depression or who use cannabis and also have acute mental illness end up being excluded from either mental
The post Patients with mental health and substance use disorders falling through NHS cracks appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England pauses ‘ground-breaking’ AI project following GP data concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162367</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/nhs-england-pauses-ground-breaking-ai-project-following-gp-data-concerns/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T15:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has decided to pause a ‘ground-breaking’ project using GP data to train an artificial intelligence (AI) model, following concerns raised by GP leaders. The BMA and RCGP said they were not aware that GP data, collected for Covid-19 research, was being used by NHS England to train an AI model, Foresight. According to
The post NHS England pauses ‘ground-breaking’ AI project following GP data concerns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4662 - Google Releases Security Updates for Chrome]]></title>
        <id>26bf6432-f21e-472b-b6e5-230cc1f87952</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4662"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T13:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 Security update addresses an exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome for Windows
 Security update addresses an exploited high severity vulnerability in Google Chrome
 Updated: 03 Jun 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI service to go live at The Royal Marsden to improve cancer care]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229985</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/ai-service-to-go-live-at-the-royal-marsden-to-improve-cancer-care/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T12:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Royal Marsden NHS Foundation Trust is launching an AI radiology analysis service to improve cancer research and patient outcomes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming 10-year plan will be positive for GPs, suggests RCGP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162361</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/politics/upcoming-10-year-plan-will-be-positive-for-gps-suggests-rcgp/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T10:43:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Government’s much-anticipated 10-year plan for health is likely to be positive for general practice, the RCGP has suggested. In an update to members last week, college chair Professor Kamila Hawthorne said she met with NHS England chief executive Sir Jim Mackey to discuss the 10-year plan, as well as GP retention and the long-term
The post Upcoming 10-year plan will be positive for GPs, suggests RCGP appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229147</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-74/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T10:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's coffee briefing covers Boots' new SmartSkin tool and a £1.2m population health contract awarded by Norfolk and Waveney NHS ICB.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance for panels on the updated job matching profiles for nursing and midwifery]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/guidance-for-panels-on-the-updated-job-matching-profiles-for-nursing-and-midwifery.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/guidance-for-panels-on-the-updated-job-matching-profiles-for-nursing-and-midwifery.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T10:19:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - This guidance has been written for local job evaluation leads and panellists to support their understanding and use of the updated profiles for nursing and midwifery. It provides an explanation of the updated format for profiles and provides further advice to ensure matching panels are able to use the profiles effectively and consistently. Guidance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Action needed on job evaluation outcomes for nursing and midwifery staff]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/action-needed-on-job-evaluation-outcomes-for-nursing-and-midwifery-staff.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/action-needed-on-job-evaluation-outcomes-for-nursing-and-midwifery-staff.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T10:17:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - This guidance, produced by the NHS Staff Council, is for local partnerships to support the publication of updated profiles for nursing and midwifery and improvement of local job evaluation practices. Guidance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New feeds allow Welsh health boards to send data to DHCW]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229827</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/new-feeds-allow-welsh-health-boards-to-send-data-to-dhcw/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T10:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four national data feeds have gone live in Wales through the National Data and Analytics Platform (NDAP) to connect data across services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Care Act 2014 and occupational therapy: a handy summary]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/the-care-act-2014-and-occupational-therapy-a-handy-summary.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/the-care-act-2014-and-occupational-therapy-a-handy-summary.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:56:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local Government Association (LGA) - This short resource has been developed to support the occupational therapy workforce as part of council preparations for CQC assessment. It summarises the key principles of the Care Act 2014 and the universal and specific duties placed on councils as they relate to occupational therapy, with particular focus on prevention, wellbeing, and promoting independence. Where...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for CQC assessment: a resource for principal occupational therapists]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/preparing-for-cqc-assessment-a-resource-for-principal-occupational-therapists.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/preparing-for-cqc-assessment-a-resource-for-principal-occupational-therapists.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:53:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local Government Association (LGA) - This resource was developed following consultation with principal occupational therapists (POTs) from the national and ADASS regional POT networks and incorporates learning and tips from POTs who have gone through Care Quality Commission (CQC) assessment. Guidance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices will not be asked to repay seniority overpayments received before 2016]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162338</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/gp-practices-will-not-be-asked-to-repay-seniority-overpayments-received-before-2016/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:52:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices will not be asked to pay back seniority payments they received in error before 2016/17, Primary Care Support England (PCSE) has confirmed. NHS England and PCSE have been undertaking a ‘reconciliation exercise’ for seniority payments, to claim back £28m the commissioner has ‘overpaid’ GPs over the years, with some practices facing potentially large bills
The post GP practices will not be asked to repay seniority overpayments received before 2016 appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices face days of extra work after hospital IT glitch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920315</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-practices-face-days-extra-work-hospital-glitch/article/1920315"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:29:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs in part of East Anglia are facing days of extra work and concerns over patient safety after a hospital IT error flooded practices with thousands of duplicate pathology results.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP leaders call for UK government action on Gaza crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1920360</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-leaders-call-uk-government-action-gaza-crisis/article/1920360"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:22:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP chair Professor Kamila Hawthorne has written to the UK foreign secretary to demand 'urgent action in response to the escalating healthcare crisis in Gaza'.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Play well: resources for health play services for England]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/play-well-resources-for-health-play-services-for-england.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/play-well-resources-for-health-play-services-for-england.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:10:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England - This toolkit will help commissioners, service managers, health play practitioners and clinical leaders to design, plan and deliver high-quality health play services for babies, children and young people. The resources include guidelines, recommended standards and a quality checklist. Toolkit]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2025 Spending Review: what's the RCN asking for?]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/2025-spending-review-whats-the-rcn-asking-for.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/2025-spending-review-whats-the-rcn-asking-for.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T09:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Nursing (RCN) - This submission to the government's 2025 Spending Review argues that there is an opportunity to start addressing some of the challenges within the nursing workforce and wider health and care system. The RCN ask that the 10-Year Health Plan and the forthcoming Workforce Plan for England, and the Spending Review are aligned in terms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cancer in the UK: overview 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/cancer-in-the-uk-overview-2025.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/cancer-in-the-uk-overview-2025.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T08:51:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cancer Research UK - This report finds that over the last 50 years, the proportion of the UK population dying from cancer has fallen by more than a fifth. However it also finds while people are now less likely to die from cancer, more people are likely to get it. And due to the UK’s growing and ageing population, the...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE warns that AI translation apps could impact patient safety]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229761</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/nhse-warns-that-ai-translation-apps-could-impact-patient-safety/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-03T07:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS England has raised concerns that the inappropriate use of AI translation apps in healthcare could cause risks to patient safety.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minister Smyth address to Medicine 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/minister-smyth-address-to-medicine-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/minister-smyth-address-to-medicine-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T17:49:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minister Smyth addressed the Royal College of Physicians  annual conference]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four big decisions for the 2025 Spending Review]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/four-big-decisions-for-the-2025-spending-review.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/four-big-decisions-for-the-2025-spending-review.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T16:31:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institute for Fiscal Studies - The Spending Review 2025 will set detailed departmental budgets for most of this parliament. This analysis examines the key choices facing the government on spending in the NHS, health and care, pay and the public sector. Report]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spending Review 2025: priorities for health, the NHS and social care in England]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/spending-review-2025-priorities-for-health-the-nhs-and-social-care-in-england.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/06/spending-review-2025-priorities-for-health-the-nhs-and-social-care-in-england.html"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T16:18:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Health Foundation - This analysis sets out the Health Foundation’s priorities for health and care investment at the Spending Review and options for how they could be achieved. It draws on evidence submitted to the Treasury in February 2025. It covers the investment needed in public health, the NHS and adult social care services; additionally, it sets out policy...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How does local enhanced service funding vary across England?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=161258</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/practice-personal-finance/how-does-local-enhanced-service-funding-vary-across-england/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T15:21:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The suite of local enhanced services offered to GP practices across England varies massively, with ICBs free to decide the number and value of services they commission. In this part of Pulse’s new investigation into LESs, Eliza Parr looks at how much ICBs spend per patient Pulse’s investigation into local enhanced service (LES) funding at
The post How does local enhanced service funding vary across England? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mindfulness approach effective where NHS talking therapies have not worked]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=161940</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/mindfulness-approach-effective-where-nhs-talking-therapies-have-not-worked/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T15:16:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A programme of mindfulness-based cognitive therapy has been shown to be beneficial in people with depression who had not benefitted from NHS Talking Therapies. The effect seen was small-to-moderate but comparable to that shown with antidepressants, the researchers said. At less than £100 per person it was also a cost-effective alternative to usual treatment, the
The post Mindfulness approach effective where NHS talking therapies have not worked appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RCGP chair calls on UK Government to address Gaza healthcare crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162325</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/rcgp-chair-calls-on-uk-government-to-address-gaza-healthcare-crisis/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T14:59:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The chair of the RCGP has written to the UK foreign secretary, calling for the Government to address the escalating healthcare crisis in Gaza. In a letter published 30 May, RCGP chair Professor Kamila Hawthorne told David Lammy that she was ‘profoundly concerned’ about the impact of the Israel-Gaza war on health services and those
The post RCGP chair calls on UK Government to address Gaza healthcare crisis appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices improve access by embracing technology and increasing appointments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267395</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/gp-practices-improve-access-embracing-technology-increasing-appointments/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T14:19:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Around 3 in 4 patients find it easy to contact a GP, up more than 10% since last summer as the NHS drives to improve access. Almost every (99%) GP practice in England now has a digital telephone system in place to make it easier for people to get through to their family doctor. Office […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom W</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Networks advisory panels’ new members announced]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229921</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/digital-health-networks-advisory-panels-new-members-announced/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T12:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The newly elected members for the Digital Health Networks Advisory Panel 2025–2027 term have been announced.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly £1 billion for NHS frontline after agency spend crackdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nearly-1-billion-for-nhs-frontline-after-agency-spend-crackdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/nearly-1-billion-for-nhs-frontline-after-agency-spend-crackdown"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T11:41:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government crack-down on rip-off temporary staffing agencies delivers unprecedented savings, as NHS trusts are urged to eradicate agency spending altogether]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trust hands back all GP contracts due to ‘neighbourhood care’ shift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162277</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/trust-hands-back-all-gp-contracts-due-to-neighbourhood-care-shift/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T10:47:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A community health trust is pulling out of all its GP contracts, stating the national shift towards ‘neighbourhood care’ as the reason. Humber Teaching NHS Foundation Trust currently manages three GP practices under a mixture of GMS and PMS contracts, and across four surgery sites.  It announced this month that all three practices will be
The post Trust hands back all GP contracts due to ‘neighbourhood care’ shift appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mid and south Essex to launch ‘hub and spoke’ pathology service]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229619</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/mid-and-south-essex-to-launch-hub-and-spoke-pathology-service/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T10:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mid and South Essex NHS Foundation Trust has signed a 15-year contract with SYNLAB for the delivery of a ‘hub and spoke’ pathology service.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of GPs seeking support from specialist NHS mental health service]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1919947</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/thousands-gps-seeking-support-specialist-nhs-mental-health-service/article/1919947"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T09:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs make up more than half of health professionals receiving support from a confidential specialist NHS mental health service.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs to vote on options for collective action in Northern Ireland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162311</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/breaking-news/gps-to-vote-on-options-for-collective-action-in-northern-ireland/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T09:10:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BMA in Northern Ireland is developing options for collective action which GPs will vote on via a referendum, the union has announced. Last month, the country’s health minister imposed the GMS contract for 2025/26 on GP practices for the first time, despite the offer being overwhelmingly rejected by the profession. Now the Northern Ireland
The post GPs to vote on options for collective action in Northern Ireland appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP who quit ARRS job after six months feared 'losing skills']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1919603</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-quit-arrs-job-six-months-feared-losing-skills/article/1919603"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T08:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A GP who resigned from an additional roles reimbursement scheme (ARRS) job after just six months - despite a long struggle to find work - has revealed why leaving was the only option.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barts Health deploys imaging de-identification tool]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229589</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/06/barts-health-deploys-imaging-de-identification-tool/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T07:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Barts Health NHS Trust has implemented Sectra’s Anonymise and Export functionality, which de-identifies medical images for research purposes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Volunteers support the NHS for 6 million hours this year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267307</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/06/volunteers-support-the-nhs-for-6-million-hours-this-year/"/>
        <updated>2025-06-01T23:01:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tens of thousands of people have volunteered to help the NHS over the last year, according to new figures. From people in their late teens to those in their late eights volunteers have helped with tasks such as directing loved ones around hospitals, collecting medication or basic admin tasks. Around 70,000 people volunteer with the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telecare users and their loved ones across the UK urged to speak to telecoms providers ahead of switch to digital landlines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/telecare-users-and-their-loved-ones-across-the-uk-urged-to-speak-to-telecoms-providers-ahead-of-switch-to-digital-landlines</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/telecare-users-and-their-loved-ones-across-the-uk-urged-to-speak-to-telecoms-providers-ahead-of-switch-to-digital-landlines"/>
        <updated>2025-06-01T23:01:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 2 million vulnerable people who rely on lifesaving telecare alarms to call for help have today been urged to get in touch with their landline providers so companies can provide additional support for them during the switch to digital landlines.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO Director-General: Member States reaffirm commitment to WHO and global health at historic World Health Assembly]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:815e534c-538b-4e45-a7e4-1c623f746b29</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/30-05-2025-who-director-general--member-states-reaffirm-commitment-to-who-and-global-health-at-historic-world-health-assembly"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T16:59:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO Director-General Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus praised the commitment shown by the Organization’s Member States which, during nearly two weeks of meetings, adopted historic measures to make the world safer and healthier.
The landmark adoptions of the first global agreement to make the world safer from future pandemics and increase in financial support to the World Health Organization were the highlights of the Seventy-eighth World Health Assembly, which ran from 19–27 May. Immediately after, the WHO Executive Board met for two days, until 29 May, to address the Health Assembly’s outcome, WHO governance reform and the nomination and appointment of regional directors. 
Dr Tedros said Member States demonstrated their commitment to WHO and multilateral action to protect and promote public …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact assessment: Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill: impact assessment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/terminally-ill-adults-end-of-life-bill-impact-assessment</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/terminally-ill-adults-end-of-life-bill-impact-assessment"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T15:55:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The impact assessment presents the impacts of the Terminally Ill Adults (End of Life) Bill.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[People with adult-onset type 1 diabetes face increased risk of CVD, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162294</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/people-with-adult-onset-type-1-diabetes-face-increased-risk-of-cvd-study-finds/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T15:43:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People who develop type 1 diabetes (T1D) in adulthood have an increased risk of cardiovascular disease and death, a study has found. Patients diagnosed later in life do not have a better prognosis than those diagnosed earlier, say researchers from the Karolinska Institutet in Sweden. Researchers have identified smoking, poor glucose control and obesity as the
The post People with adult-onset type 1 diabetes face increased risk of CVD, study finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are local enhanced services unfunded charity work?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162293</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/analysis/practice-personal-finance/are-local-enhanced-services-unfunded-charity-work/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T15:13:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local enhanced services form a crucial part of GP income, helping practices stay afloat. But a major new Pulse investigation shows that in many areas, ICB funding is stagnating. Here, Eliza Parr looks at the impact on practices ‘If a management consultancy firm was asked to review a GP surgery then a fair and expected
The post Are local enhanced services unfunded charity work? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trying to be less "demanding on the brain"]]></title>
        <id>6af7703b-803f-4bfb-a271-8377ec592702</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/design-matters/2022/trying-to-be-less-demanding-on-the-brain"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T15:13:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tosin Balogun, Associate Interaction Designer for the NHS website, looks at how we design and how we try to make a difference.


It is pretty obvious to say that design changes people’s lives. If it didn’t, we wouldn’t spend so much of our time trying to get it right.


But the reality beneath that unoriginal claim struck home for me recently as I worked on a report tool, part of the replacement system for national cervical screening.


It’s not the most dramatic or heart-rending example of our impact – but is perhaps no less meaningful for that. It’s a small piece of work that speaks to the everyday reality we try to grapple with as interaction designers in the NHS.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expert analysis: why are we not retaining GPs?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=161487</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/expert-analysis-why-are-we-not-retaining-gps/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T14:14:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following their recent study, Drs Victoria Tzortziou Brown, William Palmer, Lucina Rolewicz, and Giuliano Russo explore the retention patterns of recently qualified GPs Earlier this year, it was revealed that over 40% of GP registrars who qualified in 2022 and 2023 have yet to take up substantive roles in UK general practice. This troubling figure
The post Expert analysis: why are we not retaining GPs? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Healthy Start extension: application guidance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/healthy-start-extension-application-guidance</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/healthy-start-extension-application-guidance"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T13:56:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sets out who is eligible to apply for the Healthy Start scheme under the extended criteria, and how to apply.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trinity Homecare trials AI-powered support app for carers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=228373</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/trinity-homecare-trials-ai-powered-support-app-for-carers/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T12:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At-home and domicilliary provider Trinity Homecare has completed a successful pilot of CareBrain's AI-driven support app.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Late-life depression associated with increased risk of dementia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162282</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/late-life-depression-associated-with-increased-risk-of-dementia/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T11:03:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Depression in late-life is associated with an increased risk of dementia, a new study has found.  Researchers found a ‘consistent relationship’ between late-life depression and risk for all cause dementia. The study, published in eClinicalMedicine, highlights the importance of managing depression ‘across the life-course’, with ‘opportune access’ to both pharmacological and nonpharmacological treatments, in order
The post Late-life depression associated with increased risk of dementia appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Estates Safety Fund: 2025 to 2026]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/estates-safety-fund-2025-to-2026</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/estates-safety-fund-2025-to-2026"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T10:57:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A full list of schemes included in the Estates Safety Fund 2025 to 2026, addressing critical infrastructure and safety risk in NHS hospital buildings.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 1,600 GPs miss out on pension tax compensation due to ‘admin failures’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162281</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/practice-personal-finance/over-1600-gps-miss-out-on-pension-tax-compensation-due-to-admin-failures/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T10:32:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 1,600 GPs are missing out on millions of pounds in pension tax compensation due to ‘administrative failures’, a new data analysis has revealed. FOI data from NHS Business Services Authority (NHSBSA) gathered by Medifintech, a specialist provider of NHS pension analysis, has found that nearly 4,000 NHS staff will miss out on over
The post Over 1,600 GPs miss out on pension tax compensation due to ‘admin failures’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing innovative flexible working to combat escalating demand on services]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/implementing-innovative-flexible-working-to-combat-escalating-demand-on-services.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/implementing-innovative-flexible-working-to-combat-escalating-demand-on-services.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T10:28:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Employers - This case study outlines how Imperial College Healthcare NHS Trust used an innovative flexible working model to combat escalating demand for imaging diagnostic services. Case study]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unlocking the potential of primary care provider collaboratives]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/unlocking-the-potential-of-primary-care-provider-collaboratives.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/unlocking-the-potential-of-primary-care-provider-collaboratives.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T10:18:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Confederation - Primary care provider collaboratives are fundamental to the successful delivery of a neighbourhood health service. Their role will be pivotal in shifting care from hospitals to community, reducing health inequalities and ensuring that everyone has access to high-quality care. In partnership with KPMG, the NHS Confederation's Primary Care Network has been exploring what is needed to unlock...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI chest X-ray software rolled out at Leeds Teaching Hospitals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229527</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/ai-chest-x-ray-software-rolled-out-at-leeds-teaching-hospitals/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T10:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust (LTHT) has deployed Annalise.ai’s AI chest X-ray solution to speed up diagnosis and improve patient care.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CC-4661 - Santesoft Releases Security Update for Sante DICOM Viewer Pro]]></title>
        <id>be3399d2-b2a5-4504-8a1d-513e9e6a0f93</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/cyber-alerts/2025/cc-4661"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Severity: Medium
 CVE-2025-5307 could allow a local attacker to disclose sensitive information or execute arbitrary code
 CVE-2025-5307 could allow a local attacker to disclose sensitive information or execute arbitrary code
 Updated: 30 May 2025]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evaluation of the Better Care Fund Support Programme 2023 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/evaluation-of-the-better-care-fund-support-programme-2023-to-2025.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/evaluation-of-the-better-care-fund-support-programme-2023-to-2025.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T09:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) - The Department of Health and Social Care commissioned Ipsos UK, in partnership with the Institute of Public Care at Oxford Brookes University, to conduct an evaluation of the Better Care Fund (BCF) Support Programme. The evaluation explores local authorities' perceptions of the design and delivery of the BCF support programme; the enablers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO outlines recommendations to protect infants against RSV – respiratory syncytial virus]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:9c9a1000-dd2b-4ee9-948e-769c7b1e17a5</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/30-05-2025-who-outlines-recommendations-to-protect-infants-against-rsv-respiratory-syncytial-virus"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T09:52:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, the World Health Organization (WHO) published its first-ever position paper on immunization products to protect infants against respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) – the leading cause of acute lower respiratory infections in children globally. 
Every year, RSV causes about 100 000 deaths and over 3.6 million hospitalizations in children under the age of 5 years worldwide. About half of these deaths occur in infants younger than 6 months of age. The vast majority (97%) of RSV deaths in infants occur in low- and middle-income countries where there is limited access to supportive medical care, such as oxygen or hydration.
Published in the Weekly Epidemiological Record (WER), the position paper outlines WHO recommendations for two immunization products: a maternal vaccine that can be give…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS first in world to roll out ‘revolutionary’ blood test for cancer patients]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267290</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/05/nhs-first-in-world-to-roll-out-revolutionary-blood-test-for-cancer-patients/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T08:56:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tens of thousands of patients with lung and breast cancer are to benefit from a “revolutionary” blood test on the NHS across England which can speed up access to targeted therapy. The new ‘liquid biopsy’ test can help fast-track lung cancer patients to receive targeted therapy up to two weeks earlier, while helping some avoid […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast: The community worker scheme from Brazil that could be part of the 10-Year Health Plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1919101</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/podcast-community-worker-scheme-brazil-part-10-year-health-plan/article/1919101"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T07:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Matt Harris and London GP Dr Connie Junghans Minton explain how an initiative involving community health and wellbeing workers, which is based on a long-running scheme from Brazil, is helping to tackle health inequalities.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health’s monthly roundup of contracts and go lives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229429</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/digital-healths-monthly-roundup-of-contracts-and-go-lives-53/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T07:30:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This contracts and go lives roundup includes an electronic patient record (EPR) go-live across St George’s, Epsom and St Helier Hospitals.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs miss out on millions in tax compensation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1919725</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gps-miss-millions-tax-compensation/article/1919725"/>
        <updated>2025-05-30T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GPs have missed out on tax compensation worth millions of pounds because of complex rules around a scheme designed to protect NHS staff from charges linked to the annual allowance on pensions, experts say.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients and pupils to benefit from school and hospital repairs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/patients-and-pupils-to-benefit-from-school-and-hospital-repairs</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/patients-and-pupils-to-benefit-from-school-and-hospital-repairs"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government investing £1.2 billion to fix crumbling hospitals and schools across England]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Case of the month – answers: Did you get what was causing this child’s limp?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162258</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/infectious-diseases-immunology-allergy/case-of-the-month-answers-did-you-get-what-was-causing-this-childs-limp/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T17:15:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the latest in our series, Dr David Capehorn asked what the likely diagnosis is in this case of a child presenting repeatedly with a limp. Answer revealed below! Note that details of the case have been altered to protect individuals’ identities     A four-year-old boy initially presents to clinic with a limp. His mother
The post Case of the month – answers: Did you get what was causing this child’s limp? appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CPD: Challenges in atrial fibrillation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162247</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/clinical-feature/clinical-areas/cardiovascular/cpd-challenges-in-atrial-fibrillation/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T16:45:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Community cardiology specialist Dr Peter Savill discusses five key challenges for GPs in the management of atrial fibrillation. Learning objectives This module will support your knowledge of management of AF, in particular: 1. GPs fairly often see patients presenting with mild shortness of breath or palpitations who turn out to have atrial fibrillation (AF), but
The post CPD: Challenges in atrial fibrillation appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Price</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Claiming physician associates are trained in ‘medical model’ is ‘misleading’, says BMA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162246</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/workforce/claiming-physician-associates-are-trained-in-medical-model-is-misleading-says-bma/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T16:33:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government claims that physician associates (PAs) are trained to the ‘medical model’ are designed to ‘mislead’, the BMA has argued. Academic leaders at the union have put out a statement today examining the use of the term ‘medical model’, which they say is now an ‘outdated and inaccurate’ description of doctors’ training. The Government and
The post Claiming physician associates are trained in ‘medical model’ is ‘misleading’, says BMA  appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance: Child death overview panels: contacts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/child-death-overview-panels-contacts"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T15:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Contact details of the people in child death overview panels (CDOPs) who are responsible for receiving child death notifications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FTP decisions will be more ‘consistent’ thanks to updated guidance, GMC claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162197</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/ftp-decisions-will-be-more-consistent-thanks-to-updated-guidance-gmc-claims/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T14:45:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GMC has updated its fitness to practise (FTP) guidance to ensure ‘greater consistency’ in decisions about whether doctors are investigated or taken to tribunal.  Updates to various guidance documents, published today, are intended to provide all GMC case examiners and decision makers with a ‘single set of core principles’, while also bringing the FTP
The post FTP decisions will be more ‘consistent’ thanks to updated guidance, GMC claims appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multi-factor authentication: a silver cyber bullet?]]></title>
        <id>84fdab31-88a6-4d23-be21-6396b13b2d8f</id>
        <link href="https://digital.nhs.uk/blog/transformation-blog/2023/multi-factor-authentication-a-silver-cyber-bullet"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T13:31:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clinical lead Chris Day says full implementation of multi-factor authentication is critical to local organisations’ cyber security.


Cyber security is about risk reduction and that can make it a difficult sell in the NHS.


Hard-pressed boards often want to know how much something is going to save them, but the cost of not implementing cyber security measures can only be calculated when their network or system is compromised.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>enquiries@nhsdigital.nhs.uk (NHS Digital)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beverley Bryant confirmed as Summer Schools 2025 speaker]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229663</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/beverley-bryant-confirmed-as-lsummer-schools-2025-speaker/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T12:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beverley Bryant, one of the most experienced NHS digital leaders, has been confirmed as a speaker at Digital Health Summer Schools 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research: Evaluation of the Better Care Fund Support Programme 2023 to 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/evaluation-of-the-better-care-fund-support-programme-2023-to-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/evaluation-of-the-better-care-fund-support-programme-2023-to-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T12:24:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Findings of the evaluation of the 2023 to 2025 BCF Support Programme, which supports local areas to commission and deliver integrated health and care services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: One in six ICBs reduced LES funding for GP practices last year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=161242</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/exclusive-one-in-six-icbs-reduced-les-funding-for-gp-practices-last-year/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T10:59:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive New data has suggested that one in six ICBs reduced their local enhanced service (LES) funding for general practice last year, Pulse can reveal. According to data obtained via Freedom of Information (FOI) requests, seven ICBs across England reduced their total funding for all local enhanced services between 2023/24 and 2024/25.  FOI data from
The post Exclusive: One in six ICBs reduced LES funding for GP practices last year appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using AI to simplify clinic letters for patients can free up GP time, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162075</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/using-ai-to-simplify-clinic-letters-for-patients-can-free-up-gp-time-study-finds/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T10:56:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ChatGPT can rewrite clinic letters from consultants to make them more easily understandable to patients without losing key information and potentially free up GP time, a study has found. If adopted, the approach has the potential to free up time in general practice as patients were less likely to book appointments with their GP to
The post Using AI to simplify clinic letters for patients can free up GP time, study finds appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229097</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-73/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T10:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our coffee briefing covers UHCW's new research hub and news that DBTH will adopt Sheffield Teaching Hospitals' Oracle Cerner EPR.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO calls for urgent action to ban flavoured tobacco and nicotine products]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:e62808d1-92f9-40d8-8676-35fcc1d6e630</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/30-05-2025-who-calls-for-urgent-action-to-ban-flavoured-tobacco-and-nicotine-products"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T10:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On World No Tobacco Day, the World Health Organization (WHO) today launches a new publication and calls on governments to urgently ban all flavours in tobacco and nicotine products, including cigarettes, pouches, hookahs and e-cigarettes, to protect youth from addiction and disease.
Flavours like menthol, bubble gum and cotton candy are masking the harshness of tobacco and nicotine products turning toxic products into youth-friendly bait. Flavours not only make it harder to quit but have also been linked to serious lung diseases. Cigarettes, which still kill up to half of their users, also come in flavours or can have flavours added to them.
“Flavours are fuelling a new wave of addiction, and should be banned,” said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, Director-General of WHO. “They undermine de…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BJSS awarded £27.8m Scotland Digital Front Door contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229413</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/bjss-awarded-27-8m-scotland-digital-front-door-contract/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T10:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Education for Scotland has awarded BJSS a £27.8m contract to help deliver the Digital Front Door app for health and social care services.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practice funding data reveal root cause of GP unemployment crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1919758</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/practice-funding-data-reveal-root-cause-gp-unemployment-crisis/article/1919758"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T09:03:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Funding per patient for practices in England rose by less than 3% in 2023/24, according to NHS data that experts say reveals the root cause of an unemployment crisis that has left thousands of GPs out of work.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two NHS trusts affected by cyber attack on mobile phone software]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229623</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/two-nhs-trusts-affected-by-cyber-attack-on-mobile-phone-software/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T07:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHSE is investigating a cyber incident at two NHS trusts after hackers exploited a vulnerability in software used to manage mobile phones.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Sollof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO, Africa CDC and RKI expand unique partnership to strengthen collaborative surveillance in Africa]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:e49990d7-1975-4b68-9081-527f708f2380</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/29-05-2025-who--africa-cdc-and-rki-expand-unique-partnership-to-strengthen-collaborative-surveillance-in-africa"/>
        <updated>2025-05-29T07:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization (WHO), Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC) and the Robert Koch Institute (RKI) announced today the expansion of the successful Health Security Partnership to Strengthen Disease Surveillance in Africa (HSPA) to seven countries on the continent. 
Africa experiences more disease outbreaks than any other part of the world. While significant progress has been made in strengthening disease surveillance over the past decade, no country can tackle today’s complex health threats alone.
The Health Security Partnership strengthens disease surveillance and epidemic intelligence across the African continent, enabling countries to better detect and respond to public health threats - whether they are natural, accidental or deliberate.  Launched in …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More support for neurodivergent children in mainstream schools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/more-support-for-neurodivergent-children-in-mainstream-schools</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/more-support-for-neurodivergent-children-in-mainstream-schools"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T23:01:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Around 300,000 children across 1,200 primary schools to benefit from earlier and better neurodiversity support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-term use of antidepressants associated with higher risk of withdrawal symptoms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162070</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/long-term-use-of-antidepressants-associated-with-higher-risk-of-withdrawal-symptoms/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T16:07:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taking antidepressants for more than two years is associated with a higher risk of withdrawal symptoms compared to short-term use, UK researchers have found. The team from University College London (UCL) found that those who have been taking antidepressants for longer also tend to experience worse withdrawal symptoms, over a longer period and are less
The post Long-term use of antidepressants associated with higher risk of withdrawal symptoms appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CQC tells GP practices to ignore some scores on draft reports due to IT issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162194</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/regulation/cqc-tells-gp-practices-to-ignore-some-scores-on-draft-reports-due-to-it-issues/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T14:57:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CQC has urged healthcare providers including GP practices to ‘disregard’ scores at evidence category level that currently appear in draft assessment reports. It has reassured providers that the inclusion of such scores does not indicate a change to their assessment method, but is down IT technical constraints. Last December, the CQC announced it would no
The post CQC tells GP practices to ignore some scores on draft reports due to IT issues appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[God knows how we get through day duty]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162190</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/copperfield/god-knows-how-we-get-through-day-duty/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T14:28:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Copperfield muses on the existence of an almighty ‘Great God of General Practice’ on one of his more trying day duties I now know whether God exists. By which I mean the Great God of General Practice (GGoGP), who may or may not, each day, protect us from clinical catastrophe, litigation and stress-induced coronary ischaemia.
The post God knows how we get through day duty appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP News Update: Including GP pay rise, career switch for jobless locums, GP contract 'cost index']]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1919649</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-news-update-including-gp-pay-rise-career-switch-jobless-locums-gp-contract-cost-index/article/1919649"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T13:16:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Catch up quickly with our weekly round-up of key news stories for general practice.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seventy-eighth World Health Assembly concludes: historic outcomes, consequential highlights]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:c1e572d6-0303-4f1e-92fc-9ef34eae38b2</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/28-05-2025-seventy-eighth-world-health-assembly-concludes--historic-outcomes--consequential-highlights"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T13:07:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The  Seventy-eighth World Health Assembly (WHA78), the annual meeting of World Health Organization’s (WHO) Member States, came to a close Tuesday, as health leaders lauded vast accomplishments and global solidarity.
The Assembly, WHO’s highest decision-making body, convened from 19 May to 27 May, under the theme “One World for Health”. Member States considered approximately 75 items and sub-items across all areas of health, engaging in lively debate and adopting consequential resolutions to improve health for all.
“The words ‘historic’ and ‘landmark’ are overused, but they are perfectly apt to describe this year’s World Health Assembly,” said Dr Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, WHO Director-General. “The adoption of the Pandemic Agreement and the approval of the next increase in assessed contri…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guy’s and St Thomas’ launches AI-enabled women’s health service]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229243</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/guys-and-st-thomas-launches-ai-enabled-womens-health-service/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T12:30:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guy’s and St Thomas’ NHS Foundation Trust has partnered with Aneira Health to develop an AI-enabled workplace healthcare service for women.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs need to engage with obesity management as weight-loss jabs are rolled out, say researchers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162072</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/gastroenterology-obesity/gps-need-to-engage-with-obesity-management-as-weight-loss-jabs-are-rolled-out-say-researchers/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T11:41:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weight-loss drugs cannot be seen as short-term solutions by the NHS and GPs will inevitably need to engage with obesity management as the medicines are rolled out, researchers have said. Researchers from the University of Oxford said that while the medications are highly effective in helping patients lose weight, their recent findings strike a ‘cautionary
The post GPs need to engage with obesity management as weight-loss jabs are rolled out, say researchers appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Lind</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extra £100m needed to deliver 4% GP pay rise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1919613</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/extra-100m-needed-deliver-4-gp-pay-rise/article/1919613"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T11:24:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP practices need around £100m in additional funding to deliver pay increases promised by the government, accountants say.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The care expectation gap]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/the-care-expectation-gap.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/the-care-expectation-gap.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T10:53:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joseph Rowntree Foundation - This briefing suggests that people are unaware of the challenges of the social care system and thus are likely not preparing for a future in which they may have to meet significant care costs or care themselves. It found that only 19% of the general public correctly guessed that the cost of professional home care services...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health commissioners ‘failed’ to assess risks of closing homeless GP practice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=161945</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/clinical-areas/mental-health-pain-and-addiction/health-commissioners-failed-to-assess-risks-of-closing-homeless-gp-practice/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T10:34:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health commissioners failed to properly assess risk when closing a homeless GP practice, an independent whistleblowing review has found. The Hunter Street homeless practice, which was run by the local health board as part of a homelessness health service, was closed by the Glasgow City Health and Social Care Partnership (HSCP) in 2023. Following the
The post Health commissioners ‘failed’ to assess risks of closing homeless GP practice appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review of CQC Regulation 9A: visiting and accompanying in care homes, hospitals and hospices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/review-of-cqc-regulation-9a-visiting-and-accompanying-in-care-homes-hospitals-and-hospices</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/calls-for-evidence/review-of-cqc-regulation-9a-visiting-and-accompanying-in-care-homes-hospitals-and-hospices"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T09:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seeks views from individuals, professionals and organisations about visiting and accompanying in care homes, hospitals and hospices in England since Regulation 9A came into force on 6 April 2024.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Millions receive help from NHS high street pharmacies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=267026</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/05/millions-receive-help-from-nhs-high-street-pharmacies/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T08:26:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 5 million patients have received help from high street pharmacies for minor illnesses, as the NHS brings care closer to people’s homes.  Around 2.4 million people received help without booking an appointment at their local pharmacy for seven common conditions including sore throat, earache or shingles. Pharmacies delivered the most consultations for acute […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>jboshell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Imperial researchers create AI model to generate heart animations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229299</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/imperial-researchers-create-ai-model-to-generate-heart-animations/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-28T07:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers at Imperial have developed an AI model that creates personalised animations of human hearts to help identify abnormalities.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seventy-eighth World Health Assembly – Daily update: 27 May 2025]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:0d5ce9e3-10c1-4979-b904-232d49f85cd1</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/27-05-2025-seventy-eighth-world-health-assembly---daily-update--27-may-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T19:09:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Countries agree to update action plan to reduce deaths from antimicrobial resistance  

The Seventy-eighth World Health Assembly approved a decision to update the Global action plan (GAP) on antimicrobial resistance (AMR), for discussion at next year’s World Health Assembly (WHA79) in 2026.

An estimated 4.71 million deaths were associated with bacterial AMR as of 2021, according to the Global Burden of Diseases, Injuries, and Risk Factors Study (GBD). The GAP update will offer a practical framework for the next 10 years to achieve the targets and commitments included in the political declaration of the United Nations General Assembly High-Level Meeting on AMR in 2024 – including a 10% reduction in global deaths associated with bacterial AMR by 2030. 

Since the global action plan was adop…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EMIS postpones system maintenance following GP concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162166</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/technology/emis-postpones-system-maintenance-following-gp-concerns/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T16:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive EMIS has decided to postpone maintenance planned for today following concerns raised by GPs about increased demand after the bank holiday.  Optum, the company that acquired EMIS in 2023, told GP practices last Wednesday that it would perform ‘essential maintenance’ impacting EMIS Web and EMIS-X over lunchtime on Tuesday 27 May. Last week GPs
The post EMIS postpones system maintenance following GP concerns appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital of the future: hospital as a service, not a building]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/hospital-of-the-future-hospital-as-a-service-not-a-building.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/hospital-of-the-future-hospital-as-a-service-not-a-building.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T15:37:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Re:State - This report outlines a model that fundamentally changes the configuration of the modern hospital. The paper proposes a model that combines a radical increase in virtual care with renewed approaches at system-wide integration. It argues that instead of inefficiently relocating hospital staff and infrastructure to communities, hospital-level care should be delivered as a service through entirely new care...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BMA leaders to debate ‘prioritising’ UK medical graduates for foundation programmes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162155</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/education-and-training/bma-leaders-to-debate-prioritising-uk-medical-graduates-for-foundation-programmes/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T15:28:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctor leaders will vote on whether UK medical school graduates should be ‘prioritised’ ahead of international graduates for foundation programme posts. At the BMA’s annual representative meeting next month, union representatives will take part in a debate and vote on two motions around reforming postgraduate medical training, as the current system is ‘failing’ doctors. They
The post BMA leaders to debate ‘prioritising’ UK medical graduates for foundation programmes appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘School attendance is everyone’s business – that includes GPs’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162130</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/views/guest-opinion/school-attendance-is-everyones-business-that-includes-gps/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T15:06:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Saroja Forester on the importance of GPs’ role in improving children’s school attendance It’s a typical mid-morning mid-week consultation. Eight-year-old L has been booked in by his mother, Miss W, who is worried about his cough. In they come, accompanied by a toddler in buggy and a six-year-old playing on a phone. It’s another
The post ‘School attendance is everyone’s business – that includes GPs’ appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Dhillon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Putting young people at the heart of care]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/putting-young-people-at-the-heart-of-care-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/putting-young-people-at-the-heart-of-care-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T14:06:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Providers - This report features four case studies demonstrating how trusts are successfully improving services for children and young people across a variety of sectors: delivering mental health support to children and young people in the community; collaborating at neighbourhood level for the benefit of children and young people; improving access to care through digital interventions; and using co-production...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The short-and-medium-term impacts of Sure Start on children's outcomes]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/the-short-and-medium-term-impacts-of-sure-start-on-childrens-outcomes-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/the-short-and-medium-term-impacts-of-sure-start-on-childrens-outcomes-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T13:30:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[lnstitute for Fiscal Studies - This report finds that Sure Start – one of England’s biggest early years programmes – generated widespread and long-lasting benefits for children. It improved educational outcomes and health, and reduced school absences and less severe special educational needs and disabilities (SEND). Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global oncology trends 2025: adopting new therapies as modalities shift and expenditures rise]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/global-oncology-trends-2025-adopting-new-therapies-as-modalities-shift-and-expenditures-rise-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/global-oncology-trends-2025-adopting-new-therapies-as-modalities-shift-and-expenditures-rise-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T12:54:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[IQVIA Institute for Human Data Science - This report profiles the current state of research and development in oncology, including key mechanisms, targets, and cancer types being investigated as well as pointing to some novel areas which are only just emerging. It also looks at metrics of clinical development productivity. Report More detail]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[University Hospitals of Northamptonshire launches Data Academy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229223</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/university-hospitals-of-northamptonshire-launches-data-academy/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T12:30:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[University Hospitals of Northamptonshire has launched a Data Academy to provide training for patient and non-patient facing staff.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HIV and long lives: new challenges in high-income countries]]></title>
        <id>https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/hiv-and-long-lives-new-challenges-in-high-income-countries-.html</id>
        <link href="https://kingsfund.blogs.com/health_management/2025/05/hiv-and-long-lives-new-challenges-in-high-income-countries-.html"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T11:40:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[International Longevity Centre (ILC) - This report warns that health systems in high-income countries are dangerously underprepared for the growing number of people ageing with HIV. Thanks to advances in antiretroviral therapy, people with HIV are living longer than ever before, but social, economic and health systems have failed to keep up. Report Press release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Health Management and Policy Alert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICBs across the country plan mergers to cut running costs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162133</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/nhs-structures/icbs-across-the-country-plan-mergers-to-cut-running-costs/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T11:04:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A number of ICBs across the country are planning to merge or create new ‘clusters’ in a bid to reduce running costs.  In the East of England, there are plans to reduce the number of ICBs from six to three, although the exact configuration is yet to be confirmed.  Meanwhile, in the South West region,
The post ICBs across the country plan mergers to cut running costs appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eliza Parr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital Health Coffee Time Briefing ☕]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=228343</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/digital-health-coffee-time-briefing-%e2%98%95-72/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T10:30:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's coffee briefing covers £13m in green funding for Newham Hospital, plus insights from the Philips Future Health Index 2025.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nottingham University Hospitals introduces bedside fit notes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229075</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/nottingham-university-hospitals-introduces-bedside-fit-notes/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T10:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clinicians at Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust can now issue eMED3 electronic fit notes directly from the Nervecentre EPR.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Teaching Hospitals seeks input on plans for Innovation Village]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229165</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/leeds-teaching-hospitals-seeks-input-on-plans-for-innovation-village/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T10:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Teaching Hospitals has launched a market engagement exercise to help shape a development plan for its proposed Innovation Village site.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than half of GPs want to see staff costs ringfenced in new GMS contract]]></title>
        <id>https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/?p=162117</id>
        <link href="https://www.pulsetoday.co.uk/news/contract/more-than-half-of-gps-want-to-see-staff-costs-ringfenced-in-new-gms-contract/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T09:51:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive More than half of GPs want to see staff costs ringfenced in a new wholesale GMS contract, the results of a new Pulse survey have revealed. A poll of 667 English GPs showed that 54% ‘strongly agreed’ that staff costs should be ringfenced and funded separately to the global sum as part of a
The post More than half of GPs want to see staff costs ringfenced in new GMS contract appeared first on Pulse Today.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Colivicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unemployed locum GPs consider childminding and school teaching roles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1918908</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/unemployed-locum-gps-consider-childminding-school-teaching-roles/article/1918908"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Locum GPs struggling to find employment are considering leaving the NHS to work in childcare or as teachers, a sessional GP organisation has revealed.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GP registrars to vote on strike action as resident doctor ballot opens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gponline.com/article/1919373</id>
        <link href="https://www.gponline.com/gp-registrars-vote-strike-action-resident-doctor-ballot-opens/article/1919373"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T08:45:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Resident doctors including GP registrars have begun to receive ballots from the BMA over industrial action on pay.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GP Online 2014 News RSS Feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Birmingham Women’s and Children’s NHS FT goes live with EPR]]></title>
        <id>https://www.digitalhealth.net/?p=229195</id>
        <link href="https://www.digitalhealth.net/2025/05/birmingham-womens-and-childrens-nhs-ft-goes-live-with-epr/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-27T07:30:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Birmingham Women’s and Children’s NHS Foundation Trust has gone live with an electronic patient record (EPR) system from Epic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tammy Lovell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS initiative helps thousands more tackle their diabetes risk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.england.nhs.uk/?p=266923</id>
        <link href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2025/05/nhs-initiative-helps-thousands-more-tackle-their-diabetes-risk/"/>
        <updated>2025-05-26T23:01:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A record 166,360 more adults in England began receiving support last year from a world-leading NHS public health initiative, which helps people lose weight and make lifestyles changes to stop or delay them developing Type 2 diabetes, according to new data. The analysis also shows that more than 900,000 adults at high risk of developing […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom W</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seventy-eighth World Health Assembly – Daily update: 26 May 2025]]></title>
        <id>urn:uuid:c00c4dd2-29c9-472e-ab7d-bf74b1a127fb</id>
        <link href="https://www.who.int/news/item/26-05-2025-seventy-eighth-world-health-assembly---daily-update--26-may-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-05-26T20:04:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Countries overwhelmingly agree on a new voluntary target for air pollution and health  

Member States at the Seventy-eighth World Health Assembly strongly approved an updated road map for an enhanced global response to the adverse health effects of air pollution, reaffirming their commitment to protect populations from the world’s largest environmental health risk. The decision updates the 2016 strategy endorsed under WHA69/18 and builds on the landmark resolution WHA68.8 adopted in 2015. 

Today, 99% of the world’s population breathes air that does not meet WHO air quality guidelines. The health burden from air pollution falls disproportionately on vulnerable and marginalized populations, particularly in low-resource settings where fragile health systems face compound challenges. 

Air p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>News (English) - World Health Organization</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Faster cancer treatment thanks to new radiotherapy machines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.gov.uk/government/news/faster-cancer-treatment-thanks-to-new-radiotherapy-machines</id>
        <link href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/faster-cancer-treatment-thanks-to-new-radiotherapy-machines"/>
        <updated>2025-05-26T06:14:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of cancer patients will see faster treatment thanks to new radiotherapy machines]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Department of Health and Social Care - Activity on GOV.UK</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>